<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35365910</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>02</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2826</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Mar</Month>
              <Day>15</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of neuroendocrinology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Neuroendocrinol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>The estrous cycle and 17β-estradiol modulate the electrophysiological properties of rat nucleus accumbens core medium spiny neurons.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e13122</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e13122</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jne.13122</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The nucleus accumbens core is a key nexus within the mammalian brain for integrating the premotor and limbic systems and regulating important cognitive functions such as motivated behaviors. Nucleus accumbens core functions show sex differences and are sensitive to the presence of hormones such as 17β-estradiol (estradiol) in normal and pathological contexts. The primary neuron type of the nucleus accumbens core, the medium spiny neuron (MSN), exhibits sex differences in both intrinsic excitability and glutamatergic excitatory synapse electrophysiological properties. Here, we provide a review of recent literature showing how estradiol modulates rat nucleus accumbens core MSN electrophysiology within the context of the estrous cycle. We review the changes in MSN electrophysiological properties across the estrous cycle and how these changes can be mimicked in response to exogenous estradiol exposure. We discuss in detail recent findings regarding how acute estradiol exposure rapidly modulates excitatory synapse properties in nucleus accumbens core but not caudate-putamen MSNs, which mirror the natural changes seen across estrous cycle phases. These recent insights demonstrate the strong impact of sex-specific estradiol action upon nucleus accumbens core neuron electrophysiology.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Authors. Journal of Neuroendocrinology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of British Society for Neuroendocrinology.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Krentzel</LastName>
            <ForeName>Amanda A</ForeName>
            <Initials>AA</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6332-6951</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biological Sciences, North Carolina State University, Raleigh, NC, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Proaño</LastName>
            <ForeName>Stephanie B</ForeName>
            <Initials>SB</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Neurobiology Laboratory, National Institute of Environmental Health Sciences, NIH, Research Triangle Park, NC, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Dorris</LastName>
            <ForeName>David M</ForeName>
            <Initials>DM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biological Sciences, North Carolina State University, Raleigh, NC, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Setzer</LastName>
            <ForeName>Beverly</ForeName>
            <Initials>B</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Graduate Program for Neuroscience and Department of Biomedical Engineering, Boston University, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Meitzen</LastName>
            <ForeName>John</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8860-4110</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biological Sciences, North Carolina State University, Raleigh, NC, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Comparative Medicine Institute, North Carolina State University, Raleigh, NC, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Center for Human Health and the Environment, North Carolina State University, Raleigh, NC, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <GrantList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>P30ES025128</GrantID>
            <Acronym>ES</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIEHS NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>R01MH109471</GrantID>
            <Acronym>MH</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIMH NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
        </GrantList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Neuroendocrinol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8913461</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0953-8194</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">estradiol</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">estrogen receptors</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">estrous cycle</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nucleus accumbens</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sex differences</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>28</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35365910</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jne.13122</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmidt KL, Pradhan DS, Shah AH, Charlier TD, Chin EH, Soma KK. Neurosteroids, immunosteroids, and the balkanization of endocrinology. Gen Comp Endocrinol. 2008;157(3):266-274.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Remage-Healey L. Frank Beach award winner: steroids as neuromodulators of brain circuits and behavior. Horm Behav. 2014;66(3):552-560.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wierman ME. Sex steroid effects at target tissues: mechanisms of action. Adv Physiol Educ. 2007;31(1):26-33.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rudolph LM, Cornil CA, Mittelman-Smith MA, et al. Actions of steroids: new neurotransmitters. J Neurosci. 2016;36(45):11449-11,458.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kelly MJ, Moss RL, Dudley CA. Differential sensitivity of preoptic-septal neurons to microelectrophoresed estrogen during the estrous cycle. Brain Res. 1976;114(1):152-157.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Szego CM, Davis JS. Adenosine 3′,5′-monophosphate in rat uterus: acute elevation by estrogen. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1967;58(4):1711-1718.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Almey A, Milner TA, Brake WG. Estrogen receptors in the central nervous system and their implication for dopamine-dependent cognition in females. Horm Behav. 2015;74:125-138.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Foidart AN, Harada N, Balthazart J. Aromatase-immunoreactive cells are present in mouse brain areas that are known to express high levels of aromatase activity. Cell Tissue Res. 1995;280(3):561-574.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stanic D, Dubois S, Chua HK, et al. Characterization of aromatase expression in the adult male and female mouse brain. I. Coexistence with oestrogen receptors alpha and beta, and androgen receptors. PLoS One. 2014;9(3):e90451.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Almey A, Filardo EJ, Milner TA, Brake WG. Estrogen receptors are found in glia and at Extranuclear neuronal sites in the dorsal striatum of female rats: evidence for cholinergic but not dopaminergic colocalization. Endocrinology. 2012;153:5373-5383.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grove-Strawser D, Boulware MI, Mermelstein PG. Membrane estrogen receptors activate the metabotropic glutamate receptors mGluR5 and mGluR3 to bidirectionally regulate CREB phosphorylation in female rat striatal neurons. Neuroscience. 2010;170:1045-1055.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mermelstein PG, Becker JB, Surmeier DJ. Estradiol reduces calcium currents in rat neostriatal neurons via a membrane receptor. J Neurosci. 1996;16(2):595-604.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schultz KN, von Esenwein SA, Hu M, et al. Viral vector-mediated overexpression of estrogen receptor-alpha in striatum enhances the estradiol-induced motor activity in female rats and estradiol-modulated GABA release. J Neurosci. 2009;29(6):1897-1903.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Almey A, Milner TA, Brake WG. Estrogen receptor alpha and G-protein coupled estrogen receptor 1 are localized to GABAergic neurons in the dorsal striatum. Neurosci Lett. 2016;622:118-123.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Le Saux M, Morissette M, Di Paolo T. ERbeta mediates the estradiol increase of D2 receptors in rat striatum and nucleus accumbens. Neuropharmacology. 2006;50(4):451-457.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Becker JB, Hu M. Sex differences in drug abuse. Front Neuroendocrinol. 2008;29(1):36-47.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meitzen J, Meisel RL, Mermelstein PG. Sex differences and the effects of estradiol on striatal function. Curr Opin Behav Sci. 2018;23:42-48.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yoest KE, Quigley JA, Becker JB. Rapid effects of ovarian hormones in dorsal striatum and nucleus accumbens. Horm Behav. 2018;104:119-129.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krentzel AA, Willett JA, Johnson AG, Meitzen J. Estrogen receptor alpha, G-protein coupled estrogen receptor 1, and aromatase: developmental, sex, and region-specific differences across the rat caudate-putamen, nucleus accumbens core and shell. J Comp Neurol. 2021;529(4):786-801.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Floresco SB. The nucleus accumbens: an interface between cognition, emotion, and action. Annu Rev Psychol. 2015;66:25-52.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Francis TC, Lobo MK. Emerging role for nucleus Accumbens medium spiny neuron subtypes in depression. Biol Psychiatry. 2017;81(8):645-653.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salgado S, Kaplitt MG. The nucleus Accumbens: a comprehensive review. Stereotact Funct Neurosurg. 2015;93(2):75-93.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yager LM, Garcia AF, Wunsch AM, Ferguson SM. The ins and outs of the striatum: role in drug addiction. Neuroscience. 2015;301:529-541.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Do J, Kim JI, Bakes J, Lee K, Kaang BK. Functional roles of neurotransmitters and neuromodulators in the dorsal striatum. Learn Mem. 2012;20(1):21-28.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rolls ET. Neurophysiology and cognitive functions of the striatum. Rev Neurol (Paris). 1994;150(8-9):648-660.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hampson E. Estrogen-related variations in human spatial and articulatory-motor skills. Psychoneuroendocrinology. 1990;15(2):97-111.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kent S, Hurd M, Satinoff E. Interactions between body temperature and wheel running over the estrous cycle in rats. Physiol Behav. 1991;49(6):1079-1084.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marcondes FK, Miguel KJ, Melo LL, Spadari-Bratfisch RC. Estrous cycle influences the response of female rats in the elevated plus-maze test. Physiol Behav. 2001;74(4-5):435-440.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wickens MM, Bangasser DA, Briand LA. Sex differences in psychiatric disease: a focus on the glutamate system. Front Mol Neurosci. 2018;11:197.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Picillo M, Nicoletti A, Fetoni V, Garavaglia B, Barone P, Pellecchia MT. The relevance of gender in Parkinson's disease: a review. J Neurol. 2017;264(8):1583-1607.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Young KA, Gobrogge KL, Liu Y, Wang Z. The neurobiology of pair bonding: insights from a socially monogamous rodent. Front Neuroendocrinol. 2011;32(1):53-69.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Becker JB, Prendergast BJ, Liang JW. Female rats are not more variable than male rats: a meta-analysis of neuroscience studies. Biol Sex Differ. 2016;7:34.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carroll ME, Anker JJ. Sex differences and ovarian hormones in animal models of drug dependence. Horm Behav. 2010;58(1):44-56.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lorsch ZS, Loh YE, Purushothaman I, et al. Estrogen receptor alpha drives pro-resilient transcription in mouse models of depression. Nat Commun. 2018;9(1):1116.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Becker JB, Chartoff E. Sex differences in neural mechanisms mediating reward and addiction. Neuropsychopharmacology. 2019;44(1):166-183.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krentzel AA, Meitzen J. Biological sex, estradiol and striatal medium spiny neuron physiology: a mini-review. Front Cell Neurosci. 2018;12:492.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beatty WW. Gonadal hormones and sex differences in nonreproductive behaviors in rodents: organizational and activational influences. Horm Behav. 1979;12(2):112-163.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Becker, J.B. Hormonal influences on sensorimotor function. In: J.B. Becker, Breedlove, S.M., Crews, D., McCarthy, M. M., eds. Behavioral Endocrinology. 2002, MIT Press. p. 497-525.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bobzean SA, DeNobrega AK, Perrotti LI. Sex differences in the neurobiology of drug addiction. Exp Neurol. 2014;259C:64-74.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Davis DM, Jacobson TK, Aliakbari S, Mizumori SJ. Differential effects of estrogen on hippocampal- and striatal-dependent learning. Neurobiol Learn Mem. 2005;84(2):132-137.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fattore L, Melis M, Fadda P, Fratta W. Sex differences in addictive disorders. Front Neuroendocrinol. 2014;35:272-284.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pavon JM, Whitson HE, Okun MS. Parkinson's disease in women: a call for improved clinical studies and for comparative effectiveness research. Maturitas. 2010;65(4):352-358.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zurkovsky L, Brown SL, Boyd SE, Fell JA, Korol DL. Estrogen modulates learning in female rats by acting directly at distinct memory systems. Neuroscience. 2007;144(1):26-37.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Di Paolo T. Modulation of brain dopamine transmission by sex steroids. Rev Neurosci. 1994;5(1):27-41.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Becker JB, Perry AN, Westenbroek C. Sex differences in the neural mechanisms mediating addiction: a new synthesis and hypothesis. Biol Sex Differ. 2013;3(1):14.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Walker QD, Ray R, Kuhn CM. Sex differences in neurochemical effects of dopaminergic drugs in rat striatum. Neuropsychopharmacology. 2006;31(6):1193-1202.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Calipari ES, Juarez B, Morel C, et al. Dopaminergic dynamics underlying sex-specific cocaine reward. Nat Commun. 2017;8:13877.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bonansco C, Martínez-Pinto J, Silva RA, et al. Neonatal exposure to oestradiol increases dopaminergic transmission in nucleus accumbens and morphine-induced conditioned place preference in adult female rats. J Neuroendocrinol. 2018;30(7):e12574.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alonso-Caraballo Y, Ferrario CR. Effects of the estrous cycle and ovarian hormones on cue-triggered motivation and intrinsic excitability of medium spiny neurons in the nucleus Accumbens core of female rats. Horm Behav. 2019;116:104583.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kopec AM, Smith CJ, Ayre NR, Sweat SC, Bilbo SD. Microglial dopamine receptor elimination defines sex-specific nucleus accumbens development and social behavior in adolescent rats. Nat Commun. 2018;9(1):3769.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beery AK, Zucker I. Sex bias in neuroscience and biomedical research. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2011;35(3):565-572.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tannenbaum C, Ellis RP, Eyssel F, Zou J, Schiebinger L. Sex and gender analysis improves science and engineering. Nature. 2019;575(7781):137-146.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Galea LAM, Choleris E, Albert AYK, McCarthy MM, Sohrabji F. The promises and pitfalls of sex difference research. Front Neuroendocrinol. 2020;56:100817.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mamlouk GM, Dorris DM, Barrett LR, Meitzen J. Sex bias and omission in neuroscience research is influenced by research model and journal, but not reported NIH funding. Front Neuroendocrinol. 2020;57:100835.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Will TR, Proaño SB, Thomas AM, et al. Problems and progress regarding sex bias and omission in neuroscience research. eNeuro. 2017;4(6):ENEURO.0278-17.2017.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Becker JB. Direct effect of 17 beta-estradiol on striatum: sex differences in dopamine release. Synapse. 1990;5(2):157-164.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Becker JB. Gender differences in dopaminergic function in striatum and nucleus accumbens. Pharmacol Biochem Behav. 1999;64(4):803-812.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bédard PJ, Malouin F, Dipaolo T, Labrie F. Estradiol, TRH and striatal dopaminergic mechanisms. Prog Neuropsychopharmacol Biol Psychiatry. 1982;6(4-6):555-561.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bosse R, DiPaolo T. The modulation of brain dopamine and GABAA receptors by estradiol: a clue for CNS changes occurring at menopause. Cell Mol Neurobiol. 1996;16(2):199-212.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xiao L, Becker JB. Quantitative microdialysis determination of extracellular striatal dopamine concentration in male and female rats: effects of estrous cycle and gonadectomy. Neurosci Lett. 1994;180(2):155-158.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Russo G, Nieus TR, Maggi S, Taverna S. Dynamics of action potential firing in electrically connected striatal fast-spiking interneurons. Front Cell Neurosci. 2013;7:209.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scofield MD, Heinsbroek JA, Gipson CD, et al. The nucleus Accumbens: mechanisms of addiction across drug classes reflect the importance of glutamate homeostasis. Pharmacol Rev. 2016;68(3):816-871.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mulder AB, Hodenpijl MG, Lopes da Silva FH. Electrophysiology of the hippocampal and amygdaloid projections to the nucleus accumbens of the rat: convergence, segregation, and interaction of inputs. J Neurosci. 1998;18(13):5095-5102.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>O'Donnell P, Grace AA. Synaptic interactions among excitatory afferents to nucleus accumbens neurons: hippocampal gating of prefrontal cortical input. J Neurosci. 1995;15(5 Pt 1):3622-3639.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Britt JP, Benaliouad F, McDevitt RA, Stuber GD, Wise RA, Bonci A. Synaptic and behavioral profile of multiple glutamatergic inputs to the nucleus accumbens. Neuron. 2012;76(4):790-803.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Papp E, Borhegyi Z, Tomioka R, Rockland KS, Mody I, Freund TF. Glutamatergic input from specific sources influences the nucleus accumbens-ventral pallidum information flow. Brain Struct Funct. 2012;217(1):37-48.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sesack SR, Carr DB, Omelchenko N, Pinto A. Anatomical substrates for glutamate-dopamine interactions: evidence for specificity of connections and extrasynaptic actions. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2003;1003:36-52.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stuber GD, Sparta DR, Stamatakis AM, et al. Excitatory transmission from the amygdala to nucleus accumbens facilitates reward seeking. Nature. 2011;475(7356):377-380.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dorris DM, Cao J, Willett JA, Hauser CA, Meitzen J. Intrinsic excitability varies by sex in pre-pubertal striatal medium spiny neurons. J Neurophysiol. 2015;113(3):720-729.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cao J, Dorris DM, Meitzen J. Neonatal masculinization blocks increased excitatory synaptic input in female rat nucleus Accumbens Core. Endocrinology. 2016;157(8):3181-3196.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cao J, Willett JA, Dorris DM, Meitzen J. Sex differences in medium spiny neuron excitability and glutamatergic synaptic input: heterogeneity across striatal regions and evidence for estradiol-dependent sexual differentiation. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne). 2018;9:173.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Willett JA, Will T, Hauser CA, Dorris DM, Cao J, Meitzen J. No evidence for sex differences in the electrophysiological properties and excitatory synaptic input onto nucleus Accumbens Shell medium spiny neurons. eNeuro. 2016;3(1):pii: ENEURO.0147-15.2016.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Willett JA, Cao J, Johnson A, Patel OH, Dorris DM, Meitzen J. The estrous cycle modulates rat caudate-putamen medium spiny neuron physiology. Eur J Neurosci. 2020;52(1):2737-2755.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Proaño SB, Krentzel AA, Meitzen J. Differential and synergistic roles of 17β-estradiol and progesterone in modulating adult female rat nucleus accumbens core medium spiny neuron electrophysiology. J Neurophysiol. 2020;123(6):2390-2405.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Proano SB, Morris HJ, Kunz LM, Dorris DM, Meitzen J. Estrous cycle-induced sex differences in medium spiny neuron excitatory synaptic transmission and intrinsic excitability in adult rat nucleus accumbens core. J Neurophysiol. 2018;120(3):1356-1373.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Forlano PM, Woolley CS. Quantitative analysis of pre- and postsynaptic sex differences in the nucleus accumbens. J Comp Neurol. 2010;518(8):1330-1348.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wissman AM, McCollum AF, Huang GZ, Nikrodhanond AA, Woolley CS. Sex differences and effects of cocaine on excitatory synapses in the nucleus accumbens. Neuropharmacology. 2011;61:217-227.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wissman AM, May RM, Woolley CS. Ultrastructural analysis of sex differences in nucleus accumbens synaptic connectivity. Brain Struct Funct. 2012;217(2):181-190.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sazdanovic M, Slobodanka M, Zivanovic-Macuzic I, et al. Sexual dimorphism of medium-sized neurons with spines in human nucleus accumbens. Arch Biol Sci. 2013;65(3):1149-1155.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peterson BM, Mermelstein PG, Meisel RL. Estradiol mediates dendritic spine plasticity in the nucleus accumbens core through activation of mGluR5. Brain Struct Funct. 2015;220(4):2415-2422.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Staffend NA, Loftus CM, Meisel RL. Estradiol reduces dendritic spine density in the ventral striatum of female Syrian hamsters. Brain Struct Funct. 2011;215(3-4):187-194.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sherman BM, Korenman SG. Hormonal characteristics of the human menstrual cycle throughout reproductive life. J Clin Invest. 1975;55(4):699-706.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Erskine MS. Solicitation behavior in the estrous female rat: a review. Horm Behav. 1989;23(4):473-502.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hubscher CH, Brooks DL, Johnson JR. A quantitative method for assessing stages of the rat estrous cycle. Biotech Histochem. 2005;80(2):79-87.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Westwood FR. The female rat reproductive cycle: a practical histological guide to staging. Toxicol Pathol. 2008;36(3):375-384.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beach FA. Sexual attractivity, proceptivity, and receptivity in female mammals. Horm Behav. 1976;7(1):105-138.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blaustein JD. Neuroendocrine regulation of feminine sexual behavior: lessons from rodent models and thoughts about humans. Annu Rev Psychol. 2008;59:93-118.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kow LM, Pfaff DW. Effects of estrogen treatment on the size of receptive field and response threshold of pudendal nerve in the female rat. Neuroendocrinology. 1973;13(4):299-313.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Micevych PE, Meisel RL. Integrating neural circuits controlling female sexual behavior. Front Syst Neurosci. 2017;11:42.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Adams C, Chen X, Moenter SM. Changes in GABAergic transmission to and intrinsic excitability of gonadotropin-releasing hormone (GnRH) neurons during the Estrous Cycle in Mice. eNeuro. 2018;5(5):ENEURO.0171-18.2018.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shansky RM. Are hormones a “female problem” for animal research? Science. 2019;364(6443):825-826.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Prendergast BJ, Onishi KG, Zucker I. Female mice liberated for inclusion in neuroscience and biomedical research. Neurosci Biobehav Rev. 2014;40C:1-5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yoest KE, Cummings JA, Becker JB. Estradiol, dopamine and motivation. Cent Nerv Syst Agents Med Chem. 2014;14(2):83-89.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blume SR, Freedberg M, Vantrease JE, et al. Sex- and estrus-dependent differences in rat basolateral amygdala. J Neurosci. 2017;37(44):10567-10,586.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Olmos G, Naftolin F, Perez J, Tranque PA, Garcia-Segura LM. Synaptic remodeling in the rat arcuate nucleus during the estrous cycle. Neuroscience. 1989;32(3):663-667.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Terasawa E, Timiras PS. Electrical activity during the estrous cycle of the rat: cyclic changes in limbic structures. Endocrinology. 1968;83(2):207-216.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Woolley CS, McEwen BS. Roles of estradiol and progesterone in regulation of hippocampal dendritic spine density during the estrous cycle in the rat. J Comp Neurol. 1993;336(2):293-306.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schulz DJ. Plasticity and stability in neuronal output via changes in intrinsic excitability: it's what's inside that counts. J Exp Biol. 2006;209(Pt 24):4821-4827.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dong Y, Green T, Saal D, et al. CREB modulates excitability of nucleus accumbens neurons. Nat Neurosci. 2006;9(4):475-477.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ferguson SM, Eskenazi D, Ishikawa M, et al. Transient neuronal inhibition reveals opposing roles of indirect and direct pathways in sensitization. Nat Neurosci. 2011;14(1):22-24.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grillner S, Hellgren J, Menard A, Saitoh K, Wikstrom MA. Mechanisms for selection of basic motor programs--roles for the striatum and pallidum. Trends Neurosci. 2005;28(7):364-370.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kourrich S, Thomas MJ. Similar neurons, opposite adaptations: psychostimulant experience differentially alters firing properties in accumbens core versus shell. J Neurosci. 2009;29(39):12275-12283.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mu P, Moyer JT, Ishikawa M, et al. Exposure to cocaine dynamically regulates the intrinsic membrane excitability of nucleus accumbens neurons. J Neurosci. 2010;30(10):3689-3699.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tan CL, Plotkin JL, Veno MT, et al. MicroRNA-128 governs neuronal excitability and motor behavior in mice. Science. 2013;342(6163):1254-1258.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Werme M, Messer C, Olson L, et al. Delta FosB regulates wheel running. J Neurosci. 2002;22(18):8133-8138.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Proaño SB, Meitzen J. Estradiol decreases medium spiny neuron excitability in female rat nucleus accumbens core. J Neurophysiol. 2020;123(6):2465-2475.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scharfman HE, Hintz TM, Gomez J, et al. Changes in hippocampal function of ovariectomized rats after sequential low doses of estradiol to simulate the preovulatory estrogen surge. Eur J Neurosci. 2007;26(9):2595-2612.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gross KS, Mermelstein PG. Estrogen receptor signaling through metabotropic glutamate receptors. Vitam Horm. 2020;114:211-232.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zakon HH. The effects of steroid hormones on electrical activity of excitable cells. Trends Neurosci. 1998;21(5):202-207.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Constantin S, Moenter SM, Piet R. The electrophysiologic properties of gonadotropin-releasing hormone neurons. J Neuroendocrinol. 2021;e13073. Online ahead of print.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vail G, Roepke TA. Membrane-initiated estrogen signaling via Gq-coupled GPCR in the central nervous system. Steroids. 2019;142:77-83.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krentzel AA, Barrett LR, Meitzen J. Estradiol rapidly modulates excitatory synapse properties in a sex- and region-specific manner in rat nucleus accumbens core and caudate-putamen. J Neurophysiol. 2019;122(3):1213-1225.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peterson BM, Martinez LA, Meisel RL, Mermelstein PG. Estradiol impacts the endocannabinoid system in female rats to influence behavioral and structural responses to cocaine. Neuropharmacology. 2016;110:118-124.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meitzen J, Pflepsen KR, Stern CM, Meisel RL, Mermelstein PG. Measurements of neuron soma size and density in rat dorsal striatum, nucleus accumbens core and nucleus accumbens shell: differences between striatal region and brain hemisphere, but not sex. Neurosci Lett. 2011;487(2):177-181.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wong JE, Cao J, Dorris DM, Meitzen J. Genetic sex and the volumes of the caudate-putamen, nucleus accumbens core and shell: original data and a review. Brain Struct Funct. 2016;221(8):4257-4267.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Becker JB, Rudick CN. Rapid effects of estrogen or progesterone on the amphetamine-induced increase in striatal dopamine are enhanced by estrogen priming: a microdialysis study. Pharmacol Biochem Behav. 1999;64(1):53-57.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krentzel AA, Proano S, Patisaul HB, Meitzen J. Temporal and bidirectional influences of estradiol on voluntary wheel running in adult female and male rats. Horm Behav. 2020;120:104694.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miller CK, Krentzel AA, Patisaul HB, Meitzen J. Metabotropic glutamate receptor subtype 5 (mGlu5) is necessary for estradiol mitigation of light-induced anxiety behavior in female rats. Physiol Behav. 2020;214:112770.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Turrigiano G. Homeostatic synaptic plasticity: local and global mechanisms for stabilizing neuronal function. Cold Spring Harb Perspect Biol. 2012;4(1):a005736.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tien NW, Kerschensteiner D. Homeostatic plasticity in neural development. Neural Dev. 2018;13(1):9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tonn Eisinger KR, Larson EB, Boulware MI, Thomas MJ, Mermelstein PG. Membrane estrogen receptor signaling impacts the reward circuitry of the female brain to influence motivated behaviors. Steroids. 2018;133:53-59.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jenkins WJ, Becker JB. Role of the striatum and nucleus accumbens in paced copulatory behavior in the female rat. Behav Brain Res. 2001;121(1-2):119-128.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meisel RL, Mullins AJ. Sexual experience in female rodents: cellular mechanisms and functional consequences. Brain Res. 2006;1126(1):56-65.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miller CK, Halbing AA, Patisaul HB, Meitzen J. Interactions of the estrous cycle, novelty, and light on female and male rat open field locomotor and anxiety-related behaviors. Physiol Behav. 2021;228:113203.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krentzel AA, Kimble LC, Dorris DM, Horman BM, Meitzen J, Patisaul HB. FireMaster® 550 (FM 550) exposure during the perinatal period impacts partner preference behavior and nucleus accumbens core medium spiny neuron electrophysiology in adult male and female prairie voles, Microtus ochrogaster. Horm Behav. 2021;134:105019.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Willett JA, Johnson AG, Vogel AR, Patisaul HB, McGraw LA, Meitzen J. Nucleus accumbens core medium spiny neuron electrophysiological properties and partner preference behavior in the adult male prairie vole, Microtus ochrogaster. J Neurophysiol. 2018;119(4):1576-1588.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cao J, Dorris DM, Meitzen J. Electrophysiological properties of medium spiny neurons in the nucleus accumbens core of prepubertal male and female Drd1a-tdTomato line 6 BAC transgenic mice. J Neurophysiol. 2018;120(4):1712-1727.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Willett JA, Cao J, Dorris DM, Johnson AG, Ginnari LA, Meitzen J. Electrophysiological properties of medium spiny neuron subtypes in the caudate-putamen of Prepubertal male and female Drd1a-tdTomato line 6 BAC transgenic mice. eNeuro. 2019;6(2):pii: ENEURO.0016-19.2019.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kupchik YM, Brown RM, Heinsbroek JA, Lobo MK, Schwartz DJ, Kalivas PW. Coding the direct/indirect pathways by D1 and D2 receptors is not valid for accumbens projections. Nat Neurosci. 2015;18(9):1230-1232.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Delevich K, Hall CD, Wilbrecht L. Prepubertal ovariectomy alters dorsomedial striatum indirect pathway neuron excitability and explore/exploit balance in female mice. bioRxiv. 2021; Preprint.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Quigley JA, Becker JB. Activation of G-protein coupled estradiol receptor 1 in the dorsolateral striatum attenuates preference for cocaine and saccharin in male but not female rats. Horm Behav. 2021;130:104949.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oberlander JG, Woolley CS. 17β-estradiol acutely potentiates glutamatergic synaptic transmission in the hippocampus through distinct mechanisms in males and females. J Neurosci. 2016;36(9):2677-2690.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Becker JB, Snyder PJ, Miller MM, Westgate SA, Jenuwine MJ. The influence of estrous cycle and intrastriatal estradiol on sensorimotor performance in the female rat. Pharmacol Biochem Behav. 1987;27(1):53-59.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tansey EM, Arbuthnott GW, Fink G, Whale D. Oestradiol-17 beta increases the firing rate of antidromically identified neurones of the rat neostriatum. Neuroendocrinology. 1983;37(2):106-110.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arnauld E, Dufy B, Pestre M, Vincent JD. Effects of estrogens on the responses of caudate neurons to microiontophoretically applied dopamine. Neurosci Lett. 1981;21(3):325-331.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cao J, Meitzen J. Perinatal activation of ERα and ERβ but not GPER-1 masculinizes female rat caudate-putamen medium spiny neuron electrophysiological properties. J Neurophysiol. 2021;125(6):2322-2338.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lipscombe D, Helton TD, Xu W. L-type calcium channels: the low down. J Neurophysiol. 2004;92(5):2633-2641.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hu M, Watson CJ, Kennedy RT, Becker JB. Estradiol attenuates the K+-induced increase in extracellular GABA in rat striatum. Synapse. 2006;59(2):122-124.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tozzi A, de Iure A, Tantucci M, et al. Endogenous 17beta-estradiol is required for activity-dependent long-term potentiation in the striatum: interaction with the dopaminergic system. Front Cell Neurosci. 2015;9:192.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Remage-Healey L. Brain estrogen signaling effects acute modulation of acoustic communication behaviors: a working hypothesis. Bioessays. 2012;34:1009-1016.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brenowitz EA, Lent K. Afferent input is necessary for seasonal growth and maintenance of adult avian song control circuits. J Neurosci. 2001;21(7):2320-2329.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brenowitz EA, Lent K. Act locally and think globally: intracerebral testosterone implants induce seasonal-like growth of adult avian song control circuits. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2002;99(19):12421-12426.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Euvrard C, Labrie F, Boissier JR. Effect of estrogen on changes in the activity of striatal cholinergic neurons induced by DA drugs. Brain Res. 1979;169(1):215-220.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Labonté B, Engmann O, Purushothaman I, et al. Sex-specific transcriptional signatures in human depression. Nat Med. 2017;23(9):1102-1111.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnson AR, Thibeault KC, Lopez AJ, et al. Cues play a critical role in estrous cycle-dependent enhancement of cocaine reinforcement. Neuropsychopharmacology. 2019;44(7):1189-1197.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
