<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35363645</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1532-0987</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>41</Volume>
            <Issue>6</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
              <Day>01</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>The Pediatric infectious disease journal</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Pediatr Infect Dis J</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Differences in Bacterial Colonization and Mucosal Responses Between High and Low SES Children in Indonesia.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>496</StartPage>
          <EndPage>506</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>496-506</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/INF.0000000000003525</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">Increased nasopharyngeal carriage of pathogenic bacteria is found in low socioeconomic status (SES) settings. How SES affects local immune responses, important for controlling colonization, is currently unknown.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE">Examining bacterial colonization and cytokine response in the nasal mucosa of children from high and low SES.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS">Nasosorption samples were collected in October 2019 from 48 high SES and 50 low SES schoolchildren, in a cross-sectional study in Makassar, Indonesia. Twenty-five cytokines were measured in nasal fluid. Quantitative polymerase chain reaction was performed to determine carriage and density of Haemophilus influenzae, Streptococcus pneumoniae, Moraxella catarrhalis and Staphylococcus aureus. Data were analyzed using multivariate regression.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS">H. influenzae and S. pneumoniae densities were increased in low SES settings compared to the high SES settings (P = 0.006, P = 0.026), with 6 and 67 times higher median densities, respectively. Densities of H. influenzae and S. pneumoniae were positively associated with levels of IL-1beta and IL-6. After correcting for bacterial density, IL-6 levels were higher in colonized children from high SES than low SES for H. influenzae and S. pneumoniae (both P = 0.039).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION">Increased densities of H. influenzae and S. pneumoniae were observed in low SES children, whereas IL-6 levels associated with colonization were reduced in these children, indicating that immune responses to bacterial colonization were altered by SES.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022 The Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>van Dorst</LastName>
            <ForeName>Marloes M A R</ForeName>
            <Initials>MMAR</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>From the Department of Parasitology, Leiden University Center for Infectious Diseases (LU-CID), Leiden University Medical Center, Leiden, The Netherlands.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Azimi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Shohreh</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>From the Department of Parasitology, Leiden University Center for Infectious Diseases (LU-CID), Leiden University Medical Center, Leiden, The Netherlands.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wahyuni</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sitti</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Parasitology, Faculty of Medicine, Hasanuddin University, Makassar, Indonesia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Amaruddin</LastName>
            <ForeName>Aldian I</ForeName>
            <Initials>AI</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>From the Department of Parasitology, Leiden University Center for Infectious Diseases (LU-CID), Leiden University Medical Center, Leiden, The Netherlands.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Parasitology, Faculty of Medicine, Hasanuddin University, Makassar, Indonesia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sartono</LastName>
            <ForeName>Erliyani</ForeName>
            <Initials>E</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>From the Department of Parasitology, Leiden University Center for Infectious Diseases (LU-CID), Leiden University Medical Center, Leiden, The Netherlands.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wammes</LastName>
            <ForeName>Linda J</ForeName>
            <Initials>LJ</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medical Microbiology, Leiden University Medical Center, Leiden, the Netherlands.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yazdanbakhsh</LastName>
            <ForeName>Maria</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>From the Department of Parasitology, Leiden University Center for Infectious Diseases (LU-CID), Leiden University Medical Center, Leiden, The Netherlands.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Jochems</LastName>
            <ForeName>Simon P</ForeName>
            <Initials>SP</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4835-1032</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>From the Department of Parasitology, Leiden University Center for Infectious Diseases (LU-CID), Leiden University Medical Center, Leiden, The Netherlands.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>06</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Pediatr Infect Dis J</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8701858</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0891-3668</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D015850">Interleukin-6</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002353" MajorTopicYN="Y">Carrier State</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="N">microbiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003430" MajorTopicYN="N">Cross-Sectional Studies</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006193" MajorTopicYN="N">Haemophilus influenzae</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007214" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Indonesia</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007223" MajorTopicYN="N">Infant</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015850" MajorTopicYN="Y">Interleukin-6</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009297" MajorTopicYN="N">Nasal Mucosa</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009305" MajorTopicYN="N">Nasopharynx</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="N">microbiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013296" MajorTopicYN="N">Streptococcus pneumoniae</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors have no conflicts of interest to declare.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
          <Hour>17</Hour>
          <Minute>14</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35363645</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/INF.0000000000003525</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">00006454-990000000-00008</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Collaborators GBDCoD. Global, regional, and national age-sex specific mortality for 264 causes of death, 1980-2016: a systematic analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2016. Lancet. 2017;390:1151–1210.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Collaborators GBDLRI. Estimates of the global, regional, and national morbidity, mortality, and aetiologies of lower respiratory infections in 195 countries, 1990-2016: a systematic analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2016. Lancet Infect Dis. 2018;18:1191–1210.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Simell B, Auranen K, Käyhty H, et al.; Pneumococcal Carriage Group. The fundamental link between pneumococcal carriage and disease. Expert Rev Vaccines. 2012;11:841–855.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mackenzie GA, Leach AJ, Carapetis JR, et al. Epidemiology of nasopharyngeal carriage of respiratory bacterial pathogens in children and adults: cross-sectional surveys in a population with high rates of pneumococcal disease. BMC Infect Dis. 2010;10:304.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>von Eiff C, Becker K, Machka K, et al. Nasal carriage as a source of Staphylococcus aureus bacteremia. N Engl J Med. 2001;344:11–16.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chochua S, D’Acremont V, Hanke C, et al. Increased nasopharyngeal density and concurrent carriage of streptococcus pneumoniae, haemophilus influenzae, and moraxella catarrhalis are associated with pneumonia in febrile children. PLoS One. 2016;11:e0167725.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Park DE, Baggett HC, Howie SRC, et al.; PERCH Study Group. Colonization density of the upper respiratory tract as a predictor of pneumonia-Haemophilus influenzae, Moraxella catarrhalis, Staphylococcus aureus, and Pneumocystis jirovecii. Clin Infect Dis. 2017;64(suppl_3):S328–S336.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cole AL, Muthukrishnan G, Chong C, et al. Host innate inflammatory factors and staphylococcal protein A influence the duration of human Staphylococcus aureus nasal carriage. Mucosal Immunol. 2016;9:1537–1548.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liao SL, Hsu SY, Lai SH, et al. Infant anemia is associated with reduced TLR-stimulated cytokine responses and increased nasopharyngeal colonization with Moxarella catarrhalis. Sci Rep. 2018;8:4897.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kuipers K, Lokken KL, Zangari T, et al. Age-related differences in IL-1 signaling and capsule serotype affect persistence of Streptococcus pneumoniae colonization. PLoS Pathog. 2018;14:e1007396.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Adegbola RA, DeAntonio R, Hill PC, et al. Carriage of Streptococcus pneumoniae and other respiratory bacterial pathogens in low and lower-middle income countries: a systematic review and meta-analysis. PLoS One. 2014;9:e103293.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hanieh S, Hamaluba M, Kelly DF, et al. Streptococcus pneumoniae carriage prevalence in Nepal: evaluation of a method for delayed transport of samples from remote regions and implications for vaccine implementation. PLoS One. 2014;9:e98739.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dagan R, Juergens C, Trammel J, et al. Modeling pneumococcal nasopharyngeal acquisition as a function of anticapsular serum antibody concentrations after pneumococcal conjugate vaccine administration. Vaccine. 2016;34:4313–4320.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fadlyana E, Dunne EM, Rusmil K, et al. Risk factors associated with nasopharyngeal carriage and density of Streptococcus pneumoniae, Haemophilus influenzae, Moraxella catarrhalis, and Staphylococcus aureus in young children living in Indonesia. Pneumonia (Nathan). 2018;10:14.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wahyuni S, van Dorst MMAR, Amaruddin AI, et al. The relationship between malnutrition and TH 2 immune markers: a study in school-aged children of different socio-economic backgrounds in Makassar, Indonesia. Trop Med Int Health. 2021;26:195–203.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thwaites RS, Jarvis HC, Singh N, et al. Absorption of nasal and bronchial fluids: precision sampling of the human respiratory mucosa and laboratory processing of samples. J Vis Exp. 2018:e56413.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nikolaou E, Blizard A, Pojar S, et al. Minimally invasive nasal sampling in children offers accurate pneumococcal colonization detection. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2019;38:1147–1149.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Olwagen CP, Adrian PV, Nunes MC, et al. Evaluation of the association of pneumococcal conjugate vaccine immunization and density of nasopharyngeal bacterial colonization using a multiplex quantitative polymerase chain reaction assay. Vaccine. 2018;36:3278–3285.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bogaert D, Keijser B, Huse S, et al. Variability and diversity of nasopharyngeal microbiota in children: a metagenomic analysis. PLoS One. 2011;6:e17035.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Onis M, Onyango AW, Borghi E, et al. Development of a WHO growth reference for school-aged children and adolescents. Bull World Health Organ. 2007;85:660–667.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gonzalez I, Dejean S, Martin PGP, et al. CCA: an R package to extend canonical correlation analysis. J Stat Softw. 2008;23:1–14.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Margolis E, Yates A, Levin BR. The ecology of nasal colonization of Streptococcus pneumoniae, Haemophilus influenzae and Staphylococcus aureus: the role of competition and interactions with host’s immune response. BMC Microbiol. 2010;10:59.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chien YW, Vidal JE, Grijalva CG, et al. Density interactions among Streptococcus pneumoniae, Haemophilus influenzae and Staphylococcus aureus in the nasopharynx of young Peruvian children. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2013;32:72–77.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lemon JK, Miller MR, Weiser JN. Sensing of interleukin-1 cytokines during Streptococcus pneumoniae colonization contributes to macrophage recruitment and bacterial clearance. Infect Immun. 2015;83:3204–3212.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pizzutto SJ, Upham JW, Yerkovich ST, et al. High pulmonary levels of IL-6 and IL-1β in children with chronic suppurative lung disease are associated with low systemic IFN-γ production in response to non-typeable haemophilus influenzae. PLoS One. 2015;10:e0129517.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Law AE, Shears RK, Lopez Rodas AA, et al. Intestinal helminth co-infection is an unrecognised risk factor for increased pneumococcal carriage density and invasive disease. Sci Rep. 2021;11:6984.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tarafder MR, Carabin H, Joseph L, et al. Estimating the sensitivity and specificity of Kato-Katz stool examination technique for detection of hookworms, Ascaris lumbricoides and Trichuris trichiura infections in humans in the absence of a ‘gold standard’. Int J Parasitol. 2010;40:399–404.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang Z, Clarke TB, Weiser JN. Cellular effectors mediating Th17-dependent clearance of pneumococcal colonization in mice. J Clin Invest. 2009;119:1899–1909.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jiang XL, Zhang GL, Yang T, et al. Association of pneumococcal carriage and expression of Foxp3+ regulatory T cells and Th17 cells in the adenoids of children. Respiration. 2015;90:25–32.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dunne EM, Murad C, Sudigdoadi S, et al. Carriage of Streptococcus pneumoniae, Haemophilus influenzae, Moraxella catarrhalis, and Staphylococcus aureus in Indonesian children: a cross-sectional study. PLoS One. 2018;13:e0195098.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gessner BD, Sutanto A, Linehan M, et al. Incidences of vaccine-preventable Haemophilus influenzae type b pneumonia and meningitis in Indonesian children: hamlet-randomised vaccine-probe trial. Lancet. 2005;365:43–52.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carrión D, Kaali S, Kinney PL, et al. Examining the relationship between household air pollution and infant microbial nasal carriage in a Ghanaian cohort. Environ Int. 2019;133(Pt A):105150.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
