<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35363113</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>05</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>06</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1521-0464</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>29</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Dec</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Drug delivery</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Drug Deliv</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Gemcitabine cationic polymeric nanoparticles against ovarian cancer: formulation, characterization, and targeted drug delivery.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>1060</StartPage>
          <EndPage>1074</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>1060-1074</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1080/10717544.2022.2058645</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>This study focused on gemcitabine (GTB) delivery of cationic polymeric nanoparticles to treat ovarian cancer in order to promote effective localized delivery and drug retention during biological discharge. To begin, four GTB-loaded polymer nanoparticles were prepared: chitosan nanoparticles (CS-NPs), polysarcosin nanoparticles (PSar-NPs), poly-l-lysine &amp; polysarcosin nanoparticles (PLL-PSar-NPs), and chitosan &amp; polysarcosin nanoparticles (CS-PSar-NPs). Based on preliminary particle size, zeta potential, encapsulation efficiency, DSC, surface morphology, release profiling, and cellular internalization studies using rhodamine 123 and Nile red fluorescent markers, it was hypothesized that CS-PSar-NPs could be the best cationic formulation with strong biocompatibility and anticancer activity against the OVCAR-8 ovarian cancer cell line. To improve effective targeting, cellular penetration, and <i>in vitro</i> cytotoxicity, epidermal growth factor receptor variation III (EGFRvIII) is attached over all four polymeric nanoparticles. Confocal imaging revealed that EGFRvIII-conjugated cationic GTB polymeric nanoparticles had a greater cellular uptake and double internalization capabilities than unconjugated nanoparticles, as well as time-dependent cell entrance. GTB and EGFRvIII-conjugated polymer nanoparticles would have a stronger potential to infiltrate ovarian cancer cells during the first hour of incubation. According to TEM and FTIR findings, EGFRvIII conjugation across the non-target CS-PSar-NP surface was successful, making CS-PSar-NPS-EGFRvIII more target-specific and thus a safer drug delivery candidate for ovarian cancer treatment.HighlightsGTB loaded non-target CS-PSar-NPs &amp; active targeted CS-PSar-NPs-EGFRvII developed.SEM, AFM, DSC, particle size, zeta potential, internalization performed for CS-PSar-NPs.MTT &amp; CLSM study confirmed CS-PSar-NPS-EGFRvII was binding specific to OVCAR-8 cellsFabrication of EGFRvII over nanoparticles confirmed by TEM.CS-PSar-NPS-EGFRvII safer candidate for ovarian cancer.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bhattacharya</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sankha</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0771-9582</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutics, School of Pharmacy &amp; Technology Management, SVKM'S NMIMS Deemed-to-be University, Shirpur, Maharashtra, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Anjum</LastName>
            <ForeName>Md Meraj</ForeName>
            <Initials>MM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutical Engineering &amp; Technology, Indian Institute of Technology (Banaras Hindu University), Varanasi, Uttar Pradesh, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Patel</LastName>
            <ForeName>Krishna Kumar</ForeName>
            <Initials>KK</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutical Engineering &amp; Technology, Indian Institute of Technology (Banaras Hindu University), Varanasi, Uttar Pradesh, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Drug Deliv</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9417471</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1071-7544</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D004337">Drug Carriers</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0W860991D6</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D003841">Deoxycytidine</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>9012-76-4</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D048271">Chitosan</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>B76N6SBZ8R</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="C056507">gemcitabine</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D048271" MajorTopicYN="Y">Chitosan</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003841" MajorTopicYN="N">Deoxycytidine</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000031" MajorTopicYN="N">analogs &amp; derivatives</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004337" MajorTopicYN="N">Drug Carriers</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D053758" MajorTopicYN="Y">Nanoparticles</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D010051" MajorTopicYN="Y">Ovarian Neoplasms</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">EGFR vIII</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gemcitabine</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">OVCAR-8</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">confocal microscopy</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">polysarcosin</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no established competitive financial interests or personal relationships that may have influenced analyzing this paper.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>16</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35363113</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8979509</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10717544.2022.2058645</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abakumov MA, Nukolova NV, Sokolsky-Papkov M, et al.  (2015). VEGF-targeted magnetic nanoparticles for MRI visualization of brain tumor. Nanomedicine
11:825–33.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25652902</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Anjum MM, Patel KK, Pandey N, et al.  (2019). Development of Anacardic acid/hydroxypropyl-β-cyclodextrin inclusion complex with enhanced solubility and antimicrobial activity. J Mol Liq
296:112085.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Annaji M, Poudel I, Boddu SHS, et al.  (2021). Resveratrol-loaded nanomedicines for cancer applications. Cancer Rep
4:e1353.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8222557</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33655717</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bannigan P, Häse F, Aldeghi M, et al.  (2021). Machine learning predictions of drug release from polymeric long acting injectables. ChemRxiv. Cambridge: Cambridge Open Engage.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bhattamisra SK, Shak AT, Xi LW, et al.  (2020). Nose to brain delivery of rotigotine loaded chitosan nanoparticles in human SH-SY5Y neuroblastoma cells and animal model of Parkinson's disease. Int J Pharm
579:119148.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32084576</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brandhonneur N, Hatahet T, Amela-Cortes M, et al.  (2018). Molybdenum cluster loaded PLGA nanoparticles: an innovative theranostic approach for the treatment of ovarian cancer. Eur J Pharm Biopharm
125:95–105.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29355686</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Calvo P, Remuñan-López C, Vila-Jato JL, Alonso MJ. (1997a). Chitosan and chitosan/ethylene oxide-propylene oxide block copolymer nanoparticles as novel carriers for proteins and vaccines. Pharm Res
14:1431–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9358557</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Calvo P, Remunan‐Lopez C, Vila‐Jato JL, Alonso MJ. (1997b). Novel hydrophilic chitosan‐polyethylene oxide nanoparticles as protein carriers. J Appl Polym Sci
63:125–32.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cazzaniga ME, Giordano M, Bandera M, et al.  (2021). Managing menopausal symptoms in young women with breast cancer: when medicine is not all. The Take Care Project. Clin Breast Cancer
21(5):e547–e560.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33685833</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Charkhchi P, Cybulski C, Gronwald J, et al.  (2020). CA125 and ovarian cancer: a comprehensive review. Cancers
12:3730.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7763876</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33322519</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen T-Y, Tsai M-J, Chang L-C, Wu P-C. (2020). Co-delivery of cisplatin and gemcitabine via viscous nanoemulsion for potential synergistic intravesical chemotherapy. Pharmaceutics
12:949.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7600678</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33036448</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Costanzo S, Di Sarno A, D'Apuzzo M, et al.  (2021). Rheology and morphology of Pluronic F68 in water. Phys Fluids
33:043113.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De S, Robinson DJ. (2003). Polymer relationships during preparation of chitosan–alginate and poly-l-lysine–alginate nanospheres. J Control Release
89:101–12.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12695066</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Demchenkov E, Nagdalian A, Budkevich R, et al.  (2021). Usage of atomic force microscopy for detection of the damaging effect of CdCl2 on red blood cells membrane. Ecotoxicol Environ Saf
208:111683.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33396015</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Feng T, Chau Y. (2018). Intracellular uptake mechanism of multi-ligand polymeric nanoparticles. http://hdl.handle.net/1783.1/96491</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fu D, Ni Z, Wu K, et al.  (2021). A novel redox-responsive ursolic acid polymeric prodrug delivery system for osteosarcoma therapy. Drug Deliv
28:195–205.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7808744</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33438472</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gatenby RA, Brown JS. (2020). Integrating evolutionary dynamics into cancer therapy. Nat Rev Clin Oncol
17:675–86.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32699310</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guo X, Yi H, Li TC, et al.  (2021). Role of vascular endothelial growth factor (VEGF) in human embryo implantation: clinical implications. Biomolecules
11:253.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7916576</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33578823</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hejjaji E. (2018). Tuneable chitosan particles with potential forensic and pharmaceutical applications. Huddersfield: University of Huddersfield.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Joachim C, Véronique-Baudin J, Desroziers L, et al.  (2020). Gynaecological cancer in Caribbean women: data from the French population-based cancer registries of Martinique, Guadeloupe and French Guiana (2007–2014). BMC Cancer
20:1–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7350571</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32650744</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaufman NE, Dhingra S, Jois SD, Vicente M dGHJM. (2021). Molecular targeting of epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR) and vascular endothelial growth factor receptor (VEGFR). J Med Chem
26:1076.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7922143</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33670650</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liang J, Yang B, Zhou X, et al.  (2021). Stimuli-responsive drug delivery systems for head and neck cancer therapy. Drug Deliv
28:272–84.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7850355</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33501883</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Machado PdA, Gomes PS, Midlej V, et al.  (2021). PF-429242, a subtilisin inhibitor, is effective in vitro against Leishmania infantum. Front Microbiol
12:50.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7876069</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33584607</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mendes LP, Sarisozen C, Torchilin VP. (2021). Physiological barriers in cancer: a challenge to be overcome. In: Marlene L, Lopes CM, Elisabete M, Real Oliveira CD, eds. Functional lipid nanosystems in cancer. Singapore: Jenny Stanford Publishing, 3–43.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moreno-Vásquez MJ, Plascencia-Jatomea M, Sánchez-Valdes S, et al.  (2021). Characterization of epigallocatechin-gallate-grafted chitosan nanoparticles and evaluation of their antibacterial and antioxidant potential. Polymers
13:1375.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8122830</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33922410</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paciotti GF, Myer L, Weinreich D, et al.  (2004). Colloidal gold: a novel nanoparticle vector for tumor directed drug delivery. Drug Deliv
11:169–83.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15204636</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Piao J, Yuan W, Dong YJMB. (2021). Recent progress of DNA nanostructures on amphiphilic membranes. Macromol Biosci
21:2000440.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33759366</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pithanthanakul U, Vatanyoopaisarn S, Thumthanaruk B, et al.  (2021). Encapsulation of fragrances in zein nanoparticles and use as fabric softener for textile application . Flavour Fragrance J
36:365–73.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pitre E. (2010). The role of Hoxa7 and Pax8 in epithelial ovarian cancer differentiation. Canada: University of Ottawa.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pooja D, Kulhari H, Tunki L, et al.  (2015). Nanomedicines for targeted delivery of etoposide to non-small cell lung cancer using transferrin functionalized nanoparticles. RSC Adv
5:49122–31.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raval N, Maheshwari R, Shukla H, et al.  (2021). Multifunctional polymeric micellar nanomedicine in the diagnosis and treatment of cancer. Mater Sci Eng C
126:112186.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34082985</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Robinson M, Cognard-Plancq A-L, Cosandey C, et al.  (2003). Studies of the impact of forests on peak flows and baseflows: a European perspective. Management
186:85–97.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rostamizadeh K, Torchilin VP. (2020). Polymeric nanomicelles as versatile tool for multidrug delivery in chemotherapy. In: Shegokar R, ed. Nanopharmaceuticals. New York, NY:
Elsevier, 45–72.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sacco P, Pedroso-Santana S, Kumar Y, et al.  (2021). Ionotropic gelation of chitosan flat structures and potential applications . Molecules
26:660.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7865838</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33513925</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Samal SK, Dash M, Van Vlierberghe S, et al.  (2012). Cationic polymers and their therapeutic potential. Chem Soc Rev
41:7147–94.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22885409</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shabir S, Gill PK. (2020). Global scenario on ovarian cancer – its dynamics, relative survival, treatment, and epidemiology. J Med Res Sci
2:17–25.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shen S-F, Zhu L-F, Liu J, et al.  (2020). Novel core-shell fiber delivery system for synergistic treatment of cervical cancer. J Drug Deliv Sci Technol
59:101865.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Subhan MA, Torchilin VP. (2021a). Biocompatible polymeric nanoparticles as promising candidates for drug delivery in cancer treatment. In: Hussain CM, Thomas S, eds. Handbook of polymer and ceramic nanotechnology. Cham: Springer International Publishing, 855–872.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Subhan MA, Torchilin VP. (2021b). Neutrophils as an emerging therapeutic target and tool for cancer therapy. Life Sci
285:119952.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34520766</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yokoe I, Omata D, Unga J, et al.  (2021). Lipid bubbles combined with low-intensity ultrasound enhance the intratumoral accumulation and antitumor effect of pegylated liposomal doxorubicin in vivo. Drug Deliv
28:530–41.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7946004</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33685314</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang S, Tang C, Yin C. (2015). Effects of poly(ethylene glycol) grafting density on the tumor targeting efficacy of nanoparticles with ligand modification. Drug Deliv
22:182–90.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24215373</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
