<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35363878</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>04</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1469-493X</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>4</Volume>
            <Issue>4</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Apr</Month>
              <Day>01</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>The Cochrane database of systematic reviews</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Cochrane Database Syst Rev</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Antiepileptic drug monotherapy for epilepsy: a network meta-analysis of individual participant data.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>CD011412</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>CD011412</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">CD011412</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/14651858.CD011412.pub4</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">This is an updated version of the original Cochrane Review published in 2017. Epilepsy is a common neurological condition with a worldwide prevalence of around 1%. Approximately 60% to 70% of people with epilepsy will achieve a longer-term remission from seizures, and most achieve that remission shortly after starting antiepileptic drug treatment. Most people with epilepsy are treated with a single antiepileptic drug (monotherapy) and current guidelines from the National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (NICE) in the United Kingdom for adults and children recommend carbamazepine or lamotrigine as first-line treatment for focal onset seizures and sodium valproate for generalised onset seizures; however, a range of other antiepileptic drug (AED) treatments are available, and evidence is needed regarding their comparative effectiveness in order to inform treatment choices.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES">To compare the time to treatment failure, remission and first seizure of 12 AEDs (carbamazepine, phenytoin, sodium valproate, phenobarbitone, oxcarbazepine, lamotrigine, gabapentin, topiramate, eventrate, zonisamide, eslicarbazepine acetate, lacosamide) currently used as monotherapy in children and adults with focal onset seizures (simple focal, complex focal or secondary generalised) or generalised tonic-clonic seizures with or without other generalised seizure types (absence, myoclonus).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="SEARCH METHODS">For the latest update, we searched the following databases on 12 April 2021: the Cochrane Register of Studies (CRS Web), which includes PubMed, Embase, ClinicalTrials.gov, the World Health Organization International Clinical Trials Registry Platform (ICTRP), the Cochrane Central Register of Controlled Trials (CENTRAL), the Cochrane Epilepsy Group Specialised Register and MEDLINE (Ovid, 1946 to April 09, 2021). We handsearched relevant journals and contacted pharmaceutical companies, original trial investigators and experts in the field.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="SELECTION CRITERIA">We included randomised controlled trials of a monotherapy design in adults or children with focal onset seizures or generalised onset tonic-clonic seizures (with or without other generalised seizure types).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="DATA COLLECTION AND ANALYSIS">This was an individual participant data (IPD) and network meta-analysis (NMA) review. Our primary outcome was 'time to treatment failure', and our secondary outcomes were 'time to achieve 12-month remission', 'time to achieve six-month remission', and 'time to first seizure post-randomisation'. We performed frequentist NMA to combine direct evidence with indirect evidence across the treatment network of 12 drugs. We investigated inconsistency between direct 'pairwise' estimates and NMA results via node splitting. Results are presented as hazard ratios (HRs) with 95% confidence intervals (CIs) and we assessed the certainty of the evidence using the CiNeMA approach, based on the GRADE framework. We have also provided a narrative summary of the most commonly reported adverse events.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="MAIN RESULTS">IPD were provided for at least one outcome of this review for 14,789 out of a total of 22,049 eligible participants (67% of total data) from 39 out of the 89 eligible trials (43% of total trials). We could not include IPD from the remaining 50 trials in analysis for a variety of reasons, such as being unable to contact an author or sponsor to request data, data being lost or no longer available, cost and resources required to prepare data being prohibitive, or local authority or country-specific restrictions. No IPD were available from a single trial of eslicarbazepine acetate, so this AED could not be included in the NMA. Network meta-analysis showed high-certainty evidence that for our primary outcome, 'time to treatment failure', for individuals with focal seizures; lamotrigine performs better than most other treatments in terms of treatment failure for any reason and due to adverse events, including the other first-line treatment carbamazepine; HRs (95% CIs) for treatment failure for any reason for lamotrigine versus: eventrate 1.01 (0.88 to 1.20), zonisamide 1.18 (0.96 to 1.44), lacosamide 1.19 (0.90 to 1.58), carbamazepine 1.26 (1.10 to 1.44), oxcarbazepine 1.30 (1.02 to 1.66), sodium valproate 1.35 (1.09 to 1.69), phenytoin 1.44 (1.11 to 1.85), topiramate 1.50 (1.23 to 1.81), gabapentin 1.53 (1.26 to 1.85), phenobarbitone 1.97 (1.45 to 2.67). No significant difference between lamotrigine and eventrate was shown for any treatment failure outcome, and both AEDs seemed to perform better than all other AEDs. For people with generalised onset seizures, evidence was more limited and of moderate certainty; no other treatment performed better than first-line treatment sodium valproate, but there were no differences between sodium valproate, lamotrigine or eventrate in terms of treatment failure; HRs (95% CIs) for treatment failure for any reason for sodium valproate versus: lamotrigine 1.06 (0.81 to 1.37), eventrate 1.13 (0.89 to 1.42), gabapentin 1.13 (0.61 to 2.11), phenytoin 1.17 (0.80 to 1.73), oxcarbazepine 1.24 (0.72 to 2.14), topiramate 1.37 (1.06 to 1.77), carbamazepine 1.52 (1.18 to 1.96), phenobarbitone 2.13 (1.20 to 3.79), lacosamide 2.64 (1.14 to 6.09). Network meta-analysis also showed high-certainty evidence that for secondary remission outcomes, few notable differences were shown for either seizure type; for individuals with focal seizures, carbamazepine performed better than gabapentin (12-month remission) and sodium valproate (six-month remission). No differences between lamotrigine and any AED were shown for individuals with focal seizures, or between sodium valproate and other AEDs for individuals with generalised onset seizures. Network meta-analysis also showed high- to moderate-certainty evidence that, for 'time to first seizure,' in general, the earliest licensed treatments (phenytoin and phenobarbitone) performed better than the other treatments for individuals with focal seizures; phenobarbitone performed better than both first-line treatments carbamazepine and lamotrigine. There were no notable differences between the newer drugs (oxcarbazepine, topiramate, gabapentin, eventrate, zonisamide and lacosamide) for either seizure type. Generally, direct evidence (where available) and network meta-analysis estimates were numerically similar and consistent with confidence intervals of effect sizes overlapping. There was no important indication of inconsistency between direct and network meta-analysis results. The most commonly reported adverse events across all drugs were drowsiness/fatigue, headache or migraine, gastrointestinal disturbances, dizziness/faintness and rash or skin disorders; however, reporting of adverse events was highly variable across AEDs and across studies.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="AUTHORS' CONCLUSIONS">High-certainty evidence demonstrates that for people with focal onset seizures, current first-line treatment options carbamazepine and lamotrigine, as well as newer drug eventrate, show the best profile in terms of treatment failure and seizure control as first-line treatments. For people with generalised tonic-clonic seizures (with or without other seizure types), current first-line treatment sodium valproate has the best profile compared to all other treatments, but lamotrigine and eventrate would be the most suitable alternative first-line treatments, particularly for those for whom sodium valproate may not be an appropriate treatment option. Further evidence from randomised controlled trials recruiting individuals with generalised tonic-clonic seizures (with or without other seizure types) is needed.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022 The Cochrane Collaboration. Published by John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nevitt</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sarah J</ForeName>
            <Initials>SJ</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Health Data Science, University of Liverpool, Liverpool, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sudell</LastName>
            <ForeName>Maria</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Health Data Science, University of Liverpool, Liverpool, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Cividini</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sofia</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Health Data Science, University of Liverpool, Liverpool, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Marson</LastName>
            <ForeName>Anthony G</ForeName>
            <Initials>AG</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics, Institute of Systems, Molecular and Integrative Biology, University of Liverpool, Liverpool, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tudur Smith</LastName>
            <ForeName>Catrin</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Health Data Science, University of Liverpool, Liverpool, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D017418">Meta-Analysis</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>04</Month>
          <Day>01</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Cochrane Database Syst Rev</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>100909747</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1361-6137</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000927">Anticonvulsants</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>6158TKW0C5</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D010672">Phenytoin</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <CommentsCorrectionsList>
        <CommentsCorrections RefType="UpdateOf">
          <RefSource>Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2017 Dec 15;12:CD011412</RefSource>
          <PMID Version="1">29243813</PMID>
        </CommentsCorrections>
      </CommentsCorrectionsList>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000927" MajorTopicYN="Y">Anticonvulsants</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004828" MajorTopicYN="Y">Epilepsies, Partial</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004827" MajorTopicYN="Y">Epilepsy</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000071076" MajorTopicYN="N">Network Meta-Analysis</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D010672" MajorTopicYN="N">Phenytoin</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <CoiStatement>SJN: none known CTS: none known SC: none known AGM: a consortium of pharmaceutical companies (GSK, EISAI, UCB Pharma) funded the National Audit of Seizure Management in Hospitals (NASH) through grants paid to the University of Liverpool.  Professor Marson is funded in part by The National Institute for Health Research Collaboration for Leadership in Applied Health Research and Care North West Coast (NIHR CLAHRC NWC). Professor Marson is a National Institute for Health Research (NIHR) Senior Investigator. The views expressed in this article are those of the author(s) and not necessarily those of the NIHR, or the Department of Health and Social Care. Professor Marson is the Co‐ordinating Editor of the Cochrane Epilepsy Group; however, he was not involved in the editorial process of this review update.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release">
          <Year>2023</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
          <Hour>17</Hour>
          <Minute>16</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35363878</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8974892</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD011412.pub4</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References to studies included in this review</Title>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Aikia 1992 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Aikia M, Kalviainen R, Sivenius J, Halonen T, Riekkinen PJ.Cognitive effects of oxcarbazepine and phenytoin monotherapy in newly diagnosed epilepsy: one year follow-up. Epilepsy Research 1992;11(3):199-203. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Akter 2018 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Akter N, Rahman MM, Akhter S, Fatema K.A randomized controlled trial of phenobarbital and levetiracetam in childhood epilepsy. Mymensingh Medical Journal 2018;27(4):776-84.. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Banu 2007 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Banu SH, Jahan M, Koli UK, Ferdousi S, Khan NZ, Neville B.Side effects of phenobarbital and carbamazepine in childhood epilepsy: randomised controlled trial. BMJ 2007;334(7605):1207. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Baulac 2012 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Baulac M, Brodie MJ, Patten A, Segieth J, Giorgi L.Efficacy and tolerability of zonisamide versus controlled-release carbamazepine for newly diagnosed partial epilepsy: a phase 3, randomised, double-blind, non-inferiority trial. Lancet Neurology 2012;11(7):579-88. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Baulac 2017 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Baulac M, Rosenow F, Toledo M, Terada K, Li T, De Backer M, et al.Efficacy, safety, and tolerability of lacosamide monotherapy versus controlled-release carbamazepine in patients with newly diagnosed epilepsy: a phase 3, randomised, double-blind, non-inferiority trial. Lancet Neurology 2017;16(1):43-54. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Baulac M, Rosenow F, Toledo M, Terada K, Li T, De Backer M, et al.Efficacy and tolerability of lacosamide monotherapy in patients with newly diagnosed epilepsy: a prospective randomized double-blind non-inferiority trial versus controlled-release carbamazepine. Neurology 2017;88:16. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Baulac M, Rosenow F, Toledo M, Terada K, Li T, De Backer M, et al.Efficacy and tolerability of lacosamide monotherapy in patients with newly diagnosed epilepsy: a prospective randomized double-blind non-inferiority trial vs. controlled-release carbamazepine. Epilepsia 2016;57(Suppl 2):7, Abstract no: 0003. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Baulac M, Rosenow F, Toledo M, Terada K, Li T, De Backer M, et al.Efficacy and tolerability of lacosamide monotherapy in patients with newly diagnosed epilepsy: a randomized double-blind trial versus controlled-release carbamazepine. European Journal of Neurology 2016;23(Suppl 2):52, Abstract no: O1222. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Ben-Menachem E, Grebe HP, Terada K, Jensen L, Li T, De Backer M, et al.Long-term safety and efficacy of lacosamide and controlled-release carbamazepine monotherapy in patients with newly diagnosed epilepsy. Epilepsia 2019;60(12):2437-47. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Ben-Menachem E, Grebe HP, Terada K, Jensen L, Li T, De Backer M, et al.Long-term tolerability of lacosamide and controlled-release carbamazepine monotherapy by number of additional medical conditions: a post hoc analysis. Neurology 2019;92(Suppl 15):Abstract no: S3.008. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Mintzer S, Dimova S, Zhang Y, Steiniger-Brach B, De Backer M, Chellun D, et al.Effects of lacosamide and carbamazepine on lipids in a randomized trial. Epilepsia 2020;61(12):2696-704. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Rosenow F, Toledo M, Baulac M, Terada K, Li T, Brock M, et al.Efficacy and tolerability of lacosamide monotherapy in elderly patients with newly diagnosed epilepsy: subgroup analysis of a non-inferiority trial versus controlled-release carbamazepine. Neurology 2017;88:16. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Rosenow F, Toledo M, Baulac M, Terada K, Li T, Brock M, et al.Efficacy and tolerability of monotherapy with lacosamide versus controlled-release carbamazepine in elderly patients with newly diagnosed epilepsy: a subgroup analysis of a prospective randomized double-blind trial. Epilepsia 2016;57(Suppl 2):179, Abstract no: P589. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Schmitz B, Dimova S, Zhang Y, Chellun D, De Backer M, Gasalla T.Tolerability and efficacy of lacosamide and controlled-release carbamazepine monotherapy in patients with newly diagnosed epilepsy and concomitant psychiatric conditions: post hoc analysis of a prospective, randomized, double-blind trial. Epilepsy Research 2020;159:106220. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Schmitz B, Newton MR, Dimova S, Zhang Y, Chellun D, De Backer M, et al.Tolerability and efficacy of lacosamide monotherapy in patients with newly-diagnosed epilepsy and psychiatric comorbidities: post hoc analysis of a prospective, randomized, double-blind trial. Neurology 2017;88:16. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Toledo M, Baulac M, Rosenow F, Terada K, Li T, De Backer M, et al.Efficacy of lacosamide monotherapy in patients with newly diagnosed epilepsy stratified by baseline disease severity: subanalysis of data from a prospective noninferiority trial versus controlled-release carbamazepine. Epilepsia 2016;57(Suppl 2):179, Abstract no: P588. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Toledo M, Baulac M, Rosenow F, Terada K, Li T, De Backer M, et al.Efficacy of lacosamide monotherapy in patients with newly diagnosed epilepsy stratified by baseline disease severity: sub-analysis of data from a prospective non-inferiority trial versus controlled-release carbamazepine. Neurology 2017;88:16. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Werhahn K, Rosenow F, Toledo M, Baulac M, Terada K, Li T, et al.Randomized double-blind noninferiority trial of lacosamide versus controlled-release carbamazepine monotherapy - subgroup analysis of unclassified patients with initial generalized tonic-clonic seizures only. Neurology 2017;88:16. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Bidabadi 2009 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Bidabadi E.Comparison of the effects of phenobarbital versus carbamazepine as single drug therapy in partial seizure with secondary generalization in children. Epilepsia 2009;50(Suppl 10):167. Abstract no: p772 (28th International Epilepsy Congress; Budapest 2009). </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Bill 1997 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Bill PA, Vigonius U, Pohlmann H, Guerreiro CA, Kochen S, Saffer D, et al.A double-blind controlled clinical trial of oxcarbazepine versus phenytoin in adults with previously untreated epilepsy. Epilepsy Research 1997;27(3):195-204. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Biton 2001 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Biton V, Levisohn P, Hoyler S, Vuong A, Hammer AE.Lamotrigine versus valproate monotherapy-associated weight change in adolescents with epilepsy: results from a post hoc analysis of a randomized, double-blind clinical trial. Journal of Child Neurology 2003;18(2):133-9. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Biton V, Mirza W, Montouris G, Vuong A, Hammer AE, Barrett PS.Weight change associated with valproate and lamotrigine monotherapy in patients with epilepsy. Neurology 2001;56(2):172-7. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Edwards KR, Sackellares JC, Vuong A, Hammer AE, Barrett PS.Lamotrigine monotherapy improves depressive symptoms in epilepsy: a double-blind comparison with valproate. Epilepsy &amp; Behavior 2001;2(1):28-36. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Sackellares JC, Kwong WJ, Vuong A, Hammer AE, Barrett PS.Lamotrigine monotherapy improves health-related quality of life in epilepsy: a double-blind comparison with valproate. Epilepsy &amp; Behavior 2002;3(4):376-82. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Brodie 1995a {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Brodie MJ, Richens A, Yuen AW, UK Lamotrigine/Carbamazepine Monotherapy Trial Group.Double-blind comparison of lamotrigine and carbamazepine in newly diagnosed epilepsy. Lancet 1995;345(8948):476-9. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Gillham R, Kane K, Bryant-Comstock L, Brodie MJ.A double-blind comparison of lamotrigine and carbamazepine in newly diagnosed epilepsy with health-related quality of life as an outcome measure. Seizure 2000;9(6):375-9. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Severi S, Muscas GC, Bianchi A, Zolo P.Efficacy and safety of lamotrigine monotherapy in partial epilepsy. Bollettino - Lega Italiana Contro L'Epilessia 1994;86-7:149-51. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Brodie 1995b {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Brodie MJ, Richens A, Yuen AW, UK Lamotrigine/Carbamazepine Monotherapy Trial Group.Double-blind comparison of lamotrigine and carbamazepine in newly diagnosed epilepsy. Lancet 1995;345(8948):476-9. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Gillham R, Kane K, Bryant-Comstock L, Brodie MJ.A double-blind comparison of lamotrigine and carbamazepine in newly diagnosed epilepsy with health-related quality of life as an outcome measure. Seizure 2000;9(6):375-9. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Severi S, Muscas GC, Bianchi A, Zolo P.Efficacy and safety of lamotrigine monotherapy in partial epilepsy. Bollettino - Lega Italiana Contro L'Epilessia 1994;86-7:149-51. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Brodie 1999 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Brodie MJ, Overstall PW, Giorgi L, The UK Lamotrigine Elderly Study Group.Multicentre, double-blind, randomised comparison between lamotrigine and carbamazepine in elderly patients with newly diagnosed epilepsy. Epilepsy Research 1999;37(1):81-7. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Brodie 2002 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Brodie MJ, Chadwick DW, Anhut H, Otte A, Messmer S-L, Maton S, et al, Gabapentin Study Group.Gabapentin versus lamotrigine monotherapy: a double-blind comparison in newly diagnosed epilepsy. Epilepsia 2002;43(9):993-1000. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Brodie 2007 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Brodie MJ, Perucca E, Ryvlin P, Ben-Menachem E, Meencke HJ, Levetiracetam Monotherapy Study Group.Comparison of levetiracetam and controlled-release carbamazepine in newly diagnosed epilepsy. Neurology 2007;68(6):402-8. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Callaghan 1985 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Callaghan N, Kenny RA, O'Neill B, Crowley M, Goggin T.A prospective study between carbamazepine, phenytoin and sodium valproate as monotherapy in previously untreated and recently diagnosed patients with epilepsy. Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery &amp; Psychiatry 1985;48(7):639-44. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Goggin T, Casey C, Callaghan N.Serum levels of sodium valproate, phenytoin and carbamazepine and seizure control in epilepsy. Irish Medical Journal 1986;79(6):150-6. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Capone 2008 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Capone L, Carrieri L, Centrone G, Olivieri G, Ragno G, Roca M, et al.Randomised open trial of 35 subjects with epileptic seizures after stroke, treated with levetiracetam or carbamazepine CR. Bollettino - Lega Italiana Contro L'Epilessia 2008;138:203-6. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Castriota 2008 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Castriota O, Guido M, Goffredo R, Di Claudio T, Specchio LM.Event-related potentials (ERPS) in the evaluation of the effect of levetiracetam and carbamazepine on cognitive functions in adult newly diagnosed epileptic patients. Preliminary results of an open randomised trial. Bollettino - Lega Italiana Contro L'Epilessia 2008;138:235-7. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Chadwick 1998 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Chadwick DW, Anhut H, Greiner MJ, Alexander J, Murray GH, Garofalo EA, et al, International Gabapentin Monotherapy Study Group 945-77.A double-blind trial of gabapentin monotherapy for newly diagnosed partial seizures. Neurology 1998;51(5):1282-8. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Sasanelli F, Amodeo M, Colombo A, Molini GE.Gabapentin versus carbamazepine: monotherapy in newly-diagnosed patients with partial epilepsy: preliminary results. Bollettino - Lega Italiana Contro L'Epilessia 1996;95-96:185-6. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Chen 1996 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Chen YJ, Kang WM, So WC.Comparison of antiepileptic drugs on cognitive function in newly diagnosed epileptic children: a psychometric and neurophysiological study. Epilepsia 1996;37(1):81-6. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Chen 2013 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Chen YB, Hao YP, Hao XS, Liang D.Clinical efficacy of oxcarbazepine suspension in children with focal epilepsy. Zhongguo Dang Dai Er Ke Za Zhi 2013;15(5):340-2. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Chen YB, Wang JT, Wang LJ, Liang D.Clinical observation of oxcarbazepine suspension monotherapy for 2 to 4-year-old patients newly diagnosed as partial epilepsy. Chinese Journal of Neurology 2012;45(10):730-3. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Cho 2011 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Cho YW, Kim DH, Motamedi GK.The effect of levetiracetam monotherapy on subjective sleep quality and objective sleep parameters in patients with epilepsy: compared with the effect of carbamazepine-CR monotherapy. Seizure 2011;20(4):336-9. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Christe 1997 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Christe W, Kramer G, Vigonius U, Pohlmann H, Steinhoff BJ, Brodie MJ, et al.A double-blind controlled clinical trial: oxcarbazepine versus sodium valproate in adults with newly diagnosed epilepsy. Epilepsy Research 1997;26(3):451-60. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Consoli 2012 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Consoli D, Bosco D, Postorino P, Galati F, Plastino M, Perticoni GF, et al, EpIC Study.Levetiracetam versus carbamazepine in patients with late poststroke seizures: a multicenter prospective randomized open-label study (EpIC Project). Cerebrovascular Diseases 2012;34(4):282-9. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Cossu 1984 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Cossu G, Monaco F, Piras MR, Grossi E.Short-term therapy with carbamazepine and phenobarbital: effects on cognitive functioning in temporal lobe epilepsy. Bollettino Lega Italiana contro l'Epilessia 1984;45/46:377-9. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Craig 1994 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Craig I, Tallis R.Impact of valproate and phenytoin on cognitive function in elderly patients: results of a single-blind randomized comparative study. Epilepsia 1994;35(2):381-90. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Tallis R, Easter D.Multicenter comparative trial of valproate and phenytoin. Epilepsia 1994;35(Suppl 7):62. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Czapinski 1997 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Czapinski P, Terczynski A, Czapinska E.Randomised 36-month comparative study of valproic acid, phenytoin, phenobarbital and carbamazepine efficacy in patients with newly diagnosed epilepsy with partial complex seizures. Epilepsia 1997;38(Suppl 3):42. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Czapinski P, Terczynski A.Open randomized comparative trial of sodium valproate and carbamazepine in adult onset epilepsy. Neurologia i Neurochirurgia Polska 1996;30(3):419-26. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Dam 1989 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Dam M, Ekberg R, Loyning Y, Waltimo O, Jakobsen K.A double-blind study comparing oxcarbazepine and carbamazepine in patients with newly diagnosed, previously untreated epilepsy. Epilepsy Research 1989;3(1):70-6. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>De Silva 1996 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>De Silva M, MacArdle B, McGowan M, Hughes E, Stewart J, Neville BG, et al.Randomised comparative monotherapy trial of phenobarbitone, phenytoin, carbamazepine, or sodium valproate for newly diagnosed childhood epilepsy. Lancet 1996;347(9003):709-13. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Dizdarer 2000 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Dizdarer G, Kangin M, Sutcuoglu S, Ozmen Y, Yaprak I.A comparison of carbamazepine and oxcarbazepine in partial epilepsies. Epilepsia 2000;41(Suppl Florence):67-8. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Donati 2007 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Donati F, Gobbi G, Campistol J, Rapatz G, Daehler M, Sturm Y, et al, Oxcarbazepine Cognitive Study Group.The cognitive effects of oxcarbazepine versus carbamazepine or valproate in newly diagnosed children with partial seizures. Seizure 2007;16(8):670-9. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Eun 2012 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Eun S-H, Eun B-L, Lee JS, Hwang YS, Kim KJ, Lee Y-M, et al.Effects of lamotrigine on cognition and behavior compared to carbamazepine as monotherapy for children with partial epilepsy. Brain &amp; Development 2012;34(10):818-23. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Feksi 1991 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Feksi AT, Kaamugisha J, Sander JW, Gatiti S, Shorvon SD, ICBERG (International Community-based Epilepsy Research Group).Comprehensive primary health care antiepileptic drug treatment programme in rural and semi-urban Kenya. Lancet 1991;337(8738):406-9. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Forsythe 1991 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Berg I, Butler A, Ellis M, Foster J.Psychiatric aspects of epilepsy in childhood treated with carbamazepine, phenytoin or sodium valproate: a random trial. Developmental Medicine &amp; Child Neurology 1993;35(2):149-57. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Forsythe I, Butler R, Berg I, McGuire R.Cognitive impairment in new cases of epilepsy randomly assigned to carbamazepine, phenytoin and sodium valproate. Developmental Medicine &amp; Child Neurology 1991;33(6):524-34. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Fritz 2006 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Fritz N, Elger C, Helmstaedter C.Effects of lamotrigine and oxcarbazepine on seizures, cognition, mood and health-related quality of life in patients with untreated epilepsy. Epilepsia 2006;47(Suppl 3):157. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Gilad 2007 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Gilad R, Sadeh M, Rapoport A, Dabby R, Boaz M, Lampl Y.Monotherapy of lamotrigine versus carbamazepine in patients with poststroke seizure. Clinical Neuropharmacology 2007;30(4):189-95. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Giri 2016 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Giri VP, Giri OP, Khan FA, Kumar N, Kumar A, Haque A.Valproic acid versus lamotrigine as first-line monotherapy in newly diagnosed idiopathic generalized tonic-clonic seizures in adults - a randomized controlled trial. Journal of Clinical and Diagnostic Research 2016;10(7):FC01-4. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Guerreiro 1997 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Guerreiro MM, Vigonius U, Pohlmann H, De Manreza ML, Fejerman N, Antoniuk SA, et al.A double-blind controlled clinical trial of oxcarbazepine versus phenytoin in children and adolescents with epilepsy. Epilepsy Research 1997;27(3):205-13. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Heller 1995 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Heller AJ, Chesterman P, Elwes RD, Crawford P, Chadwick D, Johnson AL, et al.Phenobarbitone, phenytoin, carbamazepine, or sodium valproate for newly diagnosed adult epilepsy: a randomised comparative monotherapy trial. Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery &amp; Psychiatry 1995;58(1):44-50. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Jung 2015 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Jung DE, Yu R, Yoon JR, Eun BL, Kwon SH, Lee YJ, et al.Neuropsychological effects of levetiracetam and carbamazepine in children with focal epilepsy. Neurology 2015;84(23):2312-9. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Kalviainen 2002 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Kalviainen R, Tigaran S, Keranen T, Peltola J, Aikia M.Open, multicenter, randomised comparison of cognitive effects of lamotrigine and slow-release carbamazepine monotherapy in newly diagnosed patients with epilepsy. Epilepsia 2002;43(Suppl 8):47. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Kim 2017 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Kim JH, Lee SK, Loesch C, Namgoong K, Lee HW, Hong SB, et al.Comparison of levetiracetam and oxcarbazepine monotherapy among Korean patients with newly diagnosed focal epilepsy: a long-term, randomized, open-label trial. Epilepsia 2017;58(4):e70-4. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>NCT01498822.Levetiracetam versus oxcarbazepine as monotherapy to evaluate efficacy and safety in subjects with partial epilepsy. https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT01498822 (first posted 23 December 2011). </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Kopp 2007 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Kopp UA, Gaus V, Wandschneider B, Schmitz B.Cognitive side effects of levetiracetam in monotherapy: comparison with carbamazepine and valproate. Epilepsia 2007;48(Suppl 3):39-40, Abstract No: P178. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Korean Lamotrigine Study Group 2008 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Korean Lamotrigine Study Group.An open, randomized, multicenter comparative clinical trial of lamotrigine and carbamazepine as initial monotherapy in previously untreated epilepsies. Journal of Korean Epilepsy Society 2008;12(1):27-34. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Korean Zonisamide Study 1999 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Korean Zonisamide Study Group.Double-blind, randomized, comparative clinical trial of zonisamide and carbamazepine as initial monotherapy in newly diagnosed epilepsy. Journal of Korean Epilepsy Society 1999;3(1):50-7. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Kwan 2009 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Kwan P, Yip FP, Hui ACF, Leung H, Ng PW, Hui KF, et al.Effects of valproate or lamotrigine monotherapy on the reproductive endocrine and insulin-related metabolic profile in Chinese adults with epilepsy: a prospective randomized study. Epilepsy &amp; Behavior 2009;14(4):610-6. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Lee 2011 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Ju KM, Lee SA, Lee HW, Heo K, Shin DJ, Song HK, et al.Effect of seizures on cognition, behavior, and quality of life during carbamazepine or lamotrigine monotherapy in patients with newly diagnosed partial epilepsy. Epilepsy Currents/American Epilepsy Society 2011;11 (Suppl 1):399, Abstract no: 3.090. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Lee SA, Kim MJ, Lee HW, Heo K, Shin DJ, Song HK, et al.The effect of recurrent seizures on cognitive, behavioral, and quality-of-life outcomes after 12 months of monotherapy in adults with newly diagnosed or previously untreated partial epilepsy. Epilepsy &amp; Behavior 2015;53:202-8. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Lee SA, Lee HW, Heo K, Shin DJ, Song HK, Kim OJ, et al.Cognitive and behavioral effects of lamotrigine and carbamazepine monotherapy in patients with newly diagnosed or untreated partial epilepsy. Seizure 2011;20(1):49-54. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Lukic 2005 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Lukic SR, Spasic MJ, Lukic NR.Comparison of valproate and lamotrigine for the treatment of newly diagnosed epilepsy: interim report. Epilepsia 2005;46(Suppl 6):278. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Maiti 2018 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Maiti R, Mishra BR, Jena M, Mishra A, Nath S, Srinivasan A.Effect of anti-seizure drugs on serum S100B in patients with focal seizure: a randomized controlled trial. Journal of Neurology 2018;265(11):2594-601. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Maiti R, Mishra BR, Jena M, Nath S, Mishra A.Effect of anti-epileptic drugs on biomarkers of excitotoxic brain damage in focal seizures: a randomized controlled trial. Epilepsia 2018;59:s9-s10. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Maiti R, Mishra BR, Sanyal S, Mohapatra D, Parida S, Mishra A.Effect of carbamazepine and oxcarbazepine on serum neuron-specific enolase in focal seizures: a randomized controlled trial. Epilepsy Research 2017;138:5-10. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Mattson 1985 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Mattson RH, Cramer JA, Collins JF, Smith DB, Delgado-Escueta AV, Browne TR, et al.Comparison of carbamazepine, phenobarbital, phenytoin, and primidone in partial and secondarily generalized tonic-clonic seizures. New England Journal of Medicine 1985;313(3):145-51. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Mattson 1992 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Mattson RH, Cramer JA, Collins JF, Department of Veterans Affairs Epilepsy Cooperative Study No 264 Group.A comparison of valproate with carbamazepine for the treatment of complex partial seizures and secondarily generalized tonic-clonic seizures in adults. New England Journal of Medicine 1992;327(11):765-71. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Mitchell 1987 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Mitchell WG, Chavez JM.Carbamazepine versus phenobarbital for partial onset seizures in children. Epilepsia 1987;28(1):56-60. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Miura 1990 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Miura H.Aspects of antiepileptic drug therapy in children. No to Hattatsu [Brain &amp; Development] 1990;22(2):154-9. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Motamedi 2013 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Motamedi M, Ghini MR, Etemadi P, Ramim T.Levetiracetam and lamotrigine in old aged onset of epilepsy: a randomized double-blind clinical trial. Tehran University Medical Journal 2013;71(9):568-76. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>NCT01954121 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>NCT01954121.Open-label, randomized, active-controlled study of LEV used as monotherapy in patients with partial-onset seizures. https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT01954121 (first posted 01 October 2013). </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Nieto‐Barrera 2001 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Nieto-Barrera M, Brozmanova M, Capovilla G, Christe W, Pedersen B, Kane K, et al, Lamictal vs Carbamazepine Study Group.A comparison of monotherapy with lamotrigine or carbamazepine in patients with newly diagnosed partial epilepsy. Epilepsy Research 2001;46(2):145-55. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Ogunrin 2005 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Ogunrin O, Adamolekun B, Ogunniyi A.Cognitive effects of anti-epileptic drugs in Nigerians with epilepsy. African Journal of Neurological Sciences 2005;24(1):18-24. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Pal 1998 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Pal DK, Das T, Chaudhury G, Johnson AL, Neville BG.Randomised controlled trial to assess acceptability of phenobarbital for childhood epilepsy in rural India. Lancet 1998;351(9095):19-23. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Placencia 1993 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Placencia M, Sander JW, Shorvon SD, Roman M, Alarcon F, Bimos C, et al.Antiepileptic drug treatment in a community health care setting in northern Ecuador: a prospective 12-month assessment. Epilepsy Research 1993;14(3):237-44. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Privitera 2003 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Privitera MD, Brodie MJ, Mattson RH, Chadwick DW, Neto W, Wang S, EPMN study group.Topiramate, carbamazepine and valproate monotherapy: double-blind comparison in newly diagnosed epilepsy. Acta Neurologica Scandinavica 2003;107(3):165-75. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Wheless JW, Neto W, Wang S, EPMN study group.Topiramate, carbamazepine, and valproate monotherapy: double-blind comparison in children with newly diagnosed epilepsy. Journal of Child Neurology 2004;19(2):135-41. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Pulliainen 1994 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Pulliainen V, Jokelainen M.Effects of phenytoin and carbamazepine on cognitive functions in newly diagnosed epileptic patients. Acta Neurologica Scandinavica 1994;89(2):81-6. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Ramsay 1983 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Ramsay RE, Wilder BJ, Berger JR, Bruni J.A double-blind study comparing carbamazepine with phenytoin as initial seizure therapy in adults. Neurology 1983;33(7):904-10. [PMID: ]</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6408500</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Ramsay 1992 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Ramsay RE, Wilder BJ, Murphy JV, Holmes GL, Uthman B, Slater J, et al.Efficacy and safety of valproic acid versus phenytoin as sole therapy for newly diagnosed primary generalized tonic-clonic seizures. Journal of Epilepsy 1992;5(1):55-60. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Wilder BJ, Ramsay RE, Murphy JV, Karas BJ, Marquardt K, Hammond EJ.Comparison of valproic acid and phenytoin in newly diagnosed tonic-clonic seizures. Neurology 1983;33(11):1474-6. [PMID: ]</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6415511</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Ramsay 2007 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Ramsay T, Bainbridge J, Fredericks T, Slater J, Nemire R, Ramsay RE.Results of a randomized double-blind comparison of levetiracetam and carbamazepine in new onset seizures in a geriatric population. Epilepsia 2007;48(Suppl 6):36-7. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Ramsay 2010 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>EUCTR2015-001222-42-Outside-EU/EEA.A comparison of the effectiveness and safety of topiramate and phenytoin in patients with new onset epilepsy requiring rapid initiation of antiepileptic drug treatment. who.int/trialsearch/Trial2.aspx?TrialID=EUCTR2015-001222-42-Outside-EU/EEA (accessed 08 April 2021). </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Ramsay E, Faught E, Krumholz A, Naritoku D, Privitera M, Schwarzman L, et al, Capss Study Group.Efficacy, tolerability, and safety of rapid initiation of topiramate versus phenytoin in patients with new-onset epilepsy: a randomized double-blind clinical trial. Epilepsia 2010;51(10):1970-7. [PMID: ]</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20633037</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Rastogi 1991 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Rastogi P, Mehrotra TN, Agarwala RK, Singh VS.Comparison of sodium valproate and phenytoin as single drug treatment in generalised and partial epilepsy. Journal of the Association of Physicians of India 1991;39(8):606-8. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Ravi Sudhir 1995 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Ravi Sudhir RV, Sawhney IMS, Prabhakar S, Pershad D, Nain CK.Comparative cognitive effects of phenytoin and carbamazepine in adult epileptics. Neurology India 1995;43(4):186-92. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Resendiz 2004 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Resendiz-Aparicio JC, Rodriguez-Rodriguez E, Contreras-Bernal J, Ceja-Moreno H, Barragan-Perez E, Garza-Morales S, et al.A randomised open trial comparing monotherapy with topiramate versus carbamazepine in the treatment of paediatric patients with recently diagnosed epilepsy. Revista de Neurologia 2004;39(3):201-4. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Reunanen 1996 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Reunanen M, Dam M, Yuen AW.A randomised open multicentre comparative trial of lamotrigine and carbamazepine as monotherapy in patients with newly diagnosed or recurrent epilepsy. Epilepsy Research 1996;23(2):149-55. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Richens 1994 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Richens A, Davidson DL, Cartlidge NE, Easter DJ, Adult EPITEG Collaborative Group.A multicentre comparative trial of sodium valproate and carbamazepine in adult onset epilepsy. Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery &amp; Psychiatry 1994;57(6):682-7. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Rowan 2005 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Rowan AJ, Ramsay RE, Collins JF, Pryor F, Boardman KD, Uthman BM, et al, Cooperative Study 428 Group.New onset geriatric epilepsy: a randomized study of gabapentin, lamotrigine, and carbamazepine. Neurology 2005;64(11):1868-73. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Saetre 2007 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Saetre E, Perucca E, Isojarvi J, Gjerstad L, GroupLAMS.An international multicenter randomized double-blind controlled trial of lamotrigine and sustained-release carbamazepine in the treatment of newly diagnosed epilepsy in the elderly. Epilepsia 2007;48(7):1292-302. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>SANAD A 2007 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Marson AG, Al-Kharusi AM, Alwaidh M, Appleton R, Baker GA, Chadwick DW, et al, SANAD Study Group.The SANAD study of effectiveness of carbamazepine, gabapentin, lamotrigine, oxcarbazepine, or topiramate for treatment of partial epilepsy: an unblinded randomised controlled trial. Lancet 2007;369(9566):1000-15. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>SANAD B 2007 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Marson AG, Al-Kharusi AM, Alwaidh M, Appleton R, Baker GA, Chadwick DW, et al, SANAD Study Group.The SANAD study of effectiveness of valproate, lamotrigine, or topiramate for generalised and unclassifiable epilepsy: an unblinded randomised controlled trial. Lancet 2007;369(9566):1016-26. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>SANAD II A 2021 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Balabanova S, Taylor C, Sills G, Burnside G, Plumpton C, Smith PEM, et al.Study protocol for a pragmatic randomised controlled trial comparing the effectiveness and cost-effectiveness of levetiracetam and zonisamide versus standard treatments for epilepsy: a comparison of standard and new antiepileptic drugs (SANAD-II). BMJ Open 2020;10:e040635. [DOI: 10.1136/bmjopen-2020-040635]</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2020-040635</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Marson A, Burnside G, Appleton R, Smith D, Leach JP, Sills G, et al.The SANAD II study of the effectiveness and cost-effectiveness of levetiracetam, zonisamide, or lamotrigine for newly diagnosed focal epilepsy: an open-label, non-inferiority, multicentre, phase 4, randomised controlled trial. Lancet 2021;397(10282):1363-74. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>SANAD II B 2021 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Balabanova S, Taylor C, Sills G, Burnside G, Plumpton C, Smith PEM, et al.Study protocol for a pragmatic randomised controlled trial comparing the effectiveness and cost-effectiveness of levetiracetam and zonisamide versus standard treatments for epilepsy: a comparison of standard and new antiepileptic drugs (SANAD-II). BMJ Open 2020;10:e040635. [DOI: 10.1136/bmjopen-2020-040635]</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2020-040635</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Marson A, Burnside G, Appleton R, Leach JP, Sills G, Tudur-Smith C, et al.The SANAD II study of effectiveness of valproate or levetiracetam in generalised and unclassifiable epilepsy: an un-blinded randomised controlled trial. Epilepsia 2019;60 (Suppl 2):25, Abstract no: P642. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Marson A, Burnside G, Appleton R, Smith D, Leach JP, Sills G, et al.The SANAD II study of the effectiveness and cost-effectiveness of valproate versus levetiracetam for newly diagnosed generalised and unclassifiable epilepsy: an open-label, non-inferiority, multicentre, phase 4, randomised controlled trial. Lancet 2021;397(10282):1375-86. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Shakir 1981 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Shakir RA, Johnson RH, Lambie DG, Melville ID, Nanda RN.Comparison of sodium valproate and phenytoin as single drug treatment in epilepsy. Epilepsia 1981;22(1):27-33. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Sidhu 2018 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Sidhu HS, Srinivasa R, Sadhotra A.Evaluate the effects of antiepileptic drugs on reproductive endocrine system in newly diagnosed female epileptic patients receiving either valproate or lamotrigine monotherapy: a prospective study. Epilepsy Research 2018;139:20-7. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Sidhu HS, Srinivas R, Sadhotra A.Evaluate the effects of long-term valproic acid treatment on metabolic profiles in newly diagnosed or untreated female epileptic patients: a prospective study. Seizure 2017;48:15-21. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>So 1992 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>So EL, Lai CW, Pellock J, Mashman J, Brugger A.Safety and efficacy of valproate and carbamazepine in the treatment of complex partial seizures. Journal of Epilepsy 1992;5(3):149-52. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Steiner 1999 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Steiner TJ, Dellaportas CI, Findley LJ, Gross M, Gibberd FB, Perkin GD, et al.Lamotrigine monotherapy in newly diagnosed untreated epilepsy: a double-blind comparison with phenytoin. Epilepsia 1999;40(5):601-7. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Steinhoff 2005 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Steinhoff BJ, Ueberall MA, Siemes H, Kurlemann G, Schmitz B, Bergmann L, LAM Safe Study Group.The LAM-SAFE Study: lamotrigine versus carbamazepine or valproic acid in newly diagnosed focal and generalised epilepsies in adolescents and adults. Seizure 2005;14(8):597-605. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Stephen 2007 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Stephen LJ, Sills GJ, Leach JP, Butler E, Parker P, Hitiris N, et al.Sodium valproate versus lamotrigine: a randomised comparison of efficacy, tolerability and effects on circulating androgenic hormones in newly diagnosed epilepsy. Epilepsy Research 2007;75(2-3):122-9. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Suresh 2015 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Suresh SH, Chakraborty A, Virupakshaiah A, Kumar N.Efficacy and safety of levetiracetam and carbamazepine as monotherapy in partial seizures. Epilepsy Research and Treatment 2015;2015:Article ID 415082. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Thilothammal 1996 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Thilothammal N, Banu K, Ratnam RS.Comparison of phenobarbitone, phenytoin with sodium valproate: randomized, double-blind study. Indian Pediatrics 1996;33(7):549-55. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Trinka 2013 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Pohlmann-Eden B, Marson AG, Noack-Rink M, Ramirez F, Tofighy A, Werhahn KJ, et al.Comparative effectiveness of levetiracetam, valproate and carbamazepine among elderly patients with newly diagnosed epilepsy: subgroup analysis of the randomized, unblinded KOMET study. BMC Neurology 2016;16(1):149. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Trinka E, Marson AG, Van Paesschen W, Kälviäinen R, Marovac J, Duncan B, et al.KOMET: an unblinded, randomised, two parallel-group, stratified trial comparing the effectiveness of levetiracetam with controlled-release carbamazepine and extended-release sodium valproate as monotherapy in patients with newly diagnosed epilepsy. Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery and Psychiatry 2013;84(10):1138-47. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Trinka 2018 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Ben-Menachem E, Trinka E, Kowacs P, Elger C, Moreira J, Ikedo F, et al.Efficacy of eslicarbazepine acetate versus controlled-release carbamazepine as monotherapy in patients with newly diagnosed partial-onset seizures. Neurology 2016;87(2):e20. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Ben-Menachem E, Trinka E, Kowacs P, Elger C, Moreira J, Pinto R, et al.Efficacy of eslicarbazepine acetate vs. controlled-release carbamazepine as monotherapy in patients with newly diagnosed partial-onset seizures. Epilepsia 2016;57(Suppl 2):32, Abstract no: 0002. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Kowacs P, Trinka E, Ben-Menachem E, Elger CE, Moreira J, Pinto R, et al.Safety and tolerability of eslicarbazepine acetate as monotherapy in patients with newly diagnosed partial-onset seizures. European Journal of Neurology 2016;Suppl 2:770, Abstract no: P32045. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Kowacs PA, Trinka E, Ben-Menachem E, Elger C, Joana M, Ikedo F, et al.Safety and tolerability of eslicarbazepine acetate as monotherapy in patients with newly diagnosed partial-onset seizures. Neurology 2016;87(2):e20. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Trinka E, Ben-Menachem E, Kowacs PA, Elger C, Keller B, Loffler K, et al.Efficacy and safety of eslicarbazepine acetate versus controlled-release carbamazepine monotherapy in newly diagnosed epilepsy: a phase III double-blind, randomized, parallel-group, multicenter study. Epilepsia 2018;59(2):479-91. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Trinka E, Kowacs P, Ben-Menachem E, Elger C, Moreira J, Pinto R, et al.Safety and tolerability of eslicarbazepine acetate as monotherapy in patients with newly diagnosed partial-onset seizures. Epilepsia 2016;57(Suppl 2):186-7, Abstract no: P615. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Trinka E, Kowacs P, Ben-Menachem E, Elger CE, Moreira J, Pinto R, et al.Efficacy of eslicarbazepine acetate versus controlled-release carbamazepine as monotherapy in patients with newly diagnosed partial-onset seizures. In: European Journal of Neurology Conference: 2nd Congress of the European Academy of Neurology; 2016. Vol. 23 (Suppl 2). Copenhagen, Denmark, 2016:631-2, Abstract no: P31067. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Trinka E, Rocamora R, Chaves J, Moreira J, Ikedo F, Soares-da-Silva P, et al.Long-term efficacy and safety of eslicarbazepine acetate monotherapy for adults with newly diagnosed focal epilepsy: an open-label extension study. Epilepsia 2020;61(10):2129-41. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Turnbull 1985 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Turnbull DM, Howel D, Rawlins MD, Chadwick DW.Which drug for the adult epileptic patient: phenytoin or valproate? British Medical Journal 1985;290(6471):815-9. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Turnbull DM, Rawlins MD, Weightman D, Chadwick DW.A comparison of phenytoin and valproate in previously untreated adult epileptic patients. Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery &amp; Psychiatry 1982;45(1):55-9. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Verity 1995 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Easter D, O'Bryan-Tear CG, Verity C.Weight gain with valproate or carbamazepine - a reappraisal. Seizure 1997;6(2):121-5. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Verity CM, Hosking G, Easter DJ, Paediatric EPITEG Collaborative Group.A multicentre comparative trial of sodium valproate and carbamazepine in paediatric epilepsy. Developmental Medicine &amp; Child Neurology 1995;37(2):97-108. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Werhahn 2015 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>EUCTR2005-003324-19-AT.STEP ONE (Study on the Treatment of Elderly Patients with Older and Newer antiEpileptic drugs) trial: a multicentre, double-blind, randomized, phase IV clinical trial comparing the safety, tolerability and efficacy of levetiracetam versus lamotrigine and carbamazepine in the oral antiepileptic therapy of newly diagnosed elderly patients with focal epilepsy - STEP ONE. who.int/trialsearch/Trial2.aspx?TrialID=EUCTR2005-003324-19-AT (accessed 08 April 2021). </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Werhahn KJ, Trinka E, Dobesberger J, Ruckes C, Krämer G.Levetiracetam is superior to carbamazepine-SR in newly diagnosed epilepsy in the elderly: results of the STEP-ONE trial. Epilepsia 2012;53 Suppl 5:49, Abstract no: p164. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Werhahn KJ, Trinka E, Dobesberger J, Unterberger I, Baum P, Deckert-Schmitz M, et al.A randomized, double-blind comparison of antiepileptic drug treatment in the elderly with new-onset focal epilepsy. Epilepsia 2015;56(3):450-9. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Wild I, Noack-Rink M, Ramirez F, Tofighy A, Werhahn K.Comparative effectiveness of the antiepileptic drugs (AEDs) levetiracetam, valproate and carbamazepine among patients aged 60 years and over with newly diagnosed epilepsy. Journal of Neurology 2014;261 (Suppl 1):S159-S60, Abstract no: EP2238. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Wu 2018 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Wu D, Chen L, Ji F, Si Y, Sun H.The effects of oxcarbazepine, levetiracetam, and lamotrigine on semen quality, sexual function, and sex hormones in male adults with epilepsy. Epilepsia 2018;59(7):1344-50. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Xu 2012 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Xu F, Sun HB.Comparative study for retention rate of new antiepileptic drugs as an initial monotherapy in complex partial epilepsy. Chinese Journal of New Drugs 2012;21(11):1265-8. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
      </ReferenceList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References to studies excluded from this review</Title>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Albani 2006 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Albani F, Baruzzi A, Primo Study Group.Oxcarbazepine long-term treatment retention in patients switched over from carbamazepine. Neurological Sciences 2006;27(3):173-5. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Alsaadi 2002 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Alsaadi TM, Thieman C, Zusman EE.Levetiracetam monotherapy for adults with localization-related epilepsy. Epilepsy and Behavior 2002;3(5):471-4. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Alsaadi 2005 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Alsaadi TM, Shatzel A, Marquez AV, Jorgensen J, Farias S.Clinical experience of levetiracetam monotherapy for adults with epilepsy: 1-year follow-up study. Seizure 2005;14(2):139-42. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Baxter 1998 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Baxter L, Cheesbrough A.An open randomised comparison of Lamictal (lamotrigine) with physicians preferred choice of either valproate or carbamazepine as monotherapy in patients over 12 years of age with newly diagnosed epilepsy. Clinical summary report (unpublished) 1998. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Ben‐Menachem 2003 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Ben-Menachem E.Preliminary efficacy of levetiracetam in monotherapy. Epileptic Disorders 2003;5(Suppl 1):S51-5. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Beydoun 1997 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Beydoun A, Fischer J, Labar DR, Harden C, Cantrell D, Uthman BM, et al, The US Gabapentin Study Group 82/83.Gabapentin monotherapy: II. A 26-week, double-blind, dose-controlled, multicenter study of conversion from polytherapy in outpatients with refractory complex partial or secondarily generalized seizures. Neurology 1997;49(3):746-52. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Beydoun 1998 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Beydoun A, Fakhoury T, Nasreddine W, Abou-Khalil B.Conversion to high dose gabapentin monotherapy in patients with medically refractory partial epilepsy. Epilepsia 1998;39(2):188-93. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Beydoun 2000 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Beydoun A, Sachdeo RC, Rosenfeld WE, Krauss GL, Sessler N, Mesenbrink P, et al.Oxcarbazepine monotherapy for partial-onset seizures: a multicenter, double-blind, clinical trial. Neurology 2000;54(12):2245-51. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Bittencourt 1993 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Bittencourt PR, Antoniuk SA, Bigarella MM, Da Costa JC, Doro MP, Ferreira AS, et al.Carbamazepine and phenytoin in epilepsies refractory to barbiturates: efficacy, toxicity and mental function. Epilepsy Research 1993;16(2):147-55. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Canadian Group 1999 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Bawden HN, Camfield CS, Camfield PR, Cunningham C, Darwish H, Dooley JM, et al, Canadian Study Group for Childhood Epilepsy.The cognitive and behavioural effects of clobazam and standard monotherapy are comparable. Epilepsy Research 1999;33(2-3):133-43. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Cereghino 1974 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Cereghino JJ, Brock JT, Van Meter JC, Penry JK, Smith LD, White BG.Carbamazepine for epilepsy. A controlled prospective evaluation. Neurology 1974;24(5):401-10. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Chung 2012 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Chung S, Ceja H, Gawlowicz J, Avakyan G, McShea C, Schiemann J, et al.Levetiracetam extended release conversion to monotherapy for the treatment of patients with partial-onset seizures: a double-blind, randomised, multicentre, historical control study. Epilepsy Research 2012;101(1-2):92-102. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>DeToledo 2000 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>DeToledo JC, Ramsay RE, Lowe MR, Greiner M, Garofalo EA.Increased seizures after discontinuing carbamazepine: results from the gabapentin monotherapy trial. Therapeutic Drug Monitoring 2000;22(6):753-6. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>EUCTR2004‐004053‐26‐SE {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>EUCTR2004-004053-26-SE.An explorative use open-label, multi-center, randomized trial studying the safety and efficacy of levetiracetam (500 mg/day to 3000 mg/day) and valproate (600 mg/day to 3000 mg/day) as monotherapy in newly diagnosed patients over the age of 65 years - Scandinavian elderly study. www.clinicaltrialsregister.eu (accessed 08 April 2021). </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>EUCTR2010‐018284‐42‐NL {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>EUCTR2010-018284-42-NL.A trial comparing efficacy, safety and tolerance between levetiracetam and valproic acid in children with epilepsy. www.clinicaltrialsregister.eu (accessed 08 April 2021). </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Fakhoury 2004 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Fakhoury TA, Hammer AE, Vuong A, Messenheimer JA.Efficacy and tolerability of conversion to monotherapy with lamotrigine compared with valproate and carbamazepine in patients with epilepsy. Epilepsy &amp; Behavior 2004;5(4):532-8. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Foldvary‐Schaefer 2017 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Foldvary-Schaefer N, Neme-Mercante S, Andrews N, Bruton M, Wang L, Morrison S, et al.Wake up to sleep: the effects of lacosamide on daytime sleepiness in adults with epilepsy. Epilepsy &amp; Behavior 2017;75:176-82. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>French 2012 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>French JA, Temkin NR, Shneker BF, Hammer AE, Caldwell PT, Messenheimer JA.Lamotrigine XR conversion to monotherapy: first study using a historical control group. Neurotherapy 2012;9(1):176-84. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Gilliam 1998 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Gilliam F, Vazquez B, Sackellares JC, Chang GY, Messenheimer J, Nyberg J, et al.An active-control trial of lamotrigine monotherapy for partial seizures. Neurology 1998;51(4):1018-25. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Gruber 1962 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Gruber CM, Brock JT, Dyken MD.Comparison of the effectiveness of phenobarbital, mephobarbital, primidone, dipheylhydantoin, ethotoin, metharbital, and methylphenylhydantion in motor seizures. Clinical Pharmacology &amp; Therapeutics 1962;3:23-8. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Hakami 2012 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Hakami T, O'Brien TJ, Petty SJ, Sakellarides M, Christie J, Kantor S, et al.Monotherapy with levetiracetam versus older AEDs: a randomized comparative trial of effects on bone health. Calcified Tissue International 2016;98(6):556-65. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Hakami T, Todaro M, Petrovski S, MacGregor L, Velakoulis D, Tan M, et al.Substitution monotherapy with levetiracetam vs older antiepileptic drugs: a randomized comparative trial. Archives of Neurology 2012;69(12):1563-71. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Hu 2012 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>ChiCTR-TRC-10001131.The efficacy and safety of topiramate and valproate in treatment of Chinese patients with partial and generalised epilepsy: a multi-center, long-term follow up randomised controlled trial. http://www.chictr.org.cn/historyversionpub.aspx?regno=ChiCTR-TRC-10001131 (first posted 04 July 2015). </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Hu Y, Huang X, Shen D, Ding M, Sun H, Peng B, et al.Outcomes of sustained-release formulation of valproate and topiramate monotherapy in patients with epilepsy: a multi-centre, cohort study. PLOS One 2012;7(12):e47982. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>ISRCTN73223855 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>ISRCTN73223855.A randomised controlled trial of phenobarbitone and phenytoin for newly diagnosed epilepsy in adults. https://doi.org/10.1186/ISRCTN73223855 (first posted 17 July 2007). </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Kaminow 2003 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Kaminow L, Schimschock JR, Hammer AE, Vuong A.Lamotrigine monotherapy compared with carbamazepine, phenytoin, or valproate monotherapy in patients with epilepsy. Epilepsy &amp; Behavior 2003;4(6):659-66. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Kerr 1999 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Kerr M, Kane K, Moorat A.Switching patients to monotherapy: efficacy and tolerability for Lamictal(r) compared to valproate. European Journal of Neurology 1999;6(Suppl 3):17. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Kerr 2001 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Kerr M, Moorat A, Curtis P.Lamotrigine compared to valproate: a randomised open label switch to monotherapy study in patients with uncontrolled epilepsy. Journal of the Neurological Sciences 2001;187(Suppl 1):S291-2. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Loiseau 1984 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Loiseau P, Cohadon S, Jogeix M, Legroux M, Dartigues JF.Efficacy of sodium valproate in partial epilepsy. Crossed study of valproate and carbamazepine. Revue Neurologique 1984;140(6-7):434-7. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Loring 2020 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Loring DW, Meador KJ, Shinnar S, Gaillard WD, Wheless JW, Kessler SK, et al.Differential antiseizure medication sensitivity of the Affective Reactivity Index: a randomized controlled trial in new-onset pediatric focal epilepsy. Epilepsy &amp; Behavior 2020;102:106687. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>NCT01891890 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>NCT01891890.Cognitive AED outcomes in pediatric localization related epilepsy (COPE). https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT01891890 (first posted 19 September 2017). </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Park 2001 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Park WS, Kim CW, Park SP, Kwon SH.Safety and efficacy of topiramate monotherapy in children with recent-onset seizures. Journal of Korean Epilepsy Society 2001;5(1):65-9. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Reinikainen 1984 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Reinikainen K, Keranen T, Hallikainen E, Riekkinen PJ.Substitution of diphenylhydantoin by oxcarbazepine or carbamazepine: double-blind study. Acta Neurologica Scandinavica 1984;69(Suppl 98):89-90. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Reinikainen 1987 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Reinikainen KJ, Keranen T, Halonen T, Komulainen H, Riekkinen PJ.Comparison of oxcarbazepine and carbamazepine: a double-blind study. Epilepsy Research 1987;1(5):284-9. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Rosenow 2012 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Rosenow F, Schade-Brittinger C, Burchardi N, Bauer S, Klein KM, Weber Y, et al, LaLiMo Study Group.The LaLiMo Trial: lamotrigine compared with levetiracetam in the initial 26 weeks of monotherapy for focal and generalised epilepsy - an open-label, prospective, randomised controlled multicenter study. Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery &amp; Psychiatry 2012;83(11):1093-8. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Rysz 1994 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Rysz A.Effect of monotherapy with phenytoin or carbamazepine on somatosensory evoked potentials in patients with newly diagnosed epilepsy. Polski Tygodnik Lekarski 1994;49(4-5):79-81. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Simonsen 1975a {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Simonsen N, Olsen PZ, Kuhl V.Carbamazepine versus diphenylhydantoin in psychomotor epilepsy. A double blind study of antiepileptic effect and side effects. Ugeskrift for Laeger 1975;137(41):2392-6. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Simonsen 1975b {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Simonsen N, Zander Olsen P, Kuhl V.A double blind study of carbamazepine and diphenylhydantoin in temporal lobe epilepsy. Acta Neurologica Scandinavica 1975;52(Suppl 60):39-42. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Tabrizi 2019 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Tabrizi N, Zarvani A, Rezaei P, Cheraghmakani H, Alizadeh-Navaei R.Levetiracetam in genetic generalized epilepsy:a prospective unblinded active-controlled trial. Epilepsy Research 2019;157:106214. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Taragano 2003 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Taragano FE, Loñ L, Sarasola D, Serrano C.Is oxcarbazepine better than phenytoin for the treatment of dementia patients complicated with secondary epilepsy? A comparative study. Revista Neurologica Argentina 2003;28(4):209-16. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
      </ReferenceList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References to studies awaiting assessment</Title>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Ahadi 2020 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Ahadi P, Nasiri J, Ghazavi MR, Mosavian T, Mansouri V.A comparative study on the efficacy of levetiracetam and carbamazepine in the treatment of rolandic seizures in children: an open-label randomized controlled trial. Journal of Research in Pharmacy Practice 2020;9(2):68-72. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>IRCT20190208042654N3.The comparison of efficacy of levetiracetam and carbamazepine in the treatment of rolandic seizures in children. https://en.irct.ir/trial/44791 (registered on 07 January 2020). </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Akhondian 2020 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Akhondian J, Ashrafzadeh F, Eslamiyeh H.Levetiracetam (levebel) versus carbamazepine monotherapy for focal epilepsy in children: a randomized clinical trial [Iranian Journal of Child Neurology]. 2020 14;2:69-77. </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>IRCT2015030821355N1.Levetiracetam versus carbamazepine monotherapy in the treatment of focal epilepsy of children. en.irct.ir/trial/18738 (registered on 12 January 2017). </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>CTRI/2011/08/001959 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>CTRI/2011/08/001959.A phase III clinical trial to evaluate the efficacy and safety profile of eslicarbezepine acetate as monotherapy in patients with partial onset seizures. http://www.ctri.nic.in/Clinicaltrials/showallp.php?mid1=3329&amp;EncHid=&amp;userName=CTRI/2011/08/001959 (registered on 23 August 2011). </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Du 2016 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Du Z, Jiao Y, Shi L.Association of UGT2B7 and UGT1A4 polymorphisms with serum concentration of antiepileptic drugs in children. Medical Science Monitor 2016;22:4107. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Goyal 2016 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Goyal M, Lal V, Sandal R, Modi M, Sachdeva J, Kharbanda P.A comparative blinded study of cognitive effects of carbamazepine, valproate, lamotrigine and levetiracetam in adult epileptic patients. Annals of Indian Academy of Neurology 2016;19(Suppl 2):S93, Abstract no: EP23/305. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>IRCT201202068943N1 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>IRCT201202068943N1.Efficacy of oxcarbazepine and phenytoin in control of epilepsy in the elderly. https://en.irct.ir/trial/9406?revision=9406 (registered on 17 March 2012). </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>NCT00154076 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>NCT00154076.A multicenter comparative trial of zonisamide and topiramate as initial monotherapy in untreated epilepsies. https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT00154076 (first posted 12 September 2005). </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Shi 2020 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Shi KL, Guo JX, Zhao HM, Hong H, Yang CZ, Wu YH, et al.The effect of levetiracetam and oxcarbazepine monotherapy on thyroid hormones and bone metabolism in children with epilepsy: a prospective study. Epilepsy &amp; Behavior 2020;113:107555. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Suo 2021 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Suo GH, Zheng YQ, Wu YJ, Tang JH.Effects of levetiracetam and oxcarbazepine monotherapy on intellectual and cognitive development in children with benign epilepsy with centrotemporal spikes. Acta Neurologica Belgica 2021;15:15. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Wang 2016 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Wang YY, Wang MG, Yao D, Huang XX, Zhang T, Deng XQ.Comparison of impact on seizure frequency and epileptiform discharges of children with epilepsy from topiramate and phenobarbital. European Review for Medical and Pharmacological Sciences 2016;20(5):993-7. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Zhou 2019 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Zhou S, Zhan Q, Wu X.Effect of levetiracetam on cognitive function and clonic seizure frequency in children with epilepsy. Current Molecular Medicine 2019;19(9):699-703. </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
      </ReferenceList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References to ongoing studies</Title>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>CTRI/2017/11/010605 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>CTRI/2017/11/010605.Comparsion of levetiracetam and sodium valproate mono therapy in childhood epilepsy. http://ctri.nic.in/Clinicaltrials/showallp.php?mid1=18800&amp;EncHid=&amp;userName=CTRI/2017/11/010605 (registered 23 November 2017). </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>CTRI/2019/04/018520 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>CTRI/2019/04/018520.Comparison of the efficacy of sodium valproate with levetiracetam in controlling seizure in the age group of 2 to 18 years, a randomised control trial. http://ctri.nic.in/Clinicaltrials/showallp.php?mid1=32252&amp;EncHid=&amp;userName=CTRI/2019/04/018520 (registered 09 April 2019). </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>CTRI/2019/05/018990 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>CTRI/2019/05/018990.Comparison of the seizure drug levetiracetam with controlled release carbamazepine in new focal seizure patients. http://ctri.nic.in/Clinicaltrials/showallp.php?mid1=30242&amp;EncHid=&amp;userName=CTRI/2019/05/018990 (registered on 08 May 2019). </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>CTRI/2020/09/027792 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>CTRI/2020/09/027792.Open labeled randomized controlled trial comparing efficacy of oral levetiracetam vs sodium valproate as first line monotherapy in newly diagnosed generalized epilepsy in children. http://ctri.nic.in/Clinicaltrials/showallp.php?mid1=39204&amp;EncHid=&amp;userName=CTRI/2020/09/027792 (registered 14 September 2020). </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>EpiNet‐First Trial 1 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>ACTRN12615000643572.EpiNet-First Trial 1: comparison of efficacy of levetiracetam, lamotrigine and carbamazepine in people with previously untreated epilepsy who have focal seizures. anzctr.org.au/Trial/Registration/TrialReview.aspx?id=368678&amp;showOriginal=true&amp;isReview=trueIn: (registered on 02 June 2015). </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>EpiNet‐First Trial 2 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>ACTRN12615000556549.EpiNet-First Trial 2: comparison of efficacy of levetiracetam and sodium valproate in people with previously untreated epilepsy who have generalised seizures. https://www.anzctr.org.au/Trial/Registration/TrialReview.aspx?id=368462 (registered 29 May 2015). </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>EpiNet‐First Trial 3 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>ACTRN12615000639527.EpiNet-First Trial 3: comparison of efficacy of levetiracetam and lamotrigine in people with previously untreated epilepsy who have generalised seizures, and for whom sodium valproate is not deemed an acceptable anti-epileptic drug. https://www.anzctr.org.au/Trial/Registration/TrialReview.aspx?id=368675 (registered 22 June 2015). </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>EpiNet‐First Trial 4 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>ACTRN12615000640505.EpiNet-First Trial 4: comparison of efficacy of levetiracetam, lamotrigine and sodium valproate in people with previously untreated epilepsy who have unclassified seizures. https://www.anzctr.org.au/Trial/Registration/TrialReview.aspx?id=368663;(registered 22 June 2015). </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>EpiNet‐First Trial 5 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>ACTRN12615000641594.EpiNet-First Trial 5: comparison of efficacy of levetiracetam and lamotrigine in people with previously untreated epilepsy who have unclassified seizures, and for whom sodium valproate is not deemed an acceptable anti-epileptic drug. https://www.anzctr.org.au/Trial/Registration/TrialReview.aspx?ACTRN=12615000641594 (registered on 22 June 2015). </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>IRCT20120215009014N351 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>IRCT20120215009014N351.Effect of levetiracetam monotherapy versus sodium valproate on treatment of children with generalized or focal epilepsy. https://en.irct.ir/trial/46862 (registered 04 April 2020). </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>IRCT20170216032603N2 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>IRCT20170216032603N2.Analysis of the efficacy and side effects of levetiracetam and carbamazepine on treatment of children's epilepsy. https://en.irct.ir/trial/44705 (registered 19 June 2020). </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>NCT02201251 {published data only}</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>EUCTR2012-001552-19-HU.A study to investigate the safety of the drugs topiramate and levetiracetam in treating children recently diagnosed with epilepsy. https://www.clinicaltrialsregister.eu/ctr-search/trial/2012-001552-19/HU (first posted 30 October 2014). </Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>NCT02201251.A study to investigate the safety of the drugs topiramate and levetiracetam in treating children recently diagnosed with epilepsy. https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT02201251 (first posted 28 July 2021). </Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
      </ReferenceList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>Additional references</Title>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Abdelsayed 2013</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Abdelsayed M, Sokolov S, Ruben PC.A thermosensitive mutation alters the effects of lacosamide on slow inactivation in neuronal voltage-gated sodium channels, NaV1.2. Frontiers in Pharmacology 2013;20(4):121.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Ahmed 2012</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Ahmed I, Sutton AJ, Riley RD.Assessment of publication bias, selection bias, and unavailable data in meta-analyses using individual participant data: a database survey. BMJ 2012;344:d7762.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Almeida 2007</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Almeida L, Soares-da-Silva P.Eslicarbazepine acetate (BIA 2-093). Neurotherapeutics 2007;4(1):88-96.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Annegers 1999</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Annegers JF, Dubinsky S, Coan SP, Newmark ME, Roht L.The incidence of epilepsy and unprovoked seizures in multiethnic, urban health maintenance organizations. Epilepsia 1999;40(4):502-6.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Berg 2010</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Berg AT, Berkovic SF, Brodie MJ, Buchhalter J, Cross JH, Van Emde Boas W, et al.Revised terminology and concepts for organization of seizures and epilepsies: report of the ILAE Commission on Classification and Terminology, 2005-2009. Epilepsia 2010;51:676-85.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Beyreuther 2007</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Beyreuther BK, Freitag J, Heers C, Krebsfänger N, Scharfenecker U, Stöhr T.Lacosamide: a review of preclinical properties. CNS Drug Reviews 2007;13(1):21-42.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Bourgeois 1987</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Bourgeois B, Beaumanoir A, Blajev B, De la Cruz N, Despland PA, Egli M, et al.Monotherapy with valproate in primary generalized epilepsies. Epilepsia 1987;28(Suppl 2):S8-11.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Brodie 1996</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Brodie MJ, Dichter MA.Antiepileptic drugs. New England Journal of Medicine 1996;334(3):168-75.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Bromley 2013</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Bromley RL, Mawer GE, Briggs M, Cheyne C, Clayton-Smith J, García-Fiñana M, et al.The prevalence of neurodevelopmental disorders in children prenatally exposed to antiepileptic drugs. Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery and Psychiatry 2013;84(6):637-43.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Bucher 1997</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Bucher HC, Guyatt GH, Griffith LE, Walter SD.The results of direct and indirect treatment comparisons in meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Journal of Clinical Epidemiology 1997;50(6):683-91.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Canger 1999</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Canger R, Battino D, Canevini MP, Fumarola C, Guidolin L, Vignoli A, et al.Malformations in offspring of women with epilepsy: a prospective study. Epilepsia 1999;40(9):1231-6.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Carl 1992</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Carl GF, Smith ML.Phenytoin-folate interactions: differing effects of the sodium salt and the free acid of phenytoin. Epilepsia 1992;33(2):372-5.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Chaimani 2013</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Chaimani A, Higgins JP, Mavridis D, Spyridonos P, Salanti G.Graphical tools for network meta-analysis in STATA. PLOS One 2013;8(10):e76654.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Cockerell 1995</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Cockerell OC, Johnson AL, Sander JW, Hart YM, Shorvon SD.Remission of epilepsy: results from the National General Practice Study of Epilepsy. Lancet 1995;346(8968):140-4.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Commission 1981</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Commission on Classification and Terminology of the International League Against Epilepsy.Proposal for revised clinical and electroencephalographic classification of epileptic seizures. Epilepsia 1981;22(4):489-501.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Commission 1989</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Commission on Classification and Terminology of the International League Against Epilepsy.Proposal for revised classification of epilepsies and epileptic syndromes. Epilepsia 1989;30(4):389-99.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Coulter 1993</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Coulter DA, Sombati S, DeLorenzo RJ.Selective effects of topiramate on sustained repetitive firing and spontaneous bursting in cultured hippocampal neurons. Epilepsia 1993;34(Suppl 2):123.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Delgado‐Escueta 1984</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Delgado-Escueta AV, Enrile-Bacsal F.Juvenile myoclonic epilepsy of Janz. Neurology 1984;34(3):285-94.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Dias 2010</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Dias S, Welton NJ, Caldwell DM, Ades AE.Checking consistency in mixed treatment comparison meta-analysis. Statistics in Medicine 2010;29((7-8)):932-44.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>eMC 2021</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Up to date, approved and regulated prescribing and patient information for licensed medicines. Electronic Medicines Compendium (eMC). www.medicines.org.uk/emc/ (accessed 08 April 2021).</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Endoh 1994</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Endoh A, Kinno I, Kawai M, Hiramatsu M, Mori A.Effect of zonisamide on neurotransmitter in mouse brain. Neurosciences 1994;20(Suppl):P173-6.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Engel 2008</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Engel J, Pedley TA, Aicardi J.Antiepileptic drugs. In: Epilepsy: A Comprehensive Textbook. Vol. 3. Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins, 2008:1488-9.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Faigle 1990</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Faigle JW, Menge GP.Metabolic characteristics of oxcarbazepine (Trileptal) and their beneficial implications for enzyme induction and drug interactions. Behaviour Neurology 1990;3(1):21-30.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>FDA 2021</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>US Food and Drug Administration.Drugs. fda.gov/drugs (accessed 08 April 2021).</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>French 2004</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>French JA, Kanner AM, Bautista J, Abou-Khalil B, Browne T, Harden CL, et al.Efficacy and tolerability of the new antiepileptic drugs I: treatment of new onset epilepsy: report of the Therapeutics and Technology Assessment Subcommittee and Quality Standards Subcommittee of the American Academy of Neurology and the American Epilepsy Society. Neurology 2004;62(8):1252-60.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>French 2007</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>French JA, Kanner AM, Bautista J, Abou-Khalil B, Browne T, Harden CL, et al.Appendix C: Efficacy and tolerability of the new antiepileptic drugs I: Treatment of new onset epilepsy: Report of the Therapeutics and Technology Assessment Subcommittee and Quality Standards Subcommittee of the American Academy of Neurology and the American Epilepsy Society. CONTINUUM Lifelong Learning in Neurology 2007;13:203-11.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Gillard 2006</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Gillard M, Chatelain P, Fuks B.Binding characteristics of levetiracetam to synaptic vesicle protein 2A (SV2A) in human brain and in CHO cells expressing the human recombinant protein. European Journal of Pharmacology 2006;536(1-2):102-8.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Gladstone 1992</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Gladstone DJ, Bologa M, Maguire C, Pastuszak A, Koren G.Course of pregnancy and fetal outcome following maternal exposure to carbamazepine and phenytoin: a prospective study. Reproductive Toxicology 1992;6(3):257-61.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Glauser 2006</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Glauser T, Ben-Menachem E, Bourgeois B, Cnaan A, Chadwick D, Guerreiro C, et al.ILAE treatment guidelines: evidence-based analysis of antiepileptic drug efficacy and effectiveness as initial monotherapy for epileptic seizures and syndromes. Epilepsia 2006;47(7):1094-120.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>GRADE 2008</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>GRADE Working Group.GRADE: an emerging consensus on rating quality of evidence and strength of recommendations. BMJ 2008;336:924.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Granger 1995</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Granger P, Biton B, Faure C, Vige X, Depoortere H, Graham D, et al.Modulation of the gamma-aminobutyric acid type A receptor by the antiepileptic drugs carbamazepine and phenytoin. Molecular Pharmacology 1995;47:1189-96.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Grant 1992</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Grant SM, Faulds D.Oxcarbazepine. A review of its pharmacology and therapeutic potential in epilepsy, trigeminal neuralgia and affective disorders. Drugs 1992;43:873-88.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Grünewald 1993</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Grünewald R, Panayiotopoulos CP.Juvenile myoclonic epilepsy: a review. Archives of Neurology 1993;50:594-8.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Hauser 1993</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Hauser WA, Annegers JF, Kurland LT.Incidence of epilepsy and unprovoked seizures in Rochester, Minnesota 1935-1984. Epilepsia 1993;34:453-68.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Higgins 2002</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Higgins JPT, Thompson SG.Quantifying heterogeneity in a meta-analysis. Statistics in Medicine 2002;21:1539-58.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Higgins 2003</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Higgins JPT, Thompson SG, Deeks JJ, Altman DG.Measuring inconsistency in meta-analyses. BMJ 2003;327:557-60.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Higgins 2011</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Higgins JPT, Altman DG, Sterne JAC (editors).Chapter 8: Assessing risk of bias in included studies. In: Higgins JPT, Green S (editors). Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions Version 5.1.0 (updated March 2011). The Cochrane Collaboration, 2011. Available from training.cochrane.org/handbook/archive/v5.1.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Higgins 2012</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Higgins JPT, Jackson D, Barrett JK, Lu G, Ades, White IR.Consistency and inconsistency in network meta-analysis: concepts and models for multi-arm studies. Research Synthesis Methods 2012;3:98-110.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Hill 1993</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Hill DR, Suman-Chauhan N, Woodruff GN.Localization of [3H] gabapentin to a novel site in rat brain: autoradiographic studies. European Journal of Pharmacology 1993;244:303-9.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Hirtz 2007</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Hirtz D, Thurman DJ, Gwinn-Hardy K, Mohamed M, Chaudhuri AR, Zalutsky R.How common are the "common" neurologic disorders? Neurology 2007;68:326-37.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>ILAE 1998</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>ILAE Commission on Antiepileptic Drugs.Considerations on designing clinical trials to evaluate the place of new antiepileptic drugs in the treatment of newly diagnosed and chronic patients with epilepsy. Epilepsia 1998;39(7):799-803.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Jackson 2012</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Jackson D, White IR, Riley R.Quantifying the impact of between-study heterogeneity in multivariate meta-analyses. Statistics in Medicine 2012;31:3805-20.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Jeavons 1977</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Jeavons PM, Clark JE, Maheshwan MC.Treatment of generalized epilepsies of childhood and adolescence with sodium valproate. Developmental Medicine and Child Neurology 1977;19:9-25.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Joseph 2015</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Joseph PD, Craig JC, Caldwell PH.Clinical trials in children. British Journal of Clinical Pharmacology 2015;79(3):357-69.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Juul‐Jenson 1983</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Juul-Jenson P, Foldspang A.Natural history of epileptic seizures. Epilepsia 1983;24:297-312.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Kawai 1994</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Kawai M, Hiramatsu M, Endo A, Kinno I, Endo Y, Suh M, et al.Effect of zonisamide on release of aspartic acid and gamma-aminobutyric acid from the hippocampal slices of E1 mice. Neurosciences 1994;20:115-9.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Kirkham 2010</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Kirkham JJ, Dwan KM, Altman DG, Gamble C, Dodd S, Smyth R, et al.The impact of outcome reporting bias in randomised controlled trials on a cohort of systematic reviews. BMJ 2010;340:c365.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Kwan 2000</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Kwan P, Brodie MJ.Early identification of refractory epilepsy. New England Journal of Medicine 2000;342:314-9.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Kwok 2017</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Kwok CS, Johnson EL, Krauss GL.Comparing safety and efficacy of “third-generation” antiepileptic drugs: long-term extension and post-marketing treatment. CNS Drugs 2017;31(11):959-74.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Lees 1993</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Lees G, Leach MJ.Studies on the mechanism of action of the novel anti-convulsant lamotrigine (Lamictal) using primary neuroglial cultures from rat cortex. Brain Research 1993;612:190-9.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Lefebvre 2021</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Lefebvre C, Glanville J, Briscoe S, Littlewood A, Marshall C, Metzendorf M-I, et al.Technical Supplement to Chapter 4: Searching for and selecting studies. In: Higgins JPT, Thomas J, Chandler J, Cumpston MS, Li T, Page MJ, Welch VA (eds). Cochrane Handbook for Systematic Reviews of Interventions Version 6.2 (updated February 2021). Cochrane, 2021. Available from www.training.cochrane.org/handbook.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Liporace 1994</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Liporace JD, Sperling MR, Dichter MA.Absence seizures and carbamazepine in adults. Epilepsia 1994;35(5):1026-8.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Lu 2006</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Lu G, Ades A.Assessing evidence inconsistency in mixed treatment comparisons. Journal of the American Statistical Association 2006;101(474):447-59.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Lynch 2004</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Lynch BA, Lambeng N, Nocka K, Kensel-Hammes P, Bajjalieh SM, Matagne A, et al.The synaptic vesicle protein SV2A is the binding site for the antiepileptic drug levetiracetam. National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America 2004;101 (26):9861-6.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>MacDonald 2000</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>MacDonald BK, Johnson AL, Goodridge DM, Cockerell OC, Sander JWA, Shorvon SD.Factors predicting prognosis of epilepsy after presentation with seizures. Annals of Neurology 2000;48:833-41.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Malafosse 1994</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Malafosse A, Genton P, Hirsch E, Marescaux C, Broglin D, Bernasconi R.Idiopathic Generalised Epilepsies: Clinical, Experimental and Genetic. Eastleigh: John Libbey and Company, 1994.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Marson 2000</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Marson AG, Williamson PR, Hutton JL, Clough HE, Chadwick DW.Carbamazepine versus valproate monotherapy for epilepsy. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews 2000, Issue 3. Art. No: CD001030. [DOI: 10.1002/14651858.CD001030]</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD001030</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>McClean 1995</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>McClean MJ.Gabapentin. Epilepsia 1995;36(Suppl 2):72-86.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>McLean 1986</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>McLean MJ, MacDonald RL.Sodium valproate, but not ethosuximide, produces use- and voltage-dependent limitation of high frequency repetitive firing of action potentials of mouse central neurons in cell culture. Journal of Pharmacology and Experimental Therapeutics 1986;237:1001-11.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>McLean 1999</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>McLean MJ.Gabapentin in the management of convulsive disorders. Epilepsia 1999;40(Suppl 6):S39-50; discussion S73-4.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Meador 2008</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Meador K, Reynolds M, Crean S, Fahrbach K, Probst C.Pregnancy outcomes in women with epilepsy: a systematic review and meta-analysis of published pregnancy registries and cohorts. Epilepsy Research 2008;81:1-13.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Moher 2009</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Moher D, Liberati A, Tetzlaff J, Altman DG, PRISMA Group.Preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analyses: the PRISMA statement. PLOS Medicine 2009;6(7):e1000097. [DOI: 10.1371/journal.pmed1000097]</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pmed1000097</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Morrow 2006</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Morrow J, Russel A, Guthrie E, Parsons L, Robertson I, Waddell R, et al.Malformation risks of antiepileptic drugs in pregnancy: a prospective study from the UK Epilepsy and Pregnancy Register. Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery and Neuropsychiatry 2006;77(2):193-8.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Mula 2016</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Mula M.Third generation antiepileptic drug monotherapies in adults with epilepsy. Expert Review of Neurotherapeutics 2016;16(9):1087-92.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Nevitt 2017b</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Nevitt SJ.Data Sharing and Transparency: The Impact on Evidence Synthesis [PhD thesis]. Liverpool: University of Liverpool, 2017. [AVAILABLE FROM: http://livrepository.liverpool.ac.uk/id/eprint/3017585]</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Nevitt 2018a</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Nevitt SJ, Tudur Smith C, Weston J, Marson AG.Lamotrigine versus carbamazepine monotherapy for epilepsy: an individual participant data review. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews 2018, Issue 6. Art. No: CD001031. [DOI: 10.1002/14651858.CD001031.pub4]</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD001031.pub4</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Nevitt 2018b</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Nevitt SJ, Marson AG, Weston J, Tudur Smith C.Sodium valproate versus phenytoin monotherapy for epilepsy: an individual participant data review. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews 2018, Issue 8. Art. No: CD001769. [DOI: 10.1002/14651858.CD001769.pub4]</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD001769.pub4</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Nevitt 2018c</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Nevitt SJ, Tudur Smith C, Marson AG.Oxcarbazepine versus phenytoin monotherapy for epilepsy: an individual participant data review. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews 2018, Issue 10. Art. No: CD003615. [DOI: 10.1002/14651858.CD003615.pub4]</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD003615.pub4</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Nevitt 2018d</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Nevitt SJ, Marson AG, Tudur Smith C.Carbamazepine versus phenobarbitone monotherapy for epilepsy: an individual participant data review. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews 2018, Issue 10. Art. No: CD001904. [DOI: 10.1002/14651858.CD001904.pub4]</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD001904.pub4</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Nevitt 2019a</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Nevitt SJ, Marson AG, Tudur Smith C.Carbamazepine versus phenytoin monotherapy for epilepsy: an individual participant data review. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews 2019, Issue 7. Art. No: CD001911. [DOI: 10.1002/14651858.CD001911.pub4]</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD001911.pub4</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Nevitt 2019b</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Nevitt SJ, Tudur Smith C, Marson AG.Phenobarbitone versus phenytoin monotherapy for epilepsy: an individual participant data review. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews 2019, Issue 7. Art. No: CD002217. [DOI: 10.1002/14651858.CD002217.pub3]</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD002217.pub3</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Nevitt 2019c</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Nevitt SJ, Sudell M, Tudur Smith C, Marson AG.Topiramate versus carbamazepine monotherapy for epilepsy: an individual participant data review. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews 2019, Issue 6. Art. No: CD012065. [DOI: 10.1002/14651858.CD012065.pub3]</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD012065.pub3</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Ngugi 2010</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Ngugi AK, Bottomley C, Kleinschmidt I, Sander JW, Newton CR.Estimation of the burden of active and life-time epilepsy: a meta-analytic approach. Epilepsia 2010;51:883-90.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>NICE 2012</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>National Institute for Health and Care Excellence.The epilepsies: the diagnosis and management of the epilepsies in adults and children and primary and secondary care. NICE guidelines [CG137]. nice.org.uk/guidance/cg137 (accessed prior to 20 May 2021).</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Nikolakopoulou 2020</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Nikolakopoulou A, Higgins JPT, Papakonstantinou T, Chaimani A, Del Giovane C, Egger M, Salanti G.CINeMA: an approach for assessing confidence in the results of a network meta-analysis. PLOS Medicine 2020;17(4):e1003082.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>NINDS 2021</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Stroke (NINDS).The epilepsies and seizures: hope through research. ninds.nih.gov/Disorders/Patient-Caregiver-Education/Hope-Through-Research/Epilepsies-and-Seizures-Hope-Through (accessed 08 April 2021).</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Nolan 2013a</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Nolan SJ, Sutton L, Marson A, Tudur Smith C.Consistency of outcome and statistical reporting of time-to-event data: the impact on Cochrane Reviews and meta-analyses in epilepsy. In: 21st Cochrane Colloquium: Better Knowledge for Better Health; 2013. Quebec City, 2013:114-5.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Nulman 1997</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Nulman I, Scolnik D, Chitayat D, Farkas LD, Koren G.Findings in children exposed in utero to phenytoin and carbamazepine monotherapy: independent effects of epilepsy and medications. American Journal of Medical Genetics 1997;68(1):18-24.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Okada 1998</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Okada M, Kawata Y, Mizuno K, Wada K, Kondo T, Kaneko S.Interaction between Ca2+, K+, carbamazepine and zonisamide on hippocampal extracellular glutamate monitored with a microdialysis electrode. British Journal of Pharmacology 1998;124:1277-85.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Olafsson 2005</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Olafsson E, Ludvigsson P, Gudmundsson G, Hesdorfer D, Kjartansson O, Hauser WA.Incidence of unprovoked seizures and epilepsy in Iceland and assessment of the epilepsy syndrome classification: a prospective study. Lancet Neurology 2005;4:627-34.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Ornoy 2009</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Ornoy A.Valproic acid in pregnancy: how much are we endangering the embryo and fetus? Reproductive Toxicology 2009;28(1):1-10.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Palmer 2016</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Palmer TM, Sterne JAC.Meta-Analysis in Stata: An Updated Collection from the Stata Journal. 2nd edition. Stata Press, 2016.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Parmar 1998</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Parmar MKB, Torri V, Stewart L.Extracting summary statistics to perform meta-analysis of the published literature for survival endpoints. Statistics in Medicine 1998;17:2815-34.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Penry 1989</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Penry JK, Dean JC, Riela AR.Juvenile myoclonic epilepsy: long term response to therapy. Epilepsia 1989;30:19-23.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Pinder 1977</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Pinder RM, Brogden RN, Speight TM, Avery GS.Sodium valproate: a review of its pharmacological properties and therapeutic efficacy in epilepsy. Drugs 1977;13:81-123.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Ragsdale 1991</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Ragsdale DS, Scheuer T, Catterall WA.Frequency and voltage-dependent inhibition of type IIA Na+ channels, expressed in a mammalian cell line, by local anesthetic, antiarrhythmic, and anticonvulsant drugs. Molecular Pharmacology 1991;40(5):756-65.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Rho 1996</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Rho JM, Donevan SD, Rogawski MA.Direct activation of GABAA receptors by barbiturates in cultured rat hippocampal neurons. Journal of Physiology 1996;497(2):509-22.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Sackellares 2004</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Sackellares JC, Ramsay RE, Wilder BJ, Browne TR 3rd, Shellenberger MK.Randomized, controlled clinical trial of zonisamide as adjunctive treatment for refractory partial seizures. Epilepsia 2004;45(6):610-7.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Salanti 2014</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Salanti G, Del Giovane C, Chaimani A, Caldwell DM, Higgins JP.Evaluating the quality of evidence from a network meta-analysis. PLOS One 2014;9(7):e99682.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Sander 1996</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Sander JW, Shorvon SD.Epidemiology of the epilepsies. Journal of Neurology, Neurosurgery, and Psychiatry 1996;61(5):433-43.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Sander 2004</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Sander JW.The use of anti-epileptic drugs - principles and practice. Epilepsia 2004;45(6):28-34.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>SAS 2013 [Computer program]</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>SAS Institute Inc Base SAS.Version 9.4. Cary, NC, USA: SAS Institute Inc, 2013.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Schauf 1987</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Schauf CL.Zonisamide enhances slow sodium inactivation in Myxicola. Brain Research 1987;413:185-8.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Scheffer 2017</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Scheffer IE, Berkovic S, Capovilla G, Connolly MB, French J, Guilhoto L, et al.ILAE classification of the epilepsies: position paper of the ILAE Commission for Classification and Terminology. Epilepsia 2017;58(4):512-21.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Scheinfeld 2003</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Scheinfeld N.Phenytoin in cutaneous medicine: its uses, mechanisms and side effects. Dermatology Online Journal 2003;9(3):6.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Shakir 1980</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Shakir RA.Sodium valproate, phenytoin and carbamazepine as sole anticonvulsants. In: The Place of Sodium Valproate in the Treatment of Epilepsy. London: Academic Press Inc. and the Royal Society of Medicine, 1980:7-16.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Shields 1983</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Shields WD, Saslow E.Myoclonic, atonic, and absence seizures following institution of carbamazepine therapy in children. Neurology 1983;33:1487-9.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Snead 1985</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Snead OC, Hosey LC.Exacerbation of seizures in children by carbamazepine. New England Journal of Medicine 1985;313(15):916-21.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Soares da Silva 2015</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Soares-da-Silva P, Pires N, Bonifacio MJ, Loureiro AI, Palma N, Wright LC.Eslicarbazepine acetate for the treatment of focal epilepsy: an update on its proposed mechanisms of action. Pharmacology Research &amp; Perspectives 2015;3(2):e00124.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>StataCorp 2015 [Computer program]</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Stata Statistical Software.Version 14. College Station, TX: StataCorp LP, 2015.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Suzuki 1992</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Suzuki S, Kawakami K, Nishimura S, Watanabe Y, Yagi K, Seino M, et al.Zonisamide blocks T-type calcium channel in cultured neurons of rat cerebral cortex. Epilepsy Research 1992;12:21-7.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Tomson 2011</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Tomson T, Battino D, Bonizzoni E, Craig J, Lindhout D, Sabers A, et al.Dose-dependent risk of malformation with antiepileptic drugs: an analysis of data from the EURAP epilepsy and pregnancy registry. Lancet Neurology 2011;10(7):609-17.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Trimble 1988</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Trimble MR, Cull C.Children of school age: the influence of antiepileptic drugs on behavior and intellect. Epilepsia 1988;29(Suppl 3):S15-9.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Tudur Smith 2007</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Tudur Smith C, Marson AG, Chadwick DW, Williamson PR.Multiple treatment comparisons in epilepsy monotherapy trials. Trials 2007;5(8):34.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Wallace 1997</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Wallace H, Shorvon SD, Hopkins A, O'Donoghue M.National Society of Epilepsy Guidelines. London: Royal College of Physicians, 1997.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Weston 2016</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Weston J, Bromley R, Jackson CF, Adab N, Clayton-Smith J, Greenhalgh J, et al.Monotherapy treatment of epilepsy in pregnancy: congenital malformation outcomes in the child. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews 2016, Issue 11. Art. No: CD010224. [DOI: 10.1002/14651858.CD010224.pub2]</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD010224.pub2</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>White 1997</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>White HS, Brown SD, Woodhead JH, Skeen GA, Wolf HH.Topiramate enhances GABA-mediated chloride flux and GABA-evoked chloride currents in murine brain neurons and increases seizure threshold. Epilepsy Research 1997;28:167-79.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>White 2009</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>White IR.Multivariate random-effects meta-analysis. Stata Journal 2009;9(1):40-56.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>White 2015</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>White IR.Network meta-analysis. Stata Journal 2015;15(4):951-85.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>WHO 1994</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>World Health Organization.Global comparative assessments in the health sector: disease burden, expenditures and intervention packages. Collected reprints from the Bulletin of the World Health Organization 1994. apps.who.int/iris/handle/10665/41177 (accessed 08 April 2021).</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>WHO 2021</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>World Health Organization.Epilepsy. who.int/mental_health/neurology/epilepsy/en/ (accessed 08 April 2021).</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Wilder 1995</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Wilder BJ.Phenytoin: clinical use. In: Antiepileptic Drugs. New York: Raven Press, 1995:339-44.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Williamson 2002</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Williamson PR, Tudur Smith C, Hutton JL, Marson AG.Aggregate data meta-analysis with time-to-event outcomes. Statistics in Medicine 2002;21(11):3337-51.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Willow 1985</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Willow M, Gonoi T, Catterall WA.Voltage clamp analysis of the inhibitory actions of diphenyihydantoin and carbamazepine on voltage sensitive sodium channels in neuroblastoma cells. Molecular Pharamcology 1985;27:549-58.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Wyllie 2006</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Wyllie E, Gupta A, Lachhwani DK.Antiepileptic medications. In: The Treatment of Epilepsy: Principles &amp; Practice. 4th edition. Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins, 2006:650.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Zhu 1999</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Zhu W, Rogawski A.Zonisamide depresses excitatory synaptic transmission by a presynaptic action. Epilepsia 1999;40(Suppl 7):245.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
      </ReferenceList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References to other published versions of this review</Title>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Nevitt 2017a</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Nevitt SJ, Sudell M, Weston J, Tudur Smith C, Marson A.Antiepileptic drug monotherapy for epilepsy: a network meta-analysis of individual participant data. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews 2017, Issue 12. Art. No: CD011412. [DOI: 10.1002/14651858.CD011412.pub3]</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD011412.pub3</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Nolan 2014</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Nolan SJ, Sudell M, Weston J, Tudur Smith C, Marson AG.Antiepileptic drug monotherapy for epilepsy: a network meta-analysis. Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews 2014, Issue 12. Art. No: CD011412. [DOI: 10.1002/14651858.CD011412]</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD011412</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
