<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35377865</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>02</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>05</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-5636</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>32</Volume>
            <Issue>3</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
              <Day>01</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Melanoma research</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Melanoma Res</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Cardiovascular disease and malignant melanoma.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>135</StartPage>
          <EndPage>141</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>135-141</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/CMR.0000000000000817</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>In the last decade, systemic therapies such as immune checkpoint inhibitors and BRAF-MEK inhibitors have improved the prognosis of high-risk and advanced melanoma. With improved survival, melanoma survivorship is increasingly important, particularly in patients who have a good prognosis or are diagnosed at a younger age. It is increasingly recognized that cancer and its treatment is associated with increased cardiovascular morbidity and mortality. Indeed, data from observational studies and meta-analyses of randomized controls trials in melanoma show that systemic therapies may be associated with cardiac toxicities, such as myocardial infarction, heart failure, myocarditis and stroke. Our review will discuss cardiovascular disease and risk factors in the context of melanoma and outline the importance of cardiovascular risk modification in this population.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Charlie Yue</ForeName>
            <Initials>CY</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Victorian Melanoma Service, The Alfred Hospital.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Public Health and Preventative Medicine, Monash University.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zoungas</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sophia</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Public Health and Preventative Medicine, Monash University.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Voskoboynik</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mark</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Oncology, The Alfred Hospital, Melbourne, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mar</LastName>
            <ForeName>Victoria</ForeName>
            <Initials>V</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Victorian Melanoma Service, The Alfred Hospital.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Public Health and Preventative Medicine, Monash University.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Melanoma Res</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9109623</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0960-8931</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <SupplMeshList>
        <SupplMeshName Type="Disease" UI="C562393">Melanoma, Cutaneous Malignant</SupplMeshName>
      </SupplMeshList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002318" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cardiovascular Diseases</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008545" MajorTopicYN="Y">Melanoma</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012878" MajorTopicYN="Y">Skin Neoplasms</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
          <Hour>17</Hour>
          <Minute>11</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35377865</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CMR.0000000000000817</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">00008390-990000000-00004</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sung H, Ferlay J, Siegel RL, Laversanne M, Soerjomataram I, Jemal A, Bray F. Global cancer statistics 2020: GLOBOCAN estimates of incidence and mortality worldwide for 36 cancers in 185 countries. CA Cancer J Clin 2021; 71:209–249.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rahib L, Wehner MR, Matrisian LM, Nead KT. Estimated projection of US cancer incidence and death to 2040. JAMA Netw Open 2021; 4:e214708.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>US Food Drug and Administration. FDA approves pembrolizumab for adjuvant treatment of Stage IIB or IIC melanoma. Food Drug and Administration, USA; 2021. https://www.fda.gov/drugs/resources-information-approveddrugs/fda-approves-pembrolizumab-adjuvant-treatment-stage-iibor-iic-melanoma. [Accessed 13 December 2021]</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Drobni ZD, Alvi RM, Taron J, Zafar A, Murphy SP, Rambarat PK, et al. Association between immune checkpoint inhibitors with cardiovascular events and atherosclerotic plaque. Circulation 2020; 142:2299–2311.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Waheed N, Fradley MG, DeRemer DL, Mahmoud A, Shah CP, Langaee TY, et al. Newly diagnosed cardiovascular disease in patients treated with immune checkpoint inhibitors: a retrospective analysis of patients at an academic tertiary care center. Cardiooncology 2021; 7:10.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sussman TA, Li H, Hobbs B, Funchain P, McCrae KR, Khorana AA. Incidence of thromboembolism in patients with melanoma on immune checkpoint inhibitor therapy and its adverse association with survival. J Immunother Cancer 2021; 9:e001719.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dolladille C, Akroun J, Morice PM, Dompmartin A, Ezine E, Sassier M, et al. Cardiovascular immunotoxicities associated with immune checkpoint inhibitors: a safety meta-analysis. Eur Heart J 2021; 42:4964–4977.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sturgeon KM, Deng L, Bluethmann SM, Zhou S, Trifiletti DM, Jiang C, et al. A population-based study of cardiovascular disease mortality risk in US cancer patients. Eur Heart J 2019; 40:3889–3897.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Park NJ, Chang Y, Bender C, Conley Y, Chlebowski RT, van Londen GJ, et al. Cardiovascular disease and mortality after breast cancer in postmenopausal women: results from the Women’s Health Initiative. PLoS One 2017; 12:e0184174.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paulson KG, Gupta D, Kim TS, Veatch JR, Byrd DR, Bhatia S, et al. Age-specific incidence of melanoma in the United States. JAMA Dermatol 2020; 156:57–64.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Balch CM, Soong SJ, Gershenwald JE, Thompson JF, Coit DG, Atkins MB, et al. Age as a prognostic factor in patients with localized melanoma and regional metastases. Ann Surg Oncol 2013; 20:3961–3968.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bots SH, Peters SAE, Woodward M. Sex differences in coronary heart disease and stroke mortality: a global assessment of the effect of ageing between 1980 and 2010. BMJ Glob Health 2017; 2:e000298.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Olsen CM, Thompson JF, Pandeya N, Whiteman DC. Evaluation of sex-specific incidence of Melanoma. JAMA Dermatol 2020;156:553–560.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scoggins CR, Ross MI, Reintgen DS, Noyes RD, Goydos JS, Beitsch PD, et al.; Sunbelt Melanoma Trial. Gender-related differences in outcome for melanoma patients. Ann Surg 2006; 243:693–698; discussion 8-700.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Joosse A, Collette S, Suciu S, Nijsten T, Patel PM, Keilholz U, et al. Sex is an independent prognostic indicator for survival and relapse/progression-free survival in metastasized stage III to IV melanoma: a pooled analysis of five European organisation for research and treatment of cancer randomized controlled trials. J Clin Oncol 2013; 31:2337–2346.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Autier P, Boniol M, Severi G, Pedeux R, Grivegnée AR, Doré JF. Sex differences in numbers of nevi on body sites of young European children: implications for the etiology of cutaneous melanoma. Cancer Epidemiol Biomarkers Prev 2004; 13:2003–2005.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dusingize JC, Olsen CM, Pandeya N, Thompson BS, Webb PM, Green AC, et al.; QSkin Study. Smoking and cutaneous melanoma: findings from the QSkin sun and health cohort study. Cancer Epidemiol Biomarkers Prev 2018; 27:874–881.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Freedman DM, Sigurdson A, Doody MM, Rao RS, Linet MS. Risk of melanoma in relation to smoking, alcohol intake, and other factors in a large occupational cohort. Cancer Causes Control 2003; 14:847–857.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thompson CA, Zhang ZF, Arah OA. Competing risk bias to explain the inverse relationship between smoking and malignant melanoma. Eur J Epidemiol 2013; 28:557–567.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jones MS, Jones PC, Stern SL, Elashoff D, Hoon DSB, Thompson J, et al. The impact of smoking on sentinel node metastasis of primary cutaneous melanoma. Ann Surg Oncol 2017; 24:2089–2094.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lauby-Secretan B, Scoccianti C, Loomis D, Grosse Y, Bianchini F, Straif K; International Agency for Research on Cancer Handbook Working Group. Body fatness and cancer–viewpoint of the IARC working group. N Engl J Med 2016; 375:794–798.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith LK, Arabi S, Lelliott EJ, McArthur GA, Sheppard KE. Obesity and the impact on cutaneous melanoma: friend or foe? Cancers (Basel) 2020; 12:E1583.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gogas H, Trakatelli M, Dessypris N, Terzidis A, Katsambas A, Chrousos GP, Petridou ET. Melanoma risk in association with serum leptin levels and lifestyle parameters: a case-control study. Ann Oncol 2008; 19:384–389.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sergentanis TN, Antoniadis AG, Gogas HJ, Antonopoulos CN, Adami HO, Ekbom A, Petridou ET. Obesity and risk of malignant melanoma: a meta-analysis of cohort and case-control studies. Eur J Cancer 2013; 49:642–657.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Taube M, Peltonen M, Sjöholm K, Anveden Å, Andersson-Assarsson JC, Jacobson P, et al. Association of bariatric surgery with skin cancer incidence in adults with obesity: a nonrandomized controlled trial. JAMA Dermatol 2020; 156:38–43.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McQuade JL, Daniel CR, Hess KR, Mak C, Wang DY, Rai RR, et al. Association of body-mass index and outcomes in patients with metastatic melanoma treated with targeted therapy, immunotherapy, or chemotherapy: a retrospective, multicohort analysis. Lancet Oncol 2018; 19:310–322.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Richtig G, Hoeller C, Wolf M, Wolf I, Rainer BM, Schulter G, et al. Body mass index may predict the response to ipilimumab in metastatic melanoma: an observational multi-centre study. PLoS One 2018; 13:e0204729.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ahmed M, von Itzstein MS, Sheffield T, Khan S, Fattah F, Park JY, et al. Association between body mass index, dosing strategy, and efficacy of immune checkpoint inhibitors. J Immunother Cancer 2021; 9:e002349.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hemminki K, Li X, Sundquist J, Sundquist K. Risk of cancer following hospitalization for type 2 diabetes. Oncologist 2010; 15:548–555.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harding JL, Shaw JE, Peeters A, Cartensen B, Magliano DJ. Cancer risk among people with type 1 and type 2 diabetes: disentangling true associations, detection bias, and reverse causation. Diabetes Care 2015; 38:264–270.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yuan S, Kar S, Carter P, Vithayathil M, Mason AM, Burgess S, Larsson SC. Is type 2 diabetes causally associated with cancer risk? Evidence from a two-sample mendelian randomization study. Diabetes 2020; 69:1588–1596.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>von Schuckmann LA, Smith D, Hughes MCB, Malt M, van der Pols JC, Khosrotehrani K, et al. Associations of statins and diabetes with diagnosis of ulcerated cutaneous melanoma. J Invest Dermatol 2017; 137:2599–2605.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nagore E, Martinez-Garcia MA, Gomez-Olivas JD, Manrique-Silva E, Martorell A, Bañuls J, et al. Relationship between type 2 diabetes mellitus and markers of cutaneous melanoma aggressiveness: an observational multicentric study in 443 patients with melanoma. Br J Dermatol 2021; 185:756–763.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weikert S, Boeing H, Pischon T, Weikert C, Olsen A, Tjonneland A, et al. Blood pressure and risk of renal cell carcinoma in the European prospective investigation into cancer and nutrition. Am J Epidemiol 2008; 167:438–446.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stocks T, Van Hemelrijck M, Manjer J, Bjørge T, Ulmer H, Hallmans G, et al. Blood pressure and risk of cancer incidence and mortality in the Metabolic Syndrome and Cancer Project. Hypertension 2012; 59:802–810.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nagel G, Bjørge T, Stocks T, Manjer J, Hallmans G, Edlinger M, et al. Metabolic risk factors and skin cancer in the Metabolic Syndrome and Cancer Project (Me-Can). Br J Dermatol 2012; 167:59–67.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Daniels B, Pearson SA, Vajdic CM, Pottegård A, Buckley NA, Zoega H. Risk of squamous cell carcinoma of the lip and cutaneous melanoma in older Australians using hydrochlorothiazide: a population-based case-control study. Basic Clin Pharmacol Toxicol 2020; 127:320–328.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shin D, Lee ES, Kim J, Guerra L, Naik D, Prida X. Association between the use of Thiazide diuretics and the risk of skin cancers: a meta-analysis of observational studies. J Clin Med Res 2019; 11:247–255.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kuzu OF, Noory MA, Robertson GP. The role of cholesterol in cancer. Cancer Res 2016; 76:2063–2070.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ni H, Liu H, Gao R. Serum lipids and breast cancer risk: a meta-analysis of prospective cohort studies. PLoS One 2015; 10:e0142669.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elshanbary AA, Zaazouee MS, Abdelmonem M, Mohammed YA, Abdel-Aziz W. Risk factors for cardiovascular mortality and melanoma-specific mortality among patients with melanoma: a SEER based study. Eur J Cancer Prev 2021. 10.1097/CEJ.0000000000000690 [Epub ahead of print].</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CEJ.0000000000000690</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang X, Pawlikowski M, Olivo-Marston S, Williams KP, Bower JK, Felix AS. Ten-year cardiovascular risk among cancer survivors: the National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey. PLoS One 2021; 16:e0247919.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grundy SM, Stone NJ, Bailey AL, Beam C, Birtcher KK, Blumenthal RS, et al. 2018 AHA/ACC/AACVPR/AAPA/ABC/ACPM/ADA/AGS/APhA/ASPC/NLA/PCNA Guideline on the management of blood cholesterol: executive summary: a report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Task Force on Clinical Practice Guidelines. J Am Coll Cardiol 2019; 73:3168–3209.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mincu RI, Mahabadi AA, Michel L, Mrotzek SM, Schadendorf D, Rassaf T, Totzeck M. Cardiovascular adverse events associated with BRAF and MEK inhibitors: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA Netw Open 2019; 2:e198890.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Robert C, Grob JJ, Stroyakovskiy D, Karaszewska B, Hauschild A, Levchenko E, et al. Five-year outcomes with dabrafenib plus trametinib in metastatic melanoma. N Engl J Med 2019; 381:626–636.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ascierto PA, McArthur GA, Dréno B, Atkinson V, Liszkay G, Di Giacomo AM, et al. Cobimetinib combined with vemurafenib in advanced BRAF(V600)-mutant melanoma (coBRIM): updated efficacy results from a randomised, double-blind, phase 3 trial. Lancet Oncol 2016; 17:1248–1260.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dummer R, Ascierto PA, Gogas HJ, Arance A, Mandala M, Liszkay G, et al. Encorafenib plus binimetinib versus vemurafenib or encorafenib in patients with BRAF-mutant melanoma (COLUMBUS): a multicentre, open-label, randomised phase 3 trial. Lancet Oncol 2018; 19:603–615.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guha A, Jain P, Fradley MG, Lenihan D, Gutierrez JM, Jain C, et al. Cardiovascular adverse events associated with BRAF versus BRAF/MEK inhibitor: cross-sectional and longitudinal analysis using two large national registries. Cancer Med 2021; 10:3862–3872.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Banks M, Crowell K, Proctor A, Jensen BC. Cardiovascular effects of the MEK inhibitor, trametinib: a case report, literature review, and consideration of mechanism. Cardiovasc Toxicol 2017; 17:487–493.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Purcell NH, Wilkins BJ, York A, Saba-El-Leil MK, Meloche S, Robbins J, Molkentin JD. Genetic inhibition of cardiac ERK1/2 promotes stress-induced apoptosis and heart failure but has no effect on hypertrophy in vivo. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 2007; 104:14074–14079.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnson DB, Balko JM, Compton ML, Chalkias S, Gorham J, Xu Y, et al. Fulminant myocarditis with combination immune checkpoint blockade. N Engl J Med 2016; 375:1749–1755.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jain P, Gutierrez Bugarin J, Guha A, Jain C, Patil N, Shen T, et al. Cardiovascular adverse events are associated with usage of immune checkpoint inhibitors in real-world clinical data across the United States. ESMO Open 2021; 6:100252.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mahmood Syed S, Fradley Michael G, Cohen Justine V, Nohria A, Reynolds Kerry L, Heinzerling Lucie M, et al. Myocarditis in patients treated with immune checkpoint inhibitors. J Am Coll Cardiol 2018; 71:1755–1764.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Palaskas N, Lopez-Mattei J, Durand JB, Iliescu C, Deswal A. Immune checkpoint inhibitor myocarditis: pathophysiological characteristics, diagnosis, and treatment. J Am Heart Assoc 2020; 9:e013757.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salem JE, Manouchehri A, Moey M, Lebrun-Vignes B, Bastarache L, Pariente A, et al. Cardiovascular toxicities associated with immune checkpoint inhibitors: an observational, retrospective, pharmacovigilance study. Lancet Oncol 2018; 19:1579–1589.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen DY, Huang WK, Chien-Chia Wu V, Chang WC, Chen JS, Chuang CK, Chu PH. Cardiovascular toxicity of immune checkpoint inhibitors in cancer patients: a review when cardiology meets immuno-oncology. J Formos Med Assoc 2020; 119:1461–1475.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Waliany S, Neal JW, Reddy S, Wakelee H, Shah SA, Srinivas S, et al. Myocarditis surveillance with high-sensitivity troponin I during cancer treatment with immune checkpoint inhibitors. JACC CardioOncol 2021; 3:137–139.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bar J, Markel G, Gottfried T, Percik R, Leibowitz-Amit R, Berger R, et al. Acute vascular events as a possibly related adverse event of immunotherapy: a single-institute retrospective study. Eur J Cancer 2019; 120:122–131.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nichetti F, Ligorio F, Zattarin E, Signorelli D, Prelaj A, Proto C, et al. Is there an interplay between immune checkpoint inhibitors, thromboprophylactic treatments and thromboembolic events? Mechanisms and impact in non-small cell lung cancer patients. Cancers (Basel) 2019; 12:E67.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ando Y, Hayashi T, Sugimoto R, Nishibe S, Ito K, Kawada K, et al. Risk factors for cancer-associated thrombosis in patients undergoing treatment with immune checkpoint inhibitors. Invest New Drugs 2020; 38:1200–1206.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Agostinetto E, Eiger D, Lambertini M, Ceppi M, Bruzzone M, Pondé N, et al. Cardiotoxicity of immune checkpoint inhibitors: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomised clinical trials. Eur J Cancer 2021; 148:76–91.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Solinas C, Saba L, Sganzerla P, Petrelli F. Venous and arterial thromboembolic events with immune checkpoint inhibitors: a systematic review. Thromb Res 2020; 196:444–453.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gotsman I, Grabie N, Dacosta R, Sukhova G, Sharpe A, Lichtman AH. Proatherogenic immune responses are regulated by the PD-1/PD-L pathway in mice. J Clin Invest 2007; 117:2974–2982.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bu DX, Tarrio M, Maganto-Garcia E, Stavrakis G, Tajima G, Lederer J, et al. Impairment of the programmed cell death-1 pathway increases atherosclerotic lesion development and inflammation. Arterioscler Thromb Vasc Biol 2011; 31:1100–1107.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Poels K, van Leent MMT, Reiche ME, Kusters PJH, Huveneers S, de Winther MPJ, et al. Antibody-mediated inhibition of CTLA4 aggravates atherosclerotic plaque inflammation and progression in hyperlipidemic mice. Cells 2020; 9:E1987.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Daxini A, Cronin K, Sreih AG. Vasculitis associated with immune checkpoint inhibitors-a systematic review. Clin Rheumatol 2018; 37:2579–2584.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>University M. Statins and progression of coronary atherosclerosis in melanoma patients treated with immune checkpoint inhibitors (V2) Australia: Monash University; 2021. https://research.monash.edu/en/projects/statins-and-progression-of-coronary-atherosclerosis-in-melanoma-p. [Accessed 13 December 2021]</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moik F, Chan WE, Wiedemann S, Hoeller C, Tuchmann F, Aretin MB, et al. Incidence, risk factors, and outcomes of venous and arterial thromboembolism in immune checkpoint inhibitor therapy. Blood 2021; 137:1669–1678.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gong J, Drobni ZD, Alvi RM, Murphy SP, Sullivan RJ, Hartmann SE, et al. Immune checkpoint inhibitors for cancer and venous thromboembolic events. Eur J Cancer 2021; 158:99–110.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kewan T, Ko T, Flores M, Sallam Y, Haddad A, Daw H. Prognostic impact and risk factors of cancer-associated thrombosis events in stage-IV cancer patients treated with immune checkpoint inhibitors. Eur J Haematol 2021; 106:682–688.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gong J, Drobni ZD, Zafar A, Quinaglia T, Hartmann S, Gilman HK, et al. Pericardial disease in patients treated with immune checkpoint inhibitors. J Immunother Cancer 2021; 9:e002771.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yeh ET, Tong AT, Lenihan DJ, Yusuf SW, Swafford J, Champion C, et al. Cardiovascular complications of cancer therapy: diagnosis, pathogenesis, and management. Circulation 2004; 109:3122–3131.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mulrooney DA, Yeazel MW, Kawashima T, Mertens AC, Mitby P, Stovall M, et al. Cardiac outcomes in a cohort of adult survivors of childhood and adolescent cancer: retrospective analysis of the Childhood Cancer Survivor Study cohort. BMJ 2009; 339:b4606.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Herrmann J, Yang EH, Iliescu CA, Cilingiroglu M, Charitakis K, Hakeem A, et al. Vascular toxicities of cancer therapies: the old and the new–an evolving avenue. Circulation 2016; 133:1272–1289.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parkinson DR, Abrams JS, Wiernik PH, Rayner AA, Margolin KA, Van Echo DA, et al. Interleukin-2 therapy in patients with metastatic malignant melanoma: a phase II study. J Clin Oncol 1990; 8:1650–1656.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
