<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35384427</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>14</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">2093-2340</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>54</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Mar</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Infection &amp; chemotherapy</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Infect Chemother</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Does Tigecycline Have a Place in Therapy for Rickettsial Infection of the Central Nervous System?</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>165</StartPage>
          <EndPage>172</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>165-172</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3947/ic.2021.0070</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>This brief report documents the safety and efficacy of high-dose tigecycline as a salvage-therapy in in a case series of five patients with serious central nervous system (CNS) rocky mountain spotted fever (RMSF). These severily ill patients were unable to take any oral drug therapy, parenteral doxycycline was unavailable and absorption of oral doxycycline was a concern in these critically ill patients. As far as we know, we report the successfull use of tigecycline for the treatment of rickettsial meningitis for the first time in Italy. We suggest more studies on tigecycline in severe CNS infections from <i>Rickettsia</i> species and multi-drug resistant bacteria, especially the use of tigecycline at higher than standard doses in these life-threathening infectious diseases.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022 by The Korean Society of Infectious Diseases, Korean Society for Antimicrobial Therapy, and The Korean Society for AIDS.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mastroianni</LastName>
            <ForeName>Antonio</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1641-1491</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Infectious &amp; Tropical Diseases Unit, Annunziata Hub Hospital, Cosenza, Italy. antoniomastroianni@yahoo.it.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Greco</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sonia</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1699-3639</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Infectious &amp; Tropical Diseases Unit, Annunziata Hub Hospital, Cosenza, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Urso</LastName>
            <ForeName>Filippo</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7957-6875</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Hospital Pharmacy, Annunziata Hub Hospital, Cosenza, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mauro</LastName>
            <ForeName>Maria Vittoria</ForeName>
            <Initials>MV</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1447-3071</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Microbiology &amp; Virology, Annunziata Hub Hospital, Cosenza, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Vangeli</LastName>
            <ForeName>Valeria</ForeName>
            <Initials>V</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4066-7948</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Infectious &amp; Tropical Diseases Unit, Annunziata Hub Hospital, Cosenza, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Infect Chemother</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101531537</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1598-8112</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rickettsia</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rickettsia rickettsii</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rickettsiosis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rocky mountain spotted fever</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Tigecycline</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>No conflict of interest.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
          <Hour>9</Hour>
          <Minute>20</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35384427</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8987170</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3947/ic.2021.0070</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">54.165</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bradshaw MJ, Byrge KC, Ivey KS, Pruthi S, Bloch KC. Meningoencephalitis due to spotted fever rickettsioses, including rocky mountain spotted fever. Clin Infect Dis. 2020;71:188–195.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31412360</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yaghoubi S, Zekiy AO, Krutova M, Gholami M, Kouhsari E, Sholeh M, Ghafouri Z, Maleki F. Tigecycline antibacterial activity, clinical effectiveness, and mechanisms and epidemiology of resistance: narrative review. Eur J Clin Microbiol Infect Dis. 2021:1–20.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7785128</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33403565</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) Nationwide shortage of doxycycline: Resources for providers and recommendations for patient care.  [Accessed 7 August 2015].  Available at:  http://emergency.cdc.gov/han/han00349.asp.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barbour A, Schmidt S, Ma B, Schiefelbein L, Rand KH, Burkhardt O, Derendorf H. Clinical pharmacokinetics and pharmacodynamics of tigecycline. Clin Pharmacokinet. 2009;48:575–584.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19725592</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rodvold KA, Gotfried MH, Cwik M, Korth-Bradley JM, Dukart G, Ellis-Grosse EJ. Serum, tissue and body fluid concentrations of tigecycline after a single 100 mg dose. J Antimicrob Chemother. 2006;58:1221–1229.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17012300</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pallotto C, Fiorio M, D’Avolio A, Sgrelli A, Baldelli F, Di Perri G, De Socio GV. Cerebrospinal fluid penetration of tigecycline. Scand J Infect Dis. 2014;46:69–72.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24131423</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ray L, Levasseur K, Nicolau DP, Scheetz MH. Cerebral spinal fluid penetration of tigecycline in a patient with Acinetobacter baumannii cerebritis. Ann Pharmacother. 2010;44:582–586.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20179255</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kooli I, Brahim HB, Kilani M, Gannouni C, Aouam A, Toumi A, Loussaief C, Hattab MN, Chakroun M. Successful treatment of postoperative multidrug-resistant Acinetobacter baumannii meningitis by tigecycline. J Glob Antimicrob Resist. 2016;5:62–63.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27436468</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lauretti L, D’Alessandris QG, Fantoni M, D’Inzeo T, Fernandez E, Pallini R, Scoppettuolo G. First reported case of intraventricular tigecycline for meningitis from extremely drug-resistant Acinetobacter baumannii
. J Neurosurg. 2017;127:370–373.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27540902</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fang YQ, Zhan RC, Jia W, Zhang BQ, Wang JJ. A case report of intraventricular tigecycline therapy for intracranial infection with extremely drug resistant Acinetobacter baumannii
. Medicine (Baltimore) 2017;96:e7703. </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5626159</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28767605</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Long W, Yuan J, Liu J, Liu J, Wu M, Chen X, Peng G, Wu C, Zhang C, Wang X, Zhao W, Liu Q. Multidrug resistant brain abscess due to Acinetobacter baumannii ventriculitis cleared by intraventricular and intravenous tigecycline therapy: A case report and review of literature. Front Neurol. 2018;9:518.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6042469</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30026723</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tsolaki V, Karvouniaris M, Manoulakas E, Kotlia P, Karadontas V, Fotakopoulos G, Zakynthinos E, Makris D. Intraventricular CNS treatment with colistin-tigecycline combination: A case series. J Crit Care. 2018;47:338–341.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30097260</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu Y, Chen K, Zhao J, Wang Q, Zhou J. Intraventricular administration of tigecycline for the treatment of multidrug-resistant bacterial meningitis after craniotomy: a case report. J Chemother. 2018;30:49–52.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28614982</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fang GD, Weiss WJ, Scheld WM. Comparative efficacy of GAR-936, a novel glycylcycline alone and in combination with vancomycin against highly penicillin-resistant Streptococcus pneumoniae experimental meningitis in rabbits. Abstract 868; Program and abstracts of the 40th Interscience Conference on Antimicrobials and Chemotherapy (ICAAC); September 17–20, 2000; Toronto, Ontario, Canada. Washington, DC: ASM Press; 2000. p. 51.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blanton LS, Wilson NM, Quade BR, Walker DH. Susceptibility of Rickettsia rickettsii to tigecycline in a cell culture assay and animal model for rocky mountain spotted fever. Am J Trop Med Hyg. 2019;101:1091–1095.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6838591</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31516114</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Spyridaki I, Psaroulaki A, Vranakis I, Tselentis Y, Gikas A. Bacteriostatic and bactericidal activities of tigecycline against Coxiella burnetii and comparison with those of six other antibiotics. Antimicrob Agents Chemother. 2009;53:2690–2692.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2687195</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19332671</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Satoh M, Kato H, Takayama-Ito M, Ogawa M, Ando S, Saijo M. 
In vitro evaluation of minimum inhibitory concentration of several antibacterial agents against Rickettsia japonica using a plaque reduction assay system. J Infect Chemother. 2019;25:917–919.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31186196</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee SM, Kwon HY, Im JH, Baek JH, Hwang SS, Kang JS, Chung MH, Lee JS. 
In vitro activity of tigecycline against Orientia tsutsugamushi
. Yonsei Med J. 2016;57:1034–1037.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4951447</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27189302</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kuo MJ, Kuo CP, Chu SY, Tarng DC, Tseng WC. The case a 71-year-old man with fever, acute kidney injury, and a black crustaceous lesion. Kidney Int. 2019;95:239–240.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30606424</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sachdev SH, Joshi V, Cox ER, Amoroso A, Palekar S. Severe life-threatening Ehrlichia chaffeensis infections transmitted through solid organ transplantation. Transpl Infect Dis. 2014;16:119–124.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24330198</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
