<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35388920</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>07</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1520-636X</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Apr</Month>
              <Day>07</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Chirality</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Chirality</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>New enantioselective liquid chromatography method development and validation of dipeptidyl peptidase IV inhibitors using a macrocyclic glycopeptide (vancomycin) chiral stationary phase under polar ionic mode condition.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/chir.23448</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The direct separation of dipeptidyl peptidase IV (DPP-4) inhibitors such as Sitagliptin (STG), Linagliptin (LIG), and Saxagliptin (SAG) enantiomers in normal phase conditions have been achieved on immobilized polysaccharide-based chiral stationary phases (CSPs), as well as on the macrocyclic glycopeptide vancomycin chiral stationary phase (Chirobiotic V2) under polar ionic mode. The enantiomers of these targets could be separated completely (resolution factor Rs &gt; 2) using the Chirobiotic V2 column in polar ionic mode with the mobile phase (MeOH/AcOH/TEA 100/0.3/0.1 v/v/v) in an isocratic elution at 1.0 ml min<sup>-1</sup> . The effect of the mobile phase composition on separation, including buffer salts, acid-base modifiers, and analyte structures, was evaluated. The developed technique was validated in the polar ionic mode according to the International Conference on Harmonization (ICH) Q2R1 guidelines in terms of accuracy, precision, selectivity, linearity, limit of detection (LOD), and limit of quantification (LOQ). The calibration curve was linear in a concentration range from LOQ to 3.75 μg/ml. The LOD and LOQ of STG, LIG, and SAG were 0.15 and 0.45, 0.15 and 0.50, 0.16 and 0.50, respectively. The proposed method is said to be selective, accurate, and precise. Finally, the validated method was used successfully for the quantitative determination of DPP-4 enantiomers in pharmaceutical analytes.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Arnipalli</LastName>
            <ForeName>Manikanta Swamy</ForeName>
            <Initials>MS</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6104-0060</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Chemistry (UG &amp; PG), Dr. A P J Abdul Kalam Central Research Laboratory (CRL), Sir C R Reddy Autonomous College, Eluru, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nimmu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Narendra Varma</ForeName>
            <Initials>NV</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>D-216, Discovery Lab, Analytical Chemistry Division, Indian Institute of Chemical Technology, Tarnaka, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Boddapati</LastName>
            <ForeName>S N Murthy</ForeName>
            <Initials>SNM</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0703-9827</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Chemistry (UG &amp; PG), Dr. A P J Abdul Kalam Central Research Laboratory (CRL), Sir C R Reddy Autonomous College, Eluru, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Challa</LastName>
            <ForeName>Gangu Naidu</ForeName>
            <Initials>GN</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Basic Sciences and Humanities (BS&amp;H), Vignan's Institute of Information Technology (VIIT), Visakhapatnam, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Jaweria</LastName>
            <ForeName>Syed</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Depatment of Pharmaceutical Analysis and Quality Assurance, MESCO College of Pharmacy, Mustaidpura, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kola</LastName>
            <ForeName>A Emmanuel</ForeName>
            <Initials>AE</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Chemistry (UG &amp; PG), Dr. A P J Abdul Kalam Central Research Laboratory (CRL), Sir C R Reddy Autonomous College, Eluru, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>04</Month>
          <Day>07</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Chirality</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8914261</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0899-0042</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">-π interactions</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chirobiotic V2</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Linagliptin</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Saxagliptin</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sitagliptin</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chiral stationary phases</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dipeptidyl peptidase IV (DPP-4)</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ionic interaction</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">macrocyclic glycopeptide</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
          <Hour>8</Hour>
          <Minute>50</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35388920</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/chir.23448</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grahame-Smith DG, Aronson JK. Oxford Textbook of Clinical Pharmacology and Drug Therapy. 2nd ed. New York: Oxford University Press; 1992.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith SW. Chiral toxicology: it's the same thing … only different. Toxicol Sci. 2009;110(1):4-30. doi:10.1093/toxsci/kfp097</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tombo GMR, Belluš D. Chirality and crop protection. Angew Chem. 1991;30(10):1193-1215. doi:10.1002/anie.199111933</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang M, Zhang Q, Cong, L, Yin W, Wang M. Enantioselective degradation of metalaxyl in cucumber, cabbage, spinach and pakchoi. Chemosphere. 2014;95:241-246. doi:10.1016/j.chemosphere.2013.08.084</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maier NM, Franco P, Lindner W. Separation of enantiomers: needs, challenges, perspectives. J Chromatogr A. 2001;906(1-2):3-33. doi:10.1016/S0021-9673(00)00532-X</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sekhon BS. Enantioseparation of chiral drugs-an overview. Int J PharmTech Res. 2010;2:1584-1594.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu W, Tang M. Enantioselective activity and toxicity of chiral herbicides. In Herbicides-Mechanisms and Mode of Action. IntechOpen: London, UK, 2011:63-80. doi:10.5772/33179</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yu L, Wang S, Zeng S. Chiral Mobile Phase Additives in HPLC enantioseparations. Methods Mol Biol. 2013;970:221-231. doi:10.1007/978-1-62703-263-6_13</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ali I, Aboul-Enein, HY Impact of immobilized polysaccharide chiral stationary phase on enantiomeric separations. J Sep Sci. 2006;29(6):762-769. doi:10.1002/jssc.200500372</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kotthaus AF, Altenbach HJ. A new chiral derivatizing agent for the HPLC separation of α-amino acids on a standard reverse-phase column. Amino Acids. 2011;40(2):527-532. doi:10.1007/s00726-010-0665-5</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang Y, Wu DR, Wang-Iverson DB, Tymiak AA. Enantioselective chromatography in drug discovery. Drug Discov Today. 2005;10(8):571-577. doi:10.1016/S1359-6446(05)03407-0</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tiritan ME, Cass QB, Del Alamo A, Matlin SA, Grieb SJ. Preparative enantioseparation on polysaccharide phase using microporous silica as a support. Chirality. 1998;10(7):573-577. doi:10.1002/(SICI)1520-636X(1998)10:7%3C573::AID-CHIR4%3E3.0.CO;2-3</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shaw J.E., Sicree R.A., Zimmet P.Z., Global estimates of the prevalence of diabetes for 2010 and 2030. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2010; 87(1):4-14, doi:10.1016/j.diabres.2009.10.007</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Makrilakis K. The role of DPP-4 inhibitors in the treatment algorithm of type 2 diabetes mellitus: when to select, what to expect. Int J Environ Res Public Health. 2019;16(15):2720-2740. doi:10.3390/ijerph16152720</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Proost P, Struyt S, Schols D, et al. Truncation of macrophage-derived chemokine by CD26/dipeptidyl-peptidase IV beyond its predicted cleavage site affects chemotactic activity and CC chemokine receptor 4 interaction. J Biol Chem. 1999;274(7):3988-3993, doi:10.1074/jbc.274.7.3988</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McIntosh CH, Demuth HU, Pospisilik JA, Pederson R, Dipeptidyl peptidase IV inhibitors: how do they work as new antidiabetic agents? Regul Pept. 2005;128(2):159-165. doi:10.1016/j.regpep.2004.06.001</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dupre J, Behme MT, Hramiak IM, McFarlane P, Williamson MP, Zabel P, McDonald TJ Glucagon-like peptide I reduces postprandial glycemic excursions in IDDM. Diabetes. 1995;44(6):626-630. doi:10.2337/diab.44.6.626</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sohajda T, Hu WH, Zeng LL, Li H, Szente L, Noszál B, Béni S Evaluation of the interaction between sitagliptin and cyclodextrin derivatives by capillary electrophoresis and nuclear magnetic resonance spectroscopy. Electrophoresis. 2011;32(19):2648-2654. doi:10.1002/elps.201000639</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ramesh T, Rao PN, Suresh K. Enantiomeric separation of sitagliptin by a validated chiral liquid chromatographic method. Anal Methods. 2014;6(1):223-228. doi:10.1039/C3AY41626G</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reddy BVR, Raman N, Kumar BS, Rambabu C. Chiral separation of sitagliptin phosphate enantiomer by HPLC using amylose based chiral stationary phase. J Pharm Research. 2013;7(6):546-550. doi:10.1016/j.jopr.2013.06.014</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salapaka A, Bonige KB, Korupolu RB, Sharma HK, Ray UK. A new stability indicating reverse phase high performance liquid chromatography method for the determination of enantiomericpurity of a DPP-4 inhibitor drug linagliptin. Electrophoresis. 2019;40(7):1066-1073. doi:10.1002/elps.201800502</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vijay Kumar C, Aparna P, Pavan Kumar V, Ravindra Kumar Y. A new and enantioselective chromatographic method for linagliptin on amylose coated chiral stationary phase. Am J Analyt Chem. 2016;7(7):556-567. doi:10.4236/ajac.2016.77051</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Srinivasu G, Nagesh Kumar K, Ramachandra B, Thirupathi B, Lakshmi Narayana C, Parameswara Murthy C. Enantioseparation of DPP-4 inhibitors on immobilized crown ether-based chiral stationary phase. Chromatographia. 2018;81(12):1705-1710. doi:10.1007/s10337-018-3626-x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bosakova Z, Curınova E, Tesarova E. Study of the stability of promethazine enantiomers by liquid chromatography using a vancomycin-bonded chiral stationary phase. J Chromatogr B. 2002;770(1-2):63-69. doi:10.1016/S0378-4347(01)00559-X</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Armstrong DW, Tang Y, Chen S, Zhou Y, Bagwill C. Macrocyclic antibiotics as a new class of chiral selectors for liquid chromatography. J ChenAnal Chem. 1994;66(9):1473-1484. doi:10.1021/ac00081a019</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aboul-Enein HY, Serignese V. Quantitative determination of clenbuterol enantiomers in human plasma by high-performance liquid chromatography using the macrocyclic antibiotic chiral stationary phase teicoplanin. Biomed Chromatogr. 1999;13(8):520-524. doi:10.1002/(SICI)1099-0801(199912)13:8%3C520::AID-BMC919%3E3.0.CO;2-7</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tesarova E, Zaruba K, Flieger M. Enantioseparation of semisynthetic ergo alkaloids on vancomycin and teicoplanin stationary phases. J of Chrom A. 1999;844(1-2):137-147. doi:10.1016/S0021-9673(99)00339-8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chirobiotic Handbook. Advanced Separation Technologies. fifth ed. USA; 2004.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>ICH Q2 (R1). (2005) International conference on harmonization: validation of analytical procedures: test and methodology. http://wwwichorg/fleadmin/Public_Web_Site/ICH_Products/Guidelines/Quality/Q2_R1/Step4/Q2_R1__Guideline.pdf Accessed Nov 2005.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ekborg-Ott KH, Kullman JP, Wang X, Gahm K, He L, Armstrong DW. Evaluation of the macrocyclic antibiotic avoparcin as a new chiral selector for HPLC. Chirality. 1998; 10(7):627-660. doi:10.1002/(SICI)1520-636X(1998)10:7%3C627::AID-CHIR10%3E3.0.CO;2-1</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cardoso PA, César IC. Chiral Method Development Strategies for HPLC using Macrocyclic Glycopeptide-Based Stationary Phases. Chromatographia. 2018;81(6):841-850. doi:10.1007/s10337-018-3526-0</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beesley TE, Lee JT. Method development and optimization of enantioseparations using macrocyclic glycopeptide chiral stationary phases. In: Chiral Separation Techniques. Third ed. Weinheim; 2007.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li J, Liu R, Wang L, Liu X, Gao H. Enantioseparation of chiral pharmaceuticals by vancomycin-bonded stationary phase and analysis of chiral recognition mechanism. Chirality. 2019;1-12.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ilisz I, Berkecz R, Péter A. Retention mechanism of high-performance liquid chromatographic enantioseparation on macrocyclic glycopeptide-based chiral stationary phases. J of Chrom A. 2009;1216(10):1845-1860. doi:10.1016/j.chroma.2008.08.041</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
