<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35386014</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>07</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1573-904X</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Apr</Month>
              <Day>06</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Pharmaceutical research</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Pharm Res</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Multicomponent Droplet Drying Modeling Based on Conservation and Population Balance Equations.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s11095-022-03248-4</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The aim of this work is to present a modeling tool to describe drying kinetics and delineate evolving physical and chemical behavior of multicomponent droplets during drying. Conservation equations coupled with population balance equations (PBE) are used to achieve this goal. Modeling results are gauged with single salt-water droplet drying from literature and show congruent trends. This model is then extended to a more complex system: various droplet sizes containing methanol (solvent), Felodipine (active ingredient), and PVP (polyvinylpyrrolidone as excipient). The FIB-SEM (Focused-Ion Beam Scanning Electron Microscopy) imaging results from spray-dried particles produced with similar formulation and processing conditions are consistent with phase behavior predicted by the model. The results show competing impacts of transport phenomena on the intermittent shell formation process and final particle structure and chemical heterogeneity. Solute diffusion, solvent efflux, and intra-drop flow impact the model system. It is found that shell formation follows a fluctuating profile where the initial precipitation of the dissolved species on the droplet surface is dampened, and nucleated particles become dispersed periodically until the shell becomes strong enough to withstand internal circulations. These internal effects are dependent on droplet size and are pronounced for larger droplets. That is, the particle phase behavior and physical nature are functions of the atomized droplet size. Stemming understating from this study would inform an optimized unit, operating in target design space. This would provide better product quality control and minimize discrepancies observed in process development during the early phase vs. commercial scale.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Science+Business Media, LLC, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Poozesh</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sadegh</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Mechanical Engineering Department, Tuskegee University, Tuskegee, AL, 36088, USA. sadegh.poozesh@gmail.com.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Algasem</LastName>
            <ForeName>Faisal</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Mechanical Engineering Department, Tuskegee University, Tuskegee, AL, 36088, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Azad</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mohammad A</ForeName>
            <Initials>MA</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Chemical, Biological and Bioengineering Department, North Carolina A&amp; T State University, Greensboro, NC, 27411, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Marsac</LastName>
            <ForeName>Patrick J</ForeName>
            <Initials>PJ</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Pharmaceutical Sciences Department, University of Kentucky, Lexington, KY, 40536, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>04</Month>
          <Day>06</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Pharm Res</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8406521</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0724-8741</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">amorphous solid dispersion</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">drying kinetics</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mathematical modeling</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">multicomponent droplet</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">particle engineering</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>4</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35386014</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11095-022-03248-4</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s11095-022-03248-4</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Poozesh S, Setiawan N, Arce F, Sundararajan P, Rocca JD, Rumondor A, Wei D, Wenslow R, Xi H, Zhang S, Stellabott J, Su Y, Moser J, Marsac PJ. Understanding the Process-Product-Performance Interplay of Spray Dried Drug-Polymer Systems through Complete Structural and Chemical Characterization of Single Spray Dried Particles. Powder Technol. 2017;320:685–95.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fu N, Woo MW, Chen XD. Single droplet drying technique to study drying kinetics measurement and particle functionality: A review. Drying Technol. 2012;30(15):1771–85.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sirignano WA. Fluid dynamics and transport of droplets and sprays: Cambridge university press. 2010.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sazhin SS. Classical and novel approaches to modelling droplet heating and evaporation. In: Droplet interactions and spray processes. Cham: Springer; 2020. pp. 251–258.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mezhericher M, Levy A, Borde I. Theoretical models of single droplet drying kinetics: a review. Drying Technol. 2010;28(2):278–93.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vehring R, Foss WR, Lechuga-Ballesteros D. Particle formation in spray drying. J Aerosol Sci. 2007;38(7):728–46.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Azad M, Arteaga C, Abdelmalek B, Davé R, Bilgili E. Spray drying of drug-swellable dispersant suspensions for preparation of fast-dissolving, high drug-loaded, surfactant-free nanocomposites. Drug Dev Ind Pharm. 2015;41(10):1617–31.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25347144</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gregson F, Ordoubadi M, Miles R, Haddrell A, Barona D, Lewis D, Church T, Vehring R, Reid JJPCCP. Studies of competing evaporation rates of multiple volatile components from a single binary-component aerosol droplet. Physical Chemistry Chemical Physics. 2019;21(19):9709–19.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31025989</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Emami F, Vatanara A, Park EJ, Na DHJP. Drying technologies for the stability and bioavailability of biopharmaceuticals. Pharmaceutics. 2018;10(3):131.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6161129</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bhujbal SV, Zemlyanov DY, Cavallaro A, Mangal S, Taylor LS, Zhou QTJMp. Qualitative and quantitative characterization of composition heterogeneity on the surface of spray dried amorphous solid dispersion particles by an advanced surface analysis platform with high surface sensitivity and superior spatial resolution. Molecular Pharmaceutics. 2018;15(5):2045–53.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29641898</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5938120</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nešić S, Vodnik J. Kinetics of droplet evaporation. Chem Eng Sci. 1991;46(2):527–37.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Woo MW, Daud WRW, Mujumdar AS, Wu Z, MeorTalib MZ, Tasirin SM. CFD evaluation of droplet drying models in a spray dryer fitted with a rotary atomizer. Drying Technol. 2008;26(10):1180–98.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sturm DR, Moser JD, Sundararajan P, Danner RP. Spray Drying of Hypromellose Acetate Succinate. Ind Eng Chem Res. 2019;58(27):12291–300.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abdullahi H, Burcham CL. Vetter T. A mechanistic model to predict droplet drying history and particle shell formation in multicomponent systems. Chemical Engineering Science. 2020;224:115713.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vicente J, Pinto J, Menezes J, Gaspar F. Fundamental analysis of particle formation in spray drying. Powder Technol. 2013;247:1–7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Poozesh S, Bilgili E. Scale-up of pharmaceutical spray drying using scale-up rules: A review. International Journal of Pharmaceutics. 2019;562:271–92.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30910632</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bück A, Seidel C, Dürr R, Neugebauer C. Robust feedback control of convective drying of particulate solids. J Process Control. 2018;69:86–96.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Poozesh S, Cousin CA. Integrating a dynamic multiscale drying model into a closed loop control strategy for laboratory spray dryer. Drying Technology. 2021;2021:1–13. https://doi.org/10.1080/07373937.2021.1934692 .</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07373937.2021.1934692</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meeus J, Lenaerts M, Scurr DJ, Amssoms K, Davies MC, Roberts CJ. The influence of spray-drying parameters on phase behavior, drug distribution, and in vitro release of injectable microspheres for sustained release. J Pharm Sci. 2015;104(4):1451–60.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25648704</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Both E, Nuzzo M, Millqvist-Fureby A, Boom R, Schutyser M. Morphology development during single droplet drying of mixed component formulations and milk. Food Res Int. 2018;109:448–54.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29803471</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cho H-Y, Kim B, Chun J-Y, Choi M-JJPT. Effect of spray-drying process on physical properties of sodium chloride/maltodextrin complexes. Powder Technology. 2015;277:141–6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Malafronte L, Ahrné L, Schuster E, Innings F, Rasmuson A. Exploring drying kinetics and morphology of commercial dairy powders. J Food Eng. 2015;158:58–65.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chindapan N, Niamnuy C, Devahastin S. Physical properties, morphology and saltiness of salt particles as affected by spray drying conditions and potassium chloride substitution. Powder Technol. 2018;326:265–71.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kojima Y, Ohta T, Shiraki K, Takano R, Maeda H, Ogawa Y. Effects of spray drying process parameters on the solubility behavior and physical stability of solid dispersions prepared using a laboratory-scale spray dryer. Drug Dev Ind Pharm. 2013;39(9):1484–93.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22670826</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Langrish T, Kockel T. The assessment of a characteristic drying curve for milk powder for use in computational fluid dynamics modelling. Chem Eng J. 2001;84(1):69–74.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen X, Xie G. Fingerprints of the drying behaviour of particulate or thin layer food materials established using a reaction engineering model. Food Bioprod Process. 1997;75(4):213–22.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Putranto A, Chen XD, Xiao Z, Webley PA. Simple, accurate and robust modeling of various systems of drying of foods and biomaterials: A demonstration of the feasibility of the reaction engineering approach (REA). Drying Technol. 2011;29(13):1519–28.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmitz-Schug I, Kulozik U, Foerst P. Modeling spray drying of dairy products–Impact of drying kinetics, reaction kinetics and spray drying conditions on lysine loss. Chem Eng Sci. 2016;141:315–29.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marshall W Jr. Heat and mass transfer in spray drying. Trans ASME. 1955;77(1377):e1385.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mezhericher M, Levy A, Borde I. Three-dimensional spray-drying model based on comprehensive formulation of drying kinetics. Drying Technol. 2012;30(11–12):1256–73.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cussler EL, Cussler EL. Diffusion: mass transfer in fluid systems. Cambridge, England: Cambridge University Press; 2009.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zwanzig R. Harrison AKJTJocp. Modifications of the Stokes-Einstein formula. 1985;83(11):5861–2.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Srikiatden J, Roberts JS. Moisture transfer in solid food materials: A review of mechanisms, models, and measurements. Int J Food Prop. 2007;10(4):739–77.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cheng N-SJJoHE. Effect of concentration on settling velocity of sediment particles. Journal of Hydraulic Engineering. 1997;123(8):728–31.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Prakash S, Sirignano W. Theory of convective droplet vaporization with unsteady heat transfer in the circulating liquid phase. Int J Heat Mass Transf. 1980;23(3):253–68.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cleary M, Phillips T. A Population Balance Equation-Probability Density Function (PBE-PDF) model for the turbulent dispersion and deagglomeration of inhaled pharmaceutical powders. In.Proceedings of the 18th Australasian Fluid Mechanics Conference, AFMC 2012, Dec 3. Launceston, Australia; 2012.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kestur US, Taylor LSJCg, design. Evaluation of the crystal growth rate of felodipine polymorphs in the presence and absence of additives as a function of temperature. Crystal growth &amp; design. 2013;13(10):4349–54.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sazhin S, Krutitskii P, Gusev I, HeikalMJIjoh, transfer m. Transient heating of an evaporating droplet. International Journal of Heat and Mass Transfer. 2010;53(13–14):2826–36.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Robert HP, Don WG, James OM. Perry’s chemical engineers’ handbook. McGraw-Hill, New York: Seventh, International edition; 1997.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Poozesh S, Lu K, Marsac PJ. On the particle formation in spray drying process for bio-pharmaceutical applications: Interrogating a new model via computational fluid dynamics. Int J Heat Mass Transf. 2018;122:863–76.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lindfors L, Forssén S, Westergren J, Olsson UJJoc, science i. Nucleation and crystal growth in supersaturated solutions of a model drug. Journal of colloid and interface science. 2008;325(2):404–13.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18561941</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Seydel P, Blömer J, Bertling J. Modeling particle formation at spray drying using population balances. Drying Technol. 2006;24(2):137–46.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>LeVeque RJ, Leveque RJ. Numerical methods for conservation laws. Birkhäuser. Basel: Springer; 1992. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-0348-8629-1 .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gregson F, Robinson J, Miles R, Royall C, Reid JJTJoPCB. Drying kinetics of salt solution droplets: Water evaporation rates and crystallization. The Journal of Physical Chemistry B. 2018;123(1):266–76.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30550715</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Doß M, Baensch EJCES. Numerical study of single droplet drying in an acoustic levitator before the critical point of time. Chemical Engineering Science. 2022;248:117149.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fu N, Woo MW, Chen XDJDT. Single droplet drying technique to study drying kinetics measurement and particle functionality: A review. Drying Technology. 2012;30(15):1771–85.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu W, Midya J, Kappl M, Butt H-Jr, NikoubashmanAJAn. Segregation in drying binary colloidal droplets. ACS Nano. 2019;13(5):4972–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30897326</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6727607</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wulsten E, Kiekens F, van Dycke F, Voorspoels J, Lee GJIjop. Levitated single-droplet drying: Case study with itraconazole dried in binary organic solvent mixtures. International journal of pharmaceutics. 2009;378(1–2):116–21.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19501641</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lindfors L, Jonsson M, Weibull E, Brasseur JG, AbrahamssonBJJops. Hydrodynamic effects on drug dissolution and deaggregation in the small intestine—a study with felodipine as a model drug. Journal of pharmaceutical sciences. 2015;104(9):2969–76.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25980801</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aschi A, Jebari MM, Gharbi A. Investigation of Poly (vinyl pyrrolidone) in methanol by dynamic light scattering and viscosity techniques. e-Polymers. 2007;7(1):020. https://doi.org/10.1515/epoly.2007.7.1.225 .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wei Y, Deng W, Chen R-HJIJoH, Transfer M. Effects of internal circulation and particle mobility during nanofluid droplet evaporation. International Journal of Heat and Mass Transfer. 2016;103:1335–47.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Poozesh S, Grib SW, Renfro MW, Marsac PJJPT. Near-field dynamics of high-speed spray dryer coannular two fluid nozzle: Effects of operational conditions and formulations. Powder Technology. 2018;333:439–48.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
