<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35382445</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>03</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">0021-8502</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>163</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of aerosol science</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Aerosol Sci</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Infection control measures for public transportation derived from the flow dynamics of obstructed cough jet.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>105995</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>105995</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jaerosci.2022.105995</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>During the COVID-19 pandemic, WHO and CDC suggest people stay 1 m and 1.8 m away from others, respectively. Keeping social distance can avoid close contact and mitigate infection spread. Many researchers suspect that suggested distances are not enough because aerosols can spread up to 7-8 m away. Despite the debate on social distance, these social distances rely on unobstructed respiratory activities such as coughing and sneezing. Differently, in this work, we focused on the most common but less studied aerosol spread from an obstructed cough. The flow dynamics of a cough jet blocked by the backrest and gasper jet in a cabin environment was characterized by the particle image velocimetry (PIV) technique. It was proved that the backrest and the gasper jet can prevent the front passenger from droplet spray in public transportation where maintaining social distance was difficult. A model was developed to describe the cough jet trajectory due to the gasper jet, which matched well with PIV results. It was found that buoyancy and inside droplets almost do not affect the short-range cough jet trajectory. Infection control measures were suggested for public transportation, including using backrest/gasper jet, installing localized exhaust, and surface cleaning of the backrest.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wang</LastName>
            <ForeName>C T</ForeName>
            <Initials>CT</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering, The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Xu</LastName>
            <ForeName>J C</ForeName>
            <Initials>JC</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering, The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chan</LastName>
            <ForeName>K C</ForeName>
            <Initials>KC</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lee</LastName>
            <ForeName>H H</ForeName>
            <Initials>HH</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Energy and Environment, City University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tso</LastName>
            <ForeName>C Y</ForeName>
            <Initials>CY</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Energy and Environment, City University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lin</LastName>
            <ForeName>Carol S K</ForeName>
            <Initials>CSK</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Energy and Environment, City University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chao</LastName>
            <ForeName>Christopher Y H</ForeName>
            <Initials>CYH</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Building Environment and Energy Engineering &amp; Department of Mechanical Engineering, The Hong Kong Polytechnic University, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Fu</LastName>
            <ForeName>S C</ForeName>
            <Initials>SC</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Mechanical Engineering, The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>04</Month>
          <Day>01</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>J Aerosol Sci</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>1263115</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0021-8502</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gasper jet</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Jet interaction</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Particle image velocimetry</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Public transport</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>16</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35382445</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8971108</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaerosci.2022.105995</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">S0021-8502(22)00040-4</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>ASHRAE. ASHRAE  . 2021. Handbook-fundamentals.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bahl P., Doolan C., de Silva C., Chughtai A.A., Bourouiba L., MacIntyre C.R. Airborne or droplet precautions for health workers treating COVID-19? The Journal of Infectious Diseases. 2020</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bourouiba L. Turbulent gas clouds and respiratory pathogen emissions: Potential implications for reducing transmission of COVID-19. JAMA. 2020;323:1837–1838.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32215590</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bourouiba L., Dehandschoewercker E., Bush J.W. Violent expiratory events: On coughing and sneezing. Journal of Fluid Mechanics. 2014;745:537–563.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Broadwell J.E., Breidenthal R.E. Structure and mixing of a transverse jet in incompressible flow. Journal of Fluid Mechanics. 1984;148:405–412.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cao G., Liu S., Boor B.E., Novoselac A. Characterizing the dynamic interactions and exposure implications of a particle-laden cough jet with different room airflow regimes produced by low and high momentum jets. Aerosol and Air Quality Research. 2015;15:1955–1966.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cao G., Liu S., Boor B.E., Novoselac A. Dynamic interaction of a downward plane jet and a cough jet with respect to particle transmission: An analytical and experimental study. Journal of Occupational and Environmental Hygiene. 2017;14:618–631.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>CDC  . 2020. Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19): What is social distancing?</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chao C.Y.H., Wan M.P., Morawska L., Johnson G.R., Ristovski Z.D., Hargreaves M., et al.  Characterization of expiration air jets and droplet size distributions immediately at the mouth opening. Journal of Aerosol Science. 2009;40:122–133.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7126899</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32287373</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Wit E., Van Doremalen N., Falzarano D., Munster V.J. SARS and MERS: Recent insights into emerging coronaviruses. Nature Reviews Microbiology. 2016;14:523.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7097822</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27344959</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dudalski N., Mohamed A., Mubareka S., Bi R., Zhang C., Savory E. Experimental investigation of far‐field human cough airflows from healthy and influenza‐infected subjects. Indoor Air. 2020;30:966–977.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7264733</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32304605</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dye C., Gay N. Modeling the SARS epidemic. Science. 2003;300:1884–1885.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12766208</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Effros R.M., Hoagland K.W., Bosbous M., Castillo D., Foss B., Dunning M., et al.  Dilution of respiratory solutes in exhaled condensates. American Journal of Respiratory and Critical Care Medicine. 2002;165:663–669.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11874811</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ge H., Chen L., Xu C., Cui X. Large-eddy simulation of droplet-laden cough jets with a realistic manikin model. Indoor and Built Environment. 2021 1420326X211032247.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta J.K., Lin C., Chen Q. Flow dynamics and characterization of a cough. Indoor Air. 2009;19:517–525.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19840145</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta J.K., Lin C., Chen Q. Transport of expiratory droplets in an aircraft cabin. Indoor Air. 2011;21:3–11.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21208287</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jimenez J., Marr L., Randall K., Ewing E.T., Bourouiba L. Echoes through time: The historical origins of the droplet dogma and its role in the misidentification of airborne respiratory infection transmission. Available at SSRN. 2021</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li H., Leong F.Y., Xu G., Ge Z., Kang C.W., Lim K.H. Dispersion of evaporating cough droplets in tropical outdoor environment. Physics of Fluids. 2020;32:113301.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7685245</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33244215</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li Y., Leung G.M., Tang J.W., Yang X., Chao C.Y., Lin J.Z., et al.  Role of ventilation in airborne transmission of infectious agents in the built environment-a multidisciplinary systematic review. Indoor Air. 2007;17:2–18.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17257148</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li J., Liu J., Dai S., Guo Y., Jiang N., Yang W. PIV experimental research on gasper jets interacting with the main ventilation in an aircraft cabin. Building and Environment. 2018;138:149–159.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu Y., Ning Z., Chen Y., Guo M., Liu Y., Gali N.K., et al.  Aerodynamic analysis of SARS-CoV-2 in two Wuhan hospitals. Nature. 2020;582:557–560.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32340022</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu S., Novoselac A. Transport of airborne particles from an unobstructed cough jet. Aerosol Science and Technology. 2014;48:1183–1194.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu L., Wei J., Li Y., Ooi A. Evaporation and dispersion of respiratory droplets from coughing. Indoor Air. 2017;27:179–190.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26945674</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morawska L., Cao J. Airborne transmission of SARS-CoV-2: The world should face the reality. Environment International. 2020;139:105730.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7151430</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32294574</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morawska L., Milton D.K. It is time to address airborne transmission of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) Clinical Infectious Diseases. 2020;71:2311–2313.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7454469</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32628269</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muppidi S., Mahesh K. Study of trajectories of jets in crossflow using direct numerical simulations. Journal of Fluid Mechanics. 2005;530:81.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Or C.M., Lam K.M., Liu P. Potential core lengths of round jets in stagnant and moving environments. Journal of Hydro-environment Research. 2011;5:81–91.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Prather K.A., Marr L.C., Schooley R.T., McDiarmid M.A., Wilson M.E., Milton D.K. Airborne transmission of SARS-CoV-2. Science. 2020;370:303–304.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Redrow J., Mao S., Celik I., Posada J.A., Feng Z. Modeling the evaporation and dispersion of airborne sputum droplets expelled from a human cough. Building and Environment. 2011;46:2042–2051.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tang J.W., Li Y., Eames I., Chan P., Ridgway G.L. Factors involved in the aerosol transmission of infection and control of ventilation in healthcare premises. Journal of Hospital Infection. 2006;64:100–114.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tang J.W., Liebner T.J., Craven B.A., Settles G.S. A schlieren optical study of the human cough with and without wearing masks for aerosol infection control. Journal of The Royal Society Interface. 2009;6:S727–S736.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>VanSciver M., Miller S., Hertzberg J. Particle image velocimetry of human cough. Aerosol Science and Technology. 2011;45:415–422.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang C.T., Fu S.C., Chao C.Y. Short-range bioaerosol deposition and recovery of viable viruses and bacteria on surfaces from a cough and implications for respiratory disease transmission. Aerosol Science and Technology. 2020;55:215–230.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang C.T., Leung W.T., Xu J.C., Fu S.C., Chao C.Y. Droplet detachment behavior from a rough hydrophilic surface. Journal of Aerosol Science. 2020;139:105469.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang C., Xu J., Fu S.C., Chan K.C., Chao C.Y. Respiratory bioaerosol deposition from a cough and recovery of viable viruses on nearby seats in a cabin environment. Indoor Air. 2021;31:1913–1925.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8447388</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34297881</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang C., Xu Y., Wu Y., An Z. PIV investigation of the flow features of double and single 45° up‐pumping pitched blade turbines in a square tank. Canadian Journal of Chemical Engineering. 2018;96:788–799.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wei J., Li Y. Enhanced spread of expiratory droplets by turbulence in a cough jet. Building and Environment. 2015;93:86–96.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wells W.F. ON AIR-borne infection: Study II. Droplets and droplet nuclei. American Journal of Epidemiology. 1934;20:611–618.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wells W.F.  1955. Airborne contagion and air hygiene. An ecological study of droplet infections. Airborne contagion and air hygiene. An ecological study of droplet infections.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>WHO . 2020. Coronavirus disease (COVID-19) advice for the public.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xia L.P., Lam K.M. Velocity and concentration measurements in initial region of submerged round jets in stagnant environment and in coflow. Journal of Hydro-environment Research. 2009;3:21–34.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xie X., Li Y., Chwang A., Ho P.L., Seto W.H. How far droplets can move in indoor environments–revisiting the Wells evaporation–falling curve. Indoor Air. 2007;17:211–225.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17542834</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu J., Fu S., Chao C.Y. Performance of airflow distance from personalized ventilation on personal exposure to airborne droplets from different orientations. Indoor and Built Environment. 2020 1420326X20951245.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu Y., Wang C., Wu Y. Optimization of mechanical accelerated clarifier based on numerical simulation of flow field. Advances in Mechanical Engineering. 2017;9 1687814017720881.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang L., Li X., Yan Y., Tu J. Effects of cough-jet on airflow and contaminant transport in an airliner cabin section. The Journal of Computational Multiphase Flows. 2018;10:72–82.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yan Y., Li X., Yang L., Yan P., Tu J. Evaluation of cough-jet effects on the transport characteristics of respiratory-induced contaminants in airline passengers' local environments. Building and Environment. 2020;183:107206.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7428687</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32836705</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
