<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35382516</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>08</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2397-1991</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>5</Volume>
            <Issue>3</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2020</Year>
              <Month>Oct</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of scleroderma and related disorders</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Scleroderma Relat Disord</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Antisynthetase syndrome: A distinct disease spectrum.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>178</StartPage>
          <EndPage>191</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>178-191</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/2397198320902667</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The discovery of novel autoantibodies related to idiopathic inflammatory myopathies (collectively referred to as myositis) has not only advanced our understanding of the clinical, serological, and pathological correlation in the disease spectrum but also played a role in guiding management and prognosis. One group of the myositis-specific autoantibodies is anti-aminoacyl-tRNA synthetase (anti-ARS or anti-synthetase) which defines a syndrome with predominant interstitial lung disease, arthritis, and myositis. Autoantibodies to eight aminoacyl-tRNA synthetases have been identified with anti-Jo1 the most common in all of idiopathic inflammatory myopathies. Disease presentation and prognosis vary depending on which anti-aminoacyl-tRNA synthetase antibody is present. In this review, we will discuss the clinical characteristics, overlap features with other autoimmune diseases, prognostic factors, and management of the antisynthetase syndrome.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© The Author(s) 2020.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Huang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kun</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0242-6959</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Rheumatology, Faculty of Medicine, University of British Columbia, Vancouver, BC, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Aggarwal</LastName>
            <ForeName>Rohit</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Arthritis and Autoimmunity Center and UPMC Myositis Center, Division of Rheumatology and Clinical Immunology, School of Medicine, University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, PA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>02</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>J Scleroderma Relat Disord</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101685427</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2397-1983</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Inflammatory myositis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">antisynthetase syndrome</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">clinicoserological spectrum</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">interstitial lung disease</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">myositis-specific antibodies</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>Declaration of conflicting interests: The author(s) declared no potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2019</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>18</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
          <Hour>0</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
          <Hour>0</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35382516</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8922626</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/2397198320902667</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_2397198320902667</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Ghirardello A, Bassi N, Palma L, et al.. Autoantibodies in polymyositis and dermatomyositis. Curr Rheumatol Rep
2013; 15: 335.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23591825</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Targoff IN.
Idiopathic inflammatory myopathy: autoantibody update. Curr Rheumatol Rep
2002; 4(5): 434–441.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12217249</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Koenig M, Fritzler MJ, Targoff IN, et al.. Heterogeneity of autoantibodies in 100 patients with autoimmune myositis: insights into clinical features and outcomes. Arthritis Res Ther
2007; 9(4): R78.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2206383</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17688695</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Nishikai M, Reichlin M.
Heterogeneity of precipitating antibodies in polymyositis and dermatomyositis. Characterization of the Jo-1 antibody system. Arthritis Rheum
1980; 23: 881–888.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7406938</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Mathews MB, Reichlin M, Hughes GR, et al.. Anti-threonyl-tRNA synthetase, a second myositis-related autoantibody. J Exp Med
1984; 160(2): 420–434.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2187452</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6206177</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Bunn CC, Bernstein RM, Mathews MB.
Autoantibodies against alanyl-tRNA synthetase and tRNAAla coexist and are associated with myositis. J Exp Med
1986; 163(5): 1281–1291.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2188100</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3701255</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Targoff IN.
Autoantibodies to aminoacyl-transfer RNA synthetases for isoleucine and glycine. Two additional synthetases are antigenic in myositis. J Immunol
1990; 144(5): 1737–1743.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2307838</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Hirakata M, Suwa A, Nagai S, et al.. Anti-KS: identification of autoantibodies to asparaginyl-transfer RNA synthetase associated with interstitial lung disease. J Immunol
1999; 162(4): 2315–2320.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9973509</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Betteridge Z, Gunawardena H, North J, et al.. Anti-synthetase syndrome: a new autoantibody to phenylalanyl transfer RNA synthetase (anti-Zo) associated with polymyositis and interstitial pneumonia. Rheumatology (Oxford)
2007; 46(6): 1005–1008.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17392287</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Mahler M, Fritzler MJ.
Epitope specificity and significance in systemic autoimmune diseases. Ann N Y Acad Sci
2010; 1183: 267–287.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20146721</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Brouwer R, Hengstman GJ, Vree Egberts W, et al.. Autoantibody profiles in the sera of European patients with myositis. Ann Rheum Dis
2001; 60(2): 116–123.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1753477</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11156543</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Vazquez-Abad D, Rothfield NF.
Sensitivity and specificity of anti-Jo-1 antibodies in autoimmune diseases with myositis. Arthritis Rheum
1996; 39(2): 292–296.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8849382</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Arnett FC, Targoff IN, Mimori T, et al.. Interrelationship of major histocompatibility complex class II alleles and autoantibodies in four ethnic groups with various forms of myositis. Arthritis Rheum
1996; 39(9): 1507–1518.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8814062</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Aggarwal R, Cassidy E, Fertig N, et al.. Patients with non-Jo-1 anti-tRNA-synthetase autoantibodies have worse survival than Jo-1 positive patients. Ann Rheum Dis
2014; 73(1): 227–232.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4031026</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23422076</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Chatterjee S, Prayson R, Farver C.
Antisynthetase syndrome: not just an inflammatory myopathy. Cleve Clin J Med
2013; 80: 655–666.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24085811</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Cavagna L, Trallero-Araguas E, Meloni F, et al.. Influence of antisynthetase antibodies specificities on antisynthetase syndrome clinical spectrum time course. J Clin Med
2019; 8(11): E2013.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6912490</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31752231</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Targoff IN, Trieu EP, Miller FW.
Reaction of anti-OJ autoantibodies with components of the multi-enzyme complex of aminoacyl-tRNA synthetases in addition to isoleucyl-tRNA synthetase. J Clin Invest
1993; 91(6): 2556–2564.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC443318</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8514867</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Aggarwal R, Dhillon N, Fertig N, et al.. A negative antinuclear antibody does not indicate autoantibody negativity in myositis: role of anticytoplasmic antibody as a screening test for antisynthetase syndrome. J Rheumatol
2017; 44: 223–229.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27909085</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Dugar M, Cox S, Limaye V, et al.. Clinical heterogeneity and prognostic features of South Australian patients with anti-synthetase autoantibodies. Intern Med J
2011; 41(9): 674–679.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20059602</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Hervier B, Devilliers H, Stanciu R, et al.. Hierarchical cluster and survival analyses of antisynthetase syndrome: phenotype and outcome are correlated with anti-tRNA synthetase antibody specificity. Autoimmun Rev
2012; 12(2): 210–217.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22771754</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Cavagna L, Nuno L, Scire CA, et al.. Clinical spectrum time course in anti Jo-1 positive antisynthetase syndrome: results from an international retrospective multicenter study. Medicine (Baltimore)
2015; 94(32): e1144.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4616698</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26266346</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Cavagna L, Nuno L, Scire CA, et al.. Serum Jo-1 autoantibody and isolated arthritis in the antisynthetase syndrome: review of the literature and report of the experience of AENEAS collaborative group. Clin Rev Allergy Immunol
2017; 52(1): 71–80.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26782036</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Gonzalez-Gay MA, Montecucco C, Selva-O’Callaghan A, et al.. Timing of onset affects arthritis presentation pattern in antisyntethase syndrome. Clin Exp Rheumatol
2018; 36(1): 44–49.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28770709</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Scire CA, Gonzalez-Gay MA, Selva-O’Callaghan A, et al.. Clinical spectrum time course of interstitial pneumonia with autoimmune features in patients positive for antisynthetase antibodies. Respir Med
2017; 132: 265–266.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28385573</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Bartoloni E, Gonzalez-Gay MA, Scire C, et al.. Clinical follow-up predictors of disease pattern change in anti-Jo1 positive anti-synthetase syndrome: results from a multicenter, international and retrospective study. Autoimmun Rev
2017; 16(3): 253–257.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28147261</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Trallero-Araguas E, Grau-Junyent JM, Labirua-Iturburu A, et al.. Clinical manifestations and long-term outcome of anti-Jo1 antisynthetase patients in a large cohort of Spanish patients from the GEAS-IIM group. Semin Arthritis Rheum
2016; 46(2): 225–231.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27139168</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Lefevre G, Meyer A, Launay D, et al.. Seronegative polyarthritis revealing antisynthetase syndrome: a multicentre study of 40 patients. Rheumatology (Oxford)
2015; 54(5): 927–932.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25349440</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Meyer A, Lefevre G, Bierry G, et al.. In antisynthetase syndrome, ACPA are associated with severe and erosive arthritis: an overlapping rheumatoid arthritis and antisynthetase syndrome. Medicine (Baltimore)
2015; 94(20): e523.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4602869</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25997035</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Cavagna L, Castaneda S, Scire C, et al.. Antisynthetase syndrome or what else? Different perspectives indicate the need for new classification criteria. Ann Rheum Dis
2018; 77: e50.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28970214</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Lilleker JB, Vencovsky J, Wang G, et al.. The EuroMyositis registry: an international collaborative tool to facilitate myositis research. Ann Rheum Dis
2018; 77(1): 30–39.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5754739</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28855174</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Hamaguchi Y, Fujimoto M, Matsushita T, et al.. Common and distinct clinical features in adult patients with anti-aminoacyl-tRNA synthetase antibodies: heterogeneity within the syndrome. PLoS ONE
2013; 8(4): e60442.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3616126</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23573256</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Shi J, Li S, Yang H, et al.. Clinical profiles and prognosis of patients with distinct antisynthetase autoantibodies. J Rheumatol
2017; 44(7): 1051–1057.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28461650</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Johnson C, Connors GR, Oaks J, et al.. Clinical and pathologic differences in interstitial lung disease based on antisynthetase antibody type. Respir Med
2014; 108(10): 1542–1548.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25269710</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Marie I, Josse S, Decaux O, et al.. Comparison of long-term outcome between anti-Jo1- and anti-PL7/PL12 positive patients with antisynthetase syndrome. Autoimmun Rev
2012; 11(10): 739–745.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22326685</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Waseda Y, Johkoh T, Egashira R, et al.. Antisynthetase syndrome: pulmonary computed tomography findings of adult patients with antibodies to aminoacyl-tRNA synthetases. Eur J Radiol
2016; 85(8): 1421–1426.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27423682</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Zamora AC, Hoskote SS, Abascal-Bolado B, et al.. Clinical features and outcomes of interstitial lung disease in anti-Jo-1 positive antisynthetase syndrome. Respir Med
2016; 118: 39–45.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27578469</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Richards TJ, Eggebeen A, Gibson K, et al.. Characterization and peripheral blood biomarker assessment of anti-Jo-1 antibody-positive interstitial lung disease. Arthritis Rheum
2009; 60(7): 2183–2192.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2710404</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19565490</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Yousem SA, Schneider F, Bi D, et al.. The pulmonary histopathologic manifestations of the anti-PL7/antithreonyl transfer RNA synthetase syndrome. Hum Pathol
2014; 45(6): 1199–1204.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24767252</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Schneider F, Yousem SA, Oddis CV, et al.. Pulmonary pathologic manifestations of anti-alanyl-tRNA synthetase (anti-PL-12)-related inflammatory myopathy. Arch Pathol Lab Med
2018; 142(2): 191–197.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28967806</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Ghysen K, Leys M.
A 64-year-old woman with interstitial lung disease and positive antibodies against aminoacyl-transfer RNA synthetases in the absence of myositis: presentation of an anti-PL-12 positive antisynthetase syndrome. Acta Clin Belg
2018; 73(5): 389–392.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29173135</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Takato H, Waseda Y, Watanabe S, et al.. Pulmonary manifestations of anti-ARS antibody positive interstitial pneumonia–with or without PM/DM. Respir Med
2013; 107(1): 128–133.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23137883</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Matsushita T, Hasegawa M, Fujimoto M, et al.. Clinical evaluation of anti-aminoacyl tRNA synthetase antibodies in Japanese patients with dermatomyositis. J Rheumatol
2007; 34(5): 1012–1018.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17309126</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Nakashima R, Imura Y, Hosono Y, et al.. The multicenter study of a new assay for simultaneous detection of multiple anti-aminoacyl-tRNA synthetases in myositis and interstitial pneumonia. PLoS ONE
2014; 9(1): e85062.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3891809</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24454792</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Watanabe K, Handa T, Tanizawa K, et al.. Detection of antisynthetase syndrome in patients with idiopathic interstitial pneumonias. Respir Med
2011; 105(8): 1238–1247.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21514811</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Yura H, Sakamoto N, Satoh M, et al.. Clinical characteristics of patients with anti-aminoacyl-tRNA synthetase antibody positive idiopathic interstitial pneumonia. Respir Med
2017; 132: 189–194.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29229096</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Aggarwal R, McBurney C, Schneider F, et al.. Myositis-associated usual interstitial pneumonia has a better survival than idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. Rheumatology (Oxford)
2017; 56(3): 384–389.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28082622</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Hervier B, Meyer A, Dieval C, et al.. Pulmonary hypertension in antisynthetase syndrome: prevalence, aetiology and survival. Eur Respir J
2013; 42(5): 1271–1282.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23397301</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Chatterjee S, Farver C.
Severe pulmonary hypertension in anti-Jo-1 syndrome. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken)
2010; 62(3): 425–429.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20391490</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Gusdorf L, Morruzzi C, Goetz J, et al.. Mechanics hands in patients with antisynthetase syndrome: 25 cases. Ann Dermatol Venereol
2019; 146: 19–25.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30595338</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Cox JT, Gullotti DM, Mecoli CA, et al.. “Hiker’s feet”: a novel cutaneous finding in the inflammatory myopathies. Clin Rheumatol
2017; 36(7): 1683–1686.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6100725</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28389987</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Wernham M, Montague SJ.
Mechanic’s hands and hiker’s feet in antisynthetase syndrome. CMAJ
2017; 189(44): E1365.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5675544</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29109211</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Katzap E, Barilla-LaBarca ML, Marder G.
Antisynthetase syndrome. Curr Rheumatol Rep
2011; 13: 175–181.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21455765</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Mii S, Kobayashi R, Nakano T, et al.. A histopathologic study of mechanic’s hands associated with dermatomyositis: a report of five cases. Int J Dermatol
2009; 48(11): 1177–1182.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20064170</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Sohara E, Saraya T, Sato S, et al.. Mechanic’s hands revisited: is this sign still useful for diagnosis in patients with lung involvement of collagen vascular diseases?
BMC Res Notes
2014; 7: 303.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4035896</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24886713</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Patel HC, Lauder NN.
The antisynthetase syndrome. Am J Med
2011; 124: e3–e4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21621182</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Bachmeyer C, Tillie-Leblond I, Lacert A, et al.. “Mechanic’s hands”: a misleading cutaneous sign of the antisynthetase syndrome. Br J Dermatol
2007; 156(1): 192–194.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17199601</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Mercer LK, Moore TL, Chinoy H, et al.. Quantitative nailfold video capillaroscopy in patients with idiopathic inflammatory myopathy. Rheumatology (Oxford)
2010; 49(9): 1699–1705.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20483911</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Miyagawa F, Azukizawa H, Mimori T, et al.. Anti-PL-12 antibody-positive antisynthetase syndrome with recurrent digital ulcers. J Dermatol
2018; 46: e143–e145.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30230582</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Sebastiani M, Triantafyllias K, Manfredi A, et al.. Nailfold capillaroscopy characteristics of antisynthetase syndrome and possible clinical associations: results of a multicenter international study. J Rheumatol
2019; 46: 279–284.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30442823</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Asi K, Gourishankar A, Kamdar A.
Coronary artery dilation associated with anti-synthetase syndrome in an adolescent. Pediatr Rheumatol Online J
2019; 17(1): 3.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6329119</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30630507</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Hayashi K, Machida Y, Katayama Y, et al.. A case of antisynthetase syndrome with anti-EJ antibody complicated by pericarditis. Rins Shinkeig
2019; 59: 21–26.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30606993</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Labirua-Iturburu A, Selva-O’Callaghan A, Vincze M, et al.. Anti-PL-7 (anti-threonyl-tRNA synthetase) antisynthetase syndrome: clinical manifestations in a series of patients from a European multicenter study (EUMYONET) and review of the literature. Medicine (Baltimore)
2012; 91(4): 206–211.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22732951</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Mehndiratta P, Mehta S, Manjila SV, et al.. Isolated necrotizing myopathy associated with ANTI-PL12 antibody. Muscle Nerve
2012; 46(2): 282–286.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22806380</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Meudec L, Jelin G, Forien M, et al.. Antisynthetase syndrome and cardiac involvement: a rare association. Joint Bone Spine. Epub ahead of print 7 October 2018. DOI: 10.1016/j.jbspin.2018.09.019.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jbspin.2018.09.019</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30291977</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Rungcharunthanakul A, Sampattavanich N.
Polymy-ositis with antisynthetase syndrome presented with lobular panniculitis: a case report. Clin Case Rep
2019; 7(1): 128–130.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6333058</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30656025</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Dieval C, Deligny C, Meyer A, et al.. Myocarditis in patients with antisynthetase syndrome: prevalence, presentation, and outcomes. Medicine (Baltimore)
2015; 94(26): e798.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4504539</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26131832</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Saito G, Kono M, Tsutsumi A, et al.. Anti-PL-7 antisynthetase syndrome with eosinophilic pleural effusion. Intern Med
2018; 57(15): 2227–2232.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6120831</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29526945</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Sharma K, Orbai AM, Desai D, et al.. Brief report: antisynthetase syndrome-associated myocarditis. J Card Fail
2014; 20(12): 939–945.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4435564</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25084215</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Gorospe L, de la Puente-Bujidos C, Garcia-Gomez-Muriel I, et al.. Asymmetric calcinosis in an adult patient with antisynthetase syndrome. J Clin Rheumatol
2019; 25: 36–37.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29319552</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Aguila LA, Lopes MR, Pretti FZ, et al.. Clinical and laboratory features of overlap syndromes of idiopathic inflammatory myopathies associated with systemic lupus erythematosus, systemic sclerosis, or rheumatoid arthritis. Clin Rheumatol
2014; 33: 1093–1098.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24989017</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Garton MJ, Isenberg DA.
Clinical features of lupus myositis versus idiopathic myositis: a review of 30 cases. Br J Rheumatol
1997; 36(10): 1067–1074.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9374923</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Ghirardello A, Zampieri S, Iaccarino L, et al.. Myositis specific and myositis associated autoantibodies in idiopathic inflammatory myopathies: a serologic study of 46 patients. Reumatismo
2005; 57(1): 22–28.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15776143</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Hausmanowa-Petrusewicz I, Kowalska-Oledzka E, Miller FW, et al.. Clinical, serologic, and immunogenetic features in Polish patients with idiopathic inflammatory myopathies. Arthritis Rheum
1997; 40(7): 1257–1266.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9214426</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Hochberg MC, Feldman D, Stevens MB.
Adult onset polymyositis/dermatomyositis: an analysis of clinical and laboratory features and survival in 76 patients with a review of the literature. Semin Arthritis Rheum
1986; 15(3): 168–178.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3515559</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Ramesha KN, Kuruvilla A, Sarma PS, et al.. Clinical, electrophysiologic, and histopathologic profile, and outcome in idiopathic inflammatory myositis: an analysis of 68 cases. Ann Indian Acad Neurol
2010; 13(4): 250–256.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3021927</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21264132</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Vancsa A, Gergely L, Ponyi A, et al.. Myositis-specific and myositis-associated antibodies in overlap myositis in comparison to primary dermatopolymyositis: relevance for clinical classification: retrospective study of 169 patients. Joint Bone Spine
2010; 77(2): 125–130.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20188618</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Troyanov Y, Targoff IN, Tremblay JL, et al.. Novel classification of idiopathic inflammatory myopathies based on overlap syndrome features and autoantibodies: analysis of 100 French Canadian patients. Medicine (Baltimore)
2005; 84(4): 231–249.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16010208</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Bhansing KJ, Lammens M, Knaapen HK, et al.. Scleroderma-polymyositis overlap syndrome versus idiopathic polymyositis and systemic sclerosis: a descriptive study on clinical features and myopathology. Arthritis Res Ther
2014; 16(3): R111.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4060195</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24886750</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Pakozdi A, Nihtyanova S, Moinzadeh P, et al.. Clinical and serological hallmarks of systemic sclerosis overlap syndromes. J Rheumatol
2011; 38(11): 2406–2409.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21844148</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Sato S, Hirakata M, Kuwana M, et al.. Clinical characteristics of Japanese patients with anti-PL-7 (anti-threonyl-tRNA synthetase) autoantibodies. Clin Exp Rheumatol
2005; 23(5): 609–615.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16173235</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Hermans MAW, Miedema JR, Verdijk RM, et al.. Scleroderma-like renal crisis in a patient with anti-threonyl-tRNA synthetase-associated antisynthetase syndrome. Rheumatology (Oxford)
2018; 57(4): 763–765.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29394404</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Suzuki S, Uruha A, Suzuki N, et al.. Integrated diagnosis project for inflammatory myopathies: an association between autoantibodies and muscle pathology. Autoimmun Rev
2017; 16(7): 693–700.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28479486</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Noguchi E, Uruha A, Suzuki S, et al.. Skeletal muscle involvement in antisynthetase syndrome. JAMA Neurol
2017; 74(8): 992–999.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5710328</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28586844</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Aouizerate J, De Antonio M, Bassez G, et al.. Myofiber HLA-DR expression is a distinctive biomarker for antisynthetase-associated myopathy. Acta Neuropathol Commun
2014; 2: 154.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4210467</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25339355</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Mozaffar T, Pestronk A.
Myopathy with anti-Jo-1 antibodies: pathology in perimysium and neighbouring muscle fibres. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry
2000; 68(4): 472–478.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1736872</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10727483</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Stenzel W, Preusse C, Allenbach Y, et al.. Nuclear actin aggregation is a hallmark of anti-synthetase syndrome-induced dysimmune myopathy. Neurology
2015; 84(13): 1346–1354.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25746564</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Mescam-Mancini L, Allenbach Y, Hervier B, et al.. Anti-Jo-1 antibody-positive patients show a characteristic necrotizing perifascicular myositis. Brain
2015; 138(Pt 9): 2485–2492.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26198592</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Uruha A, Suzuki S, Suzuki N, et al.. Perifascicular necrosis in anti-synthetase syndrome beyond anti-Jo-1. Brain
2016; 139: e50.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27267378</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
De Bleecker JL, De Paepe B, Aronica E, et al.. 205th ENMC international workshop: pathology diagnosis of idiopathic inflammatory myopathies part II 28–30 March 2014, Naarden, The Netherlands. Neuromuscul Disord
2015; 25(3): 268–272.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25572016</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Uruha A, Allenbach Y, Charuel JL, et al.. Diagnostic potential of sarcoplasmic MxA expression in subsets of dermatomyositis. Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol
2019; 45: 513–522.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30267437</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Defendenti C, Atzeni F, Spina MF, et al.. Clinical and laboratory aspects of Ro/SSA-52 autoantibodies. Autoimmun Rev
2011; 10(3): 150–154.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20854935</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Zampeli E, Venetsanopoulou A, Argyropoulou OD, et al.. Myositis autoantibody profiles and their clinical associations in Greek patients with inflammatory myopathies. Clin Rheumatol
2019; 38(1): 125–132.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30145635</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Schulte-Pelkum J, Fritzler M, Mahler M.
Latest update on the Ro/SS-A autoantibody system. Autoimmun Rev
2009; 8(7): 632–637.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19393201</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Yamasaki Y, Satoh M, Mizushima M, et al.. Clinical subsets associated with different anti-aminoacyl transfer RNA synthetase antibodies and their association with coexisting anti-Ro52. Mod Rheumatol
2016; 26(3): 403–409.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26344678</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Marie I, Hatron PY, Dominique S, et al.. Short-term and long-term outcome of anti-Jo1-positive patients with anti-Ro52 antibody. Semin Arthritis Rheum
2012; 41(6): 890–899.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22078416</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Rutjes SA, Vree Egberts WT, Jongen P, et al.. Anti-Ro52 antibodies frequently co-occur with anti-Jo-1 antibodies in sera from patients with idiopathic inflammatory myopathy. Clin Exp Immunol
1997; 109(1): 32–40.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1904727</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9218821</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Ohashi K, Sada KE, Nakai Y, et al.. Cluster analysis using anti-aminoacyl-tRNA synthetases and SS-A/Ro52 antibodies in patients with polymyositis/dermatomyositis. J Clin Rheumatol
2019; 25: 246–251.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29933322</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
La Corte R, Lo Mo Naco A, Locaputo A, et al.. In patients with antisynthetase syndrome the occurrence of anti-Ro/SSA antibodies causes a more severe interstitial lung disease. Autoimmunity
2006; 39(3): 249–253.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16769659</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Vancsa A, Csipo I, Nemeth J, et al.. Characteristics of interstitial lung disease in SS-A positive/Jo-1 positive inflammatory myopathy patients. Rheumatol Int
2009; 29(9): 989–994.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19266202</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Bauhammer J, Blank N, Max R, et al.. Rituximab in the treatment of Jo1 antibody-associated antisynthetase syndrome: anti-Ro52 positivity as a marker for severity and treatment response. J Rheumatol
2016; 43(8): 1566–1574.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27252419</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Labrador-Horrillo M, Martinez MA, Selva-O’Callaghan A, et al.. Anti-MDA5 antibodies in a large Mediterranean population of adults with dermatomyositis. J Immunol Res
2014; 2014: 290797.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3987881</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24741583</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Espinosa A, Dardalhon V, Brauner S, et al.. Loss of the lupus autoantigen Ro52/Trim21 induces tissue inflammation and systemic autoimmunity by disregulating the IL-23-Th17 pathway. J Exp Med
2009; 206(8): 1661–1671.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2722164</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19635858</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Mileti LM, Strek ME, Niewold TB, et al.. Clinical characteristics of patients with anti-Jo-1 antibodies: a single center experience. J Clin Rheumatol
2009; 15(5): 254–255.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3380442</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19590436</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Rozelle A, Trieu S, Chung L.
Malignancy in the setting of the anti-synthetase syndrome. J Clin Rheumatol
2008; 14(5): 285–288.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18664993</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Boleto G, Perotin JM, Eschard JP, et al.. Squamous cell carcinoma of the lung associated with anti-Jo1 antisynthetase syndrome: a case report and review of the literature. Rheumatol Int
2017; 37(7): 1203–1206.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28447208</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Legault D, McDermott J, Crous-Tsanaclis AM, et al.. Cancer-associated myositis in the presence of anti-Jo1 autoantibodies and the antisynthetase syndrome. J Rheumatol
2008; 35(1): 169–171.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18176990</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Przybylski G, Jarzemska A, Czerniak J, et al.. A case report of a patient with dermatomyositis as a prodromal sign of lung cancer. Pol Arch Med Wewn
2008; 118(3): 143–147.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18476461</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Respicio G, Shwaiki W, Abeles M.
A 58-year-old man with anti-Jo-1 syndrome and renal cell carcinoma: a case report and discussion. Conn Med
2007; 71(3): 151–153.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17405398</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Van der Bijl AE, Meinders AE, van Duinen SG, et al.. A nasal squamous cell carcinoma complicated by a paraneoplastic syndrome consisting of a myositis and anti-Jo-1 autoantibodies. Eur J Intern Med
2005; 16(5): 369–371.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16137556</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Vincze M, Molnar PA, Zilahi E, et al.. Primary lung adenocarcinoma associated with anti-Jo-1 positive polymyositis. Joint Bone Spine
2011; 78(2): 209–211.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21094073</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Watkins J, Farzaneh-Far R, Tahir H, et al.. Jo-1 syndrome with associated poorly differentiated adenocarcinoma. Rheumatology (Oxford)
2004; 43(3): 389–390.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14963208</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Buchbinder R, Forbes A, Hall S, et al.. Incidence of malignant disease in biopsy-proven inflammatory myopathy. A population-based cohort study. Ann Intern Med
2001; 134(12): 1087–1095.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11412048</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Castaneda-Pomeda M, Prieto-Gonzalez S, Grau JM.
Antisynthetase syndrome and malignancy: our experience. J Clin Rheumatol
2011; 17(8): 458.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22126809</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Kobayashi S, Shoda H, Seri Y, et al.. Characteristics of antisynthetase syndrome patients with hyperferritinaemia. Scand J Rheumatol
2017; 46(2): 161–163.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27308737</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Pinal-Fernandez I, Casal-Dominguez M, Huapaya JA, et al.. A longitudinal cohort study of the anti-synthetase syndrome: increased severity of interstitial lung disease in black patients and patients with anti-PL7 and anti-PL12 autoantibodies. Rheumatology (Oxford)
2017; 56(6): 999–1007.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5850781</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28339994</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Cruellas MG, Viana Vdos S, Levy-Neto M, et al.. Myositis-specific and myositis-associated autoantibody profiles and their clinical associations in a large series of patients with polymyositis and dermatomyositis. Clinics (Sao Paulo)
2013; 68(7): 909–914.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3715024</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23917652</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Kalluri M, Sahn SA, Oddis CV, et al.. Clinical profile of anti-PL-12 autoantibody. Cohort study and review of the literature. Chest
2009; 135(6): 1550–1556.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19225060</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Oddis CV, Aggarwal R.
Treatment in myositis. Nat Rev Rheumatol
2018; 14: 279–289.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29593343</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Conway R, Low C, Coughlan RJ, et al.. Methotrexate use and risk of lung disease in psoriasis, psoriatic arthritis, and inflammatory bowel disease: systematic literature review and meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials. BMJ
2015; 350: h1269.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4358852</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25770113</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Bakewell CJ, Raghu G.
Polymyositis associated with severe interstitial lung disease: remission after three doses of IV immunoglobulin. Chest
2011; 139(2): 441–443.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21285059</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Suzuki Y, Hayakawa H, Miwa S, et al.. Intravenous immunoglobulin therapy for refractory interstitial lung disease associated with polymyositis/dermatomyositis. Lung
2009; 187(3): 201–206.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19387736</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Marie I, Hachulla E, Cherin P, et al.. Interstitial lung disease in polymyositis and dermatomyositis. Arthritis Rheum
2002; 47: 614–622.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12522835</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Douglas WW, Tazelaar HD, Hartman TE, et al.. Polymyositis-dermatomyositis-associated interstitial lung disease. Am J Respir Crit Care Med
2001; 164: 1182–1185.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11673206</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Fischer A, Brown KK, Du Bois RM, et al.. Mycophenolate mofetil improves lung function in connective tissue disease-associated interstitial lung disease. J Rheumatol
2013; 40(5): 640–646.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3676865</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23457378</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Hisanaga J, Kotani T, Fujiki Y, et al.. Successful multi-target therapy including rituximab and mycophenolate mofetil in anti-melanoma differentiation-associated gene 5 antibody-positive rapidly progressive interstitial lung disease with clinically amyopathic dermatomyositis. Int J Rheum Dis
2017; 20(12): 2182–2185.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28752606</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Mira-Avendano IC, Parambil JG, Yadav R, et al.. A retrospective review of clinical features and treatment outcomes in steroid-resistant interstitial lung disease from polymyositis/dermatomyositis. Respir Med
2013; 107(6): 890–896.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23517887</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Morganroth PA, Kreider ME, Werth VP.
Mycophenolate mofetil for interstitial lung disease in dermatomyositis. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken)
2010; 62: 1496–1501.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3085935</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20506189</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Tsuchiya H, Tsuno H, Inoue M, et al.. Mycophenolate mofetil therapy for rapidly progressive interstitial lung disease in a patient with clinically amyopathic dermatomyositis. Mod Rheumatol
2014; 24(4): 694–696.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24506658</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Ochi S, Nanki T, Takada K, et al.. Favorable outcomes with tacrolimus in two patients with refractory interstitial lung disease associated with polymyositis/dermatomyositis. Clin Exp Rheumatol
2005; 23(5): 707–710.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16173253</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Takada K, Nagasaka K, Miyasaka N.
Polymyositis/dermatomyositis and interstitial lung disease: a new therapeutic approach with T-cell-specific immunosuppressants. Autoimmunity
2005; 38(5): 383–392.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16227154</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Wilkes MR, Sereika SM, Fertig N, et al.. Treatment of antisynthetase-associated interstitial lung disease with tacrolimus. Arthritis Rheum
2005; 52(8): 2439–2446.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16052580</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Kotani T, Takeuchi T, Makino S, et al.. Combination with corticosteroids and cyclosporin-A improves pulmonary function test results and chest HRCT findings in dermatomyositis patients with acute/subacute interstitial pneumonia. Clin Rheumatol
2011; 30(8): 1021–1028.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21340495</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Kurita T, Yasuda S, Oba K, et al.. The efficacy of tacrolimus in patients with interstitial lung diseases complicated with polymyositis or dermatomyositis. Rheumatology (Oxford)
2015; 54: 39–44.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24764266</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Kameda H, Nagasawa H, Ogawa H, et al.. Combination therapy with corticosteroids, cyclosporin A, and intravenous pulse cyclophosphamide for acute/subacute interstitial pneumonia in patients with dermatomyositis. J Rheumatol
2005; 32(9): 1719–1726.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16142867</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Mok CC, To CH, Szeto ML.
Successful treatment of dermatomyositis-related rapidly progressive interstitial pneumonitis with sequential oral cyclophosphamide and azathioprine. Scand J Rheumatol
2003; 32(3): 181–183.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12892257</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Yamasaki Y, Yamada H, Yamasaki M, et al.. Intravenous cyclophosphamide therapy for progressive interstitial pneumonia in patients with polymyositis/dermatomyositis. Rheumatology (Oxford)
2007; 46(1): 124–130.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16754626</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Schnabel A, Reuter M, Biederer J, et al.. Interstitial lung disease in polymyositis and dermatomyositis: clinical course and response to treatment. Semin Arthritis Rheum
2003; 32(5): 273–284.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12701038</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Allenbach Y, Guiguet M, Rigolet A, et al.. Efficacy of rituximab in refractory inflammatory myopathies associated with anti- synthetase auto-antibodies: an open-label, phase II trial. PLoS ONE
2015; 10(11): e0133702.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4634756</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26539981</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Andersson H, Sem M, Lund MB, et al.. Long-term experience with rituximab in anti-synthetase syndrome-related interstitial lung disease. Rheumatology (Oxford)
2015; 54(8): 1420–1428.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25740830</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Keir GJ, Maher TM, Ming D, et al.. Rituximab in severe, treatment-refractory interstitial lung disease. Respirology
2014; 19(3): 353–359.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24286447</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Kurtzman DJ, Wright NA, Lin J, et al.. Tofacitinib citrate for refractory cutaneous dermatomyositis: an alternative treatment. JAMA Dermatol
2016; 152(8): 944–945.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27120749</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Paik JJ, Christopher-Stine L.
A case of refractory dermatomyositis responsive to tofacitinib. Semin Arthritis Rheum
2017; 46(4): e19.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27642158</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Kato M, Ikeda K, Kageyama T, et al.. Successful treatment for refractory interstitial lung disease and pneumomediastinum with multidisciplinary therapy including tofacitinib in a patient with anti-MDA5 antibody-positive dermatomyositis. J Clin Rheumatol. Epub ahead of print 8 January 2019. DOI: 10.1097/RHU.0000000000000984.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/RHU.0000000000000984</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30614890</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Kurasawa K, Arai S, Namiki Y, et al.. Tofacitinib for refractory interstitial lung diseases in anti-melanoma differentiation-associated 5 gene antibody-positive dermatomyositis. Rheumatology (Oxford)
2018; 57(12): 2114–2119.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30060040</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Wendel S, Venhoff N, Frye BC, et al.. Successful treatment of extensive calcifications and acute pulmonary involvement in dermatomyositis with the Janus—Kinase inhibitor tofacitinib—a report of two cases. J Autoimmun
2019; 100: 131–136.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30862449</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
U.S. National Library of Medicine, 2017, https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT03215927</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Rowen AJ, Reichel J.
Dermatomyositis with lung involvement, successfully treated with azathioprine. Respiration
1983; 44(2): 143–146.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6836189</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Sarahrudi K, Estenne M, Corris P, et al.. International experience with conversion from cyclosporine to tacrolimus for acute and chronic lung allograft rejection. J Thorac Cardiovasc Surg
2004; 127(4): 1126–1132.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15052212</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Go DJ, Park JK, Kang EH, et al.. Survival benefit associated with early cyclosporine treatment for dermatomyositis-associated interstitial lung disease. Rheumatol Int
2016; 36(1): 125–131.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26223808</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Witt LJ, Demchuk C, Curran JJ, et al.. Benefit of adjunctive tacrolimus in connective tissue disease-interstitial lung disease. Pulm Pharmacol Ther
2016; 36: 46–52.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4760686</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26762710</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Nakashima R, Mimori T.
Anti-MDA5 (melanoma differentiation-associated gene 5) antibody and dermatomyositis with rapidly progressive interstitial pneumonia. Nihon Rinsho Meneki Gakkai Kaishi
2013; 36(2): 71–76.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23629426</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Dasa O, Ruzieh M, Oraibi O.
Successful treatment of life-threatening interstitial lung disease secondary to antisynthetase syndrome using rituximab: a case report and review of the literature. Am J Ther
2016; 23(2): e639–e645.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25830868</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Lepri G, Avouac J, Airo P, et al.. Effects of rituximab in connective tissue disorders related interstitial lung disease. Clin Exp Rheumatol
2016; 34(5): 181–185.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27749242</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Nalotto L, Iaccarino L, Zen M, et al.. Rituximab in refractory idiopathic inflammatory myopathies and antisynthetase syndrome: personal experience and review of the literature. Immunol Res
2013; 56(2–3): 362–370.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23572427</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Sem M, Molberg O, Lund MB, et al.. Rituximab treatment of the anti-synthetase syndrome: a retrospective case series. Rheumatology (Oxford)
2009; 48(8): 968–971.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19531628</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Sharp C, McCabe M, Dodds N, et al.. Rituximab in autoimmune connective tissue disease-associated interstitial lung disease. Rheumatology (Oxford)
2016; 55: 1318–1324.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27060110</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Unger L, Kampf S, Luthke K, et al.. Rituximab therapy in patients with refractory dermatomyositis or polymyositis: differential effects in a real-life population. Rheumatology (Oxford)
2014; 53(9): 1630–1638.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24706995</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Vandenbroucke E, Grutters JC, Altenburg J, et al.. Rituximab in life threatening antisynthetase syndrome. Rheumatol Int
2009; 29: 1499–1502.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19184665</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Doyle TJ, Dhillon N, Madan R, et al.. Rituximab in the treatment of interstitial lung disease associated with antisynthetase syndrome: a multicenter retrospective case review. J Rheumatol
2018; 45(6): 841–850.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5984657</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29606668</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
De Souza FHC, Miossi R, de Moraes JCB, et al.. Favorable rituximab response in patients with refractory idiopathic inflammatory myopathies. Adv Rheumatol
2018; 58(1): 31.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30657080</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Aggarwal R, Bandos A, Reed AM, et al.. Predictors of clinical improvement in rituximab-treated refractory adult and juvenile dermatomyositis and adult polymyositis. Arthritis Rheumatol
2014; 66(3): 740–749.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3987896</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24574235</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Saunders P, Tsipouri V, Keir GJ, et al.. Rituximab versus cyclophosphamide for the treatment of connective tissue disease-associated interstitial lung disease (RECITAL): study protocol for a randomised controlled trial. Trials
2017; 18(1): 275.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5471887</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28619061</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Anh-Tu Hoa S, Hudson M. Critical review of the role of intravenous immunoglobulins in idiopathic inflammatory myopathies. Semin Arthritis Rheum
2017; 46(4): 488–508.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27908534</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Lundberg IE, Tjarnlund A, Bottai M, et al.. 2017 European League Against Rheumatism/American College of Rheu-matology classification criteria for adult and juvenile idiopathic inflammatory myopathies and their major subgroups. Arthritis Rheumatol
2017; 69: 2271–2282.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5846474</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29106061</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
