<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35385154</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>06</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1939-1676</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Apr</Month>
              <Day>06</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of veterinary internal medicine</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Vet Intern Med</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Treatment of a cat with presumed Bartonella henselae-associated immune-mediated hemolytic anemia, fever, and lymphadenitis.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jvim.16415</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>A 2.5-year-old castrated male cat presented with fever and marked generalized lymphadenopathy of 4-months duration, despite treatment with amoxicillin-clavulanate/marbofloxacin. Abnormalities were not detected on complete blood count, serum chemistry, and FIV/FeLV test apart from a borderline, non-regenerative anemia. Peripheral lymph node fine needle aspirations revealed a marked increase in the percentage of intermediate- and lymphoblastic-lymphocytes in addition to reactive macrophages. Three weeks after presentation, the cat developed a severe, regenerative, immune-mediated hemolytic anemia (IMHA) which responded to immunosuppressive therapy. Fever and lymphadenopathy persisted. Peripheral lymph nodes tested positive for Bartonella henselae DNA in real-time PCR assay and sequencing. Treatment with pradofloxacin and doxycycline resulted in resolution of clinical signs, and negative PCR tests. Despite its reported low pathogenicity, B. henselae infection should also be considered in cats with protracted unexplained fever, lymphadenitis, and IMHA. Furthermore, a combination of pradofloxacin and doxycycline might be considered in cats with bartonellosis given its apparent clinical efficacy.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Authors. Journal of Veterinary Internal Medicine published by Wiley Periodicals LLC on behalf of American College of Veterinary Internal Medicine.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nivy</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ran</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5523-6411</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Koret School of Veterinary Medicine, The Hebrew University of Jerusalem, Rehovot, Israel.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Ben-Shemen Specialist Referral Center, Ben-Shemen Youth Village, Israel.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lavi-Ginzberg</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yael</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Veterinar Toran, Petah Tikva, Israel.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>de Sousa</LastName>
            <ForeName>Keyla Carstens Marques</ForeName>
            <Initials>KCM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Koret School of Veterinary Medicine, The Hebrew University of Jerusalem, Rehovot, Israel.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Golani</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yael</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Veterinar Toran, Petah Tikva, Israel.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kuzi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sharon</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7130-1706</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Koret School of Veterinary Medicine, The Hebrew University of Jerusalem, Rehovot, Israel.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nachum-Biala</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yaarit</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Koret School of Veterinary Medicine, The Hebrew University of Jerusalem, Rehovot, Israel.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Harrus</LastName>
            <ForeName>Shimon</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Koret School of Veterinary Medicine, The Hebrew University of Jerusalem, Rehovot, Israel.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>04</Month>
          <Day>06</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Vet Intern Med</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8708660</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0891-6640</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bartonellosis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">feline</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fever</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lymphadenitis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lymphadenomegaly</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pradofloxacin</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>17</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35385154</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jvim.16415</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garden OA, Kidd L, Mexas AM, et al. ACVIM consensus statement on the diagnosis of immune-mediated hemolytic anemia in dogs and cats. J Vet Intern Med. 2019;33:313-334.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maggi RG, Breitschwerdt EB. Potential limitations of the 16S-23S rRNA intergenic region for molecular detection of Bartonella species. J Clin Microbiol. 2005;43:1171-1176.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gutiérrez R, Morick D, Gross I, Winkler R, Abdeen Z, Harrus S. Bartonellae in domestic and stray cats from Israel: comparison of bacterial cultures and high-resolution melt real-time PCR as diagnostic methods. Vector Borne Zoonotic Dis. 2013;13:857-864.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Diaz MH, Bai Y, Malania L, Winchell JM, Kosoy MY. Development of a novel genus-specific real-time PCR assay for detection and differentiation of Bartonella species and genotypes. J Clin Microbiol. 2012;50:1645-1649.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gonçalves LR, Harrus S, Gutiérrez R, et al. Molecular detection and genetic diversity of Bartonella species in large ruminants and associated ectoparasites from the Brazilian Cerrado. Transbound Emerg Dis. 2020;67:1888-1897.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Basic Local Alignment Search Tool . http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/BLAST/. Accessed August 1, 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Álvarez-Fernández A, Breitschwerdt EB, Solano-Gallego L. Bartonella infections in cats and dogs including zoonotic aspects. Parasit Vectors. 2018;11:624.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deng H, Pang Q, Zhao B, Vayssier-Taussat M. Molecular mechanisms of Bartonella and mammalian erythrocyte interactions: a review. Front Cell Infect Microbiol. 2018;8:431.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Breitschwerdt EB. Feline bartonellosis and cat scratch disease. Vet Immunol Immunopathol. 2008;123:167-171.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sykes JE, Westropp JL, Kasten RW, Chomel BB. Association between Bartonella species infection and disease in pet cats as determined using serology and culture. J Feline Med Surg. 2010;12:631-636.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pennisi MG, Marsilio F, Hartmann K, et al. Bartonella species infection in cats: ABCD guidelines on prevention and management. J Feline Med Surg. 2013;15:563-569.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abbott RC, Chomel BB, Kasten RW, et al. Experimental and natural infection with Bartonella henselae in domestic cats. Comp Immunol Microbiol Infect Dis. 1997;20:41-51.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fleischman DA, Chomel BB, Kasten RW, et al. Bartonella infection among cats adopted from a San Francisco shelter, revisited. Appl Environ Microbiol. 2015;81:6446-6450.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chomel BB, Boulouis HJ, Petersen H, et al. Prevalence of Bartonella infection in domestic cats in Denmark. Vet Res. 2002;33:205-213.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fabbi M, De Giuli L, Tranquillo M, et al. Prevalence of Bartonella henselae in Italian stray cats: evaluation of serology to assess the risk of transmission of Bartonella to humans. J Clin Microbiol. 2004;42:264-268.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raimundo JM, Guimarães A, Amaro GM, et al. Molecular survey of Bartonella species in shelter cats in Rio De Janeiro: clinical, hematological, and risk factors. Am J Trop Med Hyg. 2019;100:1321-1327.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bergh K, Bevanger L, Hanssen I, Loseth K. Low prevalence of Bartonella henselae infections in Norwegian domestic and feral cats. APMIS. 2002;110:309-314.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kordick DL, Brown TT, Shin K, Breitschwerdt EB. Clinical and pathologic evaluation of chronic Bartonella henselae or Bartonella clarridgeiae infection in cats. J Clin Microbiol. 1999;37:1536-1547.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yamamoto K, Chomel BB, Kasten RW, et al. Experimental infection of domestic cats with Bartonella koehlerae and comparison of protein and DNA profiles with those of other Bartonella species infecting felines. J Clin Microbiol. 2002;40:466-474.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chomel BB, Kasten RW. Bartonellosis, an increasingly recognized zoonosis. J Appl Microbiol. 2010;109:743-750.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chomel BB, Wey AC, Kasten RW, Stacy BA, Labelle P. Fatal case of endocarditis associated with Bartonella henselae type I infection in a domestic cat. J Clin Microbiol. 2003;41:5337-5339.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Perez C, Hummel JB, Keene BW, Maggi RG, Diniz PPVP, Breitschwerdt EB. Successful treatment of Bartonella henselae endocarditis in a cat. J Feline Med Surg. 2010;12:483-486.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Malik R, Barrs VR, Church DB, et al. Vegetative endocarditis in six cats. J Feline Med Surg. 1999;1:171-180.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nakamura RK, Zimmerman SA, Lesser MB. Suspected Bartonella-associated myocarditis and supraventricular tachycardia in a cat. J Vet Cardiol. 2011;13:277-281.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Varanat M, Broadhurst J, Linder KE, Maggi RG, Breitschwerdt EB. Identification of Bartonella henselae in 2 cats with pyogranulomatous myocarditis and diaphragmatic myositis. Vet Pathol. 2012;49:608-611.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guptill L, Slater LN, Wu CC, et al. Evidence of reproductive failure and lack of perinatal transmission of Bartonella henselae in experimentally infected cats. Vet Immunol Immunopathol. 1998;65:177-189.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Breitschwerdt EB, Broadhurst JJ, Cherry NA. Bartonella henselae as a cause of acute-onset febrile illness in cats. JFMS Open Rep. 2015;1:2055116915600454.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Varanat M, Travis A, Lee W, et al. Recurrent osteomyelitis in a cat due to infection with Bartonella vinsonii subsp. berkhoffii genotype II. J Vet Intern Med. 2009;23:1273-1277.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Castel A, Olby NJ, Breitschwerdt EB, Thomas B, Maggi RG, Shelton GD. Co-infection with Bartonella henselae and Sarcocystis sp. in a 6-year-old male neutered domestic longhair cat with progressive multifocal neurological signs. Vet Q. 2019;39:168-173.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Glaus T, Hofmann-Lehmann R, Greene C, Glaus B, Wolfensberger C, Lutz H. Seroprevalence of Bartonella henselae infection and correlation with disease status in cats in Switzerland. J Clin Microbiol. 1997;35:2883-2885.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pearce LK, Radecki SV, Brewer M, Lappin MR. Prevalence of Bartonella henselae antibodies in serum of cats with and without clinical signs of central nervous system disease. J Feline Med Surg. 2006;8:315-320.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ishak AM, Radecki S, Lappin MR. Prevalence of mycoplasma haemofelis, ‘Candidatus mycoplasma haemominutum’, Bartonella species, Ehrlichia species, and Anaplasma phagocytophilum DNA in the blood of cats with anemia. J Feline Med Surg. 2007;9:1-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lappin MR, Breitschwerdt E, Brewer M, Hawley J, Hegarty B, Radecki S. Prevalence of Bartonella species antibodies and Bartonella species DNA in the blood of cats with and without fever. J Feline Med Surg. 2009;11:141-148.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berryessa NA, Johnson LR, Kasten RW, Chomel BB. Microbial culture of blood samples and serologic testing for bartonellosis in cats with chronic rhinosinusitis. J Am Vet Med Assoc. 2008;233:1084-1089.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bayliss DB, Steiner JM, Sucholdolski JS, et al. Serum feline pancreatic lipase immunoreactivity concentration and seroprevalences of antibodies against toxoplasma gondii and Bartonella species in client-owned cats. J Feline Med Surg. 2009;11:663-667.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Breitschwerdt EB, Kordick DL. Bartonella infection in animals: carriership, reservoir potential, pathogenicity, and zoonotic potential for human infection. Clin Microbiol Rev. 2000;13:428-438.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Drut A, Bublot I, Breitschwerdt EB, Chabanne L, Vayssier-Taussat M, Cadoré JL. Comparative microbiological features of Bartonella henselae infection in a dog with fever of unknown origin and granulomatous lymphadenitis. Med Microbiol Immunol. 2014;203:85-91.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Van Audenhove A, Verhoef G, Peetermans WE, et al. Autoimmune haemolytic anaemia triggered by Bartonella henselae infection: a case report. Br J Haematol. 2001;115:924-925.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vieira-Damiani G, Ericson ME, da Silva MN, et al. Bartonella henselae initial infection of mature human erythrocytes observed in real time using bacterial endogenous fluorescence. J Trop Dis Public Health. 2016;4:207.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Donovan TA, Balakrishnan N, Carvalho Barbosa I, McCoy T, Breitschwerdt EB, Fox PR. Bartonella spp. as a possible cause or cofactor of feline endomyocarditis-left ventricular endocardial fibrosis complex. J Comp Pathol. 2018;162:29-42.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sykes JE, Blondeau JM. Pradofloxacin: a novel veterinary fluoroquinolone for treatment of bacterial infections in cats. Vet J. 2014;201:207-214.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Biswas S, Maggi RG, Papich MG, Keil D, Breitschwerdt EB. Comparative activity of pradofloxacin, enrofloxacin, and azithromycin against Bartonella henselae isolates collected from cats and a human. J Clin Microbiol. 2010;48:617-618.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
