<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35383719</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>06</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2332-4260</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Apr</Month>
              <Day>05</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Operative neurosurgery (Hagerstown, Md.)</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Oper Neurosurg (Hagerstown)</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Endoscopic Endonasal Approach for Suprasellar Mature Teratoma in Growing Teratoma Syndrome: 2-Dimensional Operative Video.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1227/ons.0000000000000166</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Intracranial growing teratoma syndrome is a rare phenomenon characterized by enlargement of a germ cell tumor during or after adjuvant therapy despite normalization of tumor markers.1,2 It has been suggested that chemotherapy acts on the nonteratomatous components or induces differentiation of the immature germ cells to mature teratomatous phenotype.3 An 8-year-old boy presented with headache, emesis, and blurry vision. Neuroimaging revealed hydrocephalus with multiple central nervous system masses: pineal gland, suprasellar region, and spine (T8). Elevated serum and cerebrospinal fluid levels of alpha-fetoprotein and beta-human chorionic gonadotropin were found. A ventriculoperitoneal shunt was placed. Despite chemotherapy and decreasing tumor markers, the pineal mass rapidly enlarged, and the patient became somnolent. He underwent microsurgical resection with the diagnosis of mixed germ cell tumor. During his second chemotherapy cycle, the patient endorsed worsening vision and panhypopituitarism. Imaging demonstrated enlargement and honeycomb appearance of the suprasellar mass. The patient and family consented to the procedure, and an endoscopic endonasal approach was performed to access the retroinfundibular region. Removal of the nonfunctional pituitary gland and dorsum sellae was performed. Careful dissection of the tumor from the optic apparatus, hypothalamus, and perforating arteries allowed total resection. Reconstruction with fascia lata and nasoseptal flap was performed. Mature teratoma was found histologically. Postoperative course was complicated by flap hemorrhage resolved by surgical revision. Postoperative imaging showed complete resection. The patient was discharged without other complications and was making excellent recovery. To the best of our knowledge, this is the first reported case of hypothalamic intracranial growing teratoma syndrome successfully treated using an endoscopic endonasal approach.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © Congress of Neurological Surgeons 2022. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Vigo</LastName>
            <ForeName>Vera</ForeName>
            <Initials>V</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, Stanford University School of Medicine, Stanford, California, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Prolo</LastName>
            <ForeName>Laura M</ForeName>
            <Initials>LM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, Stanford University School of Medicine, Stanford, California, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nunez</LastName>
            <ForeName>Maximiliano A</ForeName>
            <Initials>MA</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, Stanford University School of Medicine, Stanford, California, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nayak</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jayakar V</ForeName>
            <Initials>JV</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Otolaryngology-Head and Neck Surgery, Stanford University School of Medicine, Stanford, California, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Fernandez-Miranda</LastName>
            <ForeName>Juan C</ForeName>
            <Initials>JC</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, Stanford University School of Medicine, Stanford, California, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>04</Month>
          <Day>05</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Oper Neurosurg (Hagerstown)</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101635417</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2332-4252</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
          <Hour>9</Hour>
          <Minute>10</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35383719</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1227/ons.0000000000000166</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">01787389-990000000-00162</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Michaiel G, Strother D, Gottardo N, et al. Intracranial growing teratoma syndrome (iGTS): an international case series and review of the literature. J Neurooncol. 2020;147(3):721-730.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim CY, Choi JW, Lee JY, et al. Intracranial growing teratoma syndrome: clinical characteristics and treatment strategy. J Neurooncol. 2011;101(1):109-115.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moiyadi A, Jalali R, Kane SV. Intracranial growing teratoma syndrome following radiotherapy—an unusually fulminant course. Acta Neurochir (Wien). 2010;152(1):137-142.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
