<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35384141</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>12</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>12</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1523-5378</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>27</Volume>
            <Issue>3</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Helicobacter</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Helicobacter</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Gastric organoids: Advancing the study of H. pylori pathogenesis and inflammation.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e12891</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e12891</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/hel.12891</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>For decades, traditional in vitro and in vivo models used for the study of Helicobacter pylori infection have relied heavily on the use of gastric cancer cell lines and rodents. Major challenges faced by these methods have been the inability to study cancer initiation in already cancerous cell lines, and the difficulty in translating results obtained in animal models due to genetic differences. These challenges have prevented a thorough understanding of the pathogenesis of disease and slowed the development of cancer therapies and a suitable vaccine against the pathogen. In recent years, the development of gastric organoids has provided great advantages over the traditional in vivo and in vitro models due to their similarities to the human stomach in vivo, their ease of use, and the capacity for long-term culture. This review discusses the advantages and limitations of existing in vivo and in vitro models of H. pylori infection, and how gastric organoids have been applied to study H. pylori pathogenesis, with a focus on how the pathogen interacts with the gastric epithelium, inflammatory processes, epithelial repair, and cancer initiation. The potential applications of organoids to address more complex questions on the role of hormones, vaccine-induced immunity are also discussed.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Authors. Helicobacter published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Idowu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sulaimon</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8474-698X</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>STEM College, RMIT University, Melbourne, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bertrand</LastName>
            <ForeName>Paul P</ForeName>
            <Initials>PP</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1122-2306</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>STEM College, RMIT University, Melbourne, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Walduck</LastName>
            <ForeName>Anna K</ForeName>
            <Initials>AK</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9624-4370</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>STEM College, RMIT University, Melbourne, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>04</Month>
          <Day>05</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Helicobacter</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9605411</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1083-4389</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005753" MajorTopicYN="N">Gastric Mucosa</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016481" MajorTopicYN="Y">Helicobacter Infections</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016480" MajorTopicYN="Y">Helicobacter pylori</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007249" MajorTopicYN="N">Inflammation</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009940" MajorTopicYN="N">Organoids</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013270" MajorTopicYN="N">Stomach</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013274" MajorTopicYN="Y">Stomach Neoplasms</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">
Helicobacter pylori
</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">in vitro models</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">organoid</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
          <Hour>9</Hour>
          <Minute>14</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35384141</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/hel.12891</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Torre LA, Bray F, Siegel RL, Ferlay J, Lortet-Tieulent J, Jemal A. Global Cancer Statistics, 2012. CA Cancer J Clin. 2015;65(2):87-108. doi:10.3322/caac.21262</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim J, Koo BK, Knoblich JA. Human organoids: model systems for human biology and medicine. Nat Rev Mol Cell Biol. 2020;21:571-584. doi:10.1038/s41580-020-0259-3</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dutta D, Clevers H. Organoid culture systems to study host-pathogen interactions. Curr Opin Immunol. 2017;48:15-22. doi:10.1016/j.coi.2017.07.012</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Graham DY, Opekun AR, Osato MS, et al. Challenge model for Helicobacter pylori infection in human volunteers. Gut. 2004;53:1235-1243. doi:10.1136/gut.2003.037499</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sutton P, Boag JM. Status of vaccine research and development for Helicobacter pylori. Vaccine. 2019;37(50):7295-7299. doi:10.1016/j.vaccine.2018.01.001</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Walduck A, Raghavan S. Immunity and vaccine development against Helicobacter pylori. In: Kamiya S, Backert S, eds. Helicobacter pylori in Human Diseases. Advances in Experimental Medicine and Biology. Vol 1149. Springer, Cham; 2019:1-19. doi:10.1007/5584_2019_370</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kostic AD, Howitt MR, Garrett WS. Exploring host-microbiota interactions in animal models and humans. Genes Dev. 2013;27(7):701-718. doi:10.1101/gad.212522.112</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaparakis M, Laurie KL, Wijburg O, et al. CD4+ CD25+ regulatory T cells modulate the T-cell and antibody responses in Helicobacter-Infected BALB/c mice. Infect Immun. 2006;74(6):3519-3529. doi:10.1128/IAI.01314-05</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nedrud JG, Czinn SJ, Ding H, et al. Lack of genetic influence on the innate inflammatory response to Helicobacter infection of the gastric mucosa. Front Immunol. 2012;3:181. doi:10.3389/fimmu.2012.00181</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Toller IM, Hitzler I, Sayi A, Mueller A. Prostaglandin E2 prevents helicobacter-induced gastric preneoplasia and facilitates persistent infection in a mouse model. Gastroenterology. 2010;138(4):1455-1467.e4. doi:10.1053/j.gastro.2009.12.006</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schlaermann P, Toelle B, Berger H, et al. A novel human gastric primary cell culture system for modelling Helicobacter pylori infection in vitro. Gut. 2016;65(2):202-213. doi:10.1136/gutjnl-2014-307949</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rourke JLO, Lee A. Animal models of Helicobacter pylori infection and disease. Microbes Infect. 2003;5(8):741-748. doi:10.1016/S1286-4579(03)00123-0</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Noto JM, Gaddy JA, Lee JY, et al. Iron deficiency accelerates Helicobacter pylori-induced carcinogenesis in rodents and humans. J Clin Invest. 2013;123:479. doi:10.1172/JCI64373</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Backert S, Haas R, Gerhard M, Naumann M. The helicobacter pylori type IV secretion system encoded by the cag pathogenicity Island: Architecture, function, and signaling. In: Backert S, Backert E, Grohmann E, eds. Type IV Secretion in Gram-Negative and Gram-Positive Bacteria. Current Topics in Microbiology and Immunology. Current Topics in Microbiology and Immunology. Vol 413. Springer, Cham; 2017:187-220. doi:10.1007/978-3-319-75241-9_8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sgouras D, Tegtmeyer N, Wessler S. Activity and functional importance of Helicobacter pylori virulence factors. Adv Exp Med Biol. 2019;1149:35-56. doi:10.1007/5584_2019_358</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kwok T, Zabler D, Urman S, et al. Helicobacter exploits integrin for type IV secretion and kinase activation. Nature. 2007;449:862-866. doi:10.1038/nature06187</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boxberger HJ, Sessler MJ, Grausam MC, Becker HD, Meyer TF. Isolation and culturing of highly polarized primary epithelial cells from normal human stomach (antrum) as spheroid-like vesicles. Methods Cell Sci. 1997;19(3):169-178. doi:10.1023/A:1009751913391</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Richter-Dahlfors A, Heczko U, Meloche RM, Finlay BB, Buchan AMJ. Helicobacter pylori-infected human antral primary cell cultures: Effect on gastrin cell function. Am J Physiol - Gastrointest Liver Physiol. 1998;275(3 38-3):393-401. doi:10.1152/ajpgi.1998.275.3.g393</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ootani A, Toda S, Fujimoto K, Sugihara H. An air-liquid interface promotes the differentiation of gastric surface mucous cells (GSM06) in culture. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2000;271(3):741-746. doi:10.1006/BBRC.2000.2673</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lau HCH, Kranenburg O, Xiao H, Yu J. Organoid models of gastrointestinal cancers in basic and translational research. Nat Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2020;17(4):203-222. doi:10.1038/s41575-019-0255-2</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aguilar C, Alves da Silva M, Saraiva M, et al. Organoids as host models for infection biology - a review of methods. Exp Mol Med. 2021;53:1471-1482. doi:10.1038/s12276-021-00629-4</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dang J, Tiwari SK, Lichinchi G, et al. Zika virus depletes neural progenitors in human cerebral organoids through activation of the innate immune receptor TLR3. Cell Stem Cell. 2016;19(2):258-265. doi:10.1016/j.stem.2016.04.014</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garcez PP, Loiola EC, Madeiro da Costa R, et al. Zika virus impairs growth in human neurospheres and brain organoids. Science. 2016;352(6287):816-818. doi:10.1126/science.aaf6116</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ramani S, Atmar RL, Estes MK. Epidemiology of human noroviruses and updates on vaccine development. Curr Opin Gastroenterol. 2014;30(1):25-33. doi:10.1097/MOG.0000000000000022</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dekkers JF, Berkers G, Kruisselbrink E, et al. Characterizing responses to CFTR-modulating drugs using rectal organoids derived from subjects with cystic fibrosis. Sci Transl Med. 2016;8(344):344RA84. doi:10.1126/scitranslmed.aad8278</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berkers G, van Mourik P, Vonk AM, et al. Rectal organoids enable personalized treatment of cystic fibrosis. Cell Rep. 2019;26(7):1701-1708.e3. doi:10.1016/j.celrep.2019.01.068</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alzeeb G, Metges J-P, Corcos L, Le Jossic-Corcos C. Three-dimensional culture systems in gastric cancer research. Cancers (Basel). 2020;12(10):1-20. doi:10.3390/cancers12102800</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Traulsen J, Zagami C, Daddi AA, Boccellato F. Molecular modelling of the gastric barrier response, from infection to carcinogenesis. Best Pract Res Clin Gastroenterol. 2021;50-51:101737. doi:10.1016/J.BPG.2021.101737</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Idowu S, Bertrand PP, Walduck AK. Homeostasis and cancer initiation: Organoids as models to study the initiation of gastric cancer. Int J Mol Sci. 2022;23(5):2790. doi:10.3390/ijms23052790</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eicher AK, Berns HM, Wells JM. Translating developmental principles to generate human gastric organoids. Cell Mol Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2018;5(3):353-363. doi:10.1016/j.jcmgh.2017.12.014</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pompaiah M, Bartfeld S. Gastric organoids: An emerging model system to study Helicobacter pylori pathogenesis. In: Tegtmeyer N, Backert S, eds. Molecular Pathogenesis and Signal Transduction by Helicobacter pylori. Current Topics in Microbiology and Immunology. Vol 400. Springer, Cham; 2017:149-168. doi:10.1007/978-3-319-50520-6_7</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kurokawa K, Hayakawa Y, Koike K. Plasticity of intestinal epithelium: Stem cell niches and regulatory signals. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22(1):357. doi:10.3390/ijms22010357</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McCracken KW, Howell JC, Spence JR, Wells JM. Generating human intestinal tissue from pluripotent stem cells in vitro. Nat Protoc. 2011;6(12):1920-1928. doi:10.1038/nprot.2011.410</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Spence JR, Mayhew CN, Rankin SA, et al. Directed differentiation of human pluripotent stem cells into intestinal tissue in vitro. Nature. 2011;470(7332):105-109. doi:10.1038/nature09691</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McCracken KW, Catá EM, Crawford CM, et al. Modelling human development and disease in pluripotent stem-cell-derived gastric organoids. Nature. 2014;516:400-404.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sigal M, Logan CY, Kapalczynska M, et al. Stromal R-spondin orchestrates gastric epithelial stem cells and gland homeostasis. Nature. 2017;548:451-455. doi:10.1038/nature23642</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Demitrack ES, Gifford GB, Keeley TM, et al. Notch signaling regulates gastric antral LGR5 stem cell function. EMBO J. 2015;34(20):2522-2536. doi:10.15252/embj.201490583</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wölffling S, Daddi AA, Imai-Matsushima A, et al. EGF and BMPs govern differentiation and patterning in human gastric glands. Gastroenterology. 2021;161(2):623-636.e16. doi:10.1053/j.gastro.2021.04.062</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stange D, Koo B-K, Huch M, et al. Differentiated Troy+ chief cells act as reserve stem cells to generate all lineages of the stomach epithelium. Cell. 2013;155(2):357. doi:10.1016/j.cell.2013.09.008</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bartfeld S, Bayram T, Van De Wetering M, et al. In vitro expansion of human gastric epithelial stem cells and their responses to bacterial infection. Gastroenterology. 2015;148(1):126-136.e6. doi:10.1053/j.gastro.2014.09.042</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boccellato F, Woelffling S, Imai-Matsushima A, et al. Polarised epithelial monolayers of the gastric mucosa reveal insights into mucosal homeostasis and defence against infection. Gut. 2019;68(3):400-413. doi:10.1136/gutjnl-2017-314540</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bartfeld S, Clevers H. Organoids as model for infectious diseases: culture of human and murine stomach organoids and microinjection of Helicobacter Pylori. J vis Exp. 2015;105:53359. doi:10.3791/53359</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Broda TR, McCracken KW, Wells JM. Generation of human antral and fundic gastric organoids from pluripotent stem cells. Nat Protoc. 2019;14(1):28-50. doi:10.1038/s41596-018-0080-z</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Choudhury D, Ashok A, Naing MW. Commercialization of organoids. Trends Mol Med. 2020;26(3):245-249. doi:10.1016/j.molmed.2019.12.002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Urbischek M, Rannikmae H, Foets T, Ravn K, Hyvönen M, de la Roche M. Organoid culture media formulated with growth factors of defined cellular activity. Sci Rep. 2019;9(1):6193. doi:10.1038/s41598-019-42604-0</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barker N, Huch M, Kujala P, et al. Lgr5+ve stem cells drive self-renewal in the stomach and build long-lived gastric units in vitro. Cell Stem Cell. 2010;6(1):25-36. doi:10.1016/j.stem.2009.11.013</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bertaux-Skeirik N, Feng R, Schumacher MA, et al. CD44 plays a functional role in Helicobacter pylori-induced epithelial cell proliferation. PLoS Pathog. 2015;11(2):e1004663. doi:10.1371/journal.ppat.1004663</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huang J, Sweeney E, Sigal M, et al. Chemodetection and destruction of host urea allows Helicobacter pylori to locate the epithelium. Cell Host Microbe. 2015;18(2):147-156. doi:10.1016/j.chom.2015.07.002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hanyu H, Engevik KA, Matthis AL, Ottemann KM, Montrose MH, Aihara E. Helicobacter pylori uses the TlpB receptor to sense sites of gastric injury. Infect Immun. 2019;87(9): doi:10.1128/IAI.00202-19</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Uotani T, Murakami K, Uchida T, et al. Changes of tight junction and interleukin-8 expression using a human gastroid monolayer model of Helicobacter pylori infection. Helicobacter. 2019;24(3):1-12. doi:10.1111/hel.12583</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brandt S, Kwok T, Hartig R, Kö W, Backert S. NF-B activation and potentiation of proinflammatory responses by the Helicobacter pylori CagA protein. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2005;102(26):9300-9305. www.pnas.orgcgidoi10.1073pnas.0409873102</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Backert S, Naumann M. What a disorder: Proinflammatory signaling pathways induced by Helicobacter pylori. Trends Microbiol. 2010;18(11):479-486. doi:10.1016/j.tim.2010.08.003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miehlke S, Hackelsberger A, Meining A, et al. Severe expression of corpus gastritis is characteristic in gastric cancer patients infected with Helicobacter pylori. Br J Cancer. 1998;78(2):263-266.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kayisoglu Ö, Schlegel N, Bartfeld S. Gastrointestinal epithelial innate immunity-regionalization and organoids as new model. J Mol Med. 2021;99(4):517-530. doi:10.1007/s00109-021-02043-9</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morey P, Pfannkuch L, Pang E, et al. Helicobacter pylori depletes cholesterol in gastric glands to prevent interferon gamma signaling and escape the inflammatory response. Gastroenterology. 2018;154(5):1391-1404.e9. doi:10.1053/J.GASTRO.2017.12.008</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sebrell TA, Hashimi M, Sidar B, et al. A novel gastric spheroid co-culture model reveals chemokine-dependent recruitment of human dendritic cells to the gastric epithelium. Cell Mol Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2019;8(1):157-171.e3. doi:10.1016/j.jcmgh.2019.02.010</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tran CT, Garcia M, Garnier M, Burucoa C, Bodet C. Inflammatory signaling pathways induced by Helicobacter pylori in primary human gastric epithelial cells. Innate Immun. 2017;23(2):165-174. doi:10.1177/1753425916681077</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mejías-Luque R, Zöller J, Anderl F, et al. Lymphotoxin β receptor signalling executes Helicobacter pylori-driven gastric inflammation in a T4SS-dependent manner. Gut. 2017;66(8):1369-1381. doi:10.1136/gutjnl-2015-310783</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cook KW, Letley DP, Ingram RJM, et al. CCL20/CCR6-mediated migration of regulatory T cells to the Helicobacter pylori-infected human gastric mucosa. Gut. 2014;63(10):1550-1559. doi:10.1136/gutjnl-2013-306253</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hor Y, Voon D-C, Koo J, et al. A role for RUNX3 in inflammation-induced expression of IL23A in gastric epithelial cells. Cell Rep. 2014;8(1):50-58. doi:10.1016/j.celrep.2014.06.003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schumacher MA, Donnelly JM, Engevik AC, et al. gastric sonic hedgehog acts as a macrophage chemoattractant during the immune response to Helicobacter pylori. Gastroenterology. 2012;142(5):1150-1159.e6. doi:10.1053/J.GASTRO.2012.01.029</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schumacher M, Feng R, Aihara E, et al. Helicobacter pylori-induced Sonic Hedgehog expression is regulated by NFκB pathway activation: The use of a novel in vitro model to study epithelial response to infection. Helicobacter. 2015;20(1):19-28. doi:10.1111/hel.12152</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schumacher MA, Aihara E, Feng R, et al. The use of murine-derived fundic organoids in studies of gastric physiology. J Physiol. 2015;593(8):1809-1827. doi:10.1113/jphysiol.2014.283028</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sigal M, Rothenberg ME, Logan CY, et al. Helicobacter pylori activates and expands Lgr5+ stem cells through direct colonization of the gastric glands. Gastroenterology. 2015;148(7):1392-1404.e21. doi:10.1053/j.gastro.2015.02.049</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Howitt CR. ChePep controls Helicobacter pylori infection of the gastric glands and chemotaxis in the Epsilonproteobacteria. MBio. 2011;2(4):98-109. doi:10.1128/mBio.00098-11</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bronte-Tinkew DM, Terebiznik M, Franco A, et al. Helicobacter pylori cytotoxin-associated gene a activates the signal transducer and activator of transcription 3 pathway in vitro and in vivo. Cancer Res. 2009;69(2):632-639. doi:10.1158/0008-5472.CAN-08-1191</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ernst M, Najdovska M, Grail D, et al. STAT3 and STAT1 mediate IL-11-dependent and inflammation-associated gastric tumorigenesis in gp130 receptor mutant mice. J Clin Invest. 2008;118(5):1727-1738. doi:10.1172/JCI34944</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhu S, Soutto M, Chen Z, et al. Activation of IGF1R by DARPP-32 promotes STAT3 signaling in gastric cancer cells. Oncogene. 2019;38(29):5805-5816. doi:10.1038/s41388-019-0843-1</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ishii Y, Shibata W, Sugimori M, et al. Activation of signal transduction and activator of transcription 3 signaling contributes to helicobacter-associated gastric epithelial proliferation and inflammation. Gastroenterol Res Pract. 2018;2018:1-9. doi: 10.1155/2018/9050715</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Osaki LH, Bockerstett KA, Wong CF, et al. Interferon-γ directly induces gastric epithelial cell death and is required for progression to metaplasia. J Pathol. 2019;247(4):513-523. doi:10.1002/path.5214</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Correa P. A Human model of gastric carcinogenesis. Cancer Res. 1988;48(13):3554-3560.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reissfelder C, Stamova S, Gossmann C, et al. Tumor-specific cytotoxic T lymphocyte activity determines colorectal cancer patient prognosis. J Clin Invest. 2015;125(2):739-751. doi:10.1172/JCI74894</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Holokai L, Chakrabarti J, Broda T, et al. Increased programmed death-ligand 1 is an early epithelial cell response to Helicobacter pylori infection. PLoS Pathog. 2019;15(1):e1007468. doi:10.1371/journal.ppat.1007468</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bauer M, Nascakova Z, Mihai A-I, et al. The ALPK1/TIFA/NF-κB axis links a bacterial carcinogen to R-loop-induced replication stress. Nat Commun. 2020;11(1):5117. doi: 10.1038/s41467-020-18857-z</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sayed IM, Sahan AZ, Venkova T, et al. Helicobacter pylori infection downregulates the DNA glycosylase NEIL2, resulting in increased genome damage and inflammation in gastric epithelial cells. J Biol Chem. 2020;295(32):11082-11098. doi:10.1074/jbc.ra119.009981</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chakraborty A, Wakamiya M, Venkova-Canova T, et al. Neil2-null mice accumulate oxidized DNA bases in the transcriptionally active sequences of the genome and are susceptible to innate inflammation. J Biol Chem. 2015;290(41):24636-24648. doi:10.1074/jbc.M115.658146</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nanki K, Toshimitsu K, Takano AI, et al. Divergent routes toward Wnt and R-spondin niche independency during human gastric carcinogenesis. Cell. 2018;174(4):856-869.e17. doi:10.1016/j.cell.2018.07.027</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Engevik KA, Hanyu H, Matthis AL, et al. Trefoil factor 2 activation of CXCR4 requires calcium mobilization to drive epithelial repair in gastric organoids. J Physiol. 2019;597(10):2673-2690. doi:10.1113/JP277259</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ohki J, Sakashita A, Aihara E, et al. Comparative analysis of enteroendocrine cells and their hormones between mouse intestinal organoids and native tissues. Biosci Biotechnol Biochem. 2020;84(5):936-942. doi:10.1080/09168451.2020.1713043</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alessandro Paoluzi O, Del Vecchio BG, Caruso R, et al. Helicobacter pylori infection associates with a mucosal downregulation of ghrelin, negative regulator of Th1-cell responses. Helicobacter. 2013;18(6):406-412. doi:10.1111/hel.12065</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ichikawa H, Sugimoto M, Sakao Y, et al. Relationship between ghrelin, Helicobacter pylori and gastric mucosal atrophy in hemodialysis patients. World J Gastroenterol. 2016;22(47):10440-10449. doi:10.3748/wjg.v22.i47.10440</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tsuruta T, Saito S, Osaki Y, Hamada A, Aoki-Yoshida A, Sonoyama K. Organoids as an ex vivo model for studying the serotonin system in the murine small intestine and colon epithelium. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2016;474(1):161-167. doi:10.1016/J.BBRC.2016.03.165</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sheng W, Malagola E, Nienhüser H, et al. Hypergastrinemia expands gastric ECL cells through CCK2R+ progenitor cells via ERK activation. Cell Mol Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2020;10(2):434-449.e1. doi:10.1016/j.jcmgh.2020.04.008</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Walduck AK, Becher D, Cell CDT, Leptin RCDT. CD4 + T reg and the prospects for vaccination against H. pylori infection. Front Immunol. 2012;3(October):1-8. doi:10.3389/fimmu.2012.00316</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Becher D, Deutscher ME, Simpfendorfer KR, et al. Local recall responses in the stomach involving reduced regulation and expanded help mediate vaccine-induced protection against Helicobacter pylori in mice. Eur J Immunol. 2010;40(10):2778-2790. doi:10.1002/eji.200940219</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>afsi N, Voland P, Schwendy S, et al. Human dendritic cells respond to Helicobacter pylori promoting Nk Cell and Th1-effector responses in vitro. J Immunol. 2004;173(2):1249-1257. doi:10.4049/jimmunol.173.2.1249</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Suarez G, Romero-Gallo J, Piazuelo MB, et al. Nod1 imprints inflammatory and carcinogenic responses toward the gastric pathogen Helicobacter pylori. Cancer Res. 2019;79(7):1600-1611. doi:10.1158/0008-5472.CAN-18-2651</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Walduck A, Andersen LP, Raghavan S. Inflammation, immunity, and vaccines for Helicobacter pylori infection. Helicobacter. 2015;20:17-25. doi:10.1111/hel.12252</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Buti L, Ruiz-Puig C, Sangberg D, et al. CagA-ASPP2 complex mediates loss of cell polarity and favors H. Pylori colonization of human gastric organoids. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2020;117(5):2645-2655. doi:10.1073/pnas.1908787117</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nam KT, Lee H, Sousa JF, et al. Mature chief cells are cryptic progenitors for metaplasia in the stomach. Gastroenterology. 2010;139(6):2028-2037.e9. doi:10.1053/j.gastro.2010.09.005</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Petersen CP, Weis VG, Nam KT, Sousa JF, Fingleton B, Goldenring JR. Macrophages promote progression of spasmolytic polypeptide-expressing metaplasia after acute loss of parietal cells. Gastroenterology. 2014;146(7):1727-1738.e8. doi:10.1053/j.gastro.2014.02.007</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Keilberg D, Steele N, Fan S, Yang C, Zavros Y, Ottemann KM. Gastric metabolomics detects Helicobacter pylori correlated loss of numerous metabolites in both the corpus and antrum. Infect Immun. 2021;89(2):e00690-20. doi: 10.1128/IAI.00690-20</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sigal M, Reinés MDM, Müllerke S, et al. R-spondin-3 induces secretory, antimicrobial Lgr5 + cells in the stomach. Nat Cell Biol. 2019;21:812-823. doi:10.1038/s41556-019-0339-9</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eicher AK, Kechele DO, Sundaram N, et al. Functional human gastrointestinal organoids can be engineered from three primary germ layers derived separately from pluripotent stem cells. Cell Stem Cell. 2022;29(1):36-51.e6. doi:10.1016/j.stem.2021.10.010</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Seidlitz T, Merker SR, Rothe A, et al. Human gastric cancer modelling using organoids. Gut. 2019;68(2):207-217. doi:10.1136/gutjnl-2017-314549</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jones BC, Calà G, De Coppi P, Giobbe GG. Paediatric gastric organoids as a tool for disease modelling and clinical translation. Pediatr Surg Int. 2021;37:317-324. doi:10.1007/s00383-020-04821-x</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
