<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35393968</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>11</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>18</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1538-6899</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>28</Volume>
            <Issue>2</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Apr</Month>
              <Day>01</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Continuum (Minneapolis, Minn.)</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Continuum (Minneap Minn)</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Update on Antiseizure Medications 2022.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>500</StartPage>
          <EndPage>535</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>500-535</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1212/CON.0000000000001104</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The article "Update on Antiseizure Medications 2022" by Dr Abou-Khalil was first published in the February 2016 Epilepsy issue of Continuum: Lifelong Learning in Neurology as "Antiepileptic Drugs," and at the request of the Editor-in-Chief was updated by Dr Abou-Khalil for the 2019 issue and again for this issue.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022 American Academy of Neurology.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Abou-Khalil</LastName>
            <ForeName>Bassel W</ForeName>
            <Initials>BW</Initials>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Continuum (Minneap Minn)</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9509333</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1080-2371</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000927">Anticonvulsants</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000927" MajorTopicYN="Y">Anticonvulsants</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004827" MajorTopicYN="Y">Epilepsy</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <OtherAbstract Type="plain-language-summary" Language="eng">
        <AbstractText>This article is an update from the article on antiepileptic drug therapy (now referred to as antiseizure medication therapy) published in the two previous Continuum issues on epilepsy and is intended to cover the vast majority of agents currently available to the neurologist in the management of patients with epilepsy. Treatment of epilepsy starts with antiseizure medication monotherapy. Knowledge of the spectrum of efficacy, clinical pharmacology, and modes of use for individual antiseizure medications is essential for optimal treatment for epilepsy. This article addresses antiseizure medications individually, focusing on key pharmacokinetic characteristics, indications, and modes of use. Since the most recent version of this article was published, two new antiseizure medications, cenobamate and fenfluramine, have been approved by the US Food and Drug Administration (FDA), and the indications of some approved medications have been expanded. Older antiseizure medications are effective but have tolerability and pharmacokinetic disadvantages. Several newer antiseizure medications have undergone comparative trials demonstrating efficacy equal to and tolerability at least equal to or better than older antiseizure medications as first-line therapy for focal epilepsy. The list includes lamotrigine, oxcarbazepine, levetiracetam, topiramate, zonisamide, and lacosamide. Pregabalin was found to be less effective than lamotrigine. Lacosamide, pregabalin, and eslicarbazepine have undergone successful trials of conversion to monotherapy for focal epilepsy. Other newer antiseizure medications with a variety of mechanisms of action are suitable for adjunctive therapy. Antiseizure medications marketed since 2016 have benefited from the FDA policy allowing a drug’s efficacy as adjunctive therapy in adults to be extrapolated to efficacy in monotherapy. In addition, efficacy in adults can be extrapolated for efficacy in children 4 years of age and older. Both extrapolations require data demonstrating that an antiseizure medication has equivalent pharmacokinetics between its original approved use and its extrapolated use. Rational antiseizure medication combinations should avoid antiseizure medications with unfavorable pharmacokinetic interactions or pharmacodynamic interactions related to mechanism of action. Knowledge of antiseizure medication pharmacokinetics, efficacy, and tolerability profiles facilitates the choice of appropriate antiseizure medication therapy for patients with epilepsy.</AbstractText>
        <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022 American Academy of Neurology.</CopyrightInformation>
      </OtherAbstract>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
          <Hour>8</Hour>
          <Minute>47</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35393968</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/CON.0000000000001104</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">00132979-202204000-00013</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tomson T, Battino D, Bonizzoni E. Comparative risk of major congenital malformations with eight different antiepileptic drugs: a prospective cohort study of the EURAP registry. Lancet Neurol 2018;17(6):530–538. doi:10.1016/S1474-4422(18)30107-8</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1474-4422(18)30107-8</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hernandez-Diaz S, Smith CR, Shen A. Comparative safety of antiepileptic drugs during pregnancy. Neurology 2012;78(21):1692–1699. doi:10.1212/WNL.0b013e3182574f39</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0b013e3182574f39</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tomson T, Battino D, Bromley R. Management of epilepsy in pregnancy: a report from the International League Against Epilepsy Task Force on Women and Pregnancy. Epileptic Disord 2019;21(6):497–517. doi:10.1684/epd.2019.1105</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1684/epd.2019.1105</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vajda FJ, Eadie MJ. The clinical pharmacology of traditional antiepileptic drugs. Epileptic Disord 2014;16(4):395–408. doi:10.1684/epd.2014.0704</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1684/epd.2014.0704</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ding D, Zhang Q, Zhou D. Cognitive and mood effects of phenobarbital treatment in people with epilepsy in rural China: a prospective study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2012;83(12):1139–1144. doi:10.1136/jnnp-2012-303042</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp-2012-303042</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Janz D. Epilepsy with impulsive petit mal (juvenile myoclonic epilepsy). Acta Neurol Scand 1985;72(5):449–459. doi:10.1111/j.1600-0404.1985.tb00900.x</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0404.1985.tb00900.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Findley LJ, Cleeves L, Calzetti S. Primidone in essential tremor of the hands and head: a double blind controlled clinical study. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 1985;48(9):911–915. doi:10.1136/jnnp.48.9.911</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp.48.9.911</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mattson RH, Cramer JA, Collins JF. Comparison of carbamazepine, phenobarbital, phenytoin, and primidone in partial and secondarily generalized tonic-clonic seizures. N Engl J Med 1985;313(3):145–151. doi:10.1056/NEJM198507183130303</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJM198507183130303</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arif H, Buchsbaum R, Weintraub D. Comparison and predictors of rash associated with 15 antiepileptic drugs. Neurology 2007;68(20):1701–1709. doi:10.1212/01.wnl.0000261917.83337.db</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/01.wnl.0000261917.83337.db</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ficker DM, Privitera M, Krauss G. Improved tolerability and efficacy in epilepsy patients with extended-release carbamazepine. Neurology 2005;65(4):593–595. doi:10.1212/01.wnl.0000172932.95985.51</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/01.wnl.0000172932.95985.51</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Canger R, Altamura AC, Belvedere O. Conventional vs controlled-release carbamazepine: a multicentre, double-blind, cross-over study. Acta Neurol Scand 1990;82(1):9–13. doi:10.1111/j.1600-0404.1990.tb01579.x</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0404.1990.tb01579.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meador KJ, Loring DW, Ray PG. Differential cognitive and behavioral effects of carbamazepine and lamotrigine. Neurology 2001;56(9):1177–1182. doi:10.1212/wnl.56.9.1177</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/wnl.56.9.1177</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Malow BA, Blaxton TA, Stertz B, Theodore WH. Carbamazepine withdrawal: effects of taper rate on seizure frequency. Neurology 1993;43(11):2280–2284. doi:10.1212/wnl.43.11.2280</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/wnl.43.11.2280</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marciani MG, Gotman J, Andermann F, Olivier A. Patterns of seizure activation after withdrawal of antiepileptic medication. Neurology 1985;35(11):1537–1543. doi:10.1212/wnl.35.11.1537</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/wnl.35.11.1537</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brodie MJ, Overstall PW, Giorgi L. Multicentre, double-blind, randomised comparison between lamotrigine and carbamazepine in elderly patients with newly diagnosed epilepsy. The UK Lamotrigine Elderly Study Group. Epilepsy Res 1999;37(1):81–87. doi:10.1016/s0920-1211(99)00039-x</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0920-1211(99)00039-x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brodie MJ, Richens A, Yuen AW. Double-blind comparison of lamotrigine and carbamazepine in newly diagnosed epilepsy. UK Lamotrigine/Carbamazepine Monotherapy Trial Group. Lancet 1995;345(8948):476–479. doi:10.1016/s0140-6736(95)90581-2</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0140-6736(95)90581-2</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dam M, Ekberg R, Løyning Y. A double-blind study comparing oxcarbazepine and carbamazepine in patients with newly diagnosed, previously untreated epilepsy. Epilepsy Res 1989;3(1):70–76. doi:10.1016/0920-1211(89)90070-3</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0920-1211(89)90070-3</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marson AG, Al-Kharusi AM, Alwaidh M. The SANAD study of effectiveness of carbamazepine, gabapentin, lamotrigine, oxcarbazepine, or topiramate for treatment of partial epilepsy: an unblinded randomised controlled trial. Lancet 2007;369(9566):1000–1015. doi:10.1016/S0140-6736(07)60460-7</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(07)60460-7</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reinikainen KJ, Keranen T, Halonen T. Comparison of oxcarbazepine and carbamazepine: a double-blind study. Epilepsy Res 1987;1(5):284–289. doi:10.1016/0920-1211(87)90003-9</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0920-1211(87)90003-9</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reunanen M, Dam M, Yuen AW. A randomised open multicentre comparative trial of lamotrigine and carbamazepine as monotherapy in patients with newly diagnosed or recurrent epilepsy. Epilepsy Res 1996;23(2):149–155. doi:10.1016/0920-1211(95)00085-2</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0920-1211(95)00085-2</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rowan AJ, Ramsay RE, Collins JF. New onset geriatric epilepsy: a randomized study of gabapentin, lamotrigine, and carbamazepine. Neurology 2005;64(11):1868–1873. doi:10.1212/01.WNL.0000167384.68207.3E</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/01.WNL.0000167384.68207.3E</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baulac M, Patten A, Giorgi L. Long-term safety and efficacy of zonisamide versus carbamazepine monotherapy for treatment of partial seizures in adults with newly diagnosed epilepsy: results of a phase III, randomized, double-blind study. Epilepsia 2014;55(10):1534–1543. doi:10.1111/epi.12749</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.12749</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baulac M, Rosenow F, Toledo M. Efficacy, safety, and tolerability of lacosamide monotherapy versus controlled-release carbamazepine in patients with newly diagnosed epilepsy: a phase 3, randomised, double-blind, non-inferiority trial. Lancet Neurol 2017;16(1):43–54. doi:10.1016/S1474-4422(16)30292-7</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1474-4422(16)30292-7</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brodie MJ, Perucca E, Ryvlin P. Comparison of levetiracetam and controlled-release carbamazepine in newly diagnosed epilepsy. Neurology 2007;68(6):402–408. doi:10.1212/01.wnl.0000252941.50833.4a</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/01.wnl.0000252941.50833.4a</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saetre E, Perucca E, Isojarvi J. An international multicenter randomized double-blind controlled trial of lamotrigine and sustained-release carbamazepine in the treatment of newly diagnosed epilepsy in the elderly. Epilepsia 2007;48(7):1292–1302. doi:10.1111/j.1528-1167.2007.01128.x</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1167.2007.01128.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Trinka E, Ben-Menachem E, Kowacs PA. Efficacy and safety of eslicarbazepine acetate versus controlled-release carbamazepine monotherapy in newly diagnosed epilepsy: a phase III double-blind, randomized, parallel-group, multicenter study. Epilepsia 2018;59(2):479–491. doi:10.1111/epi.13993</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.13993</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berghuis B, Palen J, Haan GJ. Carbamazepine- and oxcarbazepine-induced hyponatremia in people with epilepsy. Epilepsia 2017;58(7):1227–1233. doi:10.1111/epi.13777</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.13777</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dong X, Leppik IE, White J, Rarick J. Hyponatremia from oxcarbazepine and carbamazepine. Neurology 2005;65(12):1976–1978. doi:10.1212/01.wnl.0000188819.45330.90</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/01.wnl.0000188819.45330.90</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Azar NJ, Wright AT, Wang L. Generalized tonic-clonic seizures after acute oxcarbazepine withdrawal. Neurology 2008;70(22. doi:10.1212/01.wnl.0000313152.89906.5a</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/01.wnl.0000313152.89906.5a</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koch MW, Polman SK. Oxcarbazepine versus carbamazepine monotherapy for partial onset seizures. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 2009;4:CD006453. doi:10.1002/14651858.CD006453.pub2</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD006453.pub2</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nolan SJ, Muller M, Tudur Smith C, Marson AG. Oxcarbazepine versus phenytoin monotherapy for epilepsy. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 2013;5:CD003615. doi:10.1002/14651858.CD003615.pub3</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD003615.pub3</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hebeisen S, Pires N, Loureiro AI. Eslicarbazepine and the enhancement of slow inactivation of voltage-gated sodium channels: a comparison with carbamazepine, oxcarbazepine and lacosamide. Neuropharmacology 2015;89:122–135. doi:10.1016/j.neuropharm.2014.09.008</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuropharm.2014.09.008</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nunes T, Rocha JF, Falcão A. Steady-state plasma and cerebrospinal fluid pharmacokinetics and tolerability of eslicarbazepine acetate and oxcarbazepine in healthy volunteers. Epilepsia 2013;54(1):108–116. doi:10.1111/j.1528-1167.2012.03595.x</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1167.2012.03595.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sperling MR, Harvey J, Grinnell T. Efficacy and safety of conversion to monotherapy with eslicarbazepine acetate in adults with uncontrolled partial-onset seizures: a randomized historical-control phase III study based in North America. Epilepsia 2015;56(4):546–555. doi:10.1111/epi.12934</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.12934</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Trinka E, Rocamora R, Chaves J. Long-term efficacy and safety of eslicarbazepine acetate monotherapy for adults with newly diagnosed focal epilepsy: an open-label extension study. Epilepsia 2020;61(10):2129–2141. doi:10.1111/epi.16666</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.16666</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meador KJ, Seliger J, Boyd A. Comparative neuropsychological effects of carbamazepine and eslicarbazepine acetate. Epilepsy Behav 2019;94:151–157. doi:10.1016/j.yebeh.2019.02.034</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yebeh.2019.02.034</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abou-Khalil B, Klein P, Shah A. Tolerability of adjunctive eslicarbazepine acetate according to concomitant lamotrigine or carbamazepine use: a subgroup analysis of three phase III trials in adults with focal (partial-onset) seizures. Epilepsy Res 2018;147:80–86. doi:10.1016/j.eplepsyres.2018.08.011</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eplepsyres.2018.08.011</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pierre-Louis SJ, Brannegan RT, Evans AT. Seizure control and side-effect profile after switching adult epileptic patients from standard to extended-release divalproex sodium. Clin Neurol Neurosurg 2009;111(5):437–441. doi:10.1016/j.clineuro.2008.12.009</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clineuro.2008.12.009</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith MC, Centorrino F, Welge JA, Collins MA. Clinical comparison of extended-release divalproex versus delayed-release divalproex: pooled data analyses from nine trials. Epilepsy Behav 2004;5(5):746–751. doi:10.1016/j.yebeh.2004.07.007</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yebeh.2004.07.007</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Belcastro V, D’Egidio C, Striano P, Verrotti A. Metabolic and endocrine effects of valproic acid chronic treatment. Epilepsy Res 2013;107(1-2):1–8. doi:10.1016/j.eplepsyres.2013.08.016</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eplepsyres.2013.08.016</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verrotti A, Mencaroni E, Cofini M. Valproic acid metabolism and its consequences on sexual functions. Curr Drug Metab 2016;17(6):573–581. doi:10.2174/1389200217666160322143504</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/1389200217666160322143504</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vajda FJ, J O’Brien T, Hitchcock A. Critical relationship between sodium valproate dose and human teratogenicity: results of the Australian register of anti-epileptic drugs in pregnancy. J Clin Neurosci 2004;11(8):854–858. doi:10.1016/j.jocn.2004.05.003</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jocn.2004.05.003</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Christensen J, Gronborg TK, Sorensen MJ. Prenatal valproate exposure and risk of autism spectrum disorders and childhood autism. JAMA 2013;309(16):1696–1703. doi:10.1001/jama.2013.2270</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2013.2270</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meador KJ, Baker GA, Browning N. Fetal antiepileptic drug exposure and cognitive outcomes at age 6 years (NEAD study): a prospective observational study. Lancet Neurol 2013;12(3):244–252. doi:10.1016/S1474-4422(12)70323-X</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1474-4422(12)70323-X</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cohen MJ, Meador KJ, May R. Fetal antiepileptic drug exposure and learning and memory functioning at 6 years of age: the NEAD prospective observational study. Epilepsy Behav 2019;92:154–164. doi:10.1016/j.yebeh.2018.12.031</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yebeh.2018.12.031</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marson AG, Al-Kharusi AM, Alwaidh M. The SANAD study of effectiveness of valproate, lamotrigine, or topiramate for generalised and unclassifiable epilepsy: an unblinded randomised controlled trial. Lancet 2007;369(9566):1016–1026. doi:10.1016/S0140-6736(07)60461-9</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(07)60461-9</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Glauser TA, Cnaan A, Shinnar S. Ethosuximide, valproic acid, and lamotrigine in childhood absence epilepsy: initial monotherapy outcomes at 12 months. Epilepsia 2013;54(1):141–155. doi:10.1111/epi.12028</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.12028</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Glauser TA, Cnaan A, Shinnar S. Ethosuximide, valproic acid, and lamotrigine in childhood absence epilepsy. N Engl J Med 2010;362(9):790–799. doi:10.1056/NEJMoa0902014</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa0902014</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mattson RH, Cramer JA, Collins JF. A comparison of valproate with carbamazepine for the treatment of complex partial seizures and secondarily generalized tonic-clonic seizures in adults. The Department of Veterans Affairs Epilepsy Cooperative Study No. 264 Group. N Engl J Med 1992;327(11):765–771. doi:10.1056/NEJM199209103271104</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJM199209103271104</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brigo F, Igwe SC, Lattanzi S. Ethosuximide, sodium valproate or lamotrigine for absence seizures in children and adolescents. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 2021;1:CD003032. doi:10.1002/14651858.CD003032.pub5</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD003032.pub5</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Riss J, Cloyd J, Gates J, Collins S. Benzodiazepines in epilepsy: pharmacology and pharmacokinetics. Acta Neurol Scand 2008;118(2):69–86. doi:10.1111/j.1600-0404.2008.01004.x</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0404.2008.01004.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jamil A, Levinson N, Gelfand M, Hill C, Khankhanian P, Davis K. Efficacy and tolerability of clobazam in adults with drug-refractory epilepsy. Neurol Clin Pract 2021;11(5):e669–e676. doi:10.1212/CPJ.0000000000000992</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/CPJ.0000000000000992</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gidal BE, DeCerce J, Bockbrader HN. Gabapentin bioavailability: effect of dose and frequency of administration in adult patients with epilepsy. Epilepsy Res 1998;31(2):91–99. doi:10.1016/s0920-1211(98)00020-5</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0920-1211(98)00020-5</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Perucca E, Gram L, Avanzini G, Dulac O. Antiepileptic drugs as a cause of worsening seizures. Epilepsia 1998;39(1):5–17. doi:10.1111/j.1528-1157.1998.tb01268.x</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1157.1998.tb01268.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kwan P, Brodie MJ, Kalviainen R. Efficacy and safety of pregabalin versus lamotrigine in patients with newly diagnosed partial seizures: a phase 3, double-blind, randomised, parallel-group trial. Lancet Neurol 2011;10(10):881–890. doi:10.1016/S1474-4422(11)70154-5</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1474-4422(11)70154-5</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>French J, Kwan P, Fakhoury T. Pregabalin monotherapy in patients with partial-onset seizures: a historical-controlled trial. Neurology 2014;82(7):590–597. doi:10.1212/WNL.0000000000000119</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000000119</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hirsch LJ, Weintraub D, Du Y. Correlating lamotrigine serum concentrations with tolerability in patients with epilepsy. Neurology 2004;63(6):1022–1026. doi:10.1212/01.wnl.0000138424.33979.0c</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/01.wnl.0000138424.33979.0c</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ramey P, Osborn M, Abou-Khalil B. Conversion from immediate-release to extended-release lamotrigine improves seizure control. Epilepsy Res 2014;108(9):1637–1641. doi:10.1016/j.eplepsyres.2014.08.004</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eplepsyres.2014.08.004</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ramey P, Osborn MR, Lowen KM. Unexplained spikes in lamotrigine serum concentration: nonlinear elimination?Acta Neurol Scand 2017;135(2):240–246. doi:10.1111/ane.12588</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ane.12588</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hirsch LJ, Arif H, Nahm EA. Cross-sensitivity of skin rashes with antiepileptic drug use. Neurology 2008;71(19):1527–1534. doi:10.1212/01.wnl.0000334295.50403.4c</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/01.wnl.0000334295.50403.4c</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brigo F, Ausserer H, Tezzon F, Nardone R. When one plus one makes three: the quest for rational antiepileptic polytherapy with supraadditive anticonvulsant efficacy. Epilepsy Behav 2013;27(3):439–442. doi:10.1016/j.yebeh.2013.03.010</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yebeh.2013.03.010</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Poolos NP, Warner LN, Humphreys SZ, Williams S. Comparative efficacy of combination drug therapy in refractory epilepsy. Neurology 2012;78(1):62–68. doi:10.1212/WNL.0b013e31823ed0dd</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0b013e31823ed0dd</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pina-Garza JE, Schwarzman L, Wiegand F, Hulihan J. A pilot study of topiramate in childhood absence epilepsy. Acta Neurol Scand 2011;123(1):54–59. doi:10.1111/j.1600-0404.2010.01347.x</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0404.2010.01347.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kockelmann E, Elger CE, Helmstaedter C. Significant improvement in frontal lobe associated neuropsychological functions after withdrawal of topiramate in epilepsy patients. Epilepsy Res 2003;54(2-3):171–178. doi:10.1016/s0920-1211(03)00078-0</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0920-1211(03)00078-0</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee S, Sziklas V, Andermann F. The effects of adjunctive topiramate on cognitive function in patients with epilepsy. Epilepsia 2003;44(3):339–347. doi:10.1046/j.1528-1157.2003.27402.x</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1528-1157.2003.27402.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hunt S, Russell A, Smithson WH. Topiramate in pregnancy: preliminary experience from the UK Epilepsy and Pregnancy Register. Neurology 2008;71(4):272–276. doi:10.1212/01.wnl.0000318293.28278.33</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/01.wnl.0000318293.28278.33</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Azar NJ, Bangalore-Vittal N, Arain A, Abou-Khalil BW. Tiagabine-induced stupor in patients with psychogenic nonepileptic seizures: nonconvulsive status epilepticus or encephalopathy?Epilepsy Behav 2013;27(2):330–332. doi:10.1016/j.yebeh.2013.02.016</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yebeh.2013.02.016</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koepp MJ, Edwards M, Collins J. Status epilepticus and tiagabine therapy revisited. Epilepsia 2005;46(10):1625–1632. doi:10.1111/j.1528-1167.2005.00263.x</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1167.2005.00263.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fukuyama K, Tanahashi S, Nakagawa M. Levetiracetam inhibits neurotransmitter release associated with CICR. Neurosci Lett 2012;518(2):69–74. doi:10.1016/j.neulet.2012.03.056</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neulet.2012.03.056</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Privitera M. Efficacy of levetiracetam: a review of three pivotal clinical trials. Epilepsia 2001;4:31–35.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beuchat I, Novy J, Rossetti AO. Newer antiepileptic drugs for status epilepticus in adults: what’s the evidence?CNS Drugs 2018;32(3):259–267. doi:10.1007/s40263-018-0509-5</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40263-018-0509-5</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brigo F, Bragazzi N, Nardone R, Trinka E. Direct and indirect comparison meta-analysis of levetiracetam versus phenytoin or valproate for convulsive status epilepticus. Epilepsy Behav 2016;64(pt A):110–115. doi:10.1016/j.yebeh.2016.09.030</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yebeh.2016.09.030</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gujjar AR, Nandhagopal R, Jacob PC. Intravenous levetiracetam vs phenytoin for status epilepticus and cluster seizures: a prospective, randomized study. Seizure 2017;49:8–12. doi:10.1016/j.seizure.2017.05.001</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.seizure.2017.05.001</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kapur J, Elm J, Chamberlain JM. Randomized trial of three anticonvulsant medications for status epilepticus. N Engl J Med 2019;381(22):2103–2113. doi:10.1056/NEJMoa1905795</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1905795</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Strzelczyk A, Kay L, Bauer S. Use of brivaracetam in genetic generalized epilepsies and for acute, intravenous treatment of absence status epilepticus. Epilepsia 2018;59(8):1549–1556. doi:10.1111/epi.14476</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.14476</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ben-Menachem E, Mameniškienė R, Quarato PP. Efficacy and safety of brivaracetam for partial-onset seizures in 3 pooled clinical studies. Neurology 2016;87(3):314–323. doi:10.1212/WNL.0000000000002864</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000002864</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Klein P, McLachlan R, Foris K. Effect of lifetime antiepileptic drug treatment history on efficacy and tolerability of adjunctive brivaracetam in adults with focal seizures: post-hoc analysis of a randomized, placebo-controlled trial. Epilepsy Res 2020;167(106369). doi:10.1016/j.eplepsyres.2020.106369</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eplepsyres.2020.106369</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Klein P, Schiemann J, Sperling MR. A randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, multicenter, parallel-group study to evaluate the efficacy and safety of adjunctive brivaracetam in adult patients with uncontrolled partial-onset seizures. Epilepsia 2015;56(12):1890–1898. doi:10.1111/epi.13212</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.13212</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yates SL, Fakhoury T, Liang W. An open-label, prospective, exploratory study of patients with epilepsy switching from levetiracetam to brivaracetam. Epilepsy Behav 2015;52(pt A):165–168. doi:10.1016/j.yebeh.2015.09.005</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yebeh.2015.09.005</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hirsch M, Hintz M, Specht A, Schulze-Bonhage A. Tolerability, efficacy and retention rate of Brivaracetam in patients previously treated with levetiracetam: a monocenter retrospective outcome analysis. Seizure 2018;61:98–103. doi:10.1016/j.seizure.2018.07.017</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.seizure.2018.07.017</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aicua-Rapun I, Andre P, Rossetti AO. Intravenous brivaracetam in status epilepticus: correlation between loading dose, plasma levels and clinical response. Epilepsy Res 2019;149:88–91. doi:10.1016/j.eplepsyres.2018.12.001</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eplepsyres.2018.12.001</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vossler DG, Knake S, O’Brien TJ. Efficacy and safety of adjunctive lacosamide in the treatment of primary generalised tonic-clonic seizures: a double-blind, randomised, placebo-controlled trial. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2020;91(10):1067–1075. doi:10.1136/jnnp-2020-323524</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp-2020-323524</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sake JK, Hebert D, Isojärvi J. A pooled analysis of lacosamide clinical trial data grouped by mechanism of action of concomitant antiepileptic drugs. CNS Drugs 2010;24(12):1055–1068. doi:10.2165/11587550-000000000-00000</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/11587550-000000000-00000</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Husain AM, Lee JW, Kolls BJ. Randomized trial of lacosamide versus fosphenytoin for nonconvulsive seizures. Ann Neurol 2018;83(6):1174–1185. doi:10.1002/ana.2524</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.2524</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brigo F, Del Giovane C, Nardone R. Intravenous antiepileptic drugs in adults with benzodiazepine-resistant convulsive status epilepticus: a systematic review and network meta-analysis. Epilepsy Behav 2019;101(pt B). doi:10.1016/j.yebeh.2019.106466</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yebeh.2019.106466</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ben-Menachem E. Medical management of refractory epilepsy—practical treatment with novel antiepileptic drugs. Epilepsia 2014;1:3–8. doi:10.1111/epi.12494</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.12494</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vigabatrin, a gabaergic antiepileptic drug, causes concentric visual field defects. Neurology 1999;53(5):922–926. doi:10.1212/wnl.53.5.922</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/wnl.53.5.922</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Toggweiler S, Wieser HG. Concentric visual field restriction under vigabatrin therapy: extent depends on the duration of drug intake. Seizure 2001;10(6):420–423. doi:10.1053/seiz.2000.0527</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/seiz.2000.0527</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Patsalos PN. The clinical pharmacology profile of the new antiepileptic drug perampanel: a novel noncompetitive AMPA receptor antagonist. Epilepsia 2015;56(1):12–27. doi:10.1111/epi.12865</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.12865</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>French J, Krauss G, Wechsler RT. Adjunctive perampanel for the treatment of drug-resistant primary generalized tonic-clonic (PGTC) seizures in patients with idiopathic generalized epilepsy (IGE): a double-blind, randomized, placebo-controlled phase III trial. Neurology 2015;84(14 Supplement).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ettinger AB, LoPresti A, Yang H. Psychiatric and behavioral adverse events in randomized clinical studies of the noncompetitive AMPA receptor antagonist perampanel. Epilepsia 2015;56(8):1252–1263. doi:10.1111/epi.13054</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.13054</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Andres E, Kerling F, Hamer H. Behavioural changes in patients with intellectual disability treated with perampanel. Acta Neurol Scand 2017;136(6):645–653. doi:10.1111/ane.12781</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ane.12781</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morgan CL, Varga S, Tsong W. Healthcare utilization and associated costs following initiation of perampanel in patients with epilepsy. Epilepsy Behav 2020;110(107137). doi:10.1016/j.yebeh.2020.107137</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yebeh.2020.107137</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Faught E, Laliberte F, Wang Z. Health care resource utilization before and after perampanel initiation among patients with epilepsy in the United States. Epilepsia 2017;58(10):1742–1748. doi:10.1111/epi.13857</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.13857</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Canafoglia L, Barbella G, Ferlazzo E. An Italian multicentre study of perampanel in progressive myoclonus epilepsies. Epilepsy Res 2019;156(106191). doi:10.1016/j.eplepsyres.2019.106191</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eplepsyres.2019.106191</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Crespel A, Gelisse P, Tang NP, Genton P. Perampanel in 12 patients with Unverricht-Lundborg disease. Epilepsia 2017;58(4):543–547. doi:10.1111/epi.13662</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.13662</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dirani M, Nasreddine W, Abdulla F, Beydoun A. Seizure control and improvement of neurological dysfunction in Lafora disease with perampanel. Epilepsy Behav Case Rep 2014;2:164–166. doi:10.1016/j.ebcr.2014.09.003</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ebcr.2014.09.003</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goldsmith D, Minassian BA. Efficacy and tolerability of perampanel in ten patients with Lafora disease. Epilepsy Behav 2016;62:132–135. doi:10.1016/j.yebeh.2016.06.041</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yebeh.2016.06.041</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bakas T, Nieuwenhuijzen PS, Devenish SO. The direct actions of cannabidiol and 2-arachidonoyl glycerol at GABAA receptors. Pharmacol Res 2017;119:358–370. doi:10.1016/j.phrs.2017.02.022</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.phrs.2017.02.022</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bih CI, Chen T, Nunn AVW, et al. Molecular targets of cannabidiol in neurological disorders. Neurotherapeutics 2015;12(4):699–730. doi:10.1007/s13311-015-0377-3</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13311-015-0377-3</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gaston TE, Bebin EM, Cutter GR. Interactions between cannabidiol and commonly used antiepileptic drugs. Epilepsia 2017;58(9):1586–1592. doi:10.1111/epi.13852</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.13852</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Geffrey AL, Pollack SF, Bruno PL, Thiele EA. Drug-drug interaction between clobazam and cannabidiol in children with refractory epilepsy. Epilepsia 2015;56(8):1246–1251. doi:10.1111/epi.13060</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.13060</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Epidiolex. Prescribing information. Greenwich Biosciences, Inc; 2018. Accessed January 11, 2022. https://www.accessdata.fda.gov/drugsatfda_docs/label/2018/210365lbl.pdf</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thiele EA, Bebin EM, Bhathal H. Add-on cannabidiol treatment for drug-resistant seizures in tuberous sclerosis complex: a placebo-controlled randomized clinical trial. JAMA Neurol 2021;78(3):285–292. doi:10.1001/jamaneurol.2020.4607</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaneurol.2020.4607</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Devinsky O, Cross JH, Laux L. Trial of cannabidiol for drug-resistant seizures in the dravet syndrome. N Engl J Med 2017;376(21):2011–2020. doi:10.1056/NEJMoa1611618</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1611618</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Devinsky O, Patel AD, Cross JH. Effect of cannabidiol on drop seizures in the Lennox-Gastaut syndrome. N Engl J Med 2018;378(20):1888–1897. doi:10.1056/NEJMoa1714631</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1714631</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thiele EA, Marsh ED, French JA. Cannabidiol in patients with seizures associated with Lennox-Gastaut syndrome (GWPCARE4): a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled phase 3 trial. Lancet 2018;391(10125):1085–1096. doi:10.1016/S0140-6736(18)30136-3</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(18)30136-3</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Devinsky O, Marsh E, Friedman D. Cannabidiol in patients with treatment-resistant epilepsy: an open-label interventional trial. Lancet Neurol 2016;15(3):270–278. doi:10.1016/S1474-4422(15)00379-8</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1474-4422(15)00379-8</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Devinsky O, Verducci C, Thiele EA. Open-label use of highly purified CBD (Epidiolex®) in patients with CDKL5 deficiency disorder and Aicardi, Dup15q, and Doose syndromes. Epilepsy Behav 2018;86:131–137. doi:10.1016/j.yebeh.2018.05.013</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yebeh.2018.05.013</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Szaflarski JP, Bebin EM, Comi AM. Long-term safety and treatment effects of cannabidiol in children and adults with treatment-resistant epilepsies: expanded access program results. Epilepsia 2018;59(8):1540–1548. doi:10.1111/epi.14477</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.14477</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Buck ML, Goodkin HP. Stiripentol: a novel antiseizure medication for the management of Dravet syndrome. Ann Pharmacother 2019;53(11):1136–1144. doi:10.1177/1060028019856008</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1060028019856008</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peigne S, Rey E, Le Guern ME. Reassessment of stiripentol pharmacokinetics in healthy adult volunteers. Epilepsy Res 2014;108(5):909–916. doi:10.1016/j.eplepsyres.2014.03.009</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eplepsyres.2014.03.009</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guignet M, Campbell A, White HS. Cenobamate (XCOPRI): can preclinical and clinical evidence provide insight into its mechanism of action?Epilepsia 2020;61(11):2329–2339. doi:10.1111/epi.16718</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.16718</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Loscher W, Sills GJ, White HS. The ups and downs of alkyl-carbamates in epilepsy therapy: how does cenobamate differ?Epilepsia 2021;62(3):596–614. doi:10.1111/epi.16832</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.16832</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lattanzi S, Trinka E, Zaccara G. Adjunctive cenobamate for focal-onset seizures in adults: a systematic review and meta-analysis. CNS Drugs 2020;34(11):1105–1120. doi:10.1007/s40263-020-00759-9</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40263-020-00759-9</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sperling MR, Klein P, Aboumatar S. Cenobamate (YKP3089) as adjunctive treatment for uncontrolled focal seizures in a large, phase 3, multicenter, open-label safety study. Epilepsia 2020;61(6):1099–1108. doi:10.1111/epi.16525</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.16525</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krauss GL, Klein P, Brandt C. Safety and efficacy of adjunctive cenobamate (YKP3089) in patients with uncontrolled focal seizures: a multicentre, double-blind, randomised, placebo-controlled, dose-response trial. Lancet Neurol 2020;19(1):38–48. doi:10.1016/S1474-4422(19)30399-0</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1474-4422(19)30399-0</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chung SS, French JA, Kowalski J. Randomized phase 2 study of adjunctive cenobamate in patients with uncontrolled focal seizures. Neurology 2020;94(22). doi:10.1212/WNL.0000000000009530</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000009530</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gogou M, Cross JH. Fenfluramine as antiseizure medication for epilepsy. Dev Med Child Neurol 2021;63(8):899–907. doi:10.1111/dmcn.14822</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/dmcn.14822</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Polster T. Individualized treatment approaches: fenfluramine, a novel antiepileptic medication for the treatment of seizures in Dravet syndrome. Epilepsy Behav 2019;91:99–102. doi:10.1016/j.yebeh.2018.08.021</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yebeh.2018.08.021</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Semah F, Thomas P, Coulbaut S, Derambure P. Early add-on treatment vs alternative monotherapy in patients with partial epilepsy. Epileptic Disord 2014;16(2):165–174. doi:10.1684/epd.2014.0650</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1684/epd.2014.0650</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zaccara G, Perucca E. Interactions between antiepileptic drugs, and between antiepileptic drugs and other drugs. Epileptic Disord 2014;16(4):409–431. doi:10.1684/epd.2014.0714</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1684/epd.2014.0714</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Margolis JM, Chu BC, Wang ZJ. Effectiveness of antiepileptic drug combination therapy for partial-onset seizures based on mechanisms of action. JAMA Neurol 2014;71(8):985–993. doi:10.1001/jamaneurol.2014.808</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaneurol.2014.808</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stafstrom CE. Mechanisms of action of antiepileptic drugs: the search for synergy. Curr Opin Neurol 2010;23(2):157–163. doi:10.1097/WCO.0b013e32833735b5</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/WCO.0b013e32833735b5</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
