<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35392264</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>09</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">1559-3258</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>20</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Season>Jan-Mar</Season>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Dose-response : a publication of International Hormesis Society</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Dose Response</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Osthole-Mediated Inhibition of Neurotoxicity Induced by Ropivacaine via Amplification of the Cyclic Adenosine Monophosphate Signaling Pathway.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>15593258221088092</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>15593258221088092</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">15593258221088092</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/15593258221088092</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Ropivacaine is widely used for clinical anesthesia and postoperative analgesia. However, the neurotoxicity induced by ropivacaine in a concentration- and duration-dependent manner, and it is difficult to prevent neurotoxicity. Osthole inhibits phosphodiesterase-4 activity by binding to its catalytic site to prevent cAMP hydrolysis. The aim of this present study is to explore the precise molecular mechanism of osthole-mediated inhibition of neurotoxicity induced by ropivacaine.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">SH-SY5Y cell viability and apoptosis were measured in different concentration and duration. Protein concentration was determined in each signaling pathway. The molecular mechanism of osthole-mediated inhibition of ropivacaine-caused neurotoxicity was evaluated.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The study demonstrated that osthole inhibits SH-SY5Y cells neurotoxicity in a duration- and concentration-dependent manner. Moreover, ropivacaine significantly increased the expression of caspase-3 by promoting the phosphorylation of p38. Osthole-induced upregulation of cAMP activated cAMP-dependent signaling pathway, sequentially leading to elevated cyclic nucleotide response element-binding protein levels, which inhibits P38-dependent signaling and decreases apoptosis of SH-SY5Y.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">This study display the evidence confirmed the molecular mechanism by which osthole amplification of cAMP-dependent signaling pathway, and overexpression of cyclic nucleotide response element-binding protein inhibits P38-dependent signaling and decreases ropivacaine-induced SH-SY5Y apoptosis.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© The Author(s) 2022.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wang</LastName>
            <ForeName>WeiBing</ForeName>
            <Initials>W</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6059-7916</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, The Affiliated AnQing Municipal Hospitals of Anhui Medical University, AnQing, China.</Affiliation>
              <Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">12485</Identifier>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhou</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hui</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, The Affiliated AnQing Municipal Hospitals of Anhui Medical University, AnQing, China.</Affiliation>
              <Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">12485</Identifier>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sun</LastName>
            <ForeName>LaiBao</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, The First Affiliated Hospitals of Sun Yat-Sen University, GuangZhou, China.</Affiliation>
              <Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">71068</Identifier>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Li</LastName>
            <ForeName>MeiNa</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, The First Affiliated Hospitals of Sun Yat-Sen University, GuangZhou, China.</Affiliation>
              <Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">71068</Identifier>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gao</LastName>
            <ForeName>FengJiao</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology, The First Affiliated Hospitals of Sun Yat-Sen University, GuangZhou, China.</Affiliation>
              <Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">71068</Identifier>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sun</LastName>
            <ForeName>AiJiao</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cardiovascularology, The Affiliated AnQing Municipal Hospital of Anhui Medical University, AnQing, China.</Affiliation>
              <Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">26469</Identifier>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zou</LastName>
            <ForeName>XueNong</ForeName>
            <Initials>X</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, The First Affiliated Hospitals of Sun Yat-Sen University, GuangZhou, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>31</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Dose Response</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101308899</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1559-3258</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">apoptosis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cyclic adenosine monophosphate</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurotoxicity</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">osthole</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">p38</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ropivacaine</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>Declaration of Conflicting Interests: The author(s) declared no potential conflicts of interest with respect to the research, authorship, and/or publication of this article.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>18</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35392264</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8980408</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/15593258221088092</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_15593258221088092</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xuebi T, Ping Y, Tiefen S, et al.
Intraperitoneal ropivacaine and early postoperative pain and postsurgical outcomes after laparoscopic herniorrhaphy in toddlers: a randomized clinical trial. Pediatric Anesthesia. 2016;26(9):891-898.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27346807</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Božidar B, Miroslav A, Dejan Ć, et al.
Efficacy and safety of 1% ropivacaine for postoperative analgesia after lower third molar surgery: a prospective, randomized, double-blinded clinical study. Clin Oral Invest. 2017;21(3):779-785.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27114091</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li M, Wan L, Mei W, Tian Y. Update on the clinical utility and practical use of ropivacaine in Chinese patients. Drug Design, Development and Therapy. 2014;8(9):1269-1276.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4166907</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25246768</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>El-Boghdadly K, Chin KJ. Local anesthetic systemic toxicity: Continuing professional development. Canadian Journal of Anesthesia/Journal canadien d'anesthésie. 2016;63(3):330-349.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26830640</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Farber SJ, Saheb-Al-Zamani M, Zieske L, Laurido-Soto O, Bery A, Hunter D, et al.. Peripheral nerve injury after local anesthetic injection. Anesth Analg. 2013;117(3):731-739.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23921658</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Werdehausen R, Fazeli S, Braun S, Hermanns H, Essmann F, Hollmann MW, et al.. Apoptosis induction by different local anaesthetics in a neuroblastoma cell line. Br J Anaesth. 2009;103(5):711-718.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19700777</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Radwan IAM, Saito S, Goto F. The neurotoxicity of local anesthetics on growing neurons: a comparative study of lidocaine, bupivacaine, mepivacaine, and ropivacaine. Anesth Analg. 2002;94(2):319-324.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11812691</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kitagawa N, Oda M, Totoki T. Possible mechanism of irreversible nerve injury caused by local anesthetics. Anesthesiology. 2004;100(4):962-967.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15087634</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Radwan IAM, Saito S, Goto aF. Neurotrophic factors can partially reverse morphological changes induced by mepivacaine and bupivacaine in developing sensory neurons. Anesth Analg. 2003;97(2):506-511.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12873945</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kasaba T, Onizuka S, Kashiwada M, Takasaki M. Increase in intracellular Ca2+ concentration is not the only cause of lidocaine-induced cell damage in the cultured neurons of Lymnaea stagnalis. J Anesth. 2006;20(3):196-201.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16897239</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen Y, Yan L, Zhang Y, Yang X. The role of DRP1 in ropivacaine-induced mitochondrial dysfunction and neurotoxicity. Artificial Cells, Nanomedicine, and Biotechnology. 2019;47(1):1788-1796.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31062606</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wen X, Li Y, Liu X, Sun C, Lin J, Zhang W, et al.. Roles of CaMKIIβ in the neurotoxicity induced by ropivacaine hydrochloride in dorsal root ganglion. Artificial Cells, Nanomedicine, and Biotechnology. 2019;47(1):2948-2956.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31317779</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wen X, Liang H, Li H, Ou W, Wang HB, Liu H, et al.. In vitro neurotoxicity by ropivacaine is reduced by silencing Cav3.3 T-type calcium subunits in neonatal rat sensory neurons. Artificial cells, nanomedicine, and biotechnology. 2018;46(8):1617-1624.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28974111</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jingwei X, Qiuyue K, Leyang D, et al.. Autophagy activated by tuberin/mTOR/p70S6K suppression is a protective mechanism against local anaesthetics neurotoxicity. J Cell Mol Med. 2017;21(3):579-587.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5323818</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27860187</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shuai W, Quan L, Zhengjie W, Pan X. Ropivacaine induces neurotoxicity by activating MAPK/p38 signal to upregulate Fas expression in neurogliocyte. Neurosci Lett
2019;27706(7):7-11.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31028842</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guo H, Cheng Y, Wang C, Wu J, Zou Z, Niu B, et al.. FFPM, a PDE4 inhibitor, reverses learning and memory deficits in APP/PS1 transgenic mice via cAMP/PKA/CREB signaling and anti-inflammatory effects. Neuropharmacology. 2017;116(4):260-269.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28065587</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li H, Li J, Zhang X, Feng C, Fan C, Yang X, et al.. DC591017, a phosphodiesterase-4 (PDE4) inhibitor with robust anti-inflammation through regulating PKA-CREB signaling. Biochem Pharmacol. 2020;177(7):113958.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32251674</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnson KR, Nicodemus-Johnson J, Danziger RS. An evolutionary analysis of cAMP-specific Phosphodiesterase 4 alternative splicing. BMC Evolutionary Biology. 2010;1110(8):247.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2929239</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20701803</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bolger GB. RACK1 and β-arrestin2 attenuate dimerization of PDE4 cAMP phosphodiesterase PDE4D5. Cell Signal. 2016;28(7):706-712.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4744576</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26257302</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Richter W, Day P, Agrawal R, Bruss MD, Granier S, Wang YL, et al.. Signaling from β1- and β2-adrenergic receptors is defined by differential interactions with PDE4. EMBO J. 2008;27(2):384-393.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2196435</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18188154</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bradaïa A, Berton F, Ferrari S, Lüscher C. β-Arrestin2, interacting with phosphodiesterase 4, regulates synaptic release probability and presynaptic inhibition by opioids. Proc Natl Acad Sci Unit States Am. 2005;102(8):3034-3039.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC549451</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15718284</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li X, Huston E, Lynch MJ, Houslay MD, Baillie GS. Phosphodiesterase-4 influences the PKA phosphorylation status and membrane translocation of G-protein receptor kinase 2 (GRK2) in HEK-293beta2 cells and cardiac myocytes. Biochem J. 2006;394(Pt 2):427-435.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1408673</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16356165</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hoffmann R, Baillie GS, MacKenzie SJ, Yarwood SJ, Houslay MD. The MAP kinase ERK2 inhibits the cyclic AMP-specific phosphodiesterase HSPDE4D3 by phosphorylating it at Ser579. EMBO J. 1999;18(4):893-903.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1171182</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10022832</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>MacKenzie SJ, Baillie GS, McPhee I, Bolger GB, Houslay MD. ERK2 Mitogen-activated Protein Kinase Binding, Phosphorylation, and Regulation of the PDE4D cAMP-specific Phosphodiesterases. J Biol Chem. 2000;275(22):16609-16617.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10828059</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Song RS, Massenburg B, Wenderski W, Jayaraman V, Thompson L, Neves SR. ERK regulation of phosphodiesterase 4 enhances dopamine-stimulated AMPA receptor membrane insertion. Proc Natl Acad Sci Unit States Am. 2013;110(38):15437-15442.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3780840</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23986500</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Houslay KF, Christian F, MacLeod R, Adams DR, Houslay MD, Baillie GS. Identification of a multifunctional docking site on the catalytic unit of phosphodiesterase-4 (PDE4) that is utilised by multiple interaction partners. Biochem J. 2017;474(4):597-609.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5290487</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27993970</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sette C, Conti M. Phosphorylation and Activation of a cAMP-specific Phosphodiesterase by the cAMP-dependent Protein Kinase. J Biol Chem. 1996;271(28):16526-16534.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8663227</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hill EV, Sheppard CL, Cheung Y-F, Gall I, Krause E, Houslay MD. Oxidative stress employs phosphatidyl inositol 3-kinase and ERK signalling pathways to activate cAMP phosphodiesterase-4D3 (PDE4D3) through multi-site phosphorylation at Ser239 and Ser579. Cell Signal. 2006;18(11):2056-2069.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16973330</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang ZR, Leung WN, CheungCheung HY, Chan CW. Osthole: A review on its bioactivities, pharmacological properties, and potential as alternative medicine. Evid base Compl Alternative Med : eCAM. 2015;2015:919616.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4515521</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26246843</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fan H, Gao Z, Ji K, et al.
The in vitro and in vivo anti-inflammatory effect of osthole, the major natural coumarin from Cnidium monnieri (L.) Cuss, via the blocking of the activation of the NF-κB and MAPK/p38 pathways. Phytomedicine : International Journal of Phytotherapy and Phytopharmacology. 2019;58(5):152864.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30878874</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yun Y, Feng R, Ziyin T, Song W, Cheng B, Feng Z. Osthole synergizes with HER2 inhibitor, trastuzumab in HER2-overexpressed N87 gastric cancer by inducing apoptosis and inhibition of AKT-MAPK pathway. Front Pharmacol
2018;27(11):9-1392.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6277458</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30538636</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sun W, Cai Y, Zhang X-x., Chen H, Lin Y-d., Li H. Osthole pretreatment alleviates TNBS-induced colitis in mice via both cAMP/PKA-dependent and independent pathways. Acta Pharmacol Sin. 2017;38(8):1120-1128.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5547558</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28603288</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhong-Rong Z, Wing NL, Gang L, et al.
Osthole enhances osteogenesis in osteoblasts by elevating transcription factor osterix via cAMP/CREB signaling in vitro and in vivo. Nutrients. 2017;9(6):588.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5490567</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28629115</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sheng W, Yan X, YanWu H, et al.
Airway relaxation mechanisms and structural basis of osthole for improving lung function in asthma. Sci Signal, 2020.  ,24;13(659):eaax0273.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8720283</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33234690</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arnaud M, Marie-Odile F, Nathalie D, Pereira B, Haas J, Lambert G. The comparative cytotoxic effects of different local anesthetics on a human neuroblastoma cell line. Anesth Analg
2015;120(3):589-596.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25514420</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nikhil KT, Srinath K, Ganesh SA. Channeling of cAMP in PDE-PKA complexes promotes signal adaptation. Biophys J. 2017;112(12):2552-2566.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5479052</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28636912</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hollmann MW, Wieczorek KS, Berger A, Durieux ME. Local anesthetic inhibition of G protein-coupled receptor signaling by interference with gαq protein function. Mol Pharmacol. 2001;59(2):294-301.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11160866</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tamm I, Wang Y, Sausville E, Scudiero DA, Vigna N, Oltersdorf T, et al.. IAP-family protein survivin inhibits caspase activity and apoptosis induced by Fas (CD95), Bax, caspases, and anticancer drugs. Cancer Research. 1998;58:5315-5320.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9850056</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tian FZ, Chang HS, Liu JX, Zheng J, Cheng D, Lu Y. Cynomorium songaricum extract alleviates memory impairment through increasing CREB/BDNF via suppression of p38MAPK/ERK pathway in ovariectomized rats. Evid base Compl Alternative Med : eCAM. 2019;2019:20199689325.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6556289</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31239867</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
