<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35394147</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>09</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>09</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1432-0584</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>101</Volume>
            <Issue>6</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Annals of hematology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Ann Hematol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>High-flow nasal cannula oxygen in patients with haematological malignancy: a retrospective observational study.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>1191</StartPage>
          <EndPage>1199</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>1191-1199</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00277-022-04824-9</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Patients with haematological malignancies (HM) face high rates of intensive care unit (ICU) admission and mortality. High-flow nasal cannula oxygen (HFNCO) is increasingly used to support HM patients in ward settings, but there is limited evidence on the safety and efficacy of HFNCO in this group. We retrospectively reviewed all HM patients receiving ward-based HFNCO, supervised by a critical care outreach service (CCOS), from January 2014 to January 2019. We included 130 consecutive patients. Forty-three (33.1%) were weaned off HFNCO without ICU admission. Eighty-seven (66.9%) were admitted to ICU, 20 (23.3%) required non-invasive and 34 (39.5%) invasive mechanical ventilation. ICU and hospital mortality were 42% and 55% respectively. Initial FiO<sub>2</sub> &lt; 0.4 (OR 0.27, 95% CI 0.09-0.81, p = 0.019) and HFNCO use on the ward &gt; 1 day (OR 0.16, 95% CI 0.04, 0.59, p = 0.006) were associated with reduced likelihood for ICU admission. Invasive ventilation was associated with reduced survival (OR 0.27, 95%CI 0.1-0.7, p = 0.007). No significant adverse events were reported. HM patients receiving ward-based HFNCO have higher rates of ICU admission, but comparable hospital mortality to those requiring CCOS review without respiratory support. Results should be interpreted cautiously, as the model proposed depends on the existence of CCOS.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer-Verlag GmbH Germany, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tetlow</LastName>
            <ForeName>Simon</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3110-1125</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>University College Hospital NHS Foundation Trust, 235 Euston Rd, Bloomsbury, London, NW1 2BU, UK. simon.tetlow@nhs.net.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Anandanadesan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Rathai</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Royal Brompton Hospital, Sydney St, Chelsea, London, SW3 6NP, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Taheri</LastName>
            <ForeName>Leila</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Guy's and St Thomas' NHS Foundation Trust, Westminster Bridge Road, London, SE1 7EH, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Pagkalidou</LastName>
            <ForeName>Eirini</ForeName>
            <Initials>E</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Medicine, Aristotle University of Thessaloniki, University Campus, 54124, Thessaloniki, Greece.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>De Lavallade</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hugues</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Haematological Medicine, King's College Hospital, Denmark Hill, Brixton, London, SE5 9RS, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Metaxa</LastName>
            <ForeName>Victoria</ForeName>
            <Initials>V</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Critical Care, King's College Hospital, Denmark Hill, Brixton, London, SE5 9RS, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D064888">Observational Study</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>04</Month>
          <Day>08</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>Germany</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Ann Hematol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9107334</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0939-5555</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>S88TT14065</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D010100">Oxygen</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000072601" MajorTopicYN="N">Cannula</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D019337" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hematologic Neoplasms</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007362" MajorTopicYN="N">Intensive Care Units</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D010100" MajorTopicYN="N">Oxygen</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012131" MajorTopicYN="Y">Respiratory Insufficiency</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cancer</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Haematology</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Non-invasive respiratory support</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Respiratory failure</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Supportive care</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35394147</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00277-022-04824-9</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00277-022-04824-9</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mohty B, Mohty M (2011) Long-term complications and side effects after allogeneic hematopoietic stem cell transplantation: an update. Blood Cancer J 1(4):e16–e16</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/bcj.2011.14</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bayraktar U, Nates J (2016) Intensive care outcomes in adult hematopoietic stem cell transplantation patients. World J Clin Oncol 7(1):98</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5306/wjco.v7.i1.98</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Azoulay E, Mokart D, Pène F, Lambert J, Kouatchet A, Mayaux J et al (2013) Outcomes of critically ill patients with hematologic malignancies: prospective multicenter data from France and Belgium—A Groupe de Recherche Respiratoire en Réanimation Onco-Hématologique Study. J Clin Oncol 31(22):2810–2818</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2012.47.2365</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grgić Medić M, Gornik I, Gašparović V (2014) Hematologic malignancies in the medical intensive care unit — outcomes and prognostic factors. Hematology 20(5):247–253</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1179/1607845414Y.0000000206</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lemiale V, Mokart D, Mayaux J, Lambert J, Rabbat A, Demoule A et al (2015) The effects of a 2-h trial of high-flow oxygen by nasal cannula versus Venturi mask in immunocompromised patients with hypoxemic acute respiratory failure: a multicenter randomized trial. Crit Care 19(1)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Azoulay E, Lemiale V (2012) Non-invasive mechanical ventilation in hematology patients with hypoxemic acute respiratory failure: a false belief? Bone Marrow Transplant 47(4):469–472</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/bmt.2011.232</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gristina G, Antonelli M, Conti G, Ciarlone A, Rogante S, Rossi C et al (2011) Noninvasive versus invasive ventilation for acute respiratory failure in patients with hematologic malignancies: a 5-year multicenter observational survey*. Crit Care Med 39(10):2232–2239</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CCM.0b013e3182227a27</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Azevedo L, Caruso P, Silva U, Torelly A, Silva E, Rezende E et al (2014) Outcomes for patients with cancer admitted to the ICU requiring ventilatory support. Chest 146(2):257–266</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1378/chest.13-1870</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Azoulay E, Lemiale V, Mokart D, Pène F, Kouatchet A, Perez P et al (2014) Acute respiratory distress syndrome in patients with malignancies. Intensive Care Med 40(8):1106–1114</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00134-014-3354-0</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hilbert G, Gruson D, Vargas F, Valentino R, Gbikpi-Benissan G, Dupon M et al (2001) Noninvasive ventilation in immunosuppressed patients with pulmonary infiltrates, fever, and acute respiratory failure. N Engl J Med 344(7):481–487</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJM200102153440703</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mokart D, Lambert J, Schnell D, Fouché L, Rabbat A, Kouatchet A et al (2012) Delayed intensive care unit admission is associated with increased mortality in patients with cancer with acute respiratory failure. Leuk Lymphoma 54(8):1724–1729</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/10428194.2012.753446</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Azoulay É, Kouatchet A, Jaber S, Lambert J, Meziani F, Schmidt M et al (2012) Noninvasive mechanical ventilation in patients having declined tracheal intubation. Intensive Care Med 39(2):292–301</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00134-012-2746-2</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hernández G, Roca O, Colinas L (2017) High-flow nasal cannula support therapy: new insights and improving performance. Crit Care 21(1)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ischaki E, Pantazopoulos I, Zakynthinos S (2017) Nasal high flow therapy: a novel treatment rather than a more expensive oxygen device. Eur Respir Rev 26(145):170028</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhao H, Wang H, Sun F, Lyu S, An Y (2017) High-flow nasal cannula oxygen therapy is superior to conventional oxygen therapy but not to noninvasive mechanical ventilation on intubation rate: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Crit Care 21(1)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee C, Mankodi D, Shaharyar S, Ravindranathan S, Danckers M, Herscovici P et al (2016) High flow nasal cannula versus conventional oxygen therapy and non-invasive ventilation in adults with acute hypoxemic respiratory failure: a systematic review. Respir Med 121:100–108</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.rmed.2016.11.004</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Frat J, Thille A, Mercat A, Girault C, Ragot S, Perbet S et al (2015) High-flow oxygen through nasal cannula in acute hypoxemic respiratory failure. N Engl J Med 372(23):2185–2196</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1503326</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cortegiani A, Crimi C, Sanfilippo F, Noto A, Di Falco D, Grasselli G et al (2019) High flow nasal therapy in immunocompromised patients with acute respiratory failure: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Crit Care 50:250–256</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcrc.2018.12.015</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huang H, Peng J, Weng L, Liu G, Du B (2018) High-flow oxygen therapy in immunocompromised patients with acute respiratory failure: a review and meta-analysis. J Crit Care 43:300–305</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcrc.2017.09.176</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Azoulay E, Lemiale V, Mokart D et al (2018) Effect of high-flow nasal oxygen vs standard oxygen on 28-day mortality in immunocompromised patients with acute respiratory failure. The HIGH Randomized Clinical Trial. JAMA 320(20):2099–2107</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2018.14282</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Epstein A, Hartridge-Lambert S, Ramaker J, Voigt L, Portlock C (2011) Humidified high-flow nasal oxygen utilization in patients with cancer at Memorial Sloan-Kettering Cancer Center. J Palliat Med 14(7):835–839</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/jpm.2011.0005</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rittayamai N, Tscheikuna J, Praphruetkit N, Kijpinyochai S (2015) Use of high-flow nasal cannula for acute dyspnea and hypoxemia in the emergency department. Respir Care 60(10):1377–1382</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4187/respcare.03837</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Taheri L, Anandanadesan R, de Lavallade H, Pagkalidou E, Pagliuca A, Mufti G et al (2019) The role of a critical care outreach service in the management of patients with haematological malignancy. J Intensive Care Soc 20(4):327–334</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1751143719855201</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Charlson M, Pompei P, Ales K, MacKenzie C (1987) A new method of classifying prognostic comorbidity in longitudinal studies: development and validation. J Chronic Dis 40(5):373–383</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0021-9681(87)90171-8</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hayani O, Al-Beihany A, Zarychanski R, Chou A, Kharaba A, Baxter A et al (2011) Impact of critical care outreach on hematopoietic stem cell transplant recipients: a cohort study. Bone Marrow Transplant 46(8):1138–1144</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/bmt.2010.248</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Benz R, Schanz U, Maggiorini M, Seebach J, Stussi G (2014) Risk factors for ICU admission and ICU survival after allogeneic hematopoietic SCT. Bone Marrow Transplant 49(1):62–65</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/bmt.2013.141</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bokhari S, Munir T, Memon S, Byrne J, Russell N, Beed M (2010) Impact of critical care reconfiguration and track-and-trigger outreach team intervention on outcomes of haematology patients requiring intensive care admission. Ann Hematol 89(5):505–512</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00277-009-0853-0</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Azoulay E, Pène F, Darmon M, Lengliné E, Benoit D, Soares M et al (2015) Managing critically Ill hematology patients: time to think differently. Blood Rev 29(6):359–367</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.blre.2015.04.002</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roca O, Messika J, Caralt B, García-de-Acilu M, Sztrymf B, Ricard J et al (2016) Predicting success of high-flow nasal cannula in pneumonia patients with hypoxemic respiratory failure: The utility of the ROX index. J Crit Care 35:200–205</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcrc.2016.05.022</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koga Y, Kaneda K, Mizuguchi I, Nakahara T, Miyauchi T, Fujita M et al (2016) Extent of pleural effusion on chest radiograph is associated with failure of high-flow nasal cannula oxygen therapy. J Crit Care 32:165–169</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcrc.2015.12.001</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kang B, Koh Y, Lim C, Huh J, Baek S, Han M et al (2015) Failure of high-flow nasal cannula therapy may delay intubation and increase mortality. Intensive Care Med 41(4):623–632</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00134-015-3693-5</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Antonelli M, Conti G, Moro M, Esquinas A, Gonzalez-Diaz G, Confalonieri M et al (2001) Predictors of failure of noninvasive positive pressure ventilation in patients with acute hypoxemic respiratory failure: a multi-center study. Intensive Care Med 27(11):1718–1728</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00134-001-1114-4</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moretti M, Cilione C, Tampieri A, Fracchia C, Marchioni A, Nava S (2000) Incidence and causes of non-invasive mechanical ventilation failure after initial success. Thorax 55(10):819–825</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/thorax.55.10.819</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hampshire P, Welch C, McCrossan L, Francis K, Harrison D (2009) Admission factors associated with hospital mortality in patients with haematological malignancy admitted to UK adult, general critical care units: a secondary analysis of the ICNARC Case Mix Programme Database. Crit Care 13(4):R137</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/cc8016</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bird G, Farquhar-Smith P, Wigmore T, Potter M, Gruber P (2012) Outcomes and prognostic factors in patients with haematological malignancy admitted to a specialist cancer intensive care unit: a 5 yr study. Br J Anaesth 108(3):452–459</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bja/aer449</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Azoulay E, Pickkers P, Soares M, Perner A, Rello J, Bauer P et al (2017) Acute hypoxemic respiratory failure in immunocompromised patients: the Efraim multinational prospective cohort study. Intensive Care Med 43(12):1808–1819</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00134-017-4947-1</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Contejean A, Lemiale V, Resche-Rigon M, Mokart D, Pène F, Kouatchet A et al (2016) Increased mortality in hematological malignancy patients with acute respiratory failure from undetermined etiology: a Groupe de Recherche en Réanimation Respiratoire en Onco-Hématologie (Grrr-OH) study. Ann Intensive Care 6(1)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kang H, Zhao Z, Tong Z (2020) Effect of high-flow nasal cannula oxygen therapy in immunocompromised subjects with acute respiratory failure. Respir Care 65(3):369–376</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4187/respcare.07205</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rhodes A, Ferdinande P, Flaatten H, Guidet B, Metnitz P, Moreno R (2012) The variability of critical care bed numbers in Europe. Intensive Care Med 38(10):1647–1653</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00134-012-2627-8</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Department of Health (2000) Comprehensive critical care: a review of adult critical care services [Internet]. National Archives. [cited 10 March 2021]. Available from: https://webarchive.nationalarchives.gov.uk/20121014090959/http://www.dh.gov.uk/prod_consum_dh/groups/dh_digitalassets/@dh/@en/documents/digitalasset/dh_4082872.pdf</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pattison N, O’Gara G, Wigmore T (2015) Negotiating transitions: involvement of critical care outreach teams in end-of-life decision making. Am J Crit Care 24(3):232–240</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4037/ajcc2015715</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Davies J (2019) Noninvasive respiratory support at the end of life. Respir Care 64(6):701–711</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Papazian L, Corley A, Hess D, Fraser J, Frat J, Guitton C et al (2016) Use of high-flow nasal cannula oxygenation in ICU adults: a narrative review. Intensive Care Med 42(9):1336–1349</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00134-016-4277-8</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pirret A, Takerei S, Matheson C, Kelly M, Strickland W, Harford J et al (2017) Nasal high flow oxygen therapy in the ward setting: a prospective observational study. Intensive Crit Care Nurs 42:127–134</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.iccn.2017.04.001</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
