<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35394085</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>09</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>09</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1098-1136</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>70</Volume>
            <Issue>7</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jul</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Glia</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Glia</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Microglia maintain the normal structure and function of the hippocampal astrocyte network.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>1359</StartPage>
          <EndPage>1379</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>1359-1379</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/glia.24179</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Microglial control of activity-dependent plasticity and synaptic remodeling in neuronal networks has been the subject of intense research in the past several years. Although microglia-neuron interactions have been extensively studied, less is known about how microglia influence astrocyte-dependent control over neuronal structure and function. Here, we explored a role for microglia in regulating the structure and function of the astrocyte syncytium in mouse hippocampus. After depleting microglia using a CSF1R antagonist (PLX5622, Plexxikon), we observed severe disruption of astrocyte syncytial isopotentiality and dye coupling. A decrease in astrocyte-specific gap junction connexin (Cx) 30 and 43 expression, at least partially accounts for these microglia-dependent changes in astrocytes. Because neuronal function requires intact astrocyte coupling, we also evaluated the effects of microglia depletion on synaptic transmission in the hippocampus. Without microglia, the strength of synaptic transmission was reduced at baseline and after long-term potentiation (LTP). Conversely, priming microglia with systemic injections of lipopolysaccharide enhanced CA3-CA1 synaptic transmission. This microglia-induced scaling of synaptic transmission was associated with increased expression of post-synaptic scaffold proteins (Homer1) in CA1. However, astrocyte network function was not affected by microglia priming, indicating that microglia-dependent effects on astrocytes and neurons vary across functional states. Through manipulation of microglia in the brain, our results reveal the importance of microglia in homeostatic regulation of the astrocyte syncytium and scaling of synaptic transmission. These novel mechanisms uncover a new direction for future studies interrogating microglia function in various physiological and pathological contexts.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Authors. GLIA published by Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Du</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yixing</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7728-7095</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience, The Ohio State University Wexner Medical Center, Columbus, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Brennan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Faith H</ForeName>
            <Initials>FH</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9201-2476</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience, The Ohio State University Wexner Medical Center, Columbus, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Center for Brain and Spinal Cord Repair, The Ohio State University Wexner Medical Center, Columbus, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Popovich</LastName>
            <ForeName>Phillip G</ForeName>
            <Initials>PG</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1329-7395</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience, The Ohio State University Wexner Medical Center, Columbus, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Center for Brain and Spinal Cord Repair, The Ohio State University Wexner Medical Center, Columbus, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhou</LastName>
            <ForeName>Min</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6249-2977</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience, The Ohio State University Wexner Medical Center, Columbus, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <GrantList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>R01NS099532</GrantID>
            <Acronym>NH</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>R01NS083942</GrantID>
            <Acronym>NH</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>R35NS111582</GrantID>
            <Acronym>NH</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>RO1NS116059</GrantID>
            <Acronym>NH</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>R01NS099532</GrantID>
            <Acronym>NH</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>R01NS083942</GrantID>
            <Acronym>NH</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>R35NS111582</GrantID>
            <Acronym>NH</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>RO1NS116059</GrantID>
            <Acronym>NH</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
        </GrantList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>04</Month>
          <Day>08</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Glia</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8806785</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0894-1491</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000075302">Connexin 30</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001253" MajorTopicYN="Y">Astrocytes</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000075302" MajorTopicYN="N">Connexin 30</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006624" MajorTopicYN="N">Hippocampus</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017774" MajorTopicYN="N">Long-Term Potentiation</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017628" MajorTopicYN="Y">Microglia</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009473" MajorTopicYN="N">Neuronal Plasticity</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009435" MajorTopicYN="N">Synaptic Transmission</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">astrocytes</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hippocampus</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">microglia</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">synaptic plasticity</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">synaptic transmission</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
          <Hour>8</Hour>
          <Minute>47</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35394085</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/glia.24179</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Akiyoshi, R., Wake, H., Kato, D., Horiuchi, H., Ono, R., Ikegami, A., Haruwaka, K., Omori, T., Tachibana, Y., Moorhouse, A. J., &amp; Nabekura, J. (2018). Microglia enhance synapse activity to promote local network synchronization. eNeuro, 5(5), ENEURO.0088-18.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Araque, A., Carmignoto, G., Haydon, P. G., Oliet, S. H., Robitaille, R., &amp; Volterra, A. (2014). Gliotransmitters travel in time and space. Neuron, 81(4), 728-739.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Askew, K., Li, K., Olmos-Alonso, A., Garcia-Moreno, F., Liang, Y., Richardson, P., Tipton, T., Chapman, M. A., Riecken, K., Beccari, S., Sierra, A., Molnar, Z., Cragg, M. S., Garaschuk, O., Perry, V. H., &amp; Gomez-Nicola, D. (2017). Coupled proliferation and apoptosis maintain the rapid turnover of microglia in the adult brain. Cell Reports, 18(2), 391-405.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Badimon, A., Strasburger, H. J., Ayata, P., Chen, X., Nair, A., Ikegami, A., Hwang, P., Chan, A. T., Graves, S. M., Uweru, J. O., Ledderose, C., Kutlu, M. G., Wheeler, M. A., Kahan, A., Ishikawa, M., Wang, Y. C., Loh, Y. E., Jiang, J. X., Surmeier, D. J., … Schaefer, A. (2020). Negative feedback control of neuronal activity by microglia. Nature, 586(7829), 417-423.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Banerjee, A., Luong, J. A., Ho, A., Saib, A. O., &amp; Ploski, J. E. (2016). Overexpression of Homer1a in the basal and lateral amygdala impairs fear conditioning and induces an autism-like social impairment. Molecular Autism, 7, 16.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Basilico, B., Ferrucci, L., Ratano, P., Golia, M. T., Grimaldi, A., Rosito, M., Ferretti, V., Reverte, I., Sanchini, C., Marrone, M. C., Giubettini, M., De Turris, V., Salerno, D., Garofalo, S., St-Pierre, M. K., Carrier, M., Renzi, M., Pagani, F., Modi, B., … Ragozzino, D. (2022). Microglia control glutamatergic synapses in the adult mouse hippocampus. Glia, 70(1), 173-195.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bellot-Saez, A., Kekesi, O., Morley, J. W., &amp; Buskila, Y. (2017). Astrocytic modulation of neuronal excitability through K(+) spatial buffering. Neuroscience and Biobehavioral Reviews, 77, 87-97.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen, Z., Jalabi, W., Hu, W., Park, H. J., Gale, J. T., Kidd, G. J., Bernatowicz, R., Gossman, Z. C., Chen, J. T., Dutta, R., &amp; Trapp, B. D. (2014). Microglial displacement of inhibitory synapses provides neuroprotection in the adult brain. Nature Communications, 5, 4486.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen, Z., Jalabi, W., Shpargel, K. B., Farabaugh, K. T., Dutta, R., Yin, X., Kidd, G. J., Bergmann, C. C., Stohlman, S. A., &amp; Trapp, B. D. (2012). Lipopolysaccharide-induced microglial activation and neuroprotection against experimental brain injury is independent of hematogenous TLR4. The Journal of Neuroscience, 32(34), 11706-11715.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chung, W. S., Clarke, L. E., Wang, G. X., Stafford, B. K., Sher, A., Chakraborty, C., Joung, J., Foo, L. C., Thompson, A., Chen, C., Smith, S. J., &amp; Barres, B. A. (2013). Astrocytes mediate synapse elimination through MEGF10 and MERTK pathways. Nature, 504(7480), 394-400.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clark, A. K., Gruber-Schoffnegger, D., Drdla-Schutting, R., Gerhold, K. J., Malcangio, M., &amp; Sandkuhler, J. (2015). Selective activation of microglia facilitates synaptic strength. The Journal of Neuroscience, 35(11), 4552-4570.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clifton, N. E., Trent, S., Thomas, K. L., &amp; Hall, J. (2019). Regulation and function of activity-dependent Homer in synaptic plasticity. Molecular Neuropsychiatry, 5(3), 147-161.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Corsi, G., Picard, K., di Castro, M. A., Garofalo, S., Tucci, F., Chece, G., Del Percio, C., Golia, M. T., Raspa, M., Scavizzi, F., Decoeur, F., Lauro, C., Rigamonti, M., Iannello, F., Ragozzino, D. A., Russo, E., Bernardini, G., Nadjar, A., Tremblay, M. E., … Limatola, C. (2022). Microglia modulate hippocampal synaptic transmission and sleep duration along the light/dark cycle. Glia, 70(1), 89-105.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Crapser, J. D., Spangenberg, E. E., Barahona, R. A., Arreola, M. A., Hohsfield, L. A., &amp; Green, K. N. (2020). Microglia facilitate loss of perineuronal nets in the Alzheimer's disease brain. eBioMedicine, 58, 102919.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cserep, C., Posfai, B., Lenart, N., Fekete, R., Laszlo, Z. I., Lele, Z., Orsolits, B., Molnar, G., Heindl, S., Schwarcz, A. D., Ujvari, K., Kornyei, Z., Toth, K., Szabadits, E., Sperlagh, B., Baranyi, M., Csiba, L., Hortobagyi, T., Magloczky, Z., … Denes, A. (2020). Microglia monitor and protect neuronal function through specialized somatic purinergic junctions. Science, 367(6477), 528-537.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cui, Z., Zhou, L., Liu, C., Zhu, G., Wu, X., Yan, Y., Xia, X., Ben, Z., Song, Y., Zhou, Y., Zhang, H., &amp; Zhang, D. (2015). The role of Homer1b/c in neuronal apoptosis following LPS-induced neuroinflammation. Neurochemical Research, 40(1), 204-215.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dagher, N. N., Najafi, A. R., Kayala, K. M., Elmore, M. R., White, T. E., Medeiros, R., West, B. L., &amp; Green, K. N. (2015). Colony-stimulating factor 1 receptor inhibition prevents microglial plaque association and improves cognition in 3xTg-AD mice. Journal of Neuroinflammation, 12, 139.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dallerac, G., Chever, O., &amp; Rouach, N. (2013). How do astrocytes shape synaptic transmission? Insights from electrophysiology. Frontiers in Cellular Neuroscience, 7, 159.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Datko, M. C., Hu, J. H., Williams, M., Reyes, C. M., Lominac, K. D., von Jonquieres, G., Klugmann, M., Worley, P. F., &amp; Szumlinski, K. K. (2017). Behavioral and neurochemical phenotyping of mice incapable of Homer1a induction. Frontiers in Behavioral Neuroscience, 11, 208.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>David, Y., Cacheaux, L. P., Ivens, S., Lapilover, E., Heinemann, U., Kaufer, D., &amp; Friedman, A. (2009). Astrocytic dysfunction in epileptogenesis: Consequence of altered potassium and glutamate homeostasis? The Journal of Neuroscience, 29(34), 10588-10599.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deng, W., Aimone, J. B., &amp; Gage, F. H. (2010). New neurons and new memories: How does adult hippocampal neurogenesis affect learning and memory? Nature Reviews. Neuroscience, 11(5), 339-350.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Du, Y., Kiyoshi, C. M., Terman, D., &amp; Zhou, M. (2020). Analysis of the functional states of an astrocyte syncytium. Basic Neurobiology Techniques, 152, 285-313.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Du, Y., Kiyoshi, C. M., Wang, Q., Wang, W., Ma, B., Alford, C. C., Zhong, S., Wan, Q., Chen, H., Lloyd, E. E., Bryan, R. M., Jr., &amp; Zhou, M. (2016). Genetic deletion of TREK-1 or TWIK-1/TREK-1 potassium channels does not Alter the basic electrophysiological properties of mature hippocampal astrocytes in situ. Frontiers in Cellular Neuroscience, 10, 13.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Du, Y., Ma, B., Kiyoshi, C. M., Alford, C. C., Wang, W., &amp; Zhou, M. (2015). Freshly dissociated mature hippocampal astrocytes exhibit passive membrane conductance and low membrane resistance similarly to syncytial coupled astrocytes. Journal of Neurophysiology, 113(10), 3744-3750.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Du, Y., Wang, W., Lutton, A. D., Kiyoshi, C. M., Ma, B., Taylor, A. T., Olesik, J. W., McTigue, D. M., Askwith, C. C., &amp; Zhou, M. (2018). Dissipation of transmembrane potassium gradient is the main cause of cerebral ischemia-induced depolarization in astrocytes and neurons. Experimental Neurology, 303, 1-11.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eitelmann, S., Petersilie, L., Rose, C. R., &amp; Stephan, J. (2020). Altered gap junction network topography in mouse models for human hereditary deafness. International Journal of Molecular Sciences, 21(19), 7376.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ellacott, K. L., Morton, G. J., Woods, S. C., Tso, P., &amp; Schwartz, M. W. (2010). Assessment of feeding behavior in laboratory mice. Cell Metabolism, 12(1), 10-17.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elmore, M. R., Lee, R. J., West, B. L., &amp; Green, K. N. (2015). Characterizing newly repopulated microglia in the adult mouse: Impacts on animal behavior, cell morphology, and neuroinflammation. PLoS One, 10(4), e0122912.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elmore, M. R., Najafi, A. R., Koike, M. A., Dagher, N. N., Spangenberg, E. E., Rice, R. A., Kitazawa, M., Matusow, B., Nguyen, H., West, B. L., &amp; Green, K. N. (2014). Colony-stimulating factor 1 receptor signaling is necessary for microglia viability, unmasking a microglia progenitor cell in the adult brain. Neuron, 82(2), 380-397.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eroglu, C., &amp; Barres, B. A. (2010). Regulation of synaptic connectivity by glia. Nature, 468(7321), 223-231.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eyo, U. B., Peng, J., Swiatkowski, P., Mukherjee, A., Bispo, A., &amp; Wu, L. J. (2014). Neuronal hyperactivity recruits microglial processes via neuronal NMDA receptors and microglial P2Y12 receptors after status epilepticus. The Journal of Neuroscience, 34(32), 10528-10540.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fawcett, J. W., Oohashi, T., &amp; Pizzorusso, T. (2019). The roles of perineuronal nets and the perinodal extracellular matrix in neuronal function. Nature Reviews. Neuroscience, 20, 451-465.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Freria, C. M., Brennan, F. H., Sweet, D. R., Guan, Z., Hall, J. C., Kigerl, K. A., Nemeth, D. P., Liu, X., Lacroix, S., Quan, N., &amp; Popovich, P. G. (2020). Serial systemic injections of endotoxin (LPS) elicit neuroprotective spinal cord microglia through IL-1-dependent cross-talk with endothelial cells. The Journal of Neuroscience, 40, 9103-9120.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gajardo-Gomez, R., Labra, V. C., &amp; Orellana, J. A. (2016). Connexins and Pannexins: New insights into microglial functions and dysfunctions. Frontiers in Molecular Neuroscience, 9, 86.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Green, K. N., &amp; Hume, D. A. (2021). On the utility of CSF1R inhibitors. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 118(4), e2019695118.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guttenplan, K. A., Weigel, M. K., Prakash, P., Wijewardhane, P. R., Hasel, P., Rufen-Blanchette, U., Munch, A. E., Blum, J. A., Fine, J., Neal, M. C., Bruce, K. D., Gitler, A. D., Chopra, G., Liddelow, S. A., &amp; Barres, B. A. (2021). Neurotoxic reactive astrocytes induce cell death via saturated lipids. Nature, 599(7883), 102-107.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haruwaka, K., Ikegami, A., Tachibana, Y., Ohno, N., Konishi, H., Hashimoto, A., Matsumoto, M., Kato, D., Ono, R., Kiyama, H., Moorhouse, A. J., Nabekura, J., &amp; Wake, H. (2019). Dual microglia effects on blood brain barrier permeability induced by systemic inflammation. Nature Communications, 10(1), 5816.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heise, C., Schroeder, J. C., Schoen, M., Halbedl, S., Reim, D., Woelfle, S., Kreutz, M. R., Schmeisser, M. J., &amp; Boeckers, T. M. (2016). Selective localization of shanks to VGLUT1-positive excitatory synapses in the mouse hippocampus. Frontiers in Cellular Neuroscience, 10, 106.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huang, M., Du, Y., Kiyoshi, C. M., Wu, X., Askwith, C., McTigue, D. M., &amp; Zhou, M. (2018). Syncytial Isopotentiality: An electrical feature of spinal cord astrocyte networks. Neuroglia, 1(1), 271-279.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huguet, G., Joglekar, A., Messi, L. M., Buckalew, R., Wong, S., &amp; Terman, D. (2016). Neuroprotective role of gap junctions in a neuron astrocyte network model. Biophysical Journal, 111(2), 452-462.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Inoue, N., Nakao, H., Migishima, R., Hino, T., Matsui, M., Hayashi, F., Nakao, K., Manabe, T., Aiba, A., &amp; Inokuchi, K. (2009). Requirement of the immediate early gene vesl-1S/homer-1a for fear memory formation. Molecular Brain, 2, 7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ippolito, D. M., &amp; Eroglu, C. (2010). Quantifying synapses: An immunocytochemistry-based assay to quantify synapse number. Journal of Visualized Experiments, 16(45), 2270.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jha, M. K., Jo, M., Kim, J. H., &amp; Suk, K. (2019). Microglia-astrocyte crosstalk: An intimate molecular conversation. The Neuroscientist, 25(3), 227-240.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kelly, T., Kafitz, K. W., Roderigo, C., &amp; Rose, C. R. (2009). Ammonium-evoked alterations in intracellular sodium and pH reduce glial glutamate transport activity. Glia, 57(9), 921-934.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kiyoshi, C. M., Du, Y., Zhong, S., Wang, W., Taylor, A. T., Xiong, B., Ma, B., Terman, D., &amp; Zhou, M. (2018). Syncytial isopotentiality: A system-wide electrical feature of astrocytic networks in the brain. Glia, 66(12), 2756-2769.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kiyoshi, C. M., &amp; Zhou, M. (2019). Astrocyte syncytium: A functional reticular system in the brain. Neural Regeneration Research, 14(4), 595-596.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lacroix, S., Feinstein, D., &amp; Rivest, S. (1998). The bacterial endotoxin lipopolysaccharide has the ability to target the brain in upregulating its membrane CD14 receptor within specific cellular populations. Brain Pathology, 8(4), 625-640.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leis, J. A., Bekar, L. K., &amp; Walz, W. (2005). Potassium homeostasis in the ischemic brain. Glia, 50(4), 407-416.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li, T., Chiou, B., Gilman, C. K., Luo, R., Koshi, T., Yu, D., Oak, H. C., Giera, S., Johnson-Venkatesh, E., Muthukumar, A. K., Stevens, B., Umemori, H., &amp; Piao, X. (2020). A splicing isoform of GPR56 mediates microglial synaptic refinement via phosphatidylserine binding. European Molecular Biology Organization journal, 39(16), e104136.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li, W. Y., Chang, Y. C., Lee, L. J., &amp; Lee, L. J. (2014). Prenatal infection affects the neuronal architecture and cognitive function in adult mice. Developmental Neuroscience, 36(5), 359-370.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li, Y., Du, X. F., Liu, C. S., Wen, Z. L., &amp; Du, J. L. (2012). Reciprocal regulation between resting microglial dynamics and neuronal activity in vivo. Developmental Cell, 23(6), 1189-1202.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liddelow, S. A., Guttenplan, K. A., Clarke, L. E., Bennett, F. C., Bohlen, C. J., Schirmer, L., Bennett, M. L., Munch, A. E., Chung, W. S., Peterson, T. C., Wilton, D. K., Frouin, A., Napier, B. A., Panicker, N., Kumar, M., Buckwalter, M. S., Rowitch, D. H., Dawson, V. L., Dawson, T. M., … Barres, B. A. (2017). Neurotoxic reactive astrocytes are induced by activated microglia. Nature, 541(7638), 481-487.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu, Y. J., Spangenberg, E. E., Tang, B., Holmes, T. C., Green, K. N., &amp; Xu, X. (2021). Microglia elimination increases neural circuit connectivity and activity in adult mouse cortex. The Journal of Neuroscience, 41(6), 1274-1287.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ma, B., Buckalew, R., Du, Y., Kiyoshi, C. M., Alford, C. C., Wang, W., McTigue, D. M., Enyeart, J. J., Terman, D., &amp; Zhou, M. (2016). Gap junction coupling confers isopotentiality on astrocyte syncytium. Glia, 64(2), 214-226.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ma, B., Xu, G., Wang, W., Enyeart, J. J., &amp; Zhou, M. (2014). Dual patch voltage clamp study of low membrane resistance astrocytes in situ. Molecular Brain, 7, 18.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ma, B. F., Xie, M. J., &amp; Zhou, M. (2012). Bicarbonate efflux via GABA(a) receptors depolarizes membrane potential and inhibits two-pore domain potassium channels of astrocytes in rat hippocampal slices. Glia, 60(11), 1761-1772.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>MacAulay, N. (2020). Molecular mechanisms of K(+) clearance and extracellular space shrinkage-glia cells as the stars. Glia, 68, 2192-2211.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martinez-Banaclocha, M. (2020). Astroglial Isopotentiality and calcium-associated biomagnetic field effects on cortical neuronal coupling. Cells, 9(2), 439.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mayorquin, L. C., Rodriguez, A. V., Sutachan, J. J., &amp; Albarracin, S. L. (2018). Connexin-mediated functional and metabolic coupling between astrocytes and neurons. Frontiers in Molecular Neuroscience, 11, 118.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miyamoto, A., Wake, H., Ishikawa, A. W., Eto, K., Shibata, K., Murakoshi, H., Koizumi, S., Moorhouse, A. J., Yoshimura, Y., &amp; Nabekura, J. (2016). Microglia contact induces synapse formation in developing somatosensory cortex. Nature Communications, 7, 12540.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mostany, R., Anstey, J. E., Crump, K. L., Maco, B., Knott, G., &amp; Portera-Cailliau, C. (2013). Altered synaptic dynamics during normal brain aging. The Journal of Neuroscience, 33(9), 4094-4104.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nguyen, P. T., Dorman, L. C., Pan, S., Vainchtein, I. D., Han, R. T., Nakao-Inoue, H., Taloma, S. E., Barron, J. J., Molofsky, A. B., Kheirbek, M. A., &amp; Molofsky, A. V. (2020). Microglial remodeling of the extracellular matrix promotes synapse plasticity. Cell, 182(2), 388-403.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nimmerjahn, A., Kirchhoff, F., Kerr, J. N., &amp; Helmchen, F. (2004). Sulforhodamine 101 as a specific marker of astroglia in the neocortex in vivo. Nature Methods, 1(1), 31-37.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pannasch, U., Vargova, L., Reingruber, J., Ezan, P., Holcman, D., Giaume, C., Sykova, E., &amp; Rouach, N. (2011). Astroglial networks scale synaptic activity and plasticity. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 108(20), 8467-8472.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parkhurst, C. N., Yang, G., Ninan, I., Savas, J. N., Yates, J. R., 3rd, Lafaille, J. J., Hempstead, B. L., Littman, D. R., &amp; Gan, W. B. (2013). Microglia promote learning-dependent synapse formation through brain-derived neurotrophic factor. Cell, 155(7), 1596-1609.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pascual, O., Ben Achour, S., Rostaing, P., Triller, A., &amp; Bessis, A. (2012). Microglia activation triggers astrocyte-mediated modulation of excitatory neurotransmission. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 109(4), 197-205.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rothhammer, V., Borucki, D. M., Tjon, E. C., Takenaka, M. C., Chao, C. C., Ardura-Fabregat, A., de Lima, K. A., Gutierrez-Vazquez, C., Hewson, P., Staszewski, O., Blain, M., Healy, L., Neziraj, T., Borio, M., Wheeler, M., Dragin, L. L., Laplaud, D. A., Antel, J., Alvarez, J. I., … Quintana, F. J. (2018). Microglial control of astrocytes in response to microbial metabolites. Nature, 557(7707), 724-728.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rozov, A., Zivkovic, A. R., &amp; Schwarz, M. K. (2012). Homer1 gene products orchestrate ca(2+)-permeable AMPA receptor distribution and LTP expression. Frontiers in Synaptic Neuroscience, 4, 4.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schafer, D. P., Lehrman, E. K., Kautzman, A. G., Koyama, R., Mardinly, A. R., Yamasaki, R., Ransohoff, R. M., Greenberg, M. E., Barres, B. A., &amp; Stevens, B. (2012). Microglia sculpt postnatal neural circuits in an activity and complement-dependent manner. Neuron, 74(4), 691-705.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schoenenberger, P., O'Neill, J., &amp; Csicsvari, J. (2016). Activity-dependent plasticity of hippocampal place maps. Nature Communications, 7, 11824.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Seemann, S., Zohles, F., &amp; Lupp, A. (2017). Comprehensive comparison of three different animal models for systemic inflammation. Journal of Biomedical Science, 24(1), 60.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shi, S. X., Li, Y. J., Shi, K., Wood, K., Ducruet, A. F., &amp; Liu, Q. (2020). IL (interleukin)-15 bridges astrocyte-microglia crosstalk and exacerbates brain injury following intracerebral hemorrhage. Stroke, 51(3), 967-974.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Somjen, G. G. (1979). Extracellular potassium in the mammalian central nervous system. Annual Review of Physiology, 41, 159-177.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Spangenberg, E., Severson, P. L., Hohsfield, L. A., Crapser, J., Zhang, J., Burton, E. A., Zhang, Y., Spevak, W., Lin, J., Phan, N. Y., Habets, G., Rymar, A., Tsang, G., Walters, J., Nespi, M., Singh, P., Broome, S., Ibrahim, P., Zhang, C., … Green, K. N. (2019). Sustained microglial depletion with CSF1R inhibitor impairs parenchymal plaque development in an Alzheimer's disease model. Nature Communications, 10(1), 3758.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Steinhauser, C., Seifert, G., &amp; Bedner, P. (2012). Astrocyte dysfunction in temporal lobe epilepsy: K+ channels and gap junction coupling. Glia, 60(8), 1192-1202.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stephan, J., Eitelmann, S., &amp; Zhou, M. (2021). Approaches to study gap junctional coupling. Frontiers in Cellular Neuroscience, 15, 640406.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Szabo, Z., Heja, L., Szalay, G., Kekesi, O., Furedi, A., Szebenyi, K., Dobolyi, A., Orban, T. I., Kolacsek, O., Tompa, T., Miskolczy, Z., Biczok, L., Rozsa, B., Sarkadi, B., &amp; Kardos, J. (2017). Extensive astrocyte synchronization advances neuronal coupling in slow wave activity in vivo. Scientific Reports, 7(1), 6018.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tu, J. C., Xiao, B., Naisbitt, S., Yuan, J. P., Petralia, R. S., Brakeman, P., Doan, A., Aakalu, V. K., Lanahan, A. A., Sheng, M., &amp; Worley, P. F. (1999). Coupling of mGluR/Homer and PSD-95 complexes by the shank family of postsynaptic density proteins. Neuron, 23(3), 583-592.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tu, J. C., Xiao, B., Yuan, J. P., Lanahan, A. A., Leoffert, K., Li, M., Linden, D. J., &amp; Worley, P. F. (1998). Homer binds a novel proline-rich motif and links group 1 metabotropic glutamate receptors with IP3 receptors. Neuron, 21(4), 717-726.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vainchtein, I. D., Chin, G., Cho, F. S., Kelley, K. W., Miller, J. G., Chien, E. C., Liddelow, S. A., Nguyen, P. T., Nakao-Inoue, H., Dorman, L. C., Akil, O., Joshita, S., Barres, B. A., Paz, J. T., Molofsky, A. B., &amp; Molofsky, A. V. (2018). Astrocyte-derived interleukin-33 promotes microglial synapse engulfment and neural circuit development. Science, 359(6381), 1269-1273.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Venturino, A., Schulz, R., De Jesus-Cortes, H., Maes, M. E., Nagy, B., Reilly-Andujar, F., Colombo, G., Cubero, R. J. A., Schoot Uiterkamp, F. E., Bear, M. F., &amp; Siegert, S. (2021). Microglia enable mature perineuronal nets disassembly upon anesthetic ketamine exposure or 60-Hz light entrainment in the healthy brain. Cell Reports, 36(1), 109313.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vivani, B., Bartesaghi, S., Gardoni, F., Vezzani, A., Behrens, M. M., Bartfai, T., Binaglia, M., Corsini, E., Di Luca, M., Galli, C. L., &amp; Marinovich, M. (2003). Interleukin-1β enhances NMDA receptor-mediated intracellular calcium increase through activation of the Src family of kinases. The Journal of Neuroscience, 23(25), 8692-8700.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wagner, K. V., Hartmann, J., Mangold, K., Wang, X. D., Labermaier, C., Liebl, C., Wolf, M., Gassen, N. C., Holsboer, F., Rein, T., Muller, M. B., &amp; Schmidt, M. V. (2013). Homer1 mediates acute stress-induced cognitive deficits in the dorsal hippocampus. The Journal of Neuroscience, 33(9), 3857-3864.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wake, H., Moorhouse, A. J., Jinno, S., Kohsaka, S., &amp; Nabekura, J. (2009). Resting microglia directly monitor the functional state of synapses in vivo and determine the fate of ischemic terminals. The Journal of Neuroscience, 29(13), 3974-3980.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Webb, S. D., &amp; Orton, L. D. (2019). Iba1+ microglia colocalize with synaptophysin+ and Homer1+ puncta and reveal two novel sub-types of GABAergic neuron in Guinea pig inferior colliculus. BioRxiv, 1-45. https://doi.org/10.1101/606509</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Willis, E. F., MacDonald, K. P. A., Nguyen, Q. H., Garrido, A. L., Gillespie, E. R., Harley, S. B. R., Bartlett, P. F., Schroder, W. A., Yates, A. G., Anthony, D. C., Rose-John, S., Ruitenberg, M. J., &amp; Vukovic, J. (2020). Repopulating microglia promote brain repair in an IL-6-dependent manner. Cell, 180(5), 833-846.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu, W., Li, Y., Wei, Y., Bosco, D. B., Xie, M., Zhao, M. G., Richardson, J. R., &amp; Wu, L. J. (2020). Microglial depletion aggravates the severity of acute and chronic seizures in mice. Brain, Behavior, and Immunity, 89, 245-255.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu, G., Wang, W., Kimelberg, H. K., &amp; Zhou, M. (2010). Electrical coupling of astrocytes in rat hippocampal slices under physiological and simulated ischemic conditions. Glia, 58(4), 481-493.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang, C., Hung, S., Hsu, S., MacDonald, I., Lin, J., Luo, S., Lin, P., &amp; Chen, Y. (2019). Inhibiting the LPS-induced enhancement of mEPSC frequency in superficial dorsal horn neurons may serve as an electrophysiological model for alleviating pain. Scientific Reports, 9(1), 16032.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yegla, B., Boles, J., Kumar, A., &amp; Foster, T. C. (2021). Partial microglial depletion is associated with impaired hippocampal synaptic and cognitive function in young and aged rats. Glia, 69(6), 1494-1514.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yun, S. P., Kam, T. I., Panicker, N., Kim, S., Oh, Y., Park, J. S., Kwon, S. H., Park, Y. J., Karuppagounder, S. S., Park, H., Oh, N., Kim, N. A., Lee, S., Brahmachari, S., Mao, X., Lee, J. H., Kumar, M., An, D., Kang, S. U., … Ko, H. S. (2018). Block of A1 astrocyte conversion by microglia is neuroprotective in models of Parkinson's disease. Nature Medicine, 24(7), 931-938.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhong, S., Du, Y., Kiyoshi, C. M., Ma, B., Alford, C. C., Wang, Q., Yang, Y., Liu, X., &amp; Zhou, M. (2016). Electrophysiological behavior of neonatal astrocytes in hippocampal stratum radiatum. Molecular Brain, 9, 34.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhou, L. J., Peng, J., Xu, Y. N., Zeng, W. J., Zhang, J., Wei, X., Mai, C. L., Lin, Z. J., Liu, Y., Murugan, M., Eyo, U. B., Umpierre, A. D., Xin, W. J., Chen, T., Li, M., Wang, H., Richardson, J. R., Tan, Z., Liu, X. G., &amp; Wu, L. J. (2019). Microglia are indispensable for synaptic plasticity in the spinal dorsal horn and chronic pain. Cell Reports, 27(13), 3844-3859.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhou, L. J., Yang, T., Wei, X., Liu, Y., Xin, W. J., Chen, Y., Pang, R. P., Zang, Y., Li, Y. Y., &amp; Liu, X. G. (2011). Brain-derived neurotrophic factor contributes to spinal long-term potentiation and mechanical hypersensitivity by activation of spinal microglia in rat. Brain, Behavior, and Immunity, 25(2), 322-334.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhou, M., Du, Y., Aten, S., &amp; Terman, D. (2021). On the electrical passivity of astrocyte potassium conductance. Journal of Neurophysiology, 126(4), 1403-1419.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhou, M., Xu, G., Xie, M., Zhang, X., Schools, G. P., Ma, L., Kimelberg, H. K., &amp; Chen, H. (2009). TWIK-1 and TREK-1 are potassium channels contributing significantly to astrocyte passive conductance in rat hippocampal slices. The Journal of Neuroscience, 29(26), 8551-8564.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zucker, R. S., &amp; Regehr, W. G. (2002). Short-term synaptic plasticity. Annual Review of Physiology, 64, 355-405.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
