<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35394612</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>08</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1878-7479</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Apr</Month>
              <Day>08</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Neurotherapeutics : the journal of the American Society for Experimental NeuroTherapeutics</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Neurotherapeutics</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Antibody Therapies in Autoimmune Inflammatory Myopathies: Promising Treatment Options.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s13311-022-01220-z</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Inflammatory myopathies, including polymyositis (PM), dermatomyositis (DM), inclusion body myositis (IBM), necrotizing myopathy (NM), antisynthetase syndrome (ASS) and overlap myositis (OM), in short myositis, are rare diseases. All forms of myositis have progressive muscle weakness in common, with each subtype characterized by different autoantibody profiles, histological findings and extramuscular manifestations. Due to better understanding of the pathogenesis of the muscle inflammation in myositis, new molecular pathways for targeted therapy have been discovered. Current therapies aim at different components of the innate or the adaptive immune response. Additionally, non-inflammatory mechanisms in myositis have come into focus as possible treatment targets. The use of therapeutical antibodies in myositis has been examined in various clinical studies, several of them randomized controlled ones: Depletion of B-cells by rituximab has been established as treatment of refractory myositis. IVIG, an antibody therapy in the wider sense, has now been licensed for DM following a recent positive clinical trial. Negative study results were reported in randomized trials with infliximab, sifalimumab and bimagrumab. Studies on basiliximab and eculizumab are currently underway, and are expected to yield results in a couple of years. Despite some promising results of clinical studies with antibody therapy in myositis, further research is crucial to optimize the treatment for this debilitating disease and to find treatment alternatives for treatment-refractory patients.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zeng</LastName>
            <ForeName>Rachel</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Muscle Immunobiology Group, Neuromuscular Center, Department of Neurology, University Medical Center Göttingen, Göttingen, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Glaubitz</LastName>
            <ForeName>Stefanie</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Muscle Immunobiology Group, Neuromuscular Center, Department of Neurology, University Medical Center Göttingen, Göttingen, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Schmidt</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jens</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5589-2371</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Muscle Immunobiology Group, Neuromuscular Center, Department of Neurology, University Medical Center Göttingen, Göttingen, Germany. j.schmidt@gmx.org.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology and Pain Treatment, Immanuel Klinik Rüdersdorf, University Hospital of the Brandenburg Medical School Theodor Fontane, Rüdersdorf bei Berlin, Germany. j.schmidt@gmx.org.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Faculty of Health Sciences Brandenburg, Brandenburg Medical School Theodor Fontane, Rüdersdorf bei Berlin, Germany. j.schmidt@gmx.org.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>04</Month>
          <Day>08</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Neurotherapeutics</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101290381</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1878-7479</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Antibodies</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Clinical trial</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Inflammatory myopathies</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Myositis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rituximab</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>12</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35394612</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13311-022-01220-z</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s13311-022-01220-z</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lilleker JB, Vencovsky J, Wang G, et al. The EuroMyositis registry: an international collaborative tool to facilitate myositis research. Ann Rheum Dis. 2018;77:30–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28855174</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pachman LM, Lipton R, Ramsey-Goldman R, et al. History of infection before the onset of juvenile dermatomyositis: Results from the National Institute of Arthritis and Musculoskeletal and Skin Diseases Research Registry. Arthritis Rheum. 2005;53:166–72.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15818654</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lundberg IE, Tjärnlund A, Bottai M, et al. 2017 European League Against Rheumatism/American College of Rheumatology classification criteria for adult and juvenile idiopathic inflammatory myopathies and their major subgroups. Ann Rheum Dis. 2017;76:1955–64.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29079590</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lundberg IE, de Visser M, Werth VP. Classification of myositis. Nat Rev Rheumatol. 2018;14:269–78.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29651121</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moghadam-Kia S, Oddis CV, Sato S, Kuwana M, Aggarwal R. Antimelanoma differentiation-associated gene 5 antibody: Expanding the clinical spectrum in North American patients with dermatomyositis. J Rheumatol. 2017;44:319–25.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28089977</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang H, Peng Q, Yin L, et al. Identification of multiple cancer-associated myositis-specific autoantibodies in idiopathic inflammatory myopathies: a large longitudinal cohort study. Arthritis Res Ther. 2017;19:259.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29178913</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5702134</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dalakas MC, Hohlfeld R. Polymyositis and dermatomyositis. The Lancet. 2003;362:971–82.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dalakas MC. Muscle biopsy findings in inflammatory myopathies. Rheum Dis Clin North Am. 2002;28:779–98.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12506772</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mavroudis I, Petridis F, Kazis D. Inclusion body myositis. Genetics, biomarkers and muscle biopsy. Int J Neurosci. 2020;1–10.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rothwell S, Cooper RG, Lundberg IE, et al. Dense genotyping of immune-related loci in idiopathic inflammatory myopathies confirms HLA alleles as the strongest genetic risk factor and suggests different genetic background for major clinical subgroups. Ann Rheum Dis. 2016;75:1558–66.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26362759</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miller FW, Chen W, O’Hanlon TP, et al. Genome-wide association study identifies HLA 8.1 ancestral haplotype alleles as major genetic risk factors for myositis phenotypes. Genes Immun. 2015;16:470–80.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miller FW, Lamb JA, Schmidt J, Nagaraju K. Risk factors and disease mechanisms in myositis. Nat Rev Rheumatol. 2018;14:255–68.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29674613</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6745704</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barsotti S, Lundberg IE. Current treatment for myositis. Curr Treatm Opt Rheumatol. 2018;4:299–315.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30613465</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6299051</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zeng R, Glaubitz S, Schmidt J. Inflammatory myopathies: Shedding light on promising agents and combination therapies in clinical trials. Expert Opin Investig Drugs. 2021;30:1125–40.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34779311</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Glaubitz S, Zeng R, Schmidt J. New insights into the treatment of myositis. Ther Adv Musculoskelet Dis. 2020;12:1–14.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Souza RC, de Souza FHC, Miossi R, Shinjo SK. Efficacy and safety of leflunomide as an adjuvant drug in refractory dermatomyositis with primarily cutaneous activity. Clin Exp Rheumatol. 2017;35:1011–3.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28422003</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dalakas MC, Illa I, Dambrosia JM, et al. A controlled trial of high-dose intravenous immune globulin infusions as treatment for dermatomyositis. N Engl J Med. 1993;329:1993–2000.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8247075</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hoa SAT, Hudson M. Critical review of the role of intravenous immunoglobulins in idiopathic inflammatory myopathies. Semin Arthritis Rheum. 2017;46:488–508.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aggarwal R, Charles-Schoeman C, Schessl J, Dimachkie MM, Beckmann I, Levine T. Prospective, double-blind, randomized, placebo-controlled phase III study evaluating efficacy and safety of octagam 10% in patients with dermatomyositis (ProDERM Study). Medicine (Baltimore). 2021;100:e23677.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Souza JM, Hoff LS, Shinjo SK. Intravenous human immunoglobulin and/or methylprednisolone pulse therapies as a possible treat-to-target strategy in immune-mediated necrotizing myopathies. Rheumatol Int. 2019;39:1201–12.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30778655</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mammen AL, Tiniakou E. Intravenous immune globulin for statin-triggered autoimmune myopathy. N Engl J Med. 2015;373:1677–80.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lim J, Eftimov F, Verhamme C, et al. Intravenous immunoglobulins as first-line treatment in idiopathic inflammatory myopathies: a pilot study. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2021;60:1784–92.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tjärnlund A, Tang Q, Wick C, et al. Abatacept in the treatment of adult dermatomyositis and polymyositis: a randomised, phase IIb treatment delayed-start trial. Ann Rheum Dis. 2018;77:55–62.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28993346</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moghadam-Kia S, Charlton D, Aggarwal R, Oddis CV. Management of refractory cutaneous dermatomyositis: potential role of Janus kinase inhibition with tofacitinib. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2019;58:1011–5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ladislau L, Suárez-Calvet X, Toquet S, et al. JAK inhibitor improves type I interferon induced damage: Proof of concept in dermatomyositis. Brain. 2018;141:1609–21.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29741608</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paik JJ, Casciola-Rosen L, Shin JY, et al. Study of tofacitinib in refractory dermatomyositis: an open-label pilot study of ten patients. Arthritis Rheumatol (Hoboken, N.J.). 2021;73:858–65.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oddis CV, Reed AM, Aggarwal R, et al. Rituximab in the treatment of refractory adult and juvenile dermatomyositis and adult polymyositis: a randomized, placebo-phase trial. Arthritis Rheum. 2013;65:314–24.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23124935</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3558563</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hanna MG, Badrising UA, Benveniste O, et al. Safety and efficacy of intravenous bimagrumab in inclusion body myositis (RESILIENT): a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled phase 2b trial. Lancet Neurol. 2019;18:834–44.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31397289</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Naddaf E, Barohn RJ, Dimachkie MM. Inclusion body myositis: Update on pathogenesis and treatment. Neurotherapeutics. 2018;15:995–1005.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30136253</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6277289</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dalakas MC, Sonies B, Dambrosia J, Sekul E, Cupler E, Sivakumar K. Treatment of inclusion-body myositis with IVIg: a double-blind, placebo-controlled study. Neurology. 1997;48:712–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9065553</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dalakas MC, Koffman B, Fujii M, Spector S, Sivakumar K, Cupler E. A controlled study of intravenous immunoglobulin combined with prednisone in the treatment of IBM. Neurology. 2001;56:323–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11171896</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Walter MC, Lochmüller H, Toepfer M, et al. High-dose immunoglobulin therapy in sporadic inclusion body myositis: a double-blind, placebo-controlled study. J Neurol. 2000;247:22–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10701893</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmidt K, Schmidt J. Inclusion body myositis: Advancements in diagnosis, pathomechanisms, and treatment. Curr Opin Rheumatol. 2017;29:632–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28832349</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Benveniste O, Hogrel J-Y, Belin L, et al. Sirolimus for treatment of patients with inclusion body myositis: a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled, proof-of-concept, phase 2b trial. Lancet Rheum. 2021;3:e40–8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alexanderson H, Lundberg IE. Exercise as a therapeutic modality in patients with idiopathic inflammatory myopathies. Curr Opin Rheumatol. 2012;24:201–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22189517</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Souza FHC, Miossi R, de Moraes JCB, Bonfá E, Shinjo SK. Favorable rituximab response in patients with refractory idiopathic inflammatory myopathies. Adv Rheumatol. 2018;58:31.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30657080</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Unger L, Kampf S, Lüthke K, Aringer M. Rituximab therapy in patients with refractory dermatomyositis or polymyositis: Differential effects in a real-life population. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2014;53:1630–8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Couderc M, Gottenberg J-E, Mariette X, et al. Efficacy and safety of rituximab in the treatment of refractory inflammatory myopathies in adults: Results from the AIR registry. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2011;50:2283–9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mahler EAM, Blom M, Voermans NC, van Engelen BGM, van Riel PLCM, Vonk MC. Rituximab treatment in patients with refractory inflammatory myopathies. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2011;50:2206–13.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aggarwal R, Loganathan P, Koontz D, Qi Z, Reed AM, Oddis CV. Cutaneous improvement in refractory adult and juvenile dermatomyositis after treatment with rituximab. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2017;56:247–54.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aggarwal R, Oddis CV, Goudeau D, et al. Autoantibody levels in myositis patients correlate with clinical response during B cell depletion with rituximab. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2016;55:991–9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aggarwal R, Bandos A, Reed AM, et al. Predictors of clinical improvement in rituximab-treated refractory adult and juvenile dermatomyositis and adult polymyositis. Arthritis Rheumatol (Hoboken, N.J.). 2014;66:740–9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leclair V, Galindo-Feria AS, Dastmalchi M, Holmqvist M, Lundberg IE. Efficacy and safety of rituximab in anti-synthetase antibody positive and negative subjects with idiopathic inflammatory myopathy: a registry-based study. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2019;58:1214–20.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Labirua A, Lundberg IE. Interstitial lung disease and idiopathic inflammatory myopathies: Progress and pitfalls. Curr Opin Rheumatol. 2010;22:633–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20827201</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Langlois V, Gillibert A, Uzunhan Y, et al. Rituximab and cyclophosphamide in antisynthetase syndrome-related interstitial lung disease: an observational retrospective study. J Rheumatol. 2020;47:1678–86.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32173654</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sharp C, McCabe M, Dodds N, et al. Rituximab in autoimmune connective tissue disease-associated interstitial lung disease. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2016;55:1318–24.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Andersson H, Sem M, Lund MB, et al. Long-term experience with rituximab in anti-synthetase syndrome-related interstitial lung disease. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2015;54:1420–8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Allenbach Y, Guiguet M, Rigolet A, et al. Efficacy of rituximab in refractory inflammatory myopathies associated with anti-synthetase auto-antibodies: an open-label, phase II trial. PLoS One. 2015;10:e0133702.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saunders P, Tsipouri V, Keir GJ, et al. Rituximab versus cyclophosphamide for the treatment of connective tissue disease-associated interstitial lung disease (RECITAL): Study protocol for a randomised controlled trial. Trials. 2017;18:275.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28619061</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5471887</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mamarabadi M, Baisre A, Leitch M, Hsu V, Kanduri JS, Chen S. Case of anti-single recognition particle-mediated necrotizing myopathy after influenza vaccination. J Clin Neuromuscul Dis. 2018;19:211–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29794576</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Binns EL, Moraitis E, Maillard S, et al. Effective induction therapy for anti-SRP associated myositis in childhood: a small case series and review of the literature. Pediatr Rheumatol Online J. 2017;15:77.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29089059</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5664807</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Valiyil R, Casciola-Rosen L, Hong G, Mammen A, Christopher-Stine L. Rituximab therapy for myopathy associated with anti-signal recognition particle antibodies: a case series. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken). 2010;62:1328–34.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Waheed W, Jones C, Gentchos G, DeWitt J, Tandan R. Favorable response in statin-naive paraneoplastic anti-HMGCR antibody-associated myopathy to single dose of rituximab and persistent remission with management of underlying lung cancer. J Clin Neuromuscul Dis. 2019;21:14–24.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31453850</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang W, Prince HM, Reardon K. Statin-induced anti-HMGCR antibody-related immune-mediated necrotising myositis achieving complete remission with rituximab. BMJ Case Rep. 2019;12:e232406.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Landon-Cardinal O, Allenbach Y, Soulages A, et al. Rituximab in the treatment of refractory anti-HMGCR immune-mediated necrotizing myopathy. J Rheumatol. 2019;46:623–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30554155</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sugihara T, Okiyama N, Watanabe N, Miyasaka N, Kohsaka H. Interleukin-1 and tumor necrosis factor α blockade treatment of experimental polymyositis in mice. Arthritis Rheum. 2012;64:2655–62.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22392010</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chevrel G, Granet C, Miossec P. Contribution of tumour necrosis factor alpha and interleukin (IL) 1beta to IL6 production, NF-kappaB nuclear translocation, and class I MHC expression in muscle cells: In vitro regulation with specific cytokine inhibitors. Ann Rheum Dis. 2005;64:1257–62.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15731288</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">1755658</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kuru S, Inukai A, Liang Y, Doyu M, Takano A, Sobue G. Tumor necrosis factor-alpha expression in muscles of polymyositis and dermatomyositis. Acta Neuropathol. 2000;99:585–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10805105</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Efthimiou P, Schwartzman S, Kagen LJ. Possible role for tumour necrosis factor inhibitors in the treatment of resistant dermatomyositis and polymyositis: a retrospective study of eight patients. Ann Rheum Dis. 2006;65:1233–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16476710</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">1798276</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Anandacoomarasamy A, Howe G, Manolios N. Advanced refractory polymyositis responding to infliximab. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2005;44:562–3.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dastmalchi M, Grundtman C, Alexanderson H, et al. A high incidence of disease flares in an open pilot study of infliximab in patients with refractory inflammatory myopathies. Ann Rheum Dis. 2008;67:1670–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18272672</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iannone F, Scioscia C, Falappone PCF, Covelli M, Lapadula G. Use of etanercept in the treatment of dermatomyositis: a case series. J Rheumatol. 2006;33:1802–4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16960940</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schiffenbauer A, Garg M, Castro C, et al. A randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial of infliximab in refractory polymyositis and dermatomyositis. Semin Arthritis Rheum. 2018;47:858–64.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29174792</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brunasso AMG, Aberer W, Massone C. New onset of dermatomyositis/polymyositis during anti-TNF-α therapies: a systematic literature review. Scientific World J. 2014;2014:179180.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Okiyama N, Sugihara T, Iwakura Y, Yokozeki H, Miyasaka N, Kohsaka H. Therapeutic effects of interleukin-6 blockade in a murine model of polymyositis that does not require interleukin-17A. Arthritis Rheum. 2009;60:2505–12.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19644888</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scuderi F, Mannella F, Marino M, Provenzano C, Bartoccioni E. IL-6-deficient mice show impaired inflammatory response in a model of myosin-induced experimental myositis. J Neuroimmunol. 2006;176:9–15.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16725212</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang X, Zhou S, Wu C, et al. Tocilizumab for refractory rapidly progressive interstitial lung disease related to anti-MDA5-positive dermatomyositis. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2021;60:e227–8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Murphy SM, Lilleker JB, Helliwell P, Chinoy H. The successful use of tocilizumab as third-line biologic therapy in a case of refractory anti-synthetase syndrome. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2016;55:2277–8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kondo M, Murakawa Y, Matsumura T, et al. A case of overlap syndrome successfully treated with tocilizumab: a hopeful treatment strategy for refractory dermatomyositis? Rheumatology (Oxford). 2014;53:1907–8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Narazaki M, Hagihara K, Shima Y, Ogata A, Kishimoto T, Tanaka T. Therapeutic effect of tocilizumab on two patients with polymyositis. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2011;50:1344–6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li S, Li W, Jiang W, et al. The efficacy of tocilizumab in the treatment of patients with refractory immune-mediated necrotizing myopathies: an open-label pilot study. Front Pharmacol. 2021;12:635654.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aggarwal R, Rockette H, Venturupalli S, et al. Tocilizumab in myositis: results of a phase IIb double-blind randomized controlled trial. Arthritis Rheumatol. 2020:suppl 10.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bolko L, Jiang W, Tawara N, et al. The role of interferons type I, II and III in myositis: a review. Brain Pathol. 2021;31:e12955.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salajegheh M, Kong SW, Pinkus JL, et al. Interferon-stimulated gene 15 (ISG15) conjugates proteins in dermatomyositis muscle with perifascicular atrophy. Ann Neurol. 2010;67:53–63.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20186858</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2875060</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Walsh RJ, Kong SW, Yao Y, et al. Type I interferon-inducible gene expression in blood is present and reflects disease activity in dermatomyositis and polymyositis. Arthritis Rheum. 2007;56:3784–92.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17968926</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2443782</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Greenberg SA, Pinkus JL, Pinkus GS, et al. Interferon-alpha/beta-mediated innate immune mechanisms in dermatomyositis. Ann Neurol. 2005;57:664–78.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15852401</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Higgs BW, Zhu W, Morehouse C, et al. A phase 1b clinical trial evaluating sifalimumab, an anti-IFN-α monoclonal antibody, shows target neutralisation of a type I IFN signature in blood of dermatomyositis and polymyositis patients. Ann Rheum Dis. 2014;73:256–62.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23434567</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krystufková O, Vallerskog T, Helmers SB, et al. Increased serum levels of B cell activating factor (BAFF) in subsets of patients with idiopathic inflammatory myopathies. Ann Rheum Dis. 2009;68:836–43.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18628284</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chadha P, Narain S, Nandkumar P, et al. Safety and efficacy of belimumab in the treatment of adult idiopathic inflammatory myositis (polymyositis and dermatomyositis). Arthritis Rheumatol. 2021:(suppl 10).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mielnik P, Chwalinska-Sadowska H, Wiesik-Szewczyk E, Maslinski W, Olesinska M. Serum concentration of interleukin 15, interleukin 2 receptor and TNF receptor in patients with polymyositis and dermatomyositis: Correlation to disease activity. Rheumatol Int. 2012;32:639–43.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21132303</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zou J, Li T, Huang X, Chen S, Guo Q, Bao C. Basiliximab may improve the survival rate of rapidly progressive interstitial pneumonia in patients with clinically amyopathic dermatomyositis with anti-MDA5 antibody. Ann Rheum Dis. 2014;73:1591–3.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24739327</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lahoria R, Selcen D, Engel AG. Microvascular alterations and the role of complement in dermatomyositis. Brain. 2016;139:1891–903.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27190020</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Faguer S, Belliere J, Ribes D. Complement C5-blocking agent in refractory dermatomyositis. J Rheumatol. 2018;45:1710–1.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30219762</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Allenbach Y, Arouche-Delaperche L, Preusse C, et al. Necrosis in anti-SRP+ and anti-HMGCR+myopathies: Role of autoantibodies and complement. Neurology. 2018;90:e507–17.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29330311</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bergua C, Chiavelli H, Allenbach Y, et al. In vivo pathogenicity of IgG from patients with anti-SRP or anti-HMGCR autoantibodies in immune-mediated necrotising myopathy. Ann Rheum Dis. 2019;78:131–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30309969</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lutz HU, Stammler P, Bianchi V, et al. Intravenously applied IgG stimulates complement attenuation in a complement-dependent autoimmune disease at the amplifying C3 convertase level. Blood. 2004;103:465–72.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14512320</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Basta M, Dalakas MC. High-dose intravenous immunoglobulin exerts its beneficial effect in patients with dermatomyositis by blocking endomysial deposition of activated complement fragments. J Clin Invest. 1994;94:1729–35.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7962520</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">294563</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dalakas MC, Alexopoulos H, Spaeth PJ. Complement in neurological disorders and emerging complement-targeted therapeutics. Nat Rev Neurol. 2020;16:601–17.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33005040</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">7528717</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Han HQ, Zhou X, Mitch WE, Goldberg AL. Myostatin/activin pathway antagonism: Molecular basis and therapeutic potential. Int J Biochem Cell Biol. 2013;45:2333–47.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23721881</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lach-Trifilieff E, Minetti GC, Sheppard K, et al. An antibody blocking activin type II receptors induces strong skeletal muscle hypertrophy and protects from atrophy. Mol Cell Biol. 2014;34:606–18.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24298022</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3911487</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Amato AA, Sivakumar K, Goyal N, et al. Treatment of sporadic inclusion body myositis with bimagrumab. Neurology. 2014;83:2239–46.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25381300</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4277670</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Amato AA, Hanna MG, Machado PM, et al. Efficacy and safety of bimagrumab in sporadic inclusion body myositis: Long-term extension of RESILIENT. Neurology. 2021;96:e1595–607.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33597289</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">8032371</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sivakumar K, Cochrane TI, Sloth B, et al. Long-term safety and tolerability of bimagrumab (BYM338) in sporadic inclusion body myositis. Neurology. 2020;95:e1971–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32690797</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Evan JR, Bozkurt SB, Thomas NC, Bagnato F. Alemtuzumab for the treatment of multiple sclerosis. Expert Opin Biol Ther. 2018;18:323–34.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29309202</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dalakas MC, Rakocevic G, Schmidt J, et al. Effect of alemtuzumab (CAMPATH 1-H) in patients with inclusion-body myositis. Brain. 2009;132:1536–44.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19454532</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2685923</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmidt K, Kleinschnitz K, Rakocevic G, Dalakas MC, Schmidt J. Molecular treatment effects of alemtuzumab in skeletal muscles of patients with IBM. BMC Neurol. 2016;16:48.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27083892</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4833914</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sá J, Costelha J, Marinho A. Inclusion body myositis treated with alemtuzumab. Eur J Case Rep Intern Med. 2019;6:1368.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ruck T, Bittner S, Kuhlmann T, Wiendl H, Meuth SG. Long-term efficacy of alemtuzumab in polymyositis. Rheumatology (Oxford). 2015;54:560–2.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmidt J, Barthel K, Zschüntzsch J, et al. Nitric oxide stress in sporadic inclusion body myositis muscle fibres: Inhibition of inducible nitric oxide synthase prevents interleukin-1β-induced accumulation of β-amyloid and cell death. Brain. 2012;135:1102–14.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22436237</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmidt J, Barthel K, Wrede A, Salajegheh M, Bähr M, Dalakas MC. Interrelation of inflammation and APP in sIBM: IL-1 beta induces accumulation of beta-amyloid in skeletal muscle. Brain. 2008;131:1228–40.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18420712</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2367696</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kosmidis ML, Pikazis D, Vlachoyiannopoulos P, Tzioufas AG, Dalakas MC. Trial of canakinumab, an IL-1β receptor antagonist, in patients with inclusion body myositis. Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflamm. 2019;6:e581.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kosmidis ML, Alexopoulos H, Tzioufas AG, Dalakas MC. The effect of anakinra, an IL1 receptor antagonist, in patients with sporadic inclusion body myositis (sIBM): a small pilot study. J Neurol Sci. 2013;334:123–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23998706</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zong M, Dorph C, Dastmalchi M, et al. Anakinra treatment in patients with refractory inflammatory myopathies and possible predictive response biomarkers: a mechanistic study with 12 months follow-up. Ann Rheum Dis. 2014;73:913–20.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23625983</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aggarwal R, Rider LG, Ruperto N, et al. 2016 American College of Rheumatology/European League Against Rheumatism criteria for minimal, moderate, and major clinical response in adult dermatomyositis and polymyositis: an International Myositis Assessment and Clinical Studies Group/Paediatric Rheumatology International Trials Organisation Collaborative Initiative. Ann Rheum Dis. 2017;76:792–801.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28385805</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
