<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35402679</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>13</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2352-5878</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>32</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>JPRAS open</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>JPRAS Open</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Primary Lymphomas of the Breast: A Review.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>127</StartPage>
          <EndPage>143</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>127-143</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jpra.2022.01.004</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Lymphomas of the breast are rare neoplasms that arise from breast lymphoid tissue and are characterised by neoplastic B or T cells. Breast lymphomas arising from B cells include, but are not limited to, diffuse large B cell lymphoma, follicular lymphoma, extra-nodal marginal zone lymphoma and Burkitt lymphoma. Anaplastic large cell lymphoma (ALCL) is of a T cell origin and both anaplastic lymphoma kinase (ALK)-positive and ALK-negative presentations have been noted in the breast. In addition, there is a more recently identified presentation of ALK-negative ALCL that arises around textured breast implants and is usually confined to a periprosthetic fibrous capsule. Here, we discuss the clinical presentations, histological and immunohistochemical features and treatment options for each type of primary breast lymphoma. We hope that this review will highlight the importance of the timely and accurate diagnosis of breast lymphoma in order to tailor the most appropriate treatment. We also wish to raise awareness of the breast implant-associated lymphomas, with the goal of stimulating work that will aid our understanding of their epidemiology and pathogenesis.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>James</LastName>
            <ForeName>Emily R</ForeName>
            <Initials>ER</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pathology, University of Cambridge, Cambridge, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Miranda</LastName>
            <ForeName>Roberto N</ForeName>
            <Initials>RN</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Hematopathology, The University of Texas MD Anderson Cancer Center, Houston, Texas, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Turner</LastName>
            <ForeName>Suzanne D</ForeName>
            <Initials>SD</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pathology, University of Cambridge, Cambridge, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>CEITEC, Masaryk University, Brno, Czech Republic.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>02</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>JPRAS Open</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101680420</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2352-5878</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">BIA-ALCL</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">breast implant lymphoma</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">breast implants</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">breast lymphoma</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">non-Hodgkin lymphoma</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>32</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35402679</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8987598</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpra.2022.01.004</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">S2352-5878(22)00007-9</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>World Health Organisation. Breast cancer. https://www.who.int/news-room/fact-sheets/detail/breast-cancer [Accessibility verified November 3, 2021].</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moura C, Leite MI, Parreira R, Medeiros A. Primary breast lymphoma. J Surg Case Reports. 2020;2020(1):1–3.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6970344</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31976067</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wiseman C, Liao KT. Primary lymphoma of the breast. Cancer. 1972;29(6):1705–1712.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4555557</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Talwalkar SS, Miranda RN, Valbuena JR, Routbort MJ, Martin AW, Medeiros LJ. Lymphomas involving the breast: A study of 106 cases comparing localized and disseminated neoplasms. Am J Surg Pathol. 2008;32(9):1299–1309.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18636016</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shao YB, Sun XF, He YN, Liu CJ, Liu H. Clinicopathological features of thirty patients with primary breast lymphoma and review of the literature. Med Oncol. 2015;32(2):1–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25572809</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thomas A, Link BK, Altekruse S, Romitti PA, Schroeder MC. Primary Breast Lymphoma in the United States: 1975–2013. JNCI J Natl Cancer Inst. 2017;109(6)</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6059147</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28376147</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Uenaka N, Yamamoto S, Sato S, et al.  Primary breast lymphoma initially diagnosed as invasive ductal carcinoma: A case report. Clin Case Reports. 2021;9(6)</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8222742</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34194774</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marton I, Hrgović Z, Habek D. Primary hodgkin's lymphoma of the breast initially treated by surgical excision and axillary dissection. Acta Clin Croat. 2020;59(2):365.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7808226</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33456126</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen M, Zhou J, Qu X. Primary Breast Diffuse Large B-Cell Lymphoma in a 42-Year-Old Female: A Case Report and Review of Literature. J Med Cases. 2021;12(5):181.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8383536</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34434454</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yoneyama K, Nakagawa M, Hara A. Primary lymphoma of the breast: A case report and review of the literature. Radiol Case Reports. 2021;16(1):55.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7644561</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33193929</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Teras LR, Patel A.V., Hildebrand JS, Gapstur SM. Postmenopausal unopposed estrogen and estrogen plus progestin use and risk of non-Hodgkin lymphoma in the American Cancer Society Cancer Prevention Study-II Cohort. Leuk. Lymphoma. 2012;54(4):720–725.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22916741</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shen F, Li G, Jiang H, Zhao S, Qi F. Primary breast diffuse large B-cell lymphoma in a patient with systemic lupus erythematosus: A case report and review of the literature. Medicine (Baltimore) 2020;99(33):e21736.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7437807</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32872060</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yin Y, Ye M, Chen L, Chen H. Giant primary breast diffuse large B-cell lymphoma during pregnancy and lactation. Breast J. 2019;25(5):996–997.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31310414</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Villalón-López JS, Souto-del Bosque R, Méndez-Sashida PG. Linfoma no Hodgkin primario de la glándula mamaria. Reporte de un caso. Cir Cir. 2017;85(1):70–75.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26769528</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wadhwa A, Senebouttarath K. Primary lymphoma of the breast: A case series. Radiol Case Reports. 2018;13(4):815.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6034137</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29988973</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Terada T. Follicular Lymphoma of Breast. Breast J. 2016;22(3):356–357.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27016007</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martinelli G, Ryan G, Seymour JF, et al.  Primary follicular and marginal-zone lymphoma of the breast: clinical features, prognostic factors and outcome: a study by the International Extranodal Lymphoma Study Group. Ann Oncol. 2009;20(12):1993–1999.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19570964</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mirkheshti N, Mohebtash M. A rare case of bilateral breast lobular carcinoma coexisting with primary breast follicular lymphoma. J Community Hosp Intern Med Perspect. 2019;9(2):155.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6487443</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31061694</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Michalinos A, Vassilakopoulos T, Levidou G, Korkolopoulou P, Kontos M. Multifocal Bilateral Breast Cancer and Breast Follicular Lymphoma: A Simple Coincidence? J Breast Cancer. 2015;18(3):296.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4600696</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26472982</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tiong TYV, Alsannaa SM, Soon STG, Poon LM, Goh YG. A rare case of primary follicular lymphoma of the breast in a male patient. Breast J. 2020;26(7):1404–1406.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32052518</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miura S, Hashimoto H, Sawada T, Ishida T, Usuki K, Morikawa T. CD10-Negative Primary Breast Follicular Lymphoma: A Rare Case of Primary Breast Lymphoma With an Atypical Immunophenotype Mimicking Marginal Zone Lymphoma. Int. J. Surg. 2020;29(4):400–403.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33252276</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ismail S, Kherbek H, Skef J, Naser Eldine M, Alshehabi Z. Primary marginal zone lymphoma of the breast; a rare case report and review of the literature. Hum Pathol Case Reports. 2020;22</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Talluri S, Subramanian CR, Werner E, Kasireddy V, Philip L. Bilateral Primary Marginal Zone Lymphoma of the Breast – A Rare Breast Malignancy. In Vivo (Brooklyn) 2020;34(6):3597.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7811612</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33144473</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parashar K, Nepal P, Assaker R, Vargas J, Rosasco S. Incidentally detected Non-Hodgkin's lymphoma of the breast. A case report with review of literature. Radiol Case Reports. 2021;16(1):205–209.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7691161</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33294090</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liguori G, Cantile M, Cerrone M, et al.  Breast MALT lymphomas: A clinicopathological and cytogenetic study of 9 cases. Oncol Rep. 2012;28(4):1211–1216.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22842723</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gluskin J, D'Alessio D, Kim AC, Morris EA, Chiu A, Noy A. Primary lymphoma of the breast: A report of two cases. Clin Imaging. 2020;68:295–299.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7683364</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32961512</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wei Lin C, Xu C, Xi Q, Wang C. Primary Burkitt's lymphoma of the breast without Epstein-Barr virus infection: A case report and literature review. Indian J Pathol Microbiol. 2015;58(4):546.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26549090</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Testa AC, De Blasis I, Di Legge A, Belli P, Hohaus S, Ferrandina G. Burkitt's lymphoma of the breast metastatic to the ovary diagnosed during pregnancy. Ultrasound Obstet Gynecol. 2013;42(3):364–366.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24137791</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Janbabai G, Kayedimajd S, Alian S, Naghshvar F, Rashidi M, Farazmandfar T. Bilateral breast swelling in a 23-year-old woman with Burkitt lymphoma. J Res Med Sci. 2012;17(12):1188.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3703173</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23853639</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Negahban S, Ahmadi N, Oryan A, et al.  Primary Bilateral Burkitt Lymphoma of the Lactating Breast. Mol Diagnosis Ther. 2012;14(4):243–250.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20799767</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elgaafary S, Nagel I, López C, et al.  Double-hit lymphoma of the male breast: a case report. J Med Case Rep. 2020;14(1)</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7747391</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33339535</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meucci R, Pistolese CA, Perretta T, et al.  Primary Extranodal Follicular T-Cell Lymphoma and Ductal Breast Carcinoma Diagnosed by a Magnetic Resonance Imaging-Guided Vacuum-Assisted Biopsy: A Case Report. Am J Case Rep. 2021;22(1)</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8272939</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34226439</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Turner SD. An Exploration into the Origins and Pathogenesis of Anaplastic Large Cell Lymphoma. Anaplastic Lymphoma Kinase (ALK)-Positive. Cancers (Basel) 2017;9(10)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bonzheim I, Geissinger E, Roth S, et al.  Anaplastic large cell lymphomas lack the expression of T-cell receptor molecules or molecules of proximal T-cell receptor signaling. Blood. 2004;104(10):3358–3360.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15297316</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Malcolm TIM, Villarese P, Fairbairn CJ, et al.  Anaplastic large cell lymphoma arises in thymocytes and requires transient TCR expression for thymic egress. Nat Commun. 2016;7(1):1–12.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4729925</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26753883</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morris SW, Kirstein MN, Valentine MB, et al.  Fusion of a Kinase Gene, ALK, to a Nucleolar Protein Gene, NPM, in Non-Hodgkin's. Lymphoma. Science. 1994;263(5151):1281–1284.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8122112</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Turner SD, Yeung D, Hadfield K, Cook SJ, Alexander DR. The NPM-ALK tyrosine kinase mimics TCR signalling pathways, inducing NFAT and AP-1 by RAS-dependent mechanisms. Cell Signal. 2007;19(4):740–747.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17110082</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iyengar P, Reid-Nicholson M, Moreira AL. Pregnancy-associated anaplastic large-cell lymphoma of the breast: A rare mimic of ductal carcinoma. Diagn Cytopathol. 2006;34(4):298–302.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16544330</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Minard-Colin V, Brugières L, Reiter A, et al.  Non-Hodgkin Lymphoma in Children and Adolescents: Progress Through Effective Collaboration, Current Knowledge, and Challenges Ahead. J Clin Oncol. 2015;33(27):2963.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4979194</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26304908</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sathyanarayanan V, Lokesh KN, Lakshmaiah K, et al.  Anaplastic lymphoma kinase (ALK) positive anaplastic large cell lymphoma (ALCL) of breast in a patient without a breast implant. Ann Saudi Med. 2014;34(6):551.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6074583</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25971833</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ivashkevich Y, Chernov Y, Chinenov D, et al.  Unusual Case of Anaplastic Large Cell Lymphoma Presenting as a Breast Mass in a Patient with no History of Breast Implants. Case Rep Pathol. 2020;2020:1–4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7396074</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32774970</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yi JH, Kim SJ, Kim WS. Brentuximab vedotin: clinical updates and practical guidance. Blood Res. 2017;52(4):243.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5762734</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29333400</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lazzeri D, Agostini T, Bocci G, et al.  ALK-1–Negative Anaplastic Large Cell Lymphoma Associated With Breast Implants: A New Clinical Entity. Clin Breast Cancer. 2011;11(5):283–296.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21729665</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aguilera NSI, Tavassoli FA, Chu WS, Abbondanzo SL. T-Cell Lymphoma Presenting in the Breast: A Histologic, Immunophenotypic and Molecular Genetic Study of Four Cases. Mod Pathol. 2000;13(6):599–605.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10874662</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miranda RN, Lin L, Talwalkar SS, Manning JT, Medeiros LJ. Anaplastic Large Cell Lymphoma Involving the Breast: A Clinicopathologic Study of 6 Cases and Review of the Literature. Arch Pathol Lab Med. 2009;133(9):1383–1390.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19722744</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pina-Oviedo S, Ortiz-Hidalgo C, Carballo-Zarate AA, Zarate-Osorno A. ALK-Negative Anaplastic Large Cell Lymphoma: Current Concepts and Molecular Pathogenesis of a Heterogeneous Group of Large T-Cell Lymphomas. Cancers (Basel) 2021;13(18)</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8472588</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34572893</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brown RA, Fernandez-Pol S, Kim J. Primary cutaneous anaplastic large cell lymphoma. J Cutan Pathol. 2017;44(6):570–577.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28342276</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parrilla Castellar ER, Jaffe ES, Said JW, et al.  ALK-negative anaplastic large cell lymphoma is a genetically heterogeneous disease with widely disparate clinical outcomes. Blood. 2014;124(9):1473–1480.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4148769</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24894770</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lobello C, Tichy B, Bystry V, et al.  STAT3 and TP53 mutations associate with poor prognosis in anaplastic large cell lymphoma. Leuk. 2020;35(5):1500–1505.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8102183</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33247178</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dogan ZA, Miranda RN, Iyer S, Steiner RE, Singh P, Clemens MW. Anaplastic Large Cell Lymphoma of the Breast Arising in a Burn Cicatrix. Aesthetic Surg J. 2020;40(4):NP159.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7453096</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31495882</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sasaki K, Sugaya M, Fujita H, et al.  A case of primary cutaneous anaplastic large cell lymphoma with variant anaplastic lymphoma kinase translocation. Br J Dermatol. 2004;150(6):1202–1207.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15214912</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pulitzer M, Ogunrinade O, Lin O, Steinherz P. ALK-positive (2p23 rearranged) anaplastic large cell lymphoma with localization to the skin in a pediatric patient. J Cutan Pathol. 2015;42(3):182–187.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5108361</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25404214</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Booken N, Goerdt S, Klemke CD. Clinical spectrum of primary cutaneous CD30-positive anaplastic large cell lymphoma: an analysis of the Mannheim Cutaneous Lymphoma Registry. JDDG J der Dtsch Dermatologischen Gesellschaft. 2012;10(5):331–339.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22525148</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bergsten TM, Principe DR, Raicu A, Rubin J, Ong AL, Hagen C. Non-implant associated primary cutaneous anaplastic large cell lymphoma of the breast. J Surg Case Reports. 2019;2019(5):1–3.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6507588</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31086652</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mehta-Shah N, Clemens MW, Horwitz SM. How I treat breast implant–associated anaplastic large cell lymphoma. Blood. 2018;132(18):1889–1898.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6536699</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30209119</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Loch-Wilkinson A, Beath KJ, Knight RJW, et al.  Breast implant-associated anaplastic large cell lymphoma in Australia and New Zealand: High-surface-area textured implants are associated with increased risk. Plast Reconstr Surg. 2017;140(4):645–654.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28481803</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miranda RN, Aladily TN, Prince HM, et al.  Breast Implant–Associated Anaplastic Large-Cell Lymphoma: Long-Term Follow-Up of 60 Patients. J Clin Oncol. 2014;32(2):114.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4062709</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24323027</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Akhavan AA, Wirtz EC, Ollila DW, Bhatt N. An Unusual Case of BIA-ALCL Associated with Prolonged/Complicated Biocell-Textured Expander, followed by Smooth Round Breast Implant Exposure, and Concurrent Use of Adalimumab. Plast Reconstr Surg. 2021:299–303.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34133406</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Freedman J, Peredo A, Rosser J, Christian N, Kaoutzanis C. Biopsy Results Are Not Sufficient to Exclude Breast Implant–associated Anaplastic Large Cell Lymphoma: A Case Mistaken for Disseminated Silicosis. Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open. 2020;8(9)</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7544370</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33133985</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clemens MW, Medeiros LJ, Butler CE, et al.  Complete Surgical Excision Is Essential for the Management of Patients With Breast Implant–Associated Anaplastic Large-Cell Lymphoma. J Clin Oncol. 2016;34(2):160.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4872006</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26628470</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ferrufino-Schmidt MC, Jeffrey Medeiros L, Liu H, et al.  Clinicopathologic Features and Prognostic Impact of Lymph Node Involvement in Patients With Breast Implant-associated Anaplastic Large Cell Lymphoma. Am J Surg Pathol. 2018;42(3):293.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7500854</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29194092</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>D'Alessandris N, Lucatelli P, Tripodi D, Amabile MI, Ascoli V. Cytological features of breast implant-associated anaplastic large cell lymphoma in pleural effusion. Diagn Cytopathol. 2019;47(11):1213–1217.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31348611</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Evans MG, Medeiros LJ, Marques-Piubelli ML, et al.  Breast implant-associated anaplastic large cell lymphoma: clinical follow-up and analysis of sequential pathologic specimens of untreated patients shows persistent or progressive disease. Mod Pathol. 2021;34(12):2148–2153.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34155351</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tripodi D, Amabile MI, Varanese M, D'Andrea V, Sorrenti S, Cannistrà C. Large cell anaplastic lymphoma associated with breast implant: a rare case report presentation and discussion of possible management. Gland Surg. 2021;10(6):2076–2080.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8258880</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34268093</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnson L, O'Donoghue JM, McLean N, et al.  Breast implant associated anaplastic large cell lymphoma: The UK experience. Recommendations on its management and implications for informed consent. Eur J Surg Oncol. 2017;43(8):1393–1401.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28596034</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Richardson K, Alrifai T, Grant-Szymanski K, et al.  Breast implant-associated anaplastic large-cell lymphoma and the role of brentuximab vedotin (SGN-35) therapy: A case report and review of the literature. Mol Clin Oncol. 2017;6(4):539.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5374895</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28413663</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thienpaitoon P, Disphanurat W, Warnnissorn N. Breast implant-associated anaplastic large cell lymphoma in an Asian patient: The first case report from Thailand. Arch Plast Surg. 2020;47(5):478.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7520251</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32713177</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Allchin RL, Wickenden K, Pilgrim S, Wilson-Morkeh I, Miall FM. The Successful Use of Neo Adjuvant Brentuximab Vedotin in the Treatment of BIA-ALCL. HemaSphere. 2020;4(6):e501.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7710186</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33283170</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berlin E, Singh K, Mills C, Shapira I, Bakst RL, Chadha M. Breast Implant-Associated Anaplastic Large Cell Lymphoma: Case Report and Review of the Literature. Case Rep Hematol. 2018;2018:1–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5828403</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29607225</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thibodeau R, Fan KL, Wehner PB. Stage IV Breast Implant–associated Anaplastic Large-cell Lymphoma with Complete Pathologic Response to Neoadjuvant Chemotherapy. Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open. 2019;7(9):1.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6908402</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31942403</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alderuccio JP, Desai A, Yepes MM, Chapman JR, Vega F, Lossos IS. Frontline brentuximab vedotin in breast implant-associated anaplastic large-cell lymphoma. Clin Case Reports. 2018;6(4):634.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5889253</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29636930</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Keech JA, Creech BJ. Anaplastic T-cell lymphoma in proximity to a saline-filled breast implant. Plast Reconstr Surg. 1997;100(2):554–555.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9252643</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swerdlow SH, Campo E, Pileri SA, et al.  The 2016 revision of the World Health Organization classification of lymphoid neoplasms. Blood. 2016;127(20):2375–2390.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4874220</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26980727</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miranda RN, Feldman AL, Soares FA. Breast implant-associated anaplastic large cell lymphoma. In: K.H. Allison et al. (eds). World Health Organization Breast Tumours 245-248 (IARC: Lyon, 2019).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>CocoRuby Plastic Surgery. Updated Breast Implant Cancer (BIA-ALCL): Everything We Know In 2021. https://cocorubyplasticsurgery.com.au/blog/update-on-breast-implant-associated-alcl-bia-alcl-everything-we-know-in-2021/ [Accessibility verified November 12, 2021].</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ohishi Y, Mitsuda A, Ejima K, et al.  Breast implant-associated anaplastic large-cell lymphoma: first case detected in a Japanese breast cancer patient. Breast Cancer. 2020;27(3):499.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7196092</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32095988</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lai CS, Wu CY, Chen IC, Tsai YC. Breast implant-associated anaplastic large cell lymphoma (BIA-ALCL) – The first case in Taiwan. Asian J Surg. 2021;44(6):869–870.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33934969</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ionescu P, Vibert F, Amé S, Mathelin C. New Data on the Epidemiology of Breast Implant-Associated Anaplastic Large Cell Lymphoma. Eur J Breast Heal. 2021;17(4):302.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8496114</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34651107</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Jong D, Vasmel WLE, De Boer JP, et al.  Anaplastic Large-Cell Lymphoma in Women With Breast Implants. JAMA. 2008;300(17):2030–2035.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18984890</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cordeiro PG, Ghione P, Ni A, et al.  Risk of Breast Implant Associated Anaplastic Large Cell Lymphoma (BIA-ALCL) in a Cohort of 3546 Women Prospectively Followed Long Term After Reconstruction with Textured Breast Implants. J Plast Reconstr Aesthet Surg. 2020;73(5):841.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7247945</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32008941</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Santanelli Di Pompeo F, Sorotos M, Clemens MW, et al.  Breast Implant-Associated Anaplastic Large Cell Lymphoma (BIA-ALCL): Review of Epidemiology and Prevalence Assessment in Europe. Aesthetic Surg J. 2021;41(9):1014–1025.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33022037</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lechner MG, Megiel C, Church CH, et al.  Survival Signals and Targets for Therapy in Breast Implant–Associated ALK− Anaplastic Large Cell Lymphoma. Clin Cancer Res. 2012;18(17):4549–4559.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22791880</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hu H, Jacombs A, Vickery K, Merten SL, Pennington DG, Deva AK. Chronic biofilm infection in breast implants is associated with an increased T-cell lymphocytic infiltrate: implications for breast implant-associated lymphoma. Plast Reconstr Surg. 2015;135(2):319–329.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25383716</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mempin M, Hu H, Vickery K, et al.  Gram-Negative Bacterial Lipopolysaccharide Promotes Tumor Cell Proliferation in Breast Implant-Associated Anaplastic Large-Cell Lymphoma. Cancers (Basel) 2021;13(21)</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8582399</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34771464</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deva AK, Turner SD, Kadin ME, et al.  Etiology of Breast Implant-Associated Anaplastic Large Cell Lymphoma (BIA-ALCL): Current Directions in Research. Cancers (Basel) 2020;12(12):1–14.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7765924</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33371292</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Turner SD. The Cellular Origins of Breast Implant–Associated Anaplastic Large Cell Lymphoma (BIA-ALCL): Implications for Immunogenesis. Aesthetic Surg J. 2019;39(Supplement_1):S21–S27.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6355097</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30715172</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tevis SE, Hunt KK, Miranda RN, Lange C, Butler CE, Clemens MW. Differences in Human Leukocyte Antigen Expression Between Breast Implant-Associated Anaplastic Large Cell Lymphoma Patients and the General Population. Aesthetic Surg J. 2019;39(10):1065–1070.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30715139</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang HY, Thorson JA, Hinds BR, et al.  Cutaneous intralymphatic anaplastic lymphoma kinase-negative anaplastic large-cell lymphoma arising in a patient with multiple rounds of breast implants. J Cutan Pathol. 2021;48(5):659–662.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33314229</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alcalá R, Llombart B, Lavernia J, Traves V, Guillén C, Sanmartín O. Skin involvement as the first manifestation of breast implant-associated anaplastic large cell lymphoma. J Cutan Pathol. 2016;43(7):602–608.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26956670</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Evans MG, Miranda RN, Young PA, et al.  B-cell lymphomas associated with breast implants: Report of three cases and review of the literature. Ann Diagn Pathol. 2020;46</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32315816</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bletsis PP, Janssen LE, Visser O, et al.  Bilateral breast implant associated chronic lymphocytic leukemia/small lymphocytic lymphoma (CLL/SLL): A case report. Int J Surg Case Rep. 2020;71:341.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7267678</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32497784</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Medeiros LJ, Marques-Piubelli ML, Sangiorgio VFI, et al.  Epstein–Barr-virus-positive large B-cell lymphoma associated with breast implants: an analysis of eight patients suggesting a possible pathogenetic relationship. Mod Pathol. 2021;34(12):2154–2167.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34226673</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elia R, Maruccia M, De Pascale A, Di Napoli A, Ingravallo G, Giudice G. The management of breast implant-associated anaplastic large cell lymphoma in the setting of pregnancy: seeking for clinical practice guidelines. Arch Plast Surg. 2021;48(4):373.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8342241</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34352947</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Misad S.C, Walker B.K, Valbuena JR, et al.  Anaplastic large cell lymphoma associated with breast implants, diagnosed by fine needle aspiration. Report of one case. Rev Med Chil. 2020;148(8):1207–1212.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33399788</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
