<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35411674</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>12</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1601-183X</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Apr</Month>
              <Day>12</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Genes, brain, and behavior</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Genes Brain Behav</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Biological functions of α2-adrenergic-like octopamine receptor in Drosophila melanogaster.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e12807</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e12807</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/gbb.12807</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Octopamine regulates various physiological phenomena including memory, sleep, grooming and aggression in insects. In Drosophila, four types of octopamine receptors have been identified: Oamb, Oct/TyrR, OctβR and Octα2R. Among these receptors, Octα2R was recently discovered and pharmacologically characterized. However, the effects of the receptor on biological functions are still unknown. Here, we showed that Octα2R regulated several behaviors related to octopamine signaling. Octα2R hypomorphic mutant flies showed a significant decrease in locomotor activity. We found that Octα2R expressed in the pars intercerebralis, which is a brain region projected by octopaminergic neurons, is involved in control of the locomotor activity. Besides, Octα2R hypomorphic mutants increased time and frequency of grooming and inhibited starvation-induced hyperactivity. These results indicated that Octα2R expressed in the central nervous system is responsible for the involvement in physiological functions.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Authors. Genes, Brain and Behavior published by International Behavioural and Neural Genetics Society and John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nakagawa</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hiroyuki</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neuropharmacology, Graduate School of Pharmaceutical Sciences, Nagoya City University, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Maehara</LastName>
            <ForeName>Shiori</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Faculty of Advanced Science and Technology, Kumamoto University, Kumamoto, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kume</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kazuhiko</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4232-1657</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neuropharmacology, Graduate School of Pharmaceutical Sciences, Nagoya City University, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ohta</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hiroto</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0447-2630</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Faculty of Advanced Science and Technology, Kumamoto University, Kumamoto, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Applied Microbial Engineering, Faculty of Life Sciences, Sojo University, Kumamoto, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tomita</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jun</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9336-4900</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neuropharmacology, Graduate School of Pharmaceutical Sciences, Nagoya City University, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>04</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Genes Brain Behav</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101129617</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1601-183X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Drosophila melanogaster</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">grooming behavior</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">locomotor activity</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">octopamine receptor</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">starvation-induced hyperactivity</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>33</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35411674</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/gbb.12807</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Crocker A, Sehgal A. Octopamine regulates sleep in Drosophila through protein kinase A-dependent mechanisms. J Neurosci. 2008;28:9377-9385.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hoyer SC, Eckart A, Herrel A, Zars T, Fischer SA, Hardie SL, Heisenberg M. Octopamine in male aggression of Drosophila. Curr Biol. 2008;18:159-167.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yoshinari Y, Ameku T, Kondo S, Tanimoto H, Kuraishi T, Shimada-Niwa Y, Niwa R. Neuronal octopamine signaling regulates mating-induced germline stem cell increase in female Drosophila melanogaster. Elife. 2020;9:e57101.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yu Y, Huang R, Ye J, Zhang V, Wu C, Cheng G, Jia J, Wang L. Regulation of starvation-induced hyperactivity by insulin and glucagon signaling in adult Drosophila. Elife. 2016;5:e15693.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Evans PD, Maqueira B. Insect octopamine receptors: a new classification scheme based on studies of cloned Drosophila G-protein coupled receptors. Invert Neurosci. 2005;5:111-118.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Han KA, Millar NS, Davis RL. A novel octopamine receptor with preferential expression in Drosophila mushroom bodies. J Neurosci. 1998;18:3650-3658.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Burke CJ, Huetteroth W, Owald D, Perisse E, Krashes MJ, Das G, Gohl D, Silies M, Certel S, Waddell S. Layered reward signalling through octopamine and dopamine in Drosophila. Nature. 2012;492:433-437.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huetteroth W, Perisse E, Lin S, Klappenbach M, Burke C, Waddell S. Sweet taste and nutrient value subdivide rewarding dopaminergic neurons in Drosophila. Curr Biol. 2015;25:751-758.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ma Z, Stork T, Bergles DE, Freeman MR. Neuromodulators signal through astrocytes to alter neural circuit activity and behaviour. Nature. 2016;539:428-432.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maqueira B, Chatwin H, Evans PD. Identification and characterization of a novel family of Drosophila beta-adrenergic-like octopamine G-protein coupled receptors. J Neurochem. 2005;94:547-560.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu C-L, Shih M-FM, Lee P-T, Chiang A-S. An octopamine-mushroom body circuit modulates the formation of anesthesia-resistant memory in Drosophila. Curr Biol. 2013;23:2346-2354.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu S-F, Xu G, Qi Y-X, Xia R-Y, Huang J, Ye G-Y. Two splicing variants of a novel family of octopamine receptors with different signaling properties. J Neurochem. 2014;129:37-47.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blenau W, Wilms JA, Balfanz S, Baumann A. AmOctα2R: functional characterization of a honeybee Octopamine receptor inhibiting adenylyl cyclase activity. Int J Mol Sci. 2020;21:9334.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Qi Y-X, Xu G, Gu G-X, Mao F, Ye G-Y, Liu W, Huang J. A new Drosophila octopamine receptor responds to serotonin. Insect Biochem Mol Biol. 2017;90:61-70.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Uchiyama H, Maehara S, Ohta H, Seki T, Tanaka Y. Elevenin regulates the body color through a G protein-coupled receptor NlA42 in the brown planthopper Nilaparvata lugens. Gen Comp Endocrinol. 2018;258:33-38.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hendricks JC, Finn SM, Panckeri KA, Chavkin J, Williams JA, Sehgal A, Pack AI. Rest in Drosophila is a sleep-like state. Neuron. 2000;25:129-138.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shaw PJ, Cirelli C, Greenspan RJ, Tononi G. Correlates of sleep and waking in Drosophila melanogaster. Science. 2000;287:1834-1837.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ohta H, Ozoe Y. Molecular signalling, pharmacology, and physiology of octopamine and tyramine receptors as potential insect pest control targets. Advances in Insect Physiology. Elsevier Inc.; 2014:73-166.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Busch S, Selcho M, Ito K, Tanimoto H. A map of octopaminergic neurons in the Drosophila brain. J Comp Neurol. 2009;513:643-667.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deng B, Li Q, Liu X, Cao Y, Li B, Qian Y, Xu R, Mao R, Zhou E, Zhang W, Huang J, Rao Y. Chemoconnectomics: mapping chemical transmission in Drosophila. Neuron. 2019;101:876-893.e4.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee P-T, Zirin J, Kanca O, Lin W-W, Schulze KL, Li-Kroeger D, Tao R, Devereaux C, Hu Y, Chung V, Fang Y, He Y, Pan H, Ge M, Zuo Z, Housden BE, Mohr SE, Yamamoto S, Levis RW, Spradling AC, Perrimon N, Bellen HJ. A gene-specific T2A-GAL4 library for Drosophila. Elife. 2018;7:e35574.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Crocker A, Shahidullah M, Levitan IB, Sehgal A. Identification of a neural circuit that underlies the effects of octopamine on sleep:wake behavior. Neuron. 2010;65:670-681.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang Z, Yu Y, Zhang V, Tian Y, Qi W, Wang L. Octopamine mediates starvation-induced hyperactivity in adult Drosophila. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2015;112:5219-5224.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>King LB, Koch M, Murphy KR, Velazquez Y, Ja WW, Tomchik SM. Neurofibromin loss of function drives excessive grooming in Drosophila. G3 (Bethesda). 2016;6:1083-1093.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garbe DS, Bollinger WL, Vigderman A, Masek P, Gertowski J, Sehgal A, Keene AC. Context-specific comparison of sleep acquisition systems in Drosophila. Biol Open. 2015;4:1558-1568.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yellman C, Tao H, He B, Hirsh J. Conserved and sexually dimorphic behavioral responses to biogenic amines in decapitated Drosophila. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1997;94:4131-4136.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhao Z, Zhao X, He T, Wu X, Lv P, Zhu AJ, Du J. Epigenetic regulator Stuxnet modulates octopamine effect on sleep through a stuxnet-polycomb-Octβ2R cascade. EMBO Rep. 2021;22:e47910.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
