<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35416896</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>15</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>11</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1678-4464</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>38</Volume>
            <Issue>3</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Cadernos de saude publica</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Cad Saude Publica</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>[Maternal mortality trend in the state of Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, 2006-2018, according to the ICD-MM classification].</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e00195821</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e00195821</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1590/0102-311X00195821</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0102-311X2022000305015</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The study aimed to analyze the trend in the maternal mortality ratio (MMR) according to the ICD classification for maternal mortality (ICD-MM) classification in the state of Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, from 2006 to 2018. This was a time trend study of MMR in Rio de Janeiro according to type of death (direct or indirect) and groups of causes in the World Health Organization (WHO) ICD-MM. MMR was calculated with data from Brazilian Mortality Information System (SIM) and Brazilian Information System on Live Births (SINASC). Trends were estimated with the Joinpoint Regression Program. Of the 2,192 maternal deaths in the state, 61% were from direct causes, 34% from indirect causes, and 5% unspecified. There was a downward trend in total MMR and MMR from direct causes: -1.2% (95%CI: -2.3; -0.1) per year and -3.8% (95%CI: -4.9; -2.6) from 2006 to 2015, respectively. For direct causes, according to the ICD-MM, group 2 (hypertensive causes) predominated, but there was a decrease in eclampsia. Next came group 5 (other complications, featuring category O90 and subcategory O90.3 - peripartum cardiomyopathy) and group 1 (pregnancy with abortive outcomes). Indirect causes showed stability, and the majority belonged to category O99 and its subcategories related to cardiovascular and respiratory diseases. MMR in Rio de Janeiro showed a downward trend from 2006 to 2018, although far short of WHO recommendations and with different patterns among the causes. ICD-MM was useful for identifying major groups of causes, but it is necessary to disaggregate by subcategories to adequately elucidate the etiology of maternal death.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mendonça</LastName>
            <ForeName>Isabelle Moraes</ForeName>
            <Initials>IM</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8471-7679</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Universidade Federal Fluminense, Niterói, Brasil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Silva</LastName>
            <ForeName>Julia Brenner Fernandes da</ForeName>
            <Initials>JBFD</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3589-510X</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Universidade Federal Fluminense, Niterói, Brasil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Conceição</LastName>
            <ForeName>Johnatan Felipe Ferreira da</ForeName>
            <Initials>JFFD</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0354-8931</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Universidade Federal Fluminense, Niterói, Brasil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Fonseca</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sandra Costa</ForeName>
            <Initials>SC</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5493-494X</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Universidade Federal Fluminense, Niterói, Brasil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Boschi-Pinto</LastName>
            <ForeName>Cynthia</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0069-7974</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Universidade Federal Fluminense, Niterói, Brasil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>por</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <VernacularTitle>Tendência da mortalidade materna no Estado do Rio de Janeiro, Brasil, entre 2006 e 2018, segundo a classificação CID-MM.</VernacularTitle>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>04</Month>
          <Day>08</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>Brazil</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Cad Saude Publica</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8901573</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0102-311X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001938" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Brazil</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002423" MajorTopicYN="N">Cause of Death</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007256" MajorTopicYN="N">Information Systems</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D050498" MajorTopicYN="N">Live Birth</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D063130" MajorTopicYN="Y">Maternal Death</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008428" MajorTopicYN="Y">Maternal Mortality</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011247" MajorTopicYN="N">Pregnancy</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="por">
        <AbstractText>O objetivo foi analisar a tendência da razão de mortalidade materna (RMM) segundo a classificação CID-Mortalidade Materna (CID-MM) no Estado do Rio de Janeiro, Brasil, no período de 2006 a 2018. Foi realizado estudo de tendência temporal da RMM no Rio de Janeiro segundo tipo de óbito - direto ou indireto - e grupos de causas da classificação CID-MM, da Organização Mundial da Saúde (OMS). A RMM foi calculada com dados do Sistema de Informações sobre Mortalidade (SIM) e do Sistema de Informações sobre Nascidos Vivos (SINASC). As tendências foram estimadas pelo Joinpoint Regression Program. Dos 2.192 óbitos maternos no estado, 61% foram por causas diretas, 34% indiretas e 5% não especificadas. A tendência da RMM total e por causas diretas foi de declínio: 1,2% (IC95%: -2,3; -0,1) ao ano e 3,8% (IC95%: -4,9; -2,6) entre 2006 e 2015, respectivamente. Para causas diretas, segundo a CID-MM, o grupo 2 (causas hipertensivas) foi preponderante, mas houve declínio da eclâmpsia. Seguiram-se o grupo 5 (outras complicações, das quais se destacaram a categoria O90 e a subcategoria O90.3 - cardiomiopatia no puerpério) e o grupo 1 (gravidez que termina em aborto). As causas indiretas apresentaram estabilidade e a maioria pertencia à categoria O99 e suas subcategorias, relacionadas a doenças cardiovasculares e respiratórias. A RMM no Rio de Janeiro apresentou tendência de declínio entre 2006 e 2018, porém distante do recomendado pela OMS e com diferentes comportamentos entre as causas. A classificação CID-MM foi útil para identificar grandes grupos de causas, mas é preciso desagregar por subcategorias, para o adequado conhecimento da etiologia da morte materna.</AbstractText>
      </OtherAbstract>
      <OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="spa">
        <AbstractText>El objetivo fue analizar la tendencia de la razón de mortalidad materna (RMM), según la clasificación CID-Mortalidad Materna (CID-MM) en el Estado de Río de Janeiro, Brasil, durante el período de 2006 a 2018. Estudio de tendencia temporal de la RMM en Río de Janeiro según el tipo de óbito -directo o indirecto- y grupos de causas de la clasificación CID-MM, de la Organización Mundial de la Salud (OMS). Se calculó la RMM con datos del Sistema de Información sobre Mortalidad (SIM) y del Sistema de Información sobre Nacidos Vivos (SINASC). Se estimaron las tendencias mediante Joinpoint Regression Program. De los 2192 óbitos maternos en el estado, un 61% fueron por causas directas, 34% indirectas y 5% no especificadas. La tendencia de la RMM total y por causas directas fue en declive: 1,2% (IC95%: -2,3; -0,1) al año y 3,8% (IC95%: -4,9; -2,6) entre 2006 y 2015, respectivamente. Para las causas directas, según la CID-MM, el grupo 2 (causas hipertensivas) fue preponderante, pero hubo declive de la eclampsia. Siguieron en el grupo 5 (otras complicaciones, de las cuales se destacaron la categoría O90 y la subcategoría O90.3 - cardiomiopatía en el puerperio) y el grupo 1 (embarazo que termina en aborto). Las causas indirectas presentaron estabilidad y la mayoría pertenecía a la categoría O99 y sus subcategorías relacionadas con enfermedades cardiovasculares y respiratorias. La RMM en Río de Janeiro presentó una tendencia decreciente entre 2006 y 2018, no obstante, dista de lo recomendado por la OMS y cuenta con diferentes comportamientos entre las causas. La clasificación CID-MM fue útil para identificar grandes grupos de causas, pero es necesario desagregar por subcategorías, para el adecuado conocimiento de la etiología de la muerte materna.</AbstractText>
      </OtherAbstract>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>14</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35416896</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/0102-311X00195821</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">S0102-311X2022000305015</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
