<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35415298</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>14</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2452-199X</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>18</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Dec</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Bioactive materials</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Bioact Mater</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>A biomimetic nanocomposite with enzyme-like activities and CXCR4 antagonism efficiently enhances the therapeutic efficacy of acute myeloid leukemia.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>526</StartPage>
          <EndPage>538</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>526-538</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.bioactmat.2022.03.022</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Despite the progress made to improve therapeutic outcomes for acute myeloid leukemia (AML), many unmet clinical needs remain to be resolved. Unlike existing anti-AML strategies, here we developed a biomimetic nanocomposite to efficiently eliminate the leukemia cells in the bone marrow and prevent the homing of AML. To fulfill our design, the ultra-small nanozyme was conjugated onto the surface of an oxygen-carrying nanoparticle, which was further coated with bone marrow stromal cell membrane. After entering the blood, this biomimetic nanocomposite got actively internalized by the leukemia cells in the blood and released the loaded chemotherapeutics and nanozyme inside the leukemia cells to achieve a synergistic antitumor efficacy. Meanwhile, the adhesive properties of the stromal cell membrane enabled the nanocomposite to home to the bone marrow, where the nanocomposite effectively killed the retained leukemia cells. More importantly, the biomimetic cell membrane also acted as a CXCR4 antagonism to block the CXCR4/CXCL12-mediated homing of leukemia cells to the bone marrow and infiltration to other organs like the liver and spleen. In conclusion, this proof-of-concept study demonstrated that our designed platform effectively kills leukemia cells while preventing their infiltration, thus providing a promising prospect for resolving the clinical challenges in current AML treatment.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Authors.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kong</LastName>
            <ForeName>Fei</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Bioelectronics, Jiangsu Key Laboratory for Biomaterials and Devices, School of Biological Science and Medical Engineering &amp; Collaborative Innovation Center of Suzhou Nano Science and Technology, Southeast University, Nanjing, 210096, PR China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>He</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hongliang</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Bioelectronics, Jiangsu Key Laboratory for Biomaterials and Devices, School of Biological Science and Medical Engineering &amp; Collaborative Innovation Center of Suzhou Nano Science and Technology, Southeast University, Nanjing, 210096, PR China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bai</LastName>
            <ForeName>Huiyuan</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Bioelectronics, Jiangsu Key Laboratory for Biomaterials and Devices, School of Biological Science and Medical Engineering &amp; Collaborative Innovation Center of Suzhou Nano Science and Technology, Southeast University, Nanjing, 210096, PR China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Fang</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Bioelectronics, Jiangsu Key Laboratory for Biomaterials and Devices, School of Biological Science and Medical Engineering &amp; Collaborative Innovation Center of Suzhou Nano Science and Technology, Southeast University, Nanjing, 210096, PR China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ma</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ming</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Bioelectronics, Jiangsu Key Laboratory for Biomaterials and Devices, School of Biological Science and Medical Engineering &amp; Collaborative Innovation Center of Suzhou Nano Science and Technology, Southeast University, Nanjing, 210096, PR China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ning</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Bioelectronics, Jiangsu Key Laboratory for Biomaterials and Devices, School of Biological Science and Medical Engineering &amp; Collaborative Innovation Center of Suzhou Nano Science and Technology, Southeast University, Nanjing, 210096, PR China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yu</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Bioelectronics, Jiangsu Key Laboratory for Biomaterials and Devices, School of Biological Science and Medical Engineering &amp; Collaborative Innovation Center of Suzhou Nano Science and Technology, Southeast University, Nanjing, 210096, PR China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>31</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Bioact Mater</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101685294</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2452-199X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Acute myeloid leukemia</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Biomimetic nanocomposite</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CXCR4/CXCL12 axis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nanozymes</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>I declare that the authors have no known competing financial interests、 personal relationships, or other interests that might be perceived to influence the results and/or discussion reported in this paper.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>36</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35415298</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8976099</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bioactmat.2022.03.022</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">S2452-199X(22)00137-2</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abelson S., Collord G., Ng S.W.K., Weissbrod O., Hardy C., Khaw K.T., Wareham N.J., Gerstung M., Dick J.E., Brennan P., Vassiliou G.S., Shlush L.I. Prediction of acute myeloid leukaemia risk in healthy individuals. Nature. 2018;559:400–404.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6485381</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29988082</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li Z.W., W S. Tumor microenvironment and drug resistance in hematologic malignancies. Blood Rev. 2006;20:333–342.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16920238</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tyner J.W., Tognon C.E., Bottomly D., Wilmot B., Kurtz S.E., Savage S.L., Long N., Schultz A.R., Traer E., Abel M. Functional genomic landscape of acute myeloid leukaemia. Nature. 2018;562:526–531.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6280667</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30333627</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hu Q., Sun W., Wang J., Ruan H., Zhang X., Ye Y., Shen S., Wang C., Lu W., Cheng K., Dotti G., Zeidner J.F., Wang J., Gu Z. Conjugation of haematopoietic stem cells and platelets decorated with anti-PD-1 antibodies augments anti-leukaemia efficacy. Nat Biomed Eng. 2018;2:831–840.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7032014</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31015615</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Short N.J., Konopleva M., Kadia T.M., Anderson N.R., Li H., Harris M.W., Kalinkovich A., Golan K., Ludin A., Cohen D., Shulman Z., Avigdor A., Nagler A., Kollet O., Seger R., Lapidot T. Advances in the treatment of acute myeloid leukemia:new drugs and new challenges. Cancer Discov. 2020;10:506–525.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32014868</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kumar B., Garcia M., Weng L., Jung X., Murakami J.L., Hu X. Acute myeloid leukemia transforms the bone marrow niche into a leukemia-permissive microenvironment through exosome secretion. Leukemia. 2018;32:575–587.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5843902</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28816238</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bleul C.C., Thakur S., Pant D., Zhang Y., Ju E., Liu Z., Cao F., Chen Z., Ren J., Qu X. A highly efficacious lymphocyte chemoattractant, stromal cell-derived factor 1 (SDF-1) J. Exp. Med. 1996;184:1101–1109.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2192798</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9064327</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tavernier-Tardy E., Cornillon J., Campos L., Flandrin P., Duval A., Nadal N., Guyotat D. Prognostic value of CXCR4 and FAK expression in acute myelogenous leukemia. Leuk. Res. 2009;33:764–768.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19042019</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zeng Z., Shi Y.X., Samudio I.J., Wang R.Y., Ling X., Frolova O., Levis M., Rubin J.B., Negrin R.R., Estey E.H., Konoplev S., Andreeff M., Konopleva M. Targeting the leukemia microenvironment by CXCR4 inhibition overcomes resistance to kinase inhibitors and chemotherapy in AML. Blood. 2009;113:6215–6224.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2699240</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18955566</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li X., Guo H., Yang Y., Meng J., Liu J., Wang C., Xu H. A designed peptide targeting CXCR4 displays anti-acute myelocytic leukemia activity in vitro and in vivo. Sci. Rep. 2014;4:6610–6619.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4196105</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25312253</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mombled M., Rodriguez L., Avalon M., Duchez P., Vlaski-Lafarge M., Debeissat C., Perard B., Sawai K.M., Pasquet J.M., Bijou F., Thevenot F., Cabantous T., Ivanovic Z., Brunet de la Grange P. Characteristics of cells with engraftment capacity within CD34+ cell population upon G-CSF and Plerixafor mobilization. Leukemia. 2020;34:3370–3381.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32690879</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu Y., Luo J., Chen X., Liu W., Chen T. Cell membrane coating technology: a promising strategy for biomedical applications. Nano-Micro Lett. 2019:11.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7770915</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34138027</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang Y., Zhang K., Qin X., Li T., Qiu J., Yin T., Huang J., McGinty S., Pontrelli G., Ren J., Wang Q., Wu W., Wang G. Biomimetic nanotherapies: red blood cell based core-shell structured nanocomplexes for atherosclerosis management. Adv. Sci. 2019;6:1900172.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6662054</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31380165</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wan J., Wang J., Zhou M., Rao Z., Ling X. A cell membrane vehicle co-delivering sorafenib and doxorubicin remodel the tumor microenvironment and enhance immunotherapy by inducing immunogenic cell death in lung cancer cells. J. Mater. Chem. B. 2020;8:7755–7765.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32735004</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xie W., Deng W.W., Zan M., Rao L., Yu G.T., Zhu D.M., Wu W.T., Chen B., Ji L.W., Chen L., Liu K., Guo S.S., Huang H.M., Zhang W.F., Zhao X., Yuan Y., Dong W., Sun Z.J., Liu W. Cancer cell membrane camouflaged nanoparticles to realize starvation therapy cogether with checkpoint blockades for enhancing cancer therapy. ACS Nano. 2019;13:2849–2857.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30803232</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang R., Xu J., Xu L., Sun X., Chen Q., Zhao Y., Peng R., Liu Z. Cancer cell membrane-coated adjuvant nanoparticles with mannose modification for effective anticancer vaccination. ACS Nano. 2018;12:5121–5129.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29771487</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhu J., Zhang M., Zheng D., Hong S., Feng J., Zhang X.Z. A universal approach to render nanomedicine with biological identity derived from cell membranes. Biomacromolecules. 2018;19:2043–2052.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29584410</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ding H., Cai Y., Gao L., Liang M., Miao B., Wu H., Liu Y., Xie N., Tang A., Fan K., Yan X., Nie G. Exosome-like nanozyme vesicles for H2O2-responsive catalytic photoacoustic imaging of xenograft nasopharyngeal carcinoma. Nano Lett. 2019;19:203–209.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30539641</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dong X., Mu L.L., Liu X.L., Zhu H., Yang S.C., Lai X., Liu H.J., Feng H.Y., Lu Q., Zhou B.B.S., Chen H.Z., Chen G.Q., Lovell J.F., Hong D.L., Fang C. Biomimetic, hypoxia‐responsive nanoparticles overcome residual chemoresistant leukemic cells with co‐Targeting of therapy‐induced bone marrow niches. Adv. Funct. Mater. 2020;30:2000309.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schajnovitz A., Itkin T., D'Uva G., Kalinkovich A., Golan K., Ludin A., Cohen D., Shulman Z., Avigdor A., Nagler A., Kollet O., Seger R., Lapidot T. CXCL12 secretion by bone marrow stromal cells is dependent on cell contact and mediated by connexin-43 and connexin-45 gap junctions. Nat. Immunol. 2011;12:391–398.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21441933</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Anderson N.R., Li H., Harris M.W., Kalinkovich A., Golan K., Ludin A., Cohen D., Shulman Z., Avigdor A., Nagler A., Kollet O., Seger R., Lapidot T. CXCL12 knock-out enhances leukemia stem cell response to combination chemotherapy plus tyrosine kinase inhibition in Flt3-ITD acute myeloid leukemia. Blood. 2020;136:7–8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gu T., Wang Y., Lu Y., Cheng L., Feng L., Zhang H., Li X., Han G., Liu Z. Platinum nanoparticles to enable electrodynamic therapy for effective cancer treatment. Adv. Mater. 2019;31:1806803.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30734370</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gu T., Chen T., Cheng L., Li X., Han G., Liu Z. Mesoporous silica decorated with platinum nanoparticles for drug delivery and synergistic electrodynamic-chemotherapy. Nano Res. 2020;13:2209–2215.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu R., Chong Y., Fang G., Jiang X., Pan Y., Chen C., Yin J., Ge C. Synthesis of Pt hollow nanodendrites with enhanced peroxidase-Like activity against bacterial infections: implication for wound healing. Adv. Funct. Mater. 2018;28:1801484.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hao Y., Chen Y., He X., Yu Y., Han R., Li Y., Yang C., Hu D., Qian Z. Polymeric nanoparticles with ROS-responsive prodrug and platinum nanozyme for enhanced chemophotodynamic therapy of colon cancer. Adv. Sci. 2020;7:2001853.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7578901</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33101874</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dar A., Goichberg P., Shinder V., Kalinkovich A., Kollet O., Netzer N., Margalit R., Zsak M., Nagler A., Hardan I., Resnick I., Rot A., Lapidot T. Chemokine receptor CXCR4-dependent internalization and resecretion of functional chemokine SDF-1 by bone marrow endothelial and stromal cells. Nat. Immunol. 2005;6:1038–1046.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16170318</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wen T., He W., Chong Y., Liu Y., Yin J.J., Wu X. Exploring environment-dependent effects of Pd nanostructures on reactive oxygen species (ROS) using electron spin resonance (ESR) technique: implications for biomedical applications. Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys. : Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys. 2015;17:24937–24943.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26344402</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tao E., Enguo Ju, Jinsong Ren, Xiaogang Qu. Bifunctionalized mesoporous silica-supported gold nanoparticles: intrinsic oxidase and peroxidase catalytic activities for antibacterial applications. Adv. Mater. 2015;27:1097–1104.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25655182</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ge C., Fang G., Shen X., Chong Y., Wamer W.G., Gao X., Chai Z., Chen C., Yin J.J. Facet energy versus enzyme-like activities: the unexpected protection of palladium nanocrystals against oxidative damage. ACS Nano. 2016;10:10436–10445.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27934089</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim J., Yun H., Kim S. Human bone marrow endothelial cells elaborate non‐stromal‐cell‐derived factor‐1 (SDF‐1)‐dependent chemoattraction and SDF‐1‐dependent transmigration of haematopoietic progenitors. Br. J. Haematol. 2003;121</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12752108</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leopold L.H., Willemze R. The treatment of acute myeloid leukemia in first relapse: a comprehensive review of the literature. Leuk. Lymphoma. 2002;43:1715–1727.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12685823</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swami A., Reagan M.R., Basto P., Mishima Y., Kamaly N., Glavey S., Zhang S., Moschetta M., Seevaratnam D., Zhang Y.  Proceedings of the national academy of sciences of the united states of America; 2014. Engineered Nanomedicine for Myeloma and Bone Microenvironment Targeting; p. 111.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4104924</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24982170</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu H., Liu L., Song L., Ma M., Gu N., Zhang Y. Enhanced tumor synergistic therapy by injectable magnetic hydrogel mediated generation of hyperthermia and highly toxic reactive oxygen species. ACS Nano. 2019;13:14013–14023.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31639298</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xiao H., Thakur S., Pant D., Zhang Y., Ju E., Liu Z., Cao F., Chen Z., Ren J., Qu X. Red blood cell–derived nanoerythrosome for antigen delivery with enhanced cancer immunotherapy. Sci. Adv. 2019;5</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6810293</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31681841</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li X., Guo H., Duan H., Yang Y., Meng J., Liu J., Wang C., Xu H. Improving chemotherapeutic efficiency in acute myeloid leukemia treatments by chemically synthesized peptide interfering with CXCR4/CXCL12 axis. Sci. Rep. 2015;5:16228–16239.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4633653</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26538086</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35415298</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>14</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2452-199X</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>18</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Dec</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Bioactive materials</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Bioact Mater</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>A biomimetic nanocomposite with enzyme-like activities and CXCR4 antagonism efficiently enhances the therapeutic efficacy of acute myeloid leukemia.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>526</StartPage>
          <EndPage>538</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>526-538</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.bioactmat.2022.03.022</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Despite the progress made to improve therapeutic outcomes for acute myeloid leukemia (AML), many unmet clinical needs remain to be resolved. Unlike existing anti-AML strategies, here we developed a biomimetic nanocomposite to efficiently eliminate the leukemia cells in the bone marrow and prevent the homing of AML. To fulfill our design, the ultra-small nanozyme was conjugated onto the surface of an oxygen-carrying nanoparticle, which was further coated with bone marrow stromal cell membrane. After entering the blood, this biomimetic nanocomposite got actively internalized by the leukemia cells in the blood and released the loaded chemotherapeutics and nanozyme inside the leukemia cells to achieve a synergistic antitumor efficacy. Meanwhile, the adhesive properties of the stromal cell membrane enabled the nanocomposite to home to the bone marrow, where the nanocomposite effectively killed the retained leukemia cells. More importantly, the biomimetic cell membrane also acted as a CXCR4 antagonism to block the CXCR4/CXCL12-mediated homing of leukemia cells to the bone marrow and infiltration to other organs like the liver and spleen. In conclusion, this proof-of-concept study demonstrated that our designed platform effectively kills leukemia cells while preventing their infiltration, thus providing a promising prospect for resolving the clinical challenges in current AML treatment.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Authors.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kong</LastName>
            <ForeName>Fei</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Bioelectronics, Jiangsu Key Laboratory for Biomaterials and Devices, School of Biological Science and Medical Engineering &amp; Collaborative Innovation Center of Suzhou Nano Science and Technology, Southeast University, Nanjing, 210096, PR China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>He</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hongliang</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Bioelectronics, Jiangsu Key Laboratory for Biomaterials and Devices, School of Biological Science and Medical Engineering &amp; Collaborative Innovation Center of Suzhou Nano Science and Technology, Southeast University, Nanjing, 210096, PR China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bai</LastName>
            <ForeName>Huiyuan</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Bioelectronics, Jiangsu Key Laboratory for Biomaterials and Devices, School of Biological Science and Medical Engineering &amp; Collaborative Innovation Center of Suzhou Nano Science and Technology, Southeast University, Nanjing, 210096, PR China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Fang</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Bioelectronics, Jiangsu Key Laboratory for Biomaterials and Devices, School of Biological Science and Medical Engineering &amp; Collaborative Innovation Center of Suzhou Nano Science and Technology, Southeast University, Nanjing, 210096, PR China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ma</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ming</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Bioelectronics, Jiangsu Key Laboratory for Biomaterials and Devices, School of Biological Science and Medical Engineering &amp; Collaborative Innovation Center of Suzhou Nano Science and Technology, Southeast University, Nanjing, 210096, PR China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ning</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Bioelectronics, Jiangsu Key Laboratory for Biomaterials and Devices, School of Biological Science and Medical Engineering &amp; Collaborative Innovation Center of Suzhou Nano Science and Technology, Southeast University, Nanjing, 210096, PR China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yu</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Bioelectronics, Jiangsu Key Laboratory for Biomaterials and Devices, School of Biological Science and Medical Engineering &amp; Collaborative Innovation Center of Suzhou Nano Science and Technology, Southeast University, Nanjing, 210096, PR China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>31</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Bioact Mater</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101685294</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2452-199X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Acute myeloid leukemia</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Biomimetic nanocomposite</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CXCR4/CXCL12 axis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nanozymes</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>I declare that the authors have no known competing financial interests、 personal relationships, or other interests that might be perceived to influence the results and/or discussion reported in this paper.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>36</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35415298</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8976099</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bioactmat.2022.03.022</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">S2452-199X(22)00137-2</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abelson S., Collord G., Ng S.W.K., Weissbrod O., Hardy C., Khaw K.T., Wareham N.J., Gerstung M., Dick J.E., Brennan P., Vassiliou G.S., Shlush L.I. Prediction of acute myeloid leukaemia risk in healthy individuals. Nature. 2018;559:400–404.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6485381</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29988082</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li Z.W., W S. Tumor microenvironment and drug resistance in hematologic malignancies. Blood Rev. 2006;20:333–342.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16920238</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tyner J.W., Tognon C.E., Bottomly D., Wilmot B., Kurtz S.E., Savage S.L., Long N., Schultz A.R., Traer E., Abel M. Functional genomic landscape of acute myeloid leukaemia. Nature. 2018;562:526–531.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6280667</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30333627</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hu Q., Sun W., Wang J., Ruan H., Zhang X., Ye Y., Shen S., Wang C., Lu W., Cheng K., Dotti G., Zeidner J.F., Wang J., Gu Z. Conjugation of haematopoietic stem cells and platelets decorated with anti-PD-1 antibodies augments anti-leukaemia efficacy. Nat Biomed Eng. 2018;2:831–840.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7032014</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31015615</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Short N.J., Konopleva M., Kadia T.M., Anderson N.R., Li H., Harris M.W., Kalinkovich A., Golan K., Ludin A., Cohen D., Shulman Z., Avigdor A., Nagler A., Kollet O., Seger R., Lapidot T. Advances in the treatment of acute myeloid leukemia:new drugs and new challenges. Cancer Discov. 2020;10:506–525.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32014868</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kumar B., Garcia M., Weng L., Jung X., Murakami J.L., Hu X. Acute myeloid leukemia transforms the bone marrow niche into a leukemia-permissive microenvironment through exosome secretion. Leukemia. 2018;32:575–587.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5843902</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28816238</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bleul C.C., Thakur S., Pant D., Zhang Y., Ju E., Liu Z., Cao F., Chen Z., Ren J., Qu X. A highly efficacious lymphocyte chemoattractant, stromal cell-derived factor 1 (SDF-1) J. Exp. Med. 1996;184:1101–1109.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2192798</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9064327</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tavernier-Tardy E., Cornillon J., Campos L., Flandrin P., Duval A., Nadal N., Guyotat D. Prognostic value of CXCR4 and FAK expression in acute myelogenous leukemia. Leuk. Res. 2009;33:764–768.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19042019</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zeng Z., Shi Y.X., Samudio I.J., Wang R.Y., Ling X., Frolova O., Levis M., Rubin J.B., Negrin R.R., Estey E.H., Konoplev S., Andreeff M., Konopleva M. Targeting the leukemia microenvironment by CXCR4 inhibition overcomes resistance to kinase inhibitors and chemotherapy in AML. Blood. 2009;113:6215–6224.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2699240</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18955566</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li X., Guo H., Yang Y., Meng J., Liu J., Wang C., Xu H. A designed peptide targeting CXCR4 displays anti-acute myelocytic leukemia activity in vitro and in vivo. Sci. Rep. 2014;4:6610–6619.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4196105</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25312253</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mombled M., Rodriguez L., Avalon M., Duchez P., Vlaski-Lafarge M., Debeissat C., Perard B., Sawai K.M., Pasquet J.M., Bijou F., Thevenot F., Cabantous T., Ivanovic Z., Brunet de la Grange P. Characteristics of cells with engraftment capacity within CD34+ cell population upon G-CSF and Plerixafor mobilization. Leukemia. 2020;34:3370–3381.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32690879</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu Y., Luo J., Chen X., Liu W., Chen T. Cell membrane coating technology: a promising strategy for biomedical applications. Nano-Micro Lett. 2019:11.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7770915</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34138027</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang Y., Zhang K., Qin X., Li T., Qiu J., Yin T., Huang J., McGinty S., Pontrelli G., Ren J., Wang Q., Wu W., Wang G. Biomimetic nanotherapies: red blood cell based core-shell structured nanocomplexes for atherosclerosis management. Adv. Sci. 2019;6:1900172.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6662054</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31380165</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wan J., Wang J., Zhou M., Rao Z., Ling X. A cell membrane vehicle co-delivering sorafenib and doxorubicin remodel the tumor microenvironment and enhance immunotherapy by inducing immunogenic cell death in lung cancer cells. J. Mater. Chem. B. 2020;8:7755–7765.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32735004</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xie W., Deng W.W., Zan M., Rao L., Yu G.T., Zhu D.M., Wu W.T., Chen B., Ji L.W., Chen L., Liu K., Guo S.S., Huang H.M., Zhang W.F., Zhao X., Yuan Y., Dong W., Sun Z.J., Liu W. Cancer cell membrane camouflaged nanoparticles to realize starvation therapy cogether with checkpoint blockades for enhancing cancer therapy. ACS Nano. 2019;13:2849–2857.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30803232</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang R., Xu J., Xu L., Sun X., Chen Q., Zhao Y., Peng R., Liu Z. Cancer cell membrane-coated adjuvant nanoparticles with mannose modification for effective anticancer vaccination. ACS Nano. 2018;12:5121–5129.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29771487</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhu J., Zhang M., Zheng D., Hong S., Feng J., Zhang X.Z. A universal approach to render nanomedicine with biological identity derived from cell membranes. Biomacromolecules. 2018;19:2043–2052.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29584410</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ding H., Cai Y., Gao L., Liang M., Miao B., Wu H., Liu Y., Xie N., Tang A., Fan K., Yan X., Nie G. Exosome-like nanozyme vesicles for H2O2-responsive catalytic photoacoustic imaging of xenograft nasopharyngeal carcinoma. Nano Lett. 2019;19:203–209.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30539641</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dong X., Mu L.L., Liu X.L., Zhu H., Yang S.C., Lai X., Liu H.J., Feng H.Y., Lu Q., Zhou B.B.S., Chen H.Z., Chen G.Q., Lovell J.F., Hong D.L., Fang C. Biomimetic, hypoxia‐responsive nanoparticles overcome residual chemoresistant leukemic cells with co‐Targeting of therapy‐induced bone marrow niches. Adv. Funct. Mater. 2020;30:2000309.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schajnovitz A., Itkin T., D'Uva G., Kalinkovich A., Golan K., Ludin A., Cohen D., Shulman Z., Avigdor A., Nagler A., Kollet O., Seger R., Lapidot T. CXCL12 secretion by bone marrow stromal cells is dependent on cell contact and mediated by connexin-43 and connexin-45 gap junctions. Nat. Immunol. 2011;12:391–398.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21441933</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Anderson N.R., Li H., Harris M.W., Kalinkovich A., Golan K., Ludin A., Cohen D., Shulman Z., Avigdor A., Nagler A., Kollet O., Seger R., Lapidot T. CXCL12 knock-out enhances leukemia stem cell response to combination chemotherapy plus tyrosine kinase inhibition in Flt3-ITD acute myeloid leukemia. Blood. 2020;136:7–8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gu T., Wang Y., Lu Y., Cheng L., Feng L., Zhang H., Li X., Han G., Liu Z. Platinum nanoparticles to enable electrodynamic therapy for effective cancer treatment. Adv. Mater. 2019;31:1806803.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30734370</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gu T., Chen T., Cheng L., Li X., Han G., Liu Z. Mesoporous silica decorated with platinum nanoparticles for drug delivery and synergistic electrodynamic-chemotherapy. Nano Res. 2020;13:2209–2215.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu R., Chong Y., Fang G., Jiang X., Pan Y., Chen C., Yin J., Ge C. Synthesis of Pt hollow nanodendrites with enhanced peroxidase-Like activity against bacterial infections: implication for wound healing. Adv. Funct. Mater. 2018;28:1801484.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hao Y., Chen Y., He X., Yu Y., Han R., Li Y., Yang C., Hu D., Qian Z. Polymeric nanoparticles with ROS-responsive prodrug and platinum nanozyme for enhanced chemophotodynamic therapy of colon cancer. Adv. Sci. 2020;7:2001853.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7578901</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33101874</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dar A., Goichberg P., Shinder V., Kalinkovich A., Kollet O., Netzer N., Margalit R., Zsak M., Nagler A., Hardan I., Resnick I., Rot A., Lapidot T. Chemokine receptor CXCR4-dependent internalization and resecretion of functional chemokine SDF-1 by bone marrow endothelial and stromal cells. Nat. Immunol. 2005;6:1038–1046.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16170318</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wen T., He W., Chong Y., Liu Y., Yin J.J., Wu X. Exploring environment-dependent effects of Pd nanostructures on reactive oxygen species (ROS) using electron spin resonance (ESR) technique: implications for biomedical applications. Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys. : Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys. 2015;17:24937–24943.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26344402</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tao E., Enguo Ju, Jinsong Ren, Xiaogang Qu. Bifunctionalized mesoporous silica-supported gold nanoparticles: intrinsic oxidase and peroxidase catalytic activities for antibacterial applications. Adv. Mater. 2015;27:1097–1104.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25655182</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ge C., Fang G., Shen X., Chong Y., Wamer W.G., Gao X., Chai Z., Chen C., Yin J.J. Facet energy versus enzyme-like activities: the unexpected protection of palladium nanocrystals against oxidative damage. ACS Nano. 2016;10:10436–10445.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27934089</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim J., Yun H., Kim S. Human bone marrow endothelial cells elaborate non‐stromal‐cell‐derived factor‐1 (SDF‐1)‐dependent chemoattraction and SDF‐1‐dependent transmigration of haematopoietic progenitors. Br. J. Haematol. 2003;121</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12752108</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leopold L.H., Willemze R. The treatment of acute myeloid leukemia in first relapse: a comprehensive review of the literature. Leuk. Lymphoma. 2002;43:1715–1727.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12685823</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swami A., Reagan M.R., Basto P., Mishima Y., Kamaly N., Glavey S., Zhang S., Moschetta M., Seevaratnam D., Zhang Y.  Proceedings of the national academy of sciences of the united states of America; 2014. Engineered Nanomedicine for Myeloma and Bone Microenvironment Targeting; p. 111.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4104924</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24982170</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu H., Liu L., Song L., Ma M., Gu N., Zhang Y. Enhanced tumor synergistic therapy by injectable magnetic hydrogel mediated generation of hyperthermia and highly toxic reactive oxygen species. ACS Nano. 2019;13:14013–14023.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31639298</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xiao H., Thakur S., Pant D., Zhang Y., Ju E., Liu Z., Cao F., Chen Z., Ren J., Qu X. Red blood cell–derived nanoerythrosome for antigen delivery with enhanced cancer immunotherapy. Sci. Adv. 2019;5</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6810293</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31681841</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li X., Guo H., Duan H., Yang Y., Meng J., Liu J., Wang C., Xu H. Improving chemotherapeutic efficiency in acute myeloid leukemia treatments by chemically synthesized peptide interfering with CXCR4/CXCL12 axis. Sci. Rep. 2015;5:16228–16239.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4633653</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26538086</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
