<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35411663</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>12</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>12</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1523-5378</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>27</Volume>
            <Issue>3</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Helicobacter</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Helicobacter</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Age of eradication and failure rates of clarithromycin-containing triple therapy for Helicobacter pylori: A 15-year population-based study.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e12893</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e12893</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/hel.12893</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Failure rates of clarithromycin-containing triple therapy for H. pylori are rising. To determine the trend of failure rates of clarithromycin-containing triple therapy in different age groups in Hong Kong over the past 15 years.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This is a population-based retrospective age-period-cohort study involving all adult H. pylori-infected patients who had received the first course of clarithromycin-containing triple therapy in 2003-2017. Failed eradication was identified by the need of retreatment within 2 years of eradication. Logistic regression model was used to characterize the risk of retreatment.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">113,526 H. pylori-infected patients were included. The overall failure rate increased from 4.83% in 2003 to 10.2% in 2016 (p for linear trend &lt;0.001). When stratified by age of eradication, patients 75 years or above had the lowest retreatment rate of 5.11%, which progressively increased in younger patients (60-74 years: OR 1.26, 95% CI 1.15-1.38; 45-59 years: OR 1.36, 95% CI 1.24-1.48; 18-44 years: OR 1.55, 95% CI 1.41-1.69). The results remained consistent when stratified by year of birth, and period of eradication. Other risk factors for retreatment included female (OR 1.24, 95% CI 1.18-1.30), triple therapy containing metronidazole (OR 2.30, 95% CI 2.12-2.50), and shorter duration of therapy (10 days: OR 0.88, 95% CI 0.79-0.97; 14 days: OR 0.67, 95% CI 0.58-0.77 vs 7 days).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">While failure rates of clarithromycin-containing triple therapy progressively increased over the past 15 years, the failure rate was particularly high among younger patients, which could undermine the potential benefits of early H. pylori eradication.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Jiang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Fang</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Li Ka Shing Faculty of Medicine, University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Guo</LastName>
            <ForeName>Chuan-Guo</ForeName>
            <Initials>CG</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Li Ka Shing Faculty of Medicine, University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, Beijing Friendship Hospital, Capital Medical University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Cheung</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ka Shing</ForeName>
            <Initials>KS</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Li Ka Shing Faculty of Medicine, University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Li</LastName>
            <ForeName>Bofei</ForeName>
            <Initials>B</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Surgery, Li Ka Shing Faculty of Medicine, University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Surgery, Shanghai Chest Hospital, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Law</LastName>
            <ForeName>Simon Y K</ForeName>
            <Initials>SYK</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Surgery, Li Ka Shing Faculty of Medicine, University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Leung</LastName>
            <ForeName>Wai K</ForeName>
            <Initials>WK</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medicine, Li Ka Shing Faculty of Medicine, University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>04</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Helicobacter</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9605411</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1083-4389</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000900">Anti-Bacterial Agents</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>140QMO216E</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D008795">Metronidazole</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>804826J2HU</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000658">Amoxicillin</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>H1250JIK0A</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D017291">Clarithromycin</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000658" MajorTopicYN="N">Amoxicillin</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000900" MajorTopicYN="N">Anti-Bacterial Agents</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017291" MajorTopicYN="N">Clarithromycin</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015331" MajorTopicYN="N">Cohort Studies</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004359" MajorTopicYN="N">Drug Therapy, Combination</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016481" MajorTopicYN="Y">Helicobacter Infections</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016480" MajorTopicYN="Y">Helicobacter pylori</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008795" MajorTopicYN="N">Metronidazole</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">
Helicobacter pylori
</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">age</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">birth-cohort effect</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">time trend</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>33</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35411663</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/hel.12893</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Malfertheiner P, Megraud F, O'Morain C, et al. Current concepts in the management of Helicobacter pylori infection: the Maastricht III Consensus Report. Gut. 2007;56(6):772-781.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wroblewski LE, Peek RM Jr, Wilson KT. Helicobacter pylori and gastric cancer: factors that modulate disease risk. Clin Microbiol Rev. 2010;23(4):713-739.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Suerbaum S, Michetti P. Helicobacter pylori infection. N Engl J Med. 2002;347(15):1175-1186.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nagy P, Johansson S, Molloy-Bland M. Systematic review of time trends in the prevalence of Helicobacter pylori infection in China and the USA. Gut Pathog. 2016;8:8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang C, Nishiyama T, Kikuchi S, et al. Changing trends in the prevalence of H. pylori infection in Japan (1908-2003): a systematic review and meta-regression analysis of 170,752 individuals. Sci Rep. 2017;7(1):15491.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Watanabe M, Ito H, Hosono S, et al. Declining trends in prevalence of Helicobacter pylori infection by birth-year in a Japanese population. Cancer Sci. 2015;106(12):1738-1743.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boltin D, Niv Y, Schutte K, Schulz C. Review: Helicobacter pylori and non-malignant upper gastrointestinal diseases. Helicobacter. 2019;24(Suppl 1):e12637.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee YC, Chiang TH, Chou CK, et al. Association between Helicobacter pylori eradication and gastric cancer incidence: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Gastroenterology. 2016;150(5):1113-1124 e1115.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chiang TH, Chang WJ, Chen SL, et al. Mass eradication of Helicobacter pylori to reduce gastric cancer incidence and mortality: a long-term cohort study on Matsu Islands. Gut. 2021;70(2):243-250.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leung WK, Wong IOL, Cheung KS, et al. Effects of Helicobacter pylori treatment on incidence of gastric cancer in older individuals. Gastroenterology. 2018;155(1):67-75.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ford AC, Forman D, Hunt RH, Yuan Y, Moayyedi P. Helicobacter pylori eradication therapy to prevent gastric cancer in healthy asymptomatic infected individuals: systematic review and meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials. BMJ. 2014;348:g3174.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hentschel E, Brandstatter G, Dragosics B, et al. Effect of ranitidine and amoxicillin plus metronidazole on the eradication of Helicobacter pylori and the recurrence of duodenal ulcer. N Engl J Med. 1993;328(5):308-312.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jiang F, Guo CG, Cheung KS, Leung WK. Long-term risk of upper gastrointestinal bleeding after Helicobacter pylori eradication: a population-based cohort study. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2021;54(9):1162-1169.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Malfertheiner P, Megraud F, O'Morain CA, et al. Management of Helicobacter pylori infection--the Maastricht IV/Florence Consensus Report. Gut. 2012;61(5):646-664.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Savoldi A, Carrara E, Graham DY, Conti MTacconelli E. Prevalence of antibiotic resistance in Helicobacter pylori: a systematic review and meta-analysis in world health organization regions. Gastroenterology. 2018;155(5):1372-1382 e1317.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chey WD, Leontiadis GI, Howden CW, Moss SF. ACG clinical guideline: treatment of Helicobacter pylori infection. Am J Gastroenterol. 2017;112(2):212-239.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Malfertheiner P, Megraud F, O'Morain CA, et al. Management of Helicobacter pylori infection-the Maastricht V/Florence Consensus Report. Gut. 2017;66(1):6-30.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Quan H, Sundararajan V, Halfon P, et al. Coding algorithms for defining comorbidities in ICD-9-CM and ICD-10 administrative data. Med Care. 2005;43(11):1130-1139.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim SY, Hyun JJ, Jung SW, Koo JS, Yim HJ, Lee SW. Helicobacter pylori recurrence after first- and second-line eradication therapy in Korea: the problem of recrudescence or reinfection. Helicobacter. 2014;19(3):202-206.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guo CG, Jiang F, Cheung KS, Li B, Ooi PH, Leung WK. Timing of prior exposure to antibiotics and failure of Helicobacter pylori eradication: a population-based study. J Antimicrob Chemother. 2021;77:517-523.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Everhart JE, Kruszon-Moran D, Perez-Perez GI, Tralka TS, McQuillan G. Seroprevalence and ethnic differences in Helicobacter pylori infection among adults in the United States. J Infect Dis. 2000;181(4):1359-1363.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yeh JM, Goldie SJ, Kuntz KM, Ezzati M. Effects of Helicobacter pylori infection and smoking on gastric cancer incidence in China: a population-level analysis of trends and projections. Cancer Causes Control. 2009;20(10):2021-2029.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fischbach L, Evans EL. Meta-analysis: the effect of antibiotic resistance status on the efficacy of triple and quadruple first-line therapies for Helicobacter pylori. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2007;26(3):343-357.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Megraud F, Coenen S, Versporten A, et al. Helicobacter pylori resistance to antibiotics in Europe and its relationship to antibiotic consumption. Gut. 2013;62(1):34-42.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Megraud F, Bruyndonckx R, Coenen S, et al. Helicobacter pylori resistance to antibiotics in Europe in 2018 and its relationship to antibiotic consumption in the community. Gut. 2021;70:1815-1822.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Klein EY, Van Boeckel TP, Martinez EM, et al. Global increase and geographic convergence in antibiotic consumption between 2000 and 2015. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 2018;115(15):E3463-E3470.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kuo YT, Liou JM, El-Omar EM, et al. Primary antibiotic resistance in Helicobacter pylori in the Asia-Pacific region: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Lancet Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2017;2(10):707-715.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meyssonnier V, Veziris N, Bastian S, Texier-Maugein J, Jarlier V, Robert J. Increase in primary drug resistance of Mycobacterium tuberculosis in younger birth cohorts in France. J Infect. 2012;64(6):589-595.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tang Y, Tang G, Pan L, Zhu H, Zhou S, Wei Z. Clinical factors associated with initial Helicobacter pylori eradication therapy: a retrospective study in China. Sci Rep 2020;10(1):15403.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kocsmar E, Buzas GM, Szirtes I, et al. Primary and secondary clarithromycin resistance in Helicobacter pylori and mathematical modeling of the role of macrolides. Nat Commun. 2021;12(1):2255.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Broutet N, Tchamgoue S, Pereira E, Lamouliatte H, Salamon R, Megraud F. Risk factors for failure of Helicobacter pylori therapy - results of an individual data analysis of 2751 patients. Aliment Pharmacol Ther 2003;17(1):99-109.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guo CG, Cheung KS, Zhang F, et al. Incidences, temporal trends and risks of hospitalisation for gastrointestinal bleeding in new or chronic low-dose aspirin users after treatment for Helicobacter pylori: a territory-wide cohort study. Gut. 2020;69(3):445-452.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guo CG, Cheung KS, Zhang F, et al. Delay in retreatment of Helicobacter pylori infection increases risk of upper gastrointestinal bleeding. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2021;19(2):314-322 e312.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guo CG, Cheung KS, Zhang F, et al. Risks of hospitalization for upper gastrointestinal bleeding in users of selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors after Helicobacter pylori eradication therapy: a propensity score matching analysis. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2019;50(9):1001-1008.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cheung KS, Chan EW, Wong AYS, Chen L, Wong ICK, Leung WK. Long-term proton pump inhibitors and risk of gastric cancer development after treatment for Helicobacter pylori: a population-based study. Gut. 2018;67(1):28-35.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gu Q, Xia HH, Wang JD, et al. Update on clarithromycin resistance in Helicobacter pylori in Hong Kong and its effect on clarithromycin-based triple therapy. Digestion. 2006;73(2-3):101-106.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hung IF, Chan P, Leung S, et al. Clarithromycin-amoxycillin-containing triple therapy: a valid empirical first-line treatment for Helicobacter pylori eradication in Hong Kong? Helicobacter. 2009;14(6):505-511.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
