<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35427282</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>24</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>24</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-5166</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>42</Volume>
            <Issue>2</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
              <Day>01</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of neuro-ophthalmology : the official journal of the North American Neuro-Ophthalmology Society</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Neuroophthalmol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Neuro-Ophthalmological Complications of the COVID-19 Vaccines: A Systematic Review.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>154</StartPage>
          <EndPage>162</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>154-162</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/WNO.0000000000001537</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">A worldwide mass vaccination campaign against the coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) pandemic is currently underway. Although the safety data of the clinical trials did not report specific concerns regarding neuro-ophthalmological adverse events, they involved a limited number of individuals and were conducted over a relatively short time. The aim of the current review is to summarize the available postmarketing data regarding the occurrence of neuro-ophthalmological and other ocular complications of the COVID-19 vaccines.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="EVIDENCE ACQUISITION" NlmCategory="METHODS">Electronic searches for published literature were conducted using Ovid MEDLINE, Embase, Web of Science, Google Scholar, Cochrane Central Register of Controlled Trials, Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews, and ClinicalTrials.gov. The search strategy incorporated controlled vocabulary and free-text synonyms for the concepts of COVID, vaccines, and visual and neuro-ophthalmologic diseases and symptoms.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 14 case reports and 2 case series have been selected for inclusion in the final report, reporting 76 cases of post-COVID-vaccination adverse events. The most common adverse event was optic neuritis (n = 61), followed by uveitis (n = 3), herpes zoster ophthalmicus (n = 2), acute macular neuroretinopathy (n = 2), optic disc edema as an atypical presentation of Guillain-Barré syndrome (n = 1), (arteritic anterior ischemic optic neuropathy; n = 1), abducens nerve palsy (n = 1), oculomotor nerve palsy (n = 1), Tolosa-Hunt syndrome (n = 1), central serous retinopathy (n = 1), acute zonal occult outer retinopathy (n = 1), and bilateral choroiditis (n = 1). Most cases were treated with high-dose steroids and had a favorable clinical outcome.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Since the implementation of the COVID-19 vaccination campaign in the past year, several post-COVID-vaccination neuro-ophthalmological complications have been described. However, considering the number of individuals that have been exposed to the vaccines, the risk seems very low, and the clinical outcome in most cases is favorable. Therefore, on a population level, the benefits of the vaccines far outweigh the risk of neuro-ophthalmological complications.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022 by North American Neuro-Ophthalmology Society.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lotan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Itay</ForeName>
            <Initials>I</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4015-9783</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology (IL, ML), Division of Neuroimmunology and Neuroinfectious Disease, Massachusetts General Hospital and Harvard Medical School, Boston, Massachusetts; and Treadwell Virtual Library for the Massachusetts General Hospital (ML), Boston, Massachusetts.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lydston</LastName>
            <ForeName>Melissa</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Levy</LastName>
            <ForeName>Michael</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Neuroophthalmol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9431308</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1070-8022</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000086663">COVID-19 Vaccines</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000517" MajorTopicYN="N">prevention &amp; control</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000086663" MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19 Vaccines</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006563" MajorTopicYN="Y">Herpes Zoster Ophthalmicus</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D058873" MajorTopicYN="N">Pandemics</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000078202" MajorTopicYN="N">Systematic Reviews as Topic</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors report no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
          <Hour>17</Hour>
          <Minute>9</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35427282</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/WNO.0000000000001537</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">00041327-990000000-00034</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaur SP, Gupta V. COVID-19 Vaccine: a comprehensive status report. Virus Res. 2020;288:198114.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li L, Guo P, Zhang X, Yu Z, Zhang W, Sun H. SARS-CoV-2 vaccine candidates in rapid development. Hum Vaccin Immunother. 2021;17:644–653.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rawat K, Kumari P, Saha L. COVID-19 vaccine: a recent update in pipeline vaccines, their design and development strategies. Eur J Pharmacol. 2021;892:173751.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Samaranayake LP, Seneviratne CJ, Fakhruddin KS. Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) vaccines: a concise review. Oral Dis. 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Karussis D, Petrou P. The spectrum of post-vaccination inflammatory CNS demyelinating syndromes. Autoimmun Rev. 2014;13:215–224.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stubgen JP. A literature review on optic neuritis following vaccination against virus infections. Autoimmun Rev. 2013;12:990–997.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cheng JY, Margo CE, Ocular adverse events following vaccination: overview and update. Surv Ophthalmol. 2021. (epub ahead of print).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>DeStefano F, Verstraeten T, Jackson LA, Okoro CA, Benson P, Black SB, Shinefield HR, Mullooly JP, Likosky W, Chen RT. Vaccinations and risk of central nervous system demyelinating diseases in adults. Arch Neurol. 2003;60:504–509.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Benage M, Fraunfelder FW. Vaccine-associated uveitis. MO Med. 2016;113:48–52.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cunningham ET Jr., Moorthy RS, Fraunfelder FW, Zierhut M. Vaccine-associated uveitis. Ocul immunol inflamm. 2019;27:517–520.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Woo EJ, Winiecki SK, Ou AC. Motor palsies of cranial nerves (excluding VII) after vaccination: reports to the US vaccine adverse event reporting system. Hum Vaccin Immunother. 2014;10:301–305.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen RT, Pless R, Destefano F. Epidemiology of autoimmune reactions induced by vaccination. J Autoimmun. 2001;16:309–318.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schattner A. Consequence or coincidence? The occurrence, pathogenesis and significance of autoimmune manifestations after viral vaccines. Vaccine. 2005;23:3876–3886.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Polack FP, Thomas SJ, Kitchin N, Absalon J, Gurtman A, Lockhart S, Perez JL, Marc GP, Moreira ED, Zerbini C, Bailey R, Swanson KA, Roychoudhury S, Koury K, Li P, Kalina WV, Cooper D, Frenck RW Jr, Hammitt LL, Türeci O, Nell H, Schaefer A, Ünal S, Tresnan DB, Mather S, Dormitzer PR, Şahin U, Jansen KU, Gruber WC. Safety and efficacy of the BNT162b2 mRNA covid-19 vaccine. N Engl J Med. 2020;383:2603–2615.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Voysey M, Clemens SAC, Madhi SA, Weckx LY, Folegatti PM, Aley PK, Angus B, Baillie VL. Safety and efficacy of the ChAdOx1 nCoV-19 vaccine (AZD1222) against SARS-CoV-2: an interim analysis of four randomised controlled trials in Brazil, South Africa, and the UK. Lancet. 2021;397:99–111.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baden LR, El Sahly HM, Essink B, Kotloff K, Frey S, Novak R, Diemert D, Spector SA, Rouphael N, Creech CB, McGettigan J, Khetan S, Segall N, Solis J, Brosz A, Fierro C, Schwartz H, Neuzil K, Corey L, Gilbert P, Janes H, Follmann D, Marovich M, Mascola J, Polakowski L, Ledgerwood J, Graham BS, Bennett H, Pajon R, Knightly C, Leav B, Deng W, Zhou H, Han S, Ivarsson M, Miller J, Zaks T. Efficacy and safety of the mRNA-1273 SARS-CoV-2 vaccine. N Engl J Med. 2021;384:403–416.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sadoff J, Gray G, Vandebosch A, Cárdenas V, Shukarev G, Grinsztejn B, Goepfert PA, Truyers C, Fennema H, Spiessens B, Offergeld K, Scheper G, Taylor KL, Robb ML, Treanor J, Barouch DH, Stoddard J, Ryser MF, Marovich MA, Neuzil KM, Corey L, Cauwenberghs N, Tanner T, Hardt K, Ruiz-Guiñazú J, Le Gars M, Schuitemaker H, Van Hoof J, Struyf F, Douoguih M. Safety and efficacy of single-dose Ad26.COV2.S vaccine against covid-19. N Engl J Med. 2021;384:2187–2201.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Palacios R, Patiño EG, Piorelli RO, Conde MTRP, Batista AP, Zeng G, Xin Q, Kallas EG, Flores J, Ockenhouse CF, Gast C. Double-blind, randomized, placebo-controlled phase III clinical Trial to Evaluate the Efficacy and Safety of treating healthcare Professionals with the adsorbed COVID-19 (inactivated) vaccine Manufactured by sinovac - profiscov: a structured summary of a study protocol for a randomised controlled trial. Trials. 2020;21:853.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harzing AW. Publish or perish. 2007. Available at: https://harzing.com/resources/publish-or-perish.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ket JCF, Van Dusseldorp I. Coronavirus 2019 (COVID-19) (COVID-19 SARS MERS). Biomed Inf Dutch Libr Assoc (Knvi). 2021. Available at: https://blocks.bmi-online.nl/catalog/397.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rathbone J, Carter M, Hoffmann T, Glasziou P. Better duplicate detection for systematic reviewers: evaluation of Systematic Review Assistant-Deduplication Module. Syst Rev. 2015;4:6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alvarez LM, et al. Post vaccination optic neuritis: observations from the SARS-CoV-2 pandemic. 2021. (epub ahead of print).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leber HM, Ana LS, Raio MC, Mazzeo TJMM, Endo CM, Nascimento H 2, Souza CE. Acute thyroiditis and bilateral optic neuritis following SARS-CoV-2 vaccination with CoronaVac: a case report. Ocul Immunol Inflamm. 2021:1–7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Takenaka T, Matsuzaki M, Fujiwara S, Hayashida M, Suyama H, Kawamoto M. Myeloperoxidase anti-neutrophil cytoplasmic antibody positive optic perineuritis after mRNA coronavirus disease-19 vaccine: a case report. QJM. 2021;114:737–738.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaulen LD, Doubrovinskaia S, Mooshage C, Jordan B, Purrucker J. Neurological autoimmune diseases following vaccinations against SARS-CoV-2: a case series. Eur J Neurol. 2022;29:555–563.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Introna A, Caputo F, Santoro C, Guerra T, Ucci M, Mezzapesa DM, Trojano M. Guillain-Barre syndrome after AstraZeneca COVID-19-vaccination: a causal or casual association? Clin Neurol Neurosurg. 2021;208:106887.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maleki A, Look-Why S, Manhapra A, Foster CS. COVID-19 Recombinant mRNA Vaccines and serious ocular inflammatory side effects: Real or coincidence? J Ophthalmic Vis Res. 2021;16:490–501.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reyes-Capo DP, Stevens SM, Cavuoto KM. Acute abducens nerve palsy following COVID-19 vaccination. J AAPOS. 2021;25:302–303.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pappaterra MC, Rivera EJ, Oliver AL. Transient oculomotor palsy following the administration of the messenger RNA-1273 vaccine for SARS-CoV-2 diplopia following the COVID-19 vaccine. J Neuroophthalmol. 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chuang TY, Burda K, Teklemariam E, Athar K. Tolosa-hunt syndrome presenting after COVID-19 vaccination. Cureus. 2021;13:e16791.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thimmanagari K, Veeraballi S, Roach D, Omour BA, Slim J. Ipsilateral zoster ophthalmicus post COVID-19 vaccine in healthy young adults. Cureus. 2021;13:e16725.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>ElSheikh RH, Haseeb A, Eleiwa TK, Elhusseiny AM. Acute uveitis following COVID-19 vaccination. Ocul Immunol Inflamm. 2021;29:1–3.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mudie LI, Zick JD, Dacey MS, Palestine AG. Panuveitis following vaccination for COVID-19. Ocul Immunol Inflamm. 2021:1–2.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Renisi G, Lombardi A, Stanzione M, Invernizzi A, Bandera A, Gori A. Anterior uveitis onset after bnt162b2 vaccination: is this just a coincidence? Int J Infect Dis. 2021;110:95–97.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mambretti M, Huemer J, Torregrossa G, Ullrich M, Findl O, Casalino G. Acute macular neuroretinopathy following coronavirus disease 2019 vaccination. Ocul Immunol Inflamm. 2021:1–4.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fowler N, Mendez Martinez NR, Pallares BV, Maldonado RS. Acute-onset central serous retinopathy after immunization with COVID-19 mRNA vaccine. Am J Ophthalmol Case Rep. 2021;23:101136.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goyal M, Murthy SI, Annum S. Bilateral multifocal choroiditis following COVID-19 vaccination. Ocul Immunol Inflamm. 2021:1–5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vadalà M, Poddighe D, Laurino C, Palmieri B. Vaccination and autoimmune diseases: is prevention of adverse health effects on the horizon? Epma J. 2017;8:295–311.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salemi S, D'Amelio R. Could autoimmunity be induced by vaccination? Int Rev Immunol. 2010;29:247–269.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Segal Y, Shoenfeld Y. Vaccine-induced autoimmunity: the role of molecular mimicry and immune crossreaction. Cell Mol Immunol. 2018;15:586–594.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goriely S, Goldman M. From tolerance to autoimmunity: is there a risk in early life vaccination? J Comp Pathol. 2007;137:S57–S61.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stone CA Jr., Rukasin CRF, Beachkofsky TM. Immune-mediated adverse reactions to vaccines. Br J Clin Pharmacol. 2019;85:2694–2706.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Agmon-Levin N, Hughes GR, Shoenfeld Y. The spectrum of ASIA: 'autoimmune (Auto-inflammatory) syndrome induced by adjuvants'. Lupus. 2012;21:118–120.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yen MY, Liu JH. Bilateral optic neuritis following bacille Calmette-Guérin (BCG) vaccination. J Clin Neuroophthalmol. 1991;11:246–249.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hegde V, Dean F. Bilateral panuveitis and optic neuritis following Bacillus Calmette-Guérin (BCG) vaccination. Acta Paediatr. 2005;94:635–636.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Laria C, Alió J, Rodríguez JL, Sánchez J, Galal A. Optic neuritis after meningococcal vaccination. Arch soc esp oftalmol. 2006;81:479–482.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kerrison JB, Lounsbury D, Thirkill CE, Lane RG, Schatz MP, Engler RM. Optic neuritis after anthrax vaccination. Ophthalmology. 2002;109:99–104.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rubinov A, Beiran I, Krasnitz I, Miller B. Bilateral optic neuritis after inactivated influenza vaccination. Isr Med Assoc J. 2012;14:705–707.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cormack HS, Anderson LA. Bilateral papillitis following antirabic inoculation: recovery. Br J ophthalmol. 1934;18:167–168.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McReynolds WU, Havener WH, Petrohelos MA. Bilateral optic neuritis following smallpox vaccination and diphtheria-tetanus toxoid. AMA Am J Dis Child. 1953;86:601–603.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berkman N, Benzarti T, Dhaoui R, Mouly P. Bilateral neuro-papillitis after hepatitis B vaccination. Presse Med. 1996;25:1301.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Topaloglu H, Berker M, Kansu T, Saatci U, Renda Y. Optic neuritis and myelitis after booster tetanus toxoid vaccination. Lancet. 1992;339:178–179.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Menge T, Cree B, Saleh A, Waterboer T, Berthele A, Kalluri SR, Hemmer B, Aktas O, Hartung HP, Methner A, Kieseier BC. Neuromyelitis optica following human papillomavirus vaccination. Neurology. 2012;79:285–287.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Furukawa Y, Komai K, Yamada M. Neuromyelitis optica after Japanese encephalitis vaccination. Eur J Neurol. 2011;18:e26–e27.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beyer AM, Wandinger KP, Siebert E, Zschenderlein R, Klehmet J. Neuromyelitis optica in a patient with an early onset demyelinating episode: clinical and autoantibody findings. Clin Neurol Neurosurg. 2007;109:926–930.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huynh W, Cordato DJ, Kehdi E, Masters LT, Dedousis C. Post-vaccination encephalomyelitis: literature review and illustrative case. J Clin Neurosci. 2008;15:1315–1322.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen JJ, Bhatti MT. Clinical phenotype, radiological features, and treatment of myelin oligodendrocyte glycoprotein-immunoglobulin G (MOG-IgG) optic neuritis. Curr Opin Neurol. 2019;33:47–54.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dos Passos GR, Oliveira LM, Costa BK, Apostolos-Pereira SL, Callegaro D, Fujihara K, Sato DK. MOG-IgG-Associated optic neuritis, encephalitis, and myelitis: lessons learned from neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder. Front neurol. 2018;9:217.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Narayan R, Simpson A, Fritsche K, Salama S, Pardo S, Mealy M, Paul F, Levy M. MOG antibody disease: a review of MOG antibody seropositive neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder. Mult Scler Relat Disord. 2018;25:66–72.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ramanathan S, Dale RC, Brilot F. Anti-MOG antibody: The history, clinical phenotype, and pathogenicity of a serum biomarker for demyelination. Autoimmun Rev. 2016;15:307–324.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reindl M, Waters P. Myelin oligodendrocyte glycoprotein antibodies in neurological disease. Nat Rev Neurol. 2018;15:89–102.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sepúlveda M, Armangue T, Martinez-Hernandez E, Arrambide G, Sola-Valls N, Sabater L, Téllez N, Midaglia L, Ariño H, Peschl P, Reindl M, Rovira A, Montalban X, Blanco Y, Dalmau J, Graus F, Saiz A. Clinical spectrum associated with MOG autoimmunity in adults: significance of sharing rodent MOG epitopes. J Neurol. 2016;263:1349–1360.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weber MS, Derfuss T, Metz I, Brück W. Defining distinct features of anti-MOG antibody associated central nervous system demyelination. Ther Adv Neurol Disord. 2018;11:1756286418762083.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sharifian-Dorche M, Bahmanyar M, Sharifian-Dorche A, Mohammadi P, Nomovi M, Mowla A. Vaccine-induced immune thrombotic thrombocytopenia and cerebral venous sinus thrombosis post COVID-19 vaccination; a systematic review. J Neurol Sci. 2021;428:117607.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
