<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35427813</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>24</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1535-9484</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>21</Volume>
            <Issue>5</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Molecular &amp; cellular proteomics : MCP</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Mol Cell Proteomics</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>New Global Insights on the Regulation of the Biphasic Life Cycle and Virulence Via ClpP-Dependent Proteolysis in Legionella pneumophila.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>100233</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>100233</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">100233</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.mcpro.2022.100233</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1535-9476(22)00041-X</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Legionella pneumophila, an environmental bacterium that parasitizes protozoa, causes Legionnaires' disease in humans that is characterized by severe pneumonia. This bacterium adopts a distinct biphasic life cycle consisting of a nonvirulent replicative phase and a virulent transmissive phase in response to different environmental conditions. Hence, the timely and fine-tuned expression of growth and virulence factors in a life cycle-dependent manner is crucial for survival and replication. Here, we report that the completion of the biphasic life cycle and bacterial pathogenesis is greatly dependent on the protein homeostasis regulated by caseinolytic protease P (ClpP)-dependent proteolysis. We characterized the ClpP-dependent dynamic profiles of the regulatory and substrate proteins during the biphasic life cycle of L. pneumophila using proteomic approaches and discovered that ClpP-dependent proteolysis specifically and conditionally degraded the substrate proteins, thereby directly playing a regulatory role or indirectly controlling cellular events via the regulatory proteins. We further observed that ClpP-dependent proteolysis is required to monitor the abundance of fatty acid biosynthesis-related protein Lpg0102/Lpg0361/Lpg0362 and SpoT for the normal regulation of L. pneumophila differentiation. We also found that the control of the biphasic life cycle and bacterial virulence is independent. Furthermore, the ClpP-dependent proteolysis of Dot/Icm (defect in organelle trafficking/intracellular multiplication) type IVB secretion system and effector proteins at a specific phase of the life cycle is essential for bacterial pathogenesis. Therefore, our findings provide novel insights on ClpP-dependent proteolysis, which spans a broad physiological spectrum involving key metabolic pathways that regulate the transition of the biphasic life cycle and bacterial virulence of L. pneumophila, facilitating adaptation to aquatic and intracellular niches.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ge</LastName>
            <ForeName>Zhenhuang</ForeName>
            <Initials>Z</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Chemistry, Sun Yat-sen University, Guangzhou, China; School of Life Sciences, Sun Yat-sen University, Guangzhou, China; Run Ze Laboratory for Gastrointestinal Microbiome Study, Sun Yat-sen University, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yuan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Peibo</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Microbiome Medicine Center, Division of Laboratory Medicine, Zhujiang Hospital, Southern Medical University, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Lingming</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Zhongshan School of Medicine, Sun Yat-sen University, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Junyi</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Life Sciences, Sun Yat-sen University, Guangzhou, China; Run Ze Laboratory for Gastrointestinal Microbiome Study, Sun Yat-sen University, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Shen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Dong</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Life Sciences, Sun Yat-sen University, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>She</LastName>
            <ForeName>Zhigang</ForeName>
            <Initials>Z</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Chemistry, Sun Yat-sen University, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yongjun</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Life Sciences, Sun Yat-sen University, Guangzhou, China; Run Ze Laboratory for Gastrointestinal Microbiome Study, Sun Yat-sen University, Guangzhou, China. Electronic address: luyj@mail.sysu.edu.cn.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>04</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Mol Cell Proteomics</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101125647</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1535-9476</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ClpP</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Legionella pneumophila</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bacterial virulence</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">biphasic life cycle</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">proteomic analysis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">regulated proteolysis</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>Conflict of interest The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
          <Hour>20</Hour>
          <Minute>11</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35427813</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9112007</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mcpro.2022.100233</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">S1535-9476(22)00041-X</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fields B.S., Benson R.F., Besser R.E. Legionella and Legionnaires' disease: 25 years of investigation. Clin. Microbiol. Rev. 2002;15:506–526.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC118082</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12097254</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goncalves I.G., Simoes L.C., Simoes M. Legionella pneumophila. Trends Microbiol. 2021;29:860–861.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33994277</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rowbotham T.J. Preliminary report on the pathogenicity of Legionella pneumophila for freshwater and soil amoebae. J. Clin. Pathol. 1980;33:1179–1183.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1146371</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7451664</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Newton H.J., Ang D.K., van Driel I.R., Hartland E.L. Molecular pathogenesis of infections caused by Legionella pneumophila. Clin. Microbiol. Rev. 2010;23:274–298.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2863363</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20375353</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chauhan D., Shames S.R. Pathogenicity and Virulence of Legionella: Intracellular replication and host response. Virulence. 2021;12:1122–1144.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8043192</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33843434</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oliva G., Sahr T., Buchrieser C. The life cycle of L. pneumophila: Cellular differentiation is linked to virulence and metabolism. Front. Cell Infect. Microbiol. 2018;8:3.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5780407</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29404281</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Molofsky A.B., Swanson M.S. Differentiate to thrive: Lessons from the Legionella pneumophila life cycle. Mol. Microbiol. 2004;53:29–40.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15225301</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Byrne B., Swanson M.S. Expression of Legionella pneumophila virulence traits in response to growth conditions. Infect. Immun. 1998;66:3029–3034.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC108309</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9632562</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nora T., Lomma M., Gomez-Valero L., Buchrieser C. Molecular mimicry: An important virulence strategy employed by Legionella pneumophila to subvert host functions. Future Microbiol. 2009;4:691–701.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19659425</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bruggemann H., Hagman A., Jules M., Sismeiro O., Dillies M.A., Gouyette C., Kunst F., Steinert M., Heuner K., Coppee J.Y., Buchrieser C. Virulence strategies for infecting phagocytes deduced from the in vivo transcriptional program of Legionella pneumophila. Cell Microbiol. 2006;8:1228–1240.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16882028</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Faucher S.P., Mueller C.A., Shuman H.A. Legionella pneumophila transcriptome during intracellular multiplication in human macrophages. Front. Microbiol. 2011;2:60.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3128937</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21747786</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Molofsky A.B., Swanson M.S. Legionella pneumophila CsrA is a pivotal repressor of transmission traits and activator of replication. Mol. Microbiol. 2003;50:445–461.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14617170</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hayashi T., Nakamichi M., Naitou H., Ohashi N., Imai Y., Miyake M. Proteomic analysis of growth phase-dependent expression of Legionella pneumophila proteins which involves regulation of bacterial virulence traits. PLoS One. 2010;5</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aurass P., Gerlach T., Becher D., Voigt B., Karste S., Bernhardt J., Riedel K., Hecker M., Flieger A. Life stage-specific proteomes of Legionella pneumophila reveal a highly differential abundance of virulence-associated dot/icm effectors. Mol. Cell Proteomics. 2016;15:177–200.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4762515</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26545400</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hauslein I., Sahr T., Escoll P., Klausner N., Eisenreich W., Buchrieser C. Legionella pneumophila CsrA regulates a metabolic switch from amino acid to glycerolipid metabolism. Open Biol. 2017;7:170149.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5717341</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29093212</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McNealy T.L., Forsbach-Birk V., Shi C., Marre R. The Hfq homolog in Legionella pneumophila demonstrates regulation by LetA and RpoS and interacts with the global regulator CsrA. J. Bacteriol. 2005;187:1527–1532.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC545622</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15687220</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rasis M., Segal G. The LetA-RsmYZ-CsrA regulatory cascade, together with RpoS and PmrA, post-transcriptionally regulates stationary phase activation of Legionella pneumophila Icm/Dot effectors. Mol. Microbiol. 2009;72:995–1010.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19400807</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sahr T., Rusniok C., Impens F., Oliva G., Sismeiro O., Coppee J.Y., Buchrieser C. The Legionella pneumophila genome evolved to accommodate multiple regulatory mechanisms controlled by the CsrA-system. PLoS Genet. 2017;13</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bachman M.A., Swanson M.S. Genetic evidence that Legionella pneumophila RpoS modulates expression of the transmission phenotype in both the exponential phase and the stationary phase. Infect. Immun. 2004;72:2468–2476.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC387865</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15102753</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hales L.M., Shuman H.A. The Legionella pneumophila rpoS gene is required for growth within Acanthamoeba castellanii. J. Bacteriol. 1999;181:4879–4889.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC93975</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10438758</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tiaden A., Spirig T., Weber S.S., Bruggemann H., Bosshard R., Buchrieser C., Hilbi H. The Legionella pneumophila response regulator LqsR promotes host cell interactions as an element of the virulence regulatory network controlled by RpoS and LetA. Cell Microbiol. 2007;9:2903–2920.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17614967</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Trigui H., Dudyk P., Oh J., Hong J.I., Faucher S.P. A regulatory feedback loop between RpoS and SpoT supports the survival of Legionella pneumophila in water. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 2015;81:918–928.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4292471</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25416763</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zusman T., Gal-Mor O., Segal G. Characterization of a Legionella pneumophila relA insertion mutant and toles of RelA and RpoS in virulence gene expression. J. Bacteriol. 2002;184:67–75.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC134777</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11741845</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Al-Khodor S., Kalachikov S., Morozova I., Price C.T., Abu Kwaik Y. The PmrA/PmrB two-component system of Legionella pneumophila is a global regulator required for intracellular replication within macrophages and protozoa. Infect. Immun. 2009;77:374–386.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2612241</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18936184</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schulz T., Rydzewski K., Schunder E., Holland G., Bannert N., Heuner K. FliA expression analysis and influence of the regulatory proteins RpoN, FleQ and FliA on virulence and in vivo fitness in Legionella pneumophila. Arch. Microbiol. 2012;194:977–989.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23011748</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morash M.G., Brassinga A.K., Warthan M., Gourabathini P., Garduno R.A., Goodman S.D., Hoffman P.S. Reciprocal expression of integration host factor and HU in the developmental cycle and infectivity of Legionella pneumophila. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 2009;75:1826–1837.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2663186</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19201975</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pitre C.A.J., Tanner J.R., Patel P., Brassinga A.K.C. Regulatory control of temporally expressed integration host factor (IHF) in Legionella pneumophila. Microbiology (Reading) 2013;159:475–492.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23288541</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lynch D., Fieser N., Gloggler K., Forsbach-Birk V., Marre R. The response regulator LetA regulates the stationary-phase stress response in Legionella pneumophila and is required for efficient infection of Acanthamoeba castellanii. FEMS Microbiol. Lett. 2003;219:241–248.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12620627</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dalebroux Z.D., Edwards R.L., Swanson M.S. SpoT governs Legionella pneumophila differentiation in host macrophages. Mol. Microbiol. 2009;71:640–658.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19040633</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dalebroux Z.D., Svensson S.L., Gaynor E.C., Swanson M.S. ppGpp conjures bacterial virulence. Microbiol. Mol. Biol. Rev. 2010;74:171–199.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2884408</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20508246</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dalebroux Z.D., Swanson M.S. ppGpp: magic beyond RNA polymerase. Nat. Rev. Microbiol. 2012;10:203–212.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22337166</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Edwards R.L., Jules M., Sahr T., Buchrieser C., Swanson M.S. The Legionella pneumophila LetA/LetS two-component system exhibits rheostat-like behavior. Infect. Immun. 2010;78:2571–2583.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2876543</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20351136</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hammer B.K., Swanson M.S. Co-ordination of legionella pneumophila virulence with entry into stationary phase by ppGpp. Mol. Microbiol. 1999;33:721–731.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10447882</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hammer B.K., Tateda E.S., Swanson M.S. A two-component regulator induces the transmission phenotype of stationary-phase Legionella pneumophila. Mol. Microbiol. 2002;44:107–118.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11967072</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Escoll P., Mondino S., Rolando M., Buchrieser C. Targeting of host organelles by pathogenic bacteria: A sophisticated subversion strategy. Nat. Rev. Microbiol. 2016;14:5–19.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26594043</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hubber A., Roy C.R. Modulation of host cell function by Legionella pneumophila type IV effectors. Annu. Rev. Cell Dev. Biol. 2010;26:261–283.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20929312</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Isberg R.R., O'Connor T.J., Heidtman M. The Legionella pneumophila replication vacuole: Making a cosy niche inside host cells. Nat. Rev. Microbiol. 2009;7:13–24.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2631402</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19011659</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Qiu J., Luo Z.Q. Legionella and coxiella effectors: Strength in diversity and activity. Nat. Rev. Microbiol. 2017;15:591–605.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28713154</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>He L., Lin Y., Ge Z.H., He S.Y., Zhao B.B., Shen D., He J.G., Lu Y.J. The Legionella pneumophila effector WipA disrupts host F-actin polymerisation by hijacking phosphotyrosine signalling. Cell Microbiol. 2019;21</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu Y., Gao P., Banga S., Luo Z.Q. An in vivo gene deletion system for determining temporal requirement of bacterial virulence factors. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2008;105:9385–9390.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2453721</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18599442</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Neunuebel M.R., Chen Y., Gaspar A.H., Backlund P.S., Jr., Yergey A., Machner M.P. De-AMPylation of the small GTPase Rab1 by the pathogen Legionella pneumophila. Science. 2011;333:453–456.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3209958</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21680813</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Black M.H., Osinski A., Gradowski M., Servage K.A., Pawlowski K., Tomchick D.R., Tagliabracci V.S. Bacterial pseudokinase catalyzes protein polyglutamylation to inhibit the SidE-family ubiquitin ligases. Science. 2019;364:787–792.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6767918</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31123136</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gan N., Zhen X., Liu Y., Xu X., He C., Qiu J., Liu Y., Fujimoto G.M., Nakayasu E.S., Zhou B., Zhao L., Puvar K., Das C., Ouyang S., Luo Z.Q. Regulation of phosphoribosyl ubiquitination by a calmodulin-dependent glutamylase. Nature. 2019;572:387–391.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6855250</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31330531</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bhogaraju S., Bonn F., Mukherjee R., Adams M., Pfleiderer M.M., Galej W.P., Matkovic V., Lopez-Mosqueda J., Kalayil S., Shin D., Dikic I. Inhibition of bacterial ubiquitin ligases by SidJ-calmodulin catalysed glutamylation. Nature. 2019;572:382–386.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6715450</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31330532</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sulpizio A., Minelli M.E., Wan M., Burrowes P.D., Wu X., Sanford E.J., Shin J.H., Williams B.C., Goldberg M.L., Smolka M.B., Mao Y. Protein polyglutamylation catalyzed by the bacterial calmodulin-dependent pseudokinase SidJ. Elife. 2019;8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Allombert J., Jaboulay C., Michard C., Andrea C., Charpentier X., Vianney A., Doublet P. Deciphering Legionella effector delivery by Icm/Dot secretion system reveals a new role for c-di-GMP signaling. J. Mol. Biol. 2021;433:166985.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33845084</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bardill J.P., Miller J.L., Vogel J.P. IcmS-dependent translocation of SdeA into macrophages by the Legionella pneumophila type IV secretion system. Mol. Microbiol. 2005;56:90–103.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15773981</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Luo Z.Q., Isberg R.R. Multiple substrates of the Legionella pneumophila Dot/Icm system identified by interbacterial protein transfer. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2004;101:841–846.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC321768</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14715899</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nagai H., Kagan J.C., Zhu X., Kahn R.A., Roy C.R. A bacterial guanine nucleotide exchange factor activates ARF on Legionella phagosomes. Science. 2002;295:679–682.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11809974</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gottesman S. Proteolysis in bacterial regulatory circuits. Annu. Rev. Cell Dev. Biol. 2003;19:565–587.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14570582</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mahmoud S.A., Chien P. Regulated proteolysis in bacteria. Annu. Rev. Biochem. 2018;87:677–696.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6013389</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29648875</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gur E., Biran D., Ron E.Z. Regulated proteolysis in Gram-negative bacteria--how and when? Nat. Rev. Microbiol. 2011;9:839–848.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22020261</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kahne S.C., Darwin K.H. Structural determinants of regulated proteolysis in pathogenic bacteria by ClpP and the proteasome. Curr. Opin. Struct. Biol. 2021;67:120–126.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8096641</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33221704</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Konovalova A., Sogaard-Andersen L., Kroos L. Regulated proteolysis in bacterial development. FEMS Microbiol. Rev. 2014;38:493–522.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4002673</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24354618</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wettstadt S., Llamas M.A. Role of regulated proteolysis in the communication of bacteria with the environment. Front. Mol. Biosci. 2020;7:586497.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7593790</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33195433</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Becker G., Klauck E., Hengge-Aronis R. Regulation of RpoS proteolysis in Escherichia coli: The response regulator RssB is a recognition factor that interacts with the turnover element in RpoS. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 1999;96:6439–6444.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC26900</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10339606</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Turgay K., Hahn J., Burghoorn J., Dubnau D. Competence in Bacillus subtilis is controlled by regulated proteolysis of a transcription factor. EMBO J. 1998;17:6730–6738.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1171018</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9890793</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhou Y., Gottesman S., Hoskins J.R., Maurizi M.R., Wickner S. The RssB response regulator directly targets sigma(S) for degradation by ClpXP. Genes Dev. 2001;15:627–637.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC312640</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11238382</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li X.H., Zeng Y.L., Gao Y., Zheng X.C., Zhang Q.F., Zhou S.N., Lu Y.J. The ClpP protease homologue is required for the transmission traits and cell division of the pathogen Legionella pneumophila. BMC Microbiol. 2010;10:54.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2838875</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20167127</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhao B.B., Li X.H., Zeng Y.L., Lu Y.J. ClpP-deletion impairs the virulence of Legionella pneumophila and the optimal translocation of effector proteins. BMC Microbiol. 2016;16:174.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4969725</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27484084</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ge Z.H., Long Q.S., Yuan P.B., Pan X., Shen D., Lu Y.J. The temporal expression of global regulator protein CsrA is dually regulated by ClpP during the biphasic life cycle of Legionella pneumophila. Front. Microbiol. 2019;10:2495.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6853998</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31787938</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Feng J., Michalik S., Varming A.N., Andersen J.H., Albrecht D., Jelsbak L., Krieger S., Ohlsen K., Hecker M., Gerth U., Ingmer H., Frees D. Trapping and proteomic identification of cellular substrates of the ClpP protease in Staphylococcus aureus. J. Proteome Res. 2013;12:547–558.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23253041</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Feeley J.C., Gibson R.J., Gorman G.W., Langford N.C., Rasheed J.K., Mackel D.C., Baine W.B. Charcoal-yeast extract agar: Primary isolation medium for Legionella pneumophila. J. Clin. Microbiol. 1979;10:437–441.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC273193</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">393713</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Segal G., Shuman H.A. Legionella pneumophila utilizes the same genes to multiply within Acanthamoeba castellanii and human macrophages. Infect. Immun. 1999;67:2117–2124.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC115946</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10225863</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yuan P., He L., Chen D., Sun Y., Ge Z., Shen D., Lu Y. Proteomic characterization of Mycobacterium tuberculosis reveals potential targets of bostrycin. J. Proteomics. 2020;212:103576.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31706025</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bernhardt J., Funke S., Hecker M., Siebourg J.  IEEE; Copenhagen: 2009. Visualizing Gene Expression Data via Voronoi Treemaps, Sixth International Symposium on Voronoi Diagrams. 233–241.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Otto A., Bernhardt J., Meyer H., Schaffer M., Herbst F.A., Siebourg J., Mader U., Lalk M., Hecker M., Becher D. Systems-wide temporal proteomic profiling in glucose-starved Bacillus subtilis. Nat. Commun. 2010;1:137.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3105300</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21266987</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Balzer N., Deussen O.  IEEE; Minneapolis, MN: 2005. Voronoi Treemaps, Proceedings of the 2005 IEEE Symposium on Information Visualization; pp. 49–56.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Michalik S., Bernhardt J., Otto A., Moche M., Becher D., Meyer H., Lalk M., Schurmann C., Schluter R., Kock H., Gerth U., Hecker M. Life and death of proteins: A case study of glucose-starved Staphylococcus aureus. Mol. Cell Proteomics. 2012;11:558–570.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3434780</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22556279</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Breiman L. Random forests. Machine Learn. 2001;45:5–32.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>R: A Language and Environment for Statistical Computing in R Foundation for Statistical Computing. R Core Team; Vienna: 2018. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Al-Khodor S., Price C.T., Habyarimana F., Kalia A., Abu Kwaik Y. A Dot/Icm-translocated ankyrin protein of Legionella pneumophila is required for intracellular proliferation within human macrophages and protozoa. Mol. Microbiol. 2008;70:908–923.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3064707</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18811729</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Laemmli U.K. Cleavage of structural proteins during the assembly of the head of bacteriophage T4. Nature. 1970;227:680–685.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5432063</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Towbin H., Staehelin T., Gordon J. Electrophoretic transfer of proteins from polyacrylamide gels to nitrocellulose sheets: Procedure and some applications. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 1979;76:4350–4354.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC411572</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">388439</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chien M., Morozova I., Shi S., Sheng H., Chen J., Gomez S.M., Asamani G., Hill K., Nuara J., Feder M., Rineer J., Greenberg J.J., Steshenko V., Park S.H., Zhao B., et al.  The genomic sequence of the accidental pathogen Legionella pneumophila. Science. 2004;305:1966–1968.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15448271</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gillmaier N., Schunder E., Kutzner E., Tlapak H., Rydzewski K., Herrmann V., Stammler M., Lasch P., Eisenreich W., Heuner K. Growth-related metabolism of the carbon storage poly-3-hydroxybutyrate in Legionella pneumophila. J. Biol. Chem. 2016;291:6471–6482.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4813547</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26792862</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eisenreich W., Heuner K. The life stage-specific pathometabolism of Legionella pneumophila. FEBS Lett. 2016;590:3868–3886.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27455397</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Faulkner G., Garduno R.A. Ultrastructural analysis of differentiation in Legionella pneumophila. J. Bacteriol. 2002;184:7025–7041.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC135455</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12446652</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hughes E.D., Byrne B.G., Swanson M.S. A two-component system that modulates cyclic di-GMP metabolism promotes Legionella pneumophila differentiation and viability in low-nutrient conditions. J. Bacteriol. 2019;201</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zusman T., Speiser Y., Segal G. Two Fis regulators directly repress the expression of numerous effector-encoding genes in Legionella pneumophila. J. Bacteriol. 2014;196:4172–4183.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4248873</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25225276</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Edwards R.L., Bryan A., Jules M., Harada K., Buchrieser C., Swanson M.S. Nicotinic acid modulates Legionella pneumophila gene expression and induces virulence traits. Infect. Immun. 2013;81:945–955.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3584888</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23319553</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Will W.R., Fang F.C. The evolution of MarR family transcription factors as counter-silencers in regulatory networks. Curr. Opin. Microbiol. 2020;55:1–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7311280</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32044654</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta A., Pande A., Sabrin A., Thapa S.S., Gioe B.W., Grove A. MarR family transcription factors from burkholderia species: Hidden clues to control of virulence-associated genes. Microbiol. Mol. Biol. Rev. 2019;83</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grove A. Regulation of metabolic pathways by MarR family transcription factors. Comput. Struct. Biotechnol. J. 2017;15:366–371.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5487221</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28694934</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aurass P., Prager R., Flieger A. EHEC/EAEC O104:H4 strain linked with the 2011 German outbreak of haemolytic uremic syndrome enters into the viable but non-culturable state in response to various stresses and resuscitates upon stress relief. Environ. Microbiol. 2011;13:3139–3148.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21951606</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yu M.J., Ren J., Zeng Y.L., Zhou S.N., Lu Y.J. The Legionella pneumophila Dps homolog is regulated by iron and involved in multiple stress tolerance. J. Basic Microbiol. 2009;49:S79–S86.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19455515</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Quan F.S., Kong H.H., Lee H.A., Chu K.B., Moon E.K. Identification of differentially expressed Legionella genes during its intracellular growth in Acanthamoeba. Heliyon. 2020;6</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ohnishi Y., Yamazaki H., Kato J.Y., Tomono A., Horinouchi S. AdpA, a central transcriptional regulator in the A-factor regulatory cascade that leads to morphological development and secondary metabolism in Streptomyces griseus. Biosci. Biotechnol. Biochem. 2005;69:431–439.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15784968</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ueguchi C., Kakeda M., Yamada H., Mizuno T. An analogue of the DnaJ molecular chaperone in Escherichia coli. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 1994;91:1054–1058.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC521452</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8302830</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chae C., Sharma S., Hoskins J.R., Wickner S. CbpA, a DnaJ homolog, is a DnaK co-chaperone, and its activity is modulated by CbpM. J. Biol. Chem. 2004;279:33147–33153.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15184371</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sarraf N.S., Shi R., McDonald L., Baardsnes J., Zhang L., Cygler M., Ekiel I. Structure of CbpA J-domain bound to the regulatory protein Cbpm explains its specificity and suggests evolutionary link between Cbpm and transcriptional regulators. PLoS One. 2014;9</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fatima K., Naqvi F., Younas H. A review: Molecular chaperone-mediated folding, unfolding and disaggregation of expressed recombinant proteins. Cell Biochem. Biophys. 2021;79:153–174.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33634426</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eraso J.M., Markillie L.M., Mitchell H.D., Taylor R.C., Orr G., Margolin W. The highly conserved MraZ protein is a transcriptional regulator in Escherichia coli. J. Bacteriol. 2014;196:2053–2066.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4010979</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24659771</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hochstrasser R., Hilbi H. Intra-species and inter-kingdom signaling of Legionella pneumophila. Front. Microbiol. 2017;8:79.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5289986</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28217110</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hochstrasser R., Hutter C.A.J., Arnold F.M., Barlocher K., Seeger M.A., Hilbi H. The structure of the Legionella response regulator LqsR reveals amino acids critical for phosphorylation and dimerization. Mol. Microbiol. 2020;113:1070–1084.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31997467</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Personnic N., Striednig B., Lezan E., Manske C., Welin A., Schmidt A., Hilbi H. Quorum sensing modulates the formation of virulent Legionella persisters within infected cells. Nat. Commun. 2019;10:5216.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6861284</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31740681</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schell M.A. Molecular biology of the LysR family of transcriptional regulators. Annu. Rev. Microbiol. 1993;47:597–626.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8257110</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maddocks S.E., Oyston P.C.F. Structure and function of the LysR-type transcriptional regulator (LTTR) family proteins. Microbiology (Reading) 2008;154:3609–3623.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19047729</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ueta M., Yoshida H., Wada C., Baba T., Mori H., Wada A. Ribosome binding proteins YhbH and YfiA have opposite functions during 100S formation in the stationary phase of Escherichia coli. Genes Cells. 2005;10:1103–1112.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16324148</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maki Y., Yoshida H., Wada A. Two proteins, YfiA and YhbH, associated with resting ribosomes in stationary phase Escherichia coli. Genes Cells. 2000;5:965–974.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11168583</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Padilla-Vaca F., Mondragon-Jaimes V., Franco B. General aspects of two-component regulatory circuits in bacteria: Domains, signals and roles. Curr. Protein Pept. Sci. 2017;18:990–1004.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27514854</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gal-Mor O., Segal G. Identification of CpxR as a positive regulator of icm and dot virulence genes of Legionella pneumophila. J. Bacteriol. 2003;185:4908–4919.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC166489</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12897011</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gal-Mor O., Segal G. The Legionella pneumophila GacA homolog (LetA) is involved in the regulation of icm virulence genes and is required for intracellular multiplication in Acanthamoeba castellanii. Microb. Pathog. 2003;34:187–194.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12668142</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zusman T., Aloni G., Halperin E., Kotzer H., Degtyar E., Feldman M., Segal G. The response regulator PmrA is a major regulator of the icm/dot type IV secretion system in Legionella pneumophila and Coxiella burnetii. Mol. Microbiol. 2007;63:1508–1523.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17302824</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Altman E., Segal G. The response regulator CpxR directly regulates expression of several Legionella pneumophila icm/dot components as well as new translocated substrates. J. Bacteriol. 2008;190:1985–1996.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2258895</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18192394</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chatterjee D., Boyd C.D., O'Toole G.A., Sondermann H. Structural characterization of a conserved, calcium-dependent periplasmic protease from Legionella pneumophila. J. Bacteriol. 2012;194:4415–4425.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3416269</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22707706</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chatterjee D., Cooley R.B., Boyd C.D., Mehl R.A., O'Toole G.A., Sondermann H. Mechanistic insight into the conserved allosteric regulation of periplasmic proteolysis by the signaling molecule cyclic-di-GMP. Elife. 2014;3</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jacobi S., Schade R., Heuner K. Characterization of the alternative sigma factor sigma54 and the transcriptional regulator FleQ of Legionella pneumophila, which are both involved in the regulation cascade of flagellar gene expression. J. Bacteriol. 2004;186:2540–2547.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC387802</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15090493</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lenn T., Leake M.C., Mullineaux C.W. Clustering and dynamics of cytochrome bd-I complexes in the Escherichia coli plasma membrane in vivo. Mol. Microbiol. 2008;70:1397–1407.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19019148</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mason M.G., Shepherd M., Nicholls P., Dobbin P.S., Dodsworth K.S., Poole R.K., Cooper C.E. Cytochrome bd confers nitric oxide resistance to Escherichia coli. Nat. Chem. Biol. 2009;5:94–96.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19109594</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Appelt S., Heuner K. The flagellar regulon of legionella-A review. Front. Cell Infect. Microbiol. 2017;7:454.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5655016</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29104863</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Albert-Weissenberger C., Sahr T., Sismeiro O., Hacker J., Heuner K., Buchrieser C. Control of flagellar gene regulation in Legionella pneumophila and its relation to growth phase. J. Bacteriol. 2010;192:446–455.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2805308</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19915024</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heuner K., Dietrich C., Skriwan C., Steinert M., Hacker J. Influence of the alternative sigma(28) factor on virulence and flagellum expression of Legionella pneumophila. Infect. Immun. 2002;70:1604–1608.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC127743</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11854250</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bachman M.A., Swanson M.S. The LetE protein enhances expression of multiple LetA/LetS-dependent transmission traits by Legionella pneumophila. Infect. Immun. 2004;72:3284–3293.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC415668</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15155631</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Edwards R.L., Dalebroux Z.D., Swanson M.S. Legionella pneumophila couples fatty acid flux to microbial differentiation and virulence. Mol. Microbiol. 2009;71:1190–1204.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19170883</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Battesti A., Bouveret E. Acyl carrier protein/SpoT interaction, the switch linking SpoT-dependent stress response to fatty acid metabolism. Mol. Microbiol. 2006;62:1048–1063.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17078815</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xiao H., Kalman M., Ikehara K., Zemel S., Glaser G., Cashel M. Residual guanosine 3',5'-bispyrophosphate synthetic activity of relA null mutants can be eliminated by spoT null mutations. J. Biol. Chem. 1991;266:5980–5990.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2005134</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Potrykus K., Cashel M. ppGpp: still magical? Annu. Rev. Microbiol. 2008;62:35–51.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18454629</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Joshi A.D., Sturgill-Koszycki S., Swanson M.S. Evidence that Dot-dependent and -independent factors isolate the Legionella pneumophila phagosome from the endocytic network in mouse macrophages. Cell Microbiol. 2001;3:99–114.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11207624</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Losick V.P., Haenssler E., Moy M.Y., Isberg R.R. LnaB: A Legionella pneumophila activator of NF-kappaB. Cell Microbiol. 2010;12:1083–1097.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2947841</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20148897</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Belyi Y., Jank T., Aktories K. Cytotoxic glucosyltransferases of Legionella pneumophila. Curr. Top. Microbiol. Immunol. 2013;376:211–226.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23900830</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Belyi Y. Targeting eukaryotic mRNA translation by Legionella pneumophila. Front. Mol. Biosci. 2020;7:80.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7201127</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32411722</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang Y., Shi M., Feng H., Zhu Y., Liu S., Gao A., Gao P. Structural insights into non-canonical ubiquitination catalyzed by SidE. Cell. 2018;173:1231–1243.e16.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29731171</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Puvar K., Luo Z.Q., Das C. Uncovering the structural basis of a new twist in protein ubiquitination. Trends Biochem. Sci. 2019;44:467–477.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6465118</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30583962</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Toulabi L., Wu X., Cheng Y., Mao Y. Identification and structural characterization of a Legionella phosphoinositide phosphatase. J. Biol. Chem. 2013;288:24518–24527.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3750150</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23843460</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li G., Liu H., Luo Z.Q., Qiu J. Modulation of phagosome phosphoinositide dynamics by a Legionella phosphoinositide 3-kinase. EMBO Rep. 2021;22</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen J., de Felipe K.S., Clarke M., Lu H., Anderson O.R., Segal G., Shuman H.A. Legionella effectors that promote nonlytic release from protozoa. Science. 2004;303:1358–1361.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14988561</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen J., Reyes M., Clarke M., Shuman H.A. Host cell-dependent secretion and translocation of the LepA and LepB effectors of Legionella pneumophila. Cell Microbiol. 2007;9:1660–1671.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17371403</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Finsel I., Ragaz C., Hoffmann C., Harrison C.F., Weber S., van Rahden V.A., Johannes L., Hilbi H. The Legionella effector RidL inhibits retrograde trafficking to promote intracellular replication. Cell Host Microbe. 2013;14:38–50.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23870312</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Felipe K.S., Glover R.T., Charpentier X., Anderson O.R., Reyes M., Pericone C.D., Shuman H.A. Legionella eukaryotic-like type IV substrates interfere with organelle trafficking. PLoS Pathog. 2008;4</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Degtyar E., Zusman T., Ehrlich M., Segal G. A Legionella effector acquired from protozoa is involved in sphingolipids metabolism and is targeted to the host cell mitochondria. Cell Microbiol. 2009;11:1219–1235.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19438520</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Newton H.J., Sansom F.M., Bennett-Wood V., Hartland E.L. Identification of Legionella pneumophila-specific genes by genomic subtractive hybridization with Legionella micdadei and identification of lpnE, a gene required for efficient host cell entry. Infect. Immun. 2006;74:1683–1691.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1418643</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16495539</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Newton H.J., Sansom F.M., Dao J., McAlister A.D., Sloan J., Cianciotto N.P., Hartland E.L. Sel1 repeat protein LpnE is a Legionella pneumophila virulence determinant that influences vacuolar trafficking. Infect. Immun. 2007;75:5575–5585.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2168337</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17893138</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weber S.S., Ragaz C., Hilbi H. The inositol polyphosphate 5-phosphatase OCRL1 restricts intracellular growth of Legionella, localizes to the replicative vacuole and binds to the bacterial effector LpnE. Cell Microbiol. 2009;11:442–460.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19021631</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nagai H., Cambronne E.D., Kagan J.C., Amor J.C., Kahn R.A., Roy C.R. A C-terminal translocation signal required for Dot/Icm-dependent delivery of the Legionella RalF protein to host cells. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2005;102:826–831.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC545534</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15613486</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bennett T.L., Kraft S.M., Reaves B.J., Mima J., O'Brien K.M., Starai V.J. LegC3, an effector protein from Legionella pneumophila, inhibits homotypic yeast vacuole fusion in vivo and in vitro. PLoS One. 2013;8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yao D., Cherney M., Cygler M. Structure of the N-terminal domain of the effector protein LegC3 from Legionella pneumophila. Acta Crystallogr. D Biol. Crystallogr. 2014;70:436–441.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24531477</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Choy A., Dancourt J., Mugo B., O'Connor T.J., Isberg R.R., Melia T.J., Roy C.R. The Legionella effector RavZ inhibits host autophagy through irreversible Atg8 deconjugation. Science. 2012;338:1072–1076.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3682818</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23112293</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wong K., Kozlov G., Zhang Y., Gehring K. Structure of the Legionella effector, lpg1496, suggests a role in nucleotide metabolism. J. Biol. Chem. 2015;290:24727–24737.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4598985</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26294765</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Belyi I., Popoff M.R., Cianciotto N.P. Purification and characterization of a UDP-glucosyltransferase produced by Legionella pneumophila. Infect. Immun. 2003;71:181–186.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC143419</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12496164</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Belyi Y., Tabakova I., Stahl M., Aktories K. Lgt: A family of cytotoxic glucosyltransferases produced by Legionella pneumophila. J. Bacteriol. 2008;190:3026–3035.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2293231</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18281405</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hurtado-Guerrero R., Zusman T., Pathak S., Ibrahim A.F., Shepherd S., Prescott A., Segal G., van Aalten D.M. Molecular mechanism of elongation factor 1A inhibition by a Legionella pneumophila glycosyltransferase. Biochem. J. 2010;426:281–292.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3518269</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20030628</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lu W., Du J., Stahl M., Tzivelekidis T., Belyi Y., Gerhardt S., Aktories K., Einsle O. Structural basis of the action of glucosyltransferase Lgt1 from Legionella pneumophila. J. Mol. Biol. 2010;396:321–331.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19941871</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Urbanus M.L., Quaile A.T., Stogios P.J., Morar M., Rao C., Di Leo R., Evdokimova E., Lam M., Oatway C., Cuff M.E., Osipiuk J., Michalska K., Nocek B.P., Taipale M., Savchenko A., et al.  Diverse mechanisms of metaeffector activity in an intracellular bacterial pathogen, Legionella pneumophila. Mol. Syst. Biol. 2016;12:893.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5199130</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27986836</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu Y., Zhu W., Tan Y., Nakayasu E.S., Staiger C.J., Luo Z.Q. A Legionella effector disrupts host cytoskeletal structure by cleaving actin. PLoS Pathog. 2017;13</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu L., Shen X., Bryan A., Banga S., Swanson M.S., Luo Z.Q. Inhibition of host vacuolar H+-ATPase activity by a Legionella pneumophila effector. PLoS Pathog. 2010;6</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhao J., Beyrakhova K., Liu Y., Alvarez C.P., Bueler S.A., Xu L., Xu C., Boniecki M.T., Kanelis V., Luo Z.Q., Cygler M., Rubinstein J.L. Molecular basis for the binding and modulation of V-ATPase by a bacterial effector protein. PLoS Pathog. 2017;13</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Derre I., Isberg R.R. LidA, a translocated substrate of the Legionella pneumophila type IV secretion system, interferes with the early secretory pathway. Infect. Immun. 2005;73:4370–4380.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1168608</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15972532</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cheng W., Yin K., Lu D., Li B., Zhu D., Chen Y., Zhang H., Xu S., Chai J., Gu L. Structural insights into a unique Legionella pneumophila effector LidA recognizing both GDP and GTP bound Rab1 in their active state. PLoS Pathog. 2012;8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bugalhao J.N., Mota L.J., Franco I.S. Identification of regions within the Legionella pneumophila VipA effector protein involved in actin binding and polymerization and in interference with eukaryotic organelle trafficking. Microbiologyopen. 2016;5:118–133.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4767423</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26626407</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ku B., Lee K.H., Park W.S., Yang C.S., Ge J., Lee S.G., Cha S.S., Shao F., Heo W.D., Jung J.U., Oh B.H. VipD of Legionella pneumophila targets activated Rab5 and Rab22 to interfere with endosomal trafficking in macrophages. PLoS Pathog. 2012;8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gaspar A.H., Machner M.P. VipD is a Rab5-activated phospholipase A1 that protects Legionella pneumophila from endosomal fusion. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2014;111:4560–4565.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3970493</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24616501</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lucas M., Gaspar A.H., Pallara C., Rojas A.L., Fernandez-Recio J., Machner M.P., Hierro A. Structural basis for the recruitment and activation of the Legionella phospholipase VipD by the host GTPase Rab5. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2014;111:E3514–E3523.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4151760</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25114243</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ragaz C., Pietsch H., Urwyler S., Tiaden A., Weber S.S., Hilbi H. The Legionella pneumophila phosphatidylinositol-4 phosphate-binding type IV substrate SidC recruits endoplasmic reticulum vesicles to a replication-permissive vacuole. Cell Microbiol. 2008;10:2416–2433.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18673369</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Horenkamp F.A., Mukherjee S., Alix E., Schauder C.M., Hubber A.M., Roy C.R., Reinisch K.M. Legionella pneumophila subversion of host vesicular transport by SidC effector proteins. Traffic. 2014;15:488–499.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4041529</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24483784</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hsu F., Luo X., Qiu J., Teng Y.B., Jin J., Smolka M.B., Luo Z.Q., Mao Y. The Legionella effector SidC defines a unique family of ubiquitin ligases important for bacterial phagosomal remodeling. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2014;111:10538–10543.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4115505</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25006264</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tan Y., Luo Z.Q. Legionella pneumophila SidD is a deAMPylase that modifies Rab1. Nature. 2011;475:506–509.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3146296</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21734656</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen Y., Tascon I., Neunuebel M.R., Pallara C., Brady J., Kinch L.N., Fernandez-Recio J., Rojas A.L., Machner M.P., Hierro A. Structural basis for Rab1 de-AMPylation by the Legionella pneumophila effector SidD. PLoS Pathog. 2013;9</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Machner M.P., Isberg R.R. Targeting of host Rab GTPase function by the intravacuolar pathogen Legionella pneumophila. Dev. Cell. 2006;11:47–56.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16824952</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Machner M.P., Isberg R.R. A bifunctional bacterial protein links GDI displacement to Rab1 activation. Science. 2007;318:974–977.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17947549</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Murata T., Delprato A., Ingmundson A., Toomre D.K., Lambright D.G., Roy C.R. The Legionella pneumophila effector protein DrrA is a Rab1 guanine nucleotide-exchange factor. Nat. Cell Biol. 2006;8:971–977.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16906144</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brombacher E., Urwyler S., Ragaz C., Weber S.S., Kami K., Overduin M., Hilbi H. Rab1 guanine nucleotide exchange factor SidM is a major phosphatidylinositol 4-phosphate-binding effector protein of Legionella pneumophila. J. Biol. Chem. 2009;284:4846–4856.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2643517</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19095644</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ninio S., Zuckman-Cholon D.M., Cambronne E.D., Roy C.R. The Legionella IcmS-IcmW protein complex is important for Dot/Icm-mediated protein translocation. Mol. Microbiol. 2005;55:912–926.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15661013</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu Y., Luo Z.Q. The Legionella pneumophila effector SidJ is required for efficient recruitment of endoplasmic reticulum proteins to the bacterial phagosome. Infect. Immun. 2007;75:592–603.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1828518</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17101649</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lin Y.H., Doms A.G., Cheng E., Kim B., Evans T.R., Machner M.P. Host cell-catalyzed S-palmitoylation mediates golgi targeting of the Legionella ubiquitin ligase GobX. J. Biol. Chem. 2015;290:25766–25781.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4646218</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26316537</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ledvina H.E., Kelly K.A., Eshraghi A., Plemel R.L., Peterson S.B., Lee B., Steele S., Adler M., Kawula T.H., Merz A.J., Skerrett S.J., Celli J., Mougous J.D. A phosphatidylinositol 3-kinase effector alters phagosomal maturation to promote intracellular growth of francisella. Cell Host Microbe. 2018;24:285–295.e8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6394229</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30057173</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kubori T., Nagai H. The type IVB secretion system: An enigmatic chimera. Curr. Opin. Microbiol. 2016;29:22–29.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26529574</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nagai H., Kubori T. Type IVB secretion systems of Legionella and other gram-negative bacteria. Front. Microbiol. 2011;2:136.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3127085</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21743810</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berger K.H., Merriam J.J., Isberg R.R. Altered intracellular targeting properties associated with mutations in the Legionella pneumophila dotA gene. Mol. Microbiol. 1994;14:809–822.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7891566</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Flynn J.M., Neher S.B., Kim Y.I., Sauer R.T., Baker T.A. Proteomic discovery of cellular substrates of the ClpXP protease reveals five classes of ClpX-recognition signals. Mol. Cell. 2003;11:671–683.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12667450</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Neher S.B., Villen J., Oakes E.C., Bakalarski C.E., Sauer R.T., Gygi S.P., Baker T.A. Proteomic profiling of ClpXP substrates after DNA damage reveals extensive instability within SOS regulon. Mol. Cell. 2006;22:193–204.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16630889</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Frees D., Qazi S.N., Hill P.J., Ingmer H. Alternative roles of ClpX and ClpP in Staphylococcus aureus stress tolerance and virulence. Mol. Microbiol. 2003;48:1565–1578.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12791139</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Frees D., Chastanet A., Qazi S., Sorensen K., Hill P., Msadek T., Ingmer H. Clp ATPases are required for stress tolerance, intracellular replication and biofilm formation in Staphylococcus aureus. Mol. Microbiol. 2004;54:1445–1462.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15554981</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Frees D., Andersen J.H., Hemmingsen L., Koskenniemi K., Baek K.T., Muhammed M.K., Gudeta D.D., Nyman T.A., Sukura A., Varmanen P., Savijoki K. New insights into Staphylococcus aureus stress tolerance and virulence regulation from an analysis of the role of the ClpP protease in the strains Newman, COL, and SA564. J. Proteome Res. 2012;11:95–108.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22112206</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chattoraj P., Banerjee A., Biswas S., Biswas I. ClpP of Streptococcus mutans differentially regulates expression of genomic islands, mutacin production, and antibiotic tolerance. J. Bacteriol. 2010;192:1312–1323.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2820848</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20038588</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zheng J., Wu Y., Lin Z., Wang G., Jiang S., Sun X., Tu H., Yu Z., Qu D. ClpP participates in stress tolerance, biofilm formation, antimicrobial tolerance, and virulence of Enterococcus faecalis. BMC Microbiol. 2020;20:30.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7006429</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32033530</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Camberg J.L., Hoskins J.R., Wickner S. ClpXP protease degrades the cytoskeletal protein, FtsZ, and modulates FtsZ polymer dynamics. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2009;106:10614–10619.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2705540</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19541655</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Camberg J.L., Hoskins J.R., Wickner S. The interplay of ClpXP with the cell division machinery in Escherichia coli. J. Bacteriol. 2011;193:1911–1918.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3133021</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21317324</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Williams B., Bhat N., Chien P., Shapiro L. ClpXP and ClpAP proteolytic activity on divisome substrates is differentially regulated following the Caulobacter asymmetric cell division. Mol. Microbiol. 2014;93:853–866.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4285227</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24989075</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hengge R. Proteolysis of sigmaS (RpoS) and the general stress response in Escherichia coli. Res. Microbiol. 2009;160:667–676.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19765651</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Joshi K.K., Chien P. Regulated proteolysis in bacteria: Caulobacter. Annu. Rev. Genet. 2016;50:423–445.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5510660</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27893963</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tan I.S., Weiss C.A., Popham D.L., Ramamurthi K.S. A quality-control mechanism removes unfit cells from a population of sporulating bacteria. Dev. Cell. 2015;34:682–693.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4588057</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26387458</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Savijoki K., Ingmer H., Varmanen P. Proteolytic systems of lactic acid bacteria. Appl. Microbiol. Biotechnol. 2006;71:394–406.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16628446</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Frees D., Savijoki K., Varmanen P., Ingmer H. Clp ATPases and ClpP proteolytic complexes regulate vital biological processes in low GC, Gram-positive bacteria. Mol. Microbiol. 2007;63:1285–1295.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17302811</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Frees D., Brondsted L., Ingmer H. Bacterial proteases and virulence. Subcell Biochem. 2013;66:161–192.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23479441</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heuner K., Hacker J., Brand B.C. The alternative sigma factor sigma28 of Legionella pneumophila restores flagellation and motility to an Escherichia coli fliA mutant. J. Bacteriol. 1997;179:17–23.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC178656</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8981975</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hoffmann C., Finsel I., Otto A., Pfaffinger G., Rothmeier E., Hecker M., Becher D., Hilbi H. Functional analysis of novel Rab GTPases identified in the proteome of purified Legionella-containing vacuoles from macrophages. Cell Microbiol. 2014;16:1034–1052.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24373249</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>VanRheenen S.M., Dumenil G., Isberg R.R. IcmF and DotU are required for optimal effector translocation and trafficking of the Legionella pneumophila vacuole. Infect. Immun. 2004;72:5972–5982.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC517542</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15385501</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sexton J.A., Miller J.L., Yoneda A., Kehl-Fie T.E., Vogel J.P. Legionella pneumophila DotU and IcmF are required for stability of the Dot/Icm complex. Infect. Immun. 2004;72:5983–5992.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC517559</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15385502</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Das S., Chakrabortty A., Banerjee R., Roychoudhury S., Chaudhuri K. Comparison of global transcription responses allows identification of Vibrio cholerae genes differentially expressed following infection. FEMS Microbiol. Lett. 2000;190:87–91.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10981695</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ma J., Chen T., Wu S., Yang C., Bai M., Shu K., Li K., Zhang G., Jin Z., He F., Hermjakob H., Zhu Y. iProX: an integrated proteome resource. Nucleic Acids Res. 2019;47:D1211–D1217.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6323926</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30252093</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
