<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35427281</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>24</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>24</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-5166</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>42</Volume>
            <Issue>2</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
              <Day>01</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of neuro-ophthalmology : the official journal of the North American Neuro-Ophthalmology Society</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Neuroophthalmol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Internuclear Ophthalmoplegia Characterizes Multiple Sclerosis Rather Than Neuromyelitis Optica Spectrum Disease.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>239</StartPage>
          <EndPage>245</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>239-245</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/WNO.0000000000001534</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Neuromyelitis optica spectrum disease (NMOSD) and multiple sclerosis (MS) share clinical presentations including optic neuritis and brainstem syndromes. Internuclear ophthalmoplegia (INO) is characterized by slowed ipsilateral adduction saccades and results from a lesion in the medial longitudinal fasciculus (MLF). Although INO is a common clinical finding in MS, its prevalence in NMOSD is unknown. The objective of this work is to determine the comparative frequencies of INO in patients with NMOSD and MS and compare clinical features of both disease processes.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This is a retrospective study of patients 18 years and older who have an established diagnosis of NMOSD or MS and were evaluated by both neuro-ophthalmology and neuro-immunology specialists between 2014 and 2020. Electronic medical records were screened for documentation of an acute INO at any time during follow-up. Incidence rates were calculated from number of cases of new-onset INO and patient years observed. Logistic regression was used to evaluate the likelihood of developing an INO at any time point for NMOSD vs MS patients. Multivariable analysis was performed by adjusting for age, race, gender, and length of follow-up.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Two hundred eighty patients (80 NMOSD, 200 MS) were included. Age range was 18-79 years with a mean age of 35.14 (SD ± 12.41 years). Average length of follow-up in MS and NMOSD patients was 4.18 years vs 3.79 years, respectively (P &gt; 0.05), and disease duration before the start of the study in MS and NMOSD was 8.76 years vs 4.65 years, respectively (P &lt; 0.01). Mean disease duration and follow-up time of both groups was 7.58 years and 4.07 ± 2.51 years, respectively. NMOSD patients were predominantly seropositive for AQP4 antibody (61.25%, n = 49). Individuals who had MOG antibody but also met NMOSD criteria were also included (18.75%, n = 15). The frequency of INO at any time point was 1.25% (n = 1) in NMOSD compared with 16% (n = 32) in MS. The incidence rate of new-onset INO in NMOSD (excluding MOGAD) was 3.8/1,000 person years and 23.9/1,000 person years in MS. Adjusted analysis showed that NMOSD patients were 13.89 times (odds ratio [OR] 0.07, 95% confidence interval [CI] 0.01-0.598, P = 0.015) less likely to develop an INO compared with those with MS when including MOGAD patients, 12.5 times less likely (OR 0.08, 95% CI: 0.10-0.67, P = 0.02) when excluding MOGAD patients and 9.62 times less likely (OR 0.10, 95% CI: 0.01-0.87, P = 0.036) for AQP4+ patients.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Our study shows that the incidence of new INO (3.8 vs 23.9 per 1,000 person years), and the odds of having INO at any time point are significantly lower in NMOSD than MS. This suggests that INO and consequently MLF lesions are less common in NMOSD. The presence of an INO may help in the differentiation of NMOSD from MS and may aid in earlier implementation of disease appropriate therapy.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022 by North American Neuro-Ophthalmology Society.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hamza</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mahmoud M</ForeName>
            <Initials>MM</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Alas</LastName>
            <ForeName>Basheer F</ForeName>
            <Initials>BF</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Huang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Connie</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Quon</LastName>
            <ForeName>Justin C</ForeName>
            <Initials>JC</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Amezcua</LastName>
            <ForeName>Lilyana</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Robers</LastName>
            <ForeName>Michael V</ForeName>
            <Initials>MV</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gokoffski</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kimberly K</ForeName>
            <Initials>KK</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3589-0296</Identifier>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Neuroophthalmol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9431308</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1070-8022</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D051401">Aquaporin 4</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D001323">Autoantibodies</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D063308">Myelin-Oligodendrocyte Glycoprotein</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D051401" MajorTopicYN="N">Aquaporin 4</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001323" MajorTopicYN="N">Autoantibodies</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009103" MajorTopicYN="Y">Multiple Sclerosis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D063308" MajorTopicYN="N">Myelin-Oligodendrocyte Glycoprotein</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009471" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neuromyelitis Optica</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015835" MajorTopicYN="Y">Ocular Motility Disorders</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors report no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
          <Hour>17</Hour>
          <Minute>9</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35427281</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/WNO.0000000000001534</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">00041327-990000000-00033</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Flanagan EP. Neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder and other non-multiple sclerosis central nervous system inflammatory diseases. Continuum (Minneap MN). 2019;25:815–844.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fujihara K. Neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorders: still evolving and broadening. Curr Opin Neurol. 2019;32:385–394.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yokote H, Mizusawa H. Multiple sclerosis and neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorders: some similarities in two distinct diseases. Neural Regen Res. 2016;11:410–411.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lennon VA, Wingerchuk DM, Kryzer TJ, Pittock SJ, Lucchinetti CF, Fujihara K, Nakashima I, Weinshenker BG. A serum autoantibody marker of neuromyelitis optica: distinction from multiple sclerosis. Lancet. 2004;364:2106–2112.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thompson AJ, Banwell BL, Barkhof F, Carroll WM, Coetzee T, Comi G, Correale J, Fazekas F, Filippi M, Freedman MS, Fujihara K, Galetta SL, Hartung HP, Kappos L, Lublin FD, Marrie RA, Miller AE, Miller DH, Montalban X, Mowry EM, Sorensen PS, Tintoré M, Traboulsee AL, Trojano M, Uitdehaag BMJ, Vukusic S, Waubant E, Weinshenker BG, Reingold SC, Cohen JA. Diagnosis of multiple sclerosis: 2017 revisions of the McDonald criteria. Lancet Neurol. 2018;17:162–173.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nij Bijvank JA, van Rijn LJ, Balk LJ, Tan HS, Uitdehaag BMJ, Petzold A. Diagnosing and quantifying a common deficit in multiple sclerosis: internuclear ophthalmoplegia. Neurology. 2019;92:e2299–e2308.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dubey D, Pittock SJ, Krecke KN, Morris PP, Sechi E, Zalewski NL, Weinshenker BG, Shosha E, Lucchinetti CF, Fryer JP, Lopez-Chiriboga AS, Chen JC, Jitprapaikulsan J, McKeon A, Gadoth A, Keegan BM, Tillema JM, Naddaf E, Patterson MC, Messacar K, Tyler KL, Flanagan EP. Clinical, radiologic, and prognostic features of myelitis associated with myelin oligodendrocyte glycoprotein autoantibody. JAMA Neurol. 2019;76:301–309.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li LM, Guo HY, Zhao N, Zhang LJ, Zhang N, Liu J, Yang L. Comparison of olfactory function between neuromyelitis optica and multiple sclerosis. Int J Neurosci. 2018;128:772–777.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sato DK, Callegaro D, Lana-Peixoto MA, Waters PJ, de Haidar Jorge FM, Takahashi T, Nakashima I, Apostolos-Pereira SL, Talim N, Simm RF, Lino AM, Misu T, Leite MI, Aoki M, Fujihara K. Distinction between MOG antibody-positive and AQP4 antibody-positive NMO spectrum disorders. Neurology. 2014;82:474–481.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hamid SHM, Whittam D, Mutch K, Linaker S, Solomon T, Das K, Bhojak M, Jacob A. What proportion of AQP4-IgG-negative NMO spectrum disorder patients are MOG-IgG positive? A cross sectional study of 132 patients. J Neurol. 2017;264:2088–2094.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kunchok A, Chen JJ, Saadeh RS, Wingerchuk DM, Weinshenker BG, Flanagan EP, Pittock SJ. Application of 2015 seronegative neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder diagnostic criteria for patients with myelin oligodendrocyte glycoprotein IgG-associated disorders. JAMA Neurol. 2020;77:1572–1575.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bouzar M, Daoudi S, Hattab S, Bouzar AA, Deiva K, Wildemann B, Reindl M, Jarius S. Neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorders with antibodies to myelin oligodendrocyte glycoprotein or aquaporin-4: clinical and paraclinical characteristics in Algerian patients. J Neurol Sci. 2017;381:240–244.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reindl M, Rostasy K. MOG antibody-associated diseases. Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflamm. 2015;2:e60.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sato DK, Callegaro D, Lana-Peixoto MA, Nakashima I, Fujihara K. Seronegative Neuromyelitis Optica Spectrum: the challenges on disease definition and pathogenesis. Arq Neuropsiquiatr. 2014;72:445–450.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim HJ, Paul F, Lana-Peixoto MA, Tenembaum S, Asgari N, Palace J, Klawiter EC, Sato DK, de Seze J, Wuerfel J, Banwell BL, Villoslada P, Saiz A, Fujihara K, Kim SH. MRI characteristics of neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder: an international update. Neurology. 2015;84:1165–1173.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vabanesi M, Pisa M, Guerrieri S, Moiola L, Radaelli M, Medaglini S, Martinelli V, Comi G, Leocani L. In vivo structural and functional assessment of optic nerve damage in neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorders and multiple sclerosis. Sci Rep. 2019;9:10371.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pittock SJ, Lucchinetti CF. Neuromyelitis optica and the evolving spectrum of autoimmune aquaporin-4 channelopathies: a decade later. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2016;1366:20–39.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bennett JL, de Seze J, Lana-Peixoto M, Palace J, Waldman A, Schippling S, Tenembaum S, Banwell B, Greenberg B, Levy M, Fujihara K, Chan KH, Kim HJ, Asgari N, Sato DK, Saiz A, Wuerfel J, Zimmermann H, Green A, Villoslada P, Paul F. Neuromyelitis optica and multiple sclerosis: seeing differences through optical coherence tomography. Mult Scler. 2015;21:678–688.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jozefowicz-Korczynska M, Lukomski M, Pajor A. Identification of internuclear ophthalmoplegia signs in multiple sclerosis patients. Saccade test analysis. J Neurol. 2008;255:1006–1011.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Müri RM, Meienberg O. The clinical spectrum of internuclear ophthalmoplegia in multiple sclerosis. Arch Neurol. 1985;42:851–855.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Serra A, Chisari CG, Matta M. Eye movement abnormalities in multiple sclerosis: pathogenesis, modeling, and treatment. Front Neurol. 2018;9:31.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Downey DL, Stahl JS, Bhidayasiri R, Derwenskus J, Adams NL, Ruff RL, Leigh RJ. Saccadic and vestibular abnormalities in multiple sclerosis: sensitive clinical signs of brainstem and cerebellar involvement. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2002;956:438–440.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garcia-Martin E, Pinilla I, Pueyo V, Gil L, Martinez-Morales J, Fernandez J. Bilateral internuclear ophthalmoplegia in a patient with devic's neuromyelitis optica. Case Rep Neurol. 2010;2:139–144.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shinoda K, Matsushita T, Furuta K, Isobe N, Yonekawa T, Ohyagi Y, Kira J. Wall-eyed bilateral internuclear ophthalmoplegia (WEBINO) syndrome in a patient with neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder and anti-aquaporin-4 antibody. Mult Scler. 2011;17:885–887.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pittock SJ, Weinshenker BG, Lucchinetti CF, Wingerchuk DM, Corboy JR, Lennon VA. Neuromyelitis optica brain lesions localized at sites of high aquaporin 4 expression. Arch Neurol. 2006;63:964–968.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roemer SF, Parisi JE, Lennon VA, Benarroch EE, Lassmann H, Bruck W, Mandler RN, Weinshenker BG, Pittock SJ, Wingerchuk DM, Lucchinetti CF. Pattern-specific loss of aquaporin-4 immunoreactivity distinguishes neuromyelitis optica from multiple sclerosis. Brain. 2007;130(pt 5):1194–1205.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jarius S, Paul F, Franciotta D, Waters P, Zipp F, Hohlfeld R, Vincent A, Wildemann B. Mechanisms of disease: aquaporin-4 antibodies in neuromyelitis optica. Nat Clin Pract Neurol. 2008;4:202–214.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zou Z, Chen W. Can Wernekink commissure syndrome and wall-eyed bilateral internuclear ophthalmoplegia be ascribed to neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder? Neurol Sci. 2017;38:2053–2055.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaufman MD, Johnson SK, Moyer D, Bivens J, Norton HJ. Multiple sclerosis: severity and progression rate in African Americans compared with whites. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2003;82:582–590.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rivas-Rodriguez E, Amezcua L. Ethnic considerations and multiple sclerosis disease variability in the United States. Neurol Clin. 2018;36:151–162.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim SH, Mealy MA, Levy M, Schmidt F, Ruprecht K, Paul F, Ringelstein M, Aktas O, Hartung HP, Asgari N, Tsz-Ching JL, Siritho S, Prayoonwiwat N, Shin HJ, Hyun JW, Han M, Leite MI, Palace J, Kim HJ. Racial differences in neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder. Neurology. 2018;91:e2089–e2099.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Flanagan EP, Cabre P, Weinshenker BG, Sauver JS, Jacobson DJ, Majed M, Lennon VA, Lucchinetti CF, McKeon A, Matiello M, Kale N, Wingerchuk DM, Mandrekar J, Sagen JA, Fryer JP, Robinson AB, Pittock SJ. Epidemiology of aquaporin-4 autoimmunity and neuromyelitis optica spectrum. Ann Neurol. 2016;79:775–783.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Papais-Alvarenga RM, Carellos SC, Alvarenga MP, Holander C, Bichara RP, Thuler LC. Clinical course of optic neuritis in patients with relapsing neuromyelitis optica. Arch Ophthalmol. 2008;126:12–16.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sellner J, Boggild M, Clanet M, Hintzen RQ, Illes Z, Montalban X, Du Pasquier RA, Polman CH, Sorensen PS, Hemmer B. EFNS guidelines on diagnosis and management of neuromyelitis optica. Eur J Neurol. 2010;17:1019–1032.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kira J. Neuromyelitis optica and asian phenotype of multiple sclerosis. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2008;1142:58–71.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Popa GL, Papa MI. Salmonella spp. infection–a continuous threat worldwide. Germs. 2021;11:88–96.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35427281</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>24</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>24</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-5166</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>42</Volume>
            <Issue>2</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
              <Day>01</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of neuro-ophthalmology : the official journal of the North American Neuro-Ophthalmology Society</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Neuroophthalmol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Internuclear Ophthalmoplegia Characterizes Multiple Sclerosis Rather Than Neuromyelitis Optica Spectrum Disease.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>239</StartPage>
          <EndPage>245</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>239-245</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/WNO.0000000000001534</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Neuromyelitis optica spectrum disease (NMOSD) and multiple sclerosis (MS) share clinical presentations including optic neuritis and brainstem syndromes. Internuclear ophthalmoplegia (INO) is characterized by slowed ipsilateral adduction saccades and results from a lesion in the medial longitudinal fasciculus (MLF). Although INO is a common clinical finding in MS, its prevalence in NMOSD is unknown. The objective of this work is to determine the comparative frequencies of INO in patients with NMOSD and MS and compare clinical features of both disease processes.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This is a retrospective study of patients 18 years and older who have an established diagnosis of NMOSD or MS and were evaluated by both neuro-ophthalmology and neuro-immunology specialists between 2014 and 2020. Electronic medical records were screened for documentation of an acute INO at any time during follow-up. Incidence rates were calculated from number of cases of new-onset INO and patient years observed. Logistic regression was used to evaluate the likelihood of developing an INO at any time point for NMOSD vs MS patients. Multivariable analysis was performed by adjusting for age, race, gender, and length of follow-up.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Two hundred eighty patients (80 NMOSD, 200 MS) were included. Age range was 18-79 years with a mean age of 35.14 (SD ± 12.41 years). Average length of follow-up in MS and NMOSD patients was 4.18 years vs 3.79 years, respectively (P &gt; 0.05), and disease duration before the start of the study in MS and NMOSD was 8.76 years vs 4.65 years, respectively (P &lt; 0.01). Mean disease duration and follow-up time of both groups was 7.58 years and 4.07 ± 2.51 years, respectively. NMOSD patients were predominantly seropositive for AQP4 antibody (61.25%, n = 49). Individuals who had MOG antibody but also met NMOSD criteria were also included (18.75%, n = 15). The frequency of INO at any time point was 1.25% (n = 1) in NMOSD compared with 16% (n = 32) in MS. The incidence rate of new-onset INO in NMOSD (excluding MOGAD) was 3.8/1,000 person years and 23.9/1,000 person years in MS. Adjusted analysis showed that NMOSD patients were 13.89 times (odds ratio [OR] 0.07, 95% confidence interval [CI] 0.01-0.598, P = 0.015) less likely to develop an INO compared with those with MS when including MOGAD patients, 12.5 times less likely (OR 0.08, 95% CI: 0.10-0.67, P = 0.02) when excluding MOGAD patients and 9.62 times less likely (OR 0.10, 95% CI: 0.01-0.87, P = 0.036) for AQP4+ patients.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Our study shows that the incidence of new INO (3.8 vs 23.9 per 1,000 person years), and the odds of having INO at any time point are significantly lower in NMOSD than MS. This suggests that INO and consequently MLF lesions are less common in NMOSD. The presence of an INO may help in the differentiation of NMOSD from MS and may aid in earlier implementation of disease appropriate therapy.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022 by North American Neuro-Ophthalmology Society.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hamza</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mahmoud M</ForeName>
            <Initials>MM</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Alas</LastName>
            <ForeName>Basheer F</ForeName>
            <Initials>BF</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Huang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Connie</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Quon</LastName>
            <ForeName>Justin C</ForeName>
            <Initials>JC</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Amezcua</LastName>
            <ForeName>Lilyana</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Robers</LastName>
            <ForeName>Michael V</ForeName>
            <Initials>MV</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gokoffski</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kimberly K</ForeName>
            <Initials>KK</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3589-0296</Identifier>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Neuroophthalmol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9431308</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1070-8022</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D051401">Aquaporin 4</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D001323">Autoantibodies</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D063308">Myelin-Oligodendrocyte Glycoprotein</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D051401" MajorTopicYN="N">Aquaporin 4</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001323" MajorTopicYN="N">Autoantibodies</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008875" MajorTopicYN="N">Middle Aged</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009103" MajorTopicYN="Y">Multiple Sclerosis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D063308" MajorTopicYN="N">Myelin-Oligodendrocyte Glycoprotein</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009471" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neuromyelitis Optica</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015835" MajorTopicYN="Y">Ocular Motility Disorders</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors report no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
          <Hour>17</Hour>
          <Minute>9</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35427281</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/WNO.0000000000001534</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">00041327-990000000-00033</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Flanagan EP. Neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder and other non-multiple sclerosis central nervous system inflammatory diseases. Continuum (Minneap MN). 2019;25:815–844.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fujihara K. Neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorders: still evolving and broadening. Curr Opin Neurol. 2019;32:385–394.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yokote H, Mizusawa H. Multiple sclerosis and neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorders: some similarities in two distinct diseases. Neural Regen Res. 2016;11:410–411.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lennon VA, Wingerchuk DM, Kryzer TJ, Pittock SJ, Lucchinetti CF, Fujihara K, Nakashima I, Weinshenker BG. A serum autoantibody marker of neuromyelitis optica: distinction from multiple sclerosis. Lancet. 2004;364:2106–2112.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thompson AJ, Banwell BL, Barkhof F, Carroll WM, Coetzee T, Comi G, Correale J, Fazekas F, Filippi M, Freedman MS, Fujihara K, Galetta SL, Hartung HP, Kappos L, Lublin FD, Marrie RA, Miller AE, Miller DH, Montalban X, Mowry EM, Sorensen PS, Tintoré M, Traboulsee AL, Trojano M, Uitdehaag BMJ, Vukusic S, Waubant E, Weinshenker BG, Reingold SC, Cohen JA. Diagnosis of multiple sclerosis: 2017 revisions of the McDonald criteria. Lancet Neurol. 2018;17:162–173.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nij Bijvank JA, van Rijn LJ, Balk LJ, Tan HS, Uitdehaag BMJ, Petzold A. Diagnosing and quantifying a common deficit in multiple sclerosis: internuclear ophthalmoplegia. Neurology. 2019;92:e2299–e2308.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dubey D, Pittock SJ, Krecke KN, Morris PP, Sechi E, Zalewski NL, Weinshenker BG, Shosha E, Lucchinetti CF, Fryer JP, Lopez-Chiriboga AS, Chen JC, Jitprapaikulsan J, McKeon A, Gadoth A, Keegan BM, Tillema JM, Naddaf E, Patterson MC, Messacar K, Tyler KL, Flanagan EP. Clinical, radiologic, and prognostic features of myelitis associated with myelin oligodendrocyte glycoprotein autoantibody. JAMA Neurol. 2019;76:301–309.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li LM, Guo HY, Zhao N, Zhang LJ, Zhang N, Liu J, Yang L. Comparison of olfactory function between neuromyelitis optica and multiple sclerosis. Int J Neurosci. 2018;128:772–777.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sato DK, Callegaro D, Lana-Peixoto MA, Waters PJ, de Haidar Jorge FM, Takahashi T, Nakashima I, Apostolos-Pereira SL, Talim N, Simm RF, Lino AM, Misu T, Leite MI, Aoki M, Fujihara K. Distinction between MOG antibody-positive and AQP4 antibody-positive NMO spectrum disorders. Neurology. 2014;82:474–481.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hamid SHM, Whittam D, Mutch K, Linaker S, Solomon T, Das K, Bhojak M, Jacob A. What proportion of AQP4-IgG-negative NMO spectrum disorder patients are MOG-IgG positive? A cross sectional study of 132 patients. J Neurol. 2017;264:2088–2094.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kunchok A, Chen JJ, Saadeh RS, Wingerchuk DM, Weinshenker BG, Flanagan EP, Pittock SJ. Application of 2015 seronegative neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder diagnostic criteria for patients with myelin oligodendrocyte glycoprotein IgG-associated disorders. JAMA Neurol. 2020;77:1572–1575.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bouzar M, Daoudi S, Hattab S, Bouzar AA, Deiva K, Wildemann B, Reindl M, Jarius S. Neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorders with antibodies to myelin oligodendrocyte glycoprotein or aquaporin-4: clinical and paraclinical characteristics in Algerian patients. J Neurol Sci. 2017;381:240–244.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reindl M, Rostasy K. MOG antibody-associated diseases. Neurol Neuroimmunol Neuroinflamm. 2015;2:e60.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sato DK, Callegaro D, Lana-Peixoto MA, Nakashima I, Fujihara K. Seronegative Neuromyelitis Optica Spectrum: the challenges on disease definition and pathogenesis. Arq Neuropsiquiatr. 2014;72:445–450.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim HJ, Paul F, Lana-Peixoto MA, Tenembaum S, Asgari N, Palace J, Klawiter EC, Sato DK, de Seze J, Wuerfel J, Banwell BL, Villoslada P, Saiz A, Fujihara K, Kim SH. MRI characteristics of neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder: an international update. Neurology. 2015;84:1165–1173.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vabanesi M, Pisa M, Guerrieri S, Moiola L, Radaelli M, Medaglini S, Martinelli V, Comi G, Leocani L. In vivo structural and functional assessment of optic nerve damage in neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorders and multiple sclerosis. Sci Rep. 2019;9:10371.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pittock SJ, Lucchinetti CF. Neuromyelitis optica and the evolving spectrum of autoimmune aquaporin-4 channelopathies: a decade later. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2016;1366:20–39.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bennett JL, de Seze J, Lana-Peixoto M, Palace J, Waldman A, Schippling S, Tenembaum S, Banwell B, Greenberg B, Levy M, Fujihara K, Chan KH, Kim HJ, Asgari N, Sato DK, Saiz A, Wuerfel J, Zimmermann H, Green A, Villoslada P, Paul F. Neuromyelitis optica and multiple sclerosis: seeing differences through optical coherence tomography. Mult Scler. 2015;21:678–688.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jozefowicz-Korczynska M, Lukomski M, Pajor A. Identification of internuclear ophthalmoplegia signs in multiple sclerosis patients. Saccade test analysis. J Neurol. 2008;255:1006–1011.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Müri RM, Meienberg O. The clinical spectrum of internuclear ophthalmoplegia in multiple sclerosis. Arch Neurol. 1985;42:851–855.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Serra A, Chisari CG, Matta M. Eye movement abnormalities in multiple sclerosis: pathogenesis, modeling, and treatment. Front Neurol. 2018;9:31.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Downey DL, Stahl JS, Bhidayasiri R, Derwenskus J, Adams NL, Ruff RL, Leigh RJ. Saccadic and vestibular abnormalities in multiple sclerosis: sensitive clinical signs of brainstem and cerebellar involvement. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2002;956:438–440.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garcia-Martin E, Pinilla I, Pueyo V, Gil L, Martinez-Morales J, Fernandez J. Bilateral internuclear ophthalmoplegia in a patient with devic's neuromyelitis optica. Case Rep Neurol. 2010;2:139–144.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shinoda K, Matsushita T, Furuta K, Isobe N, Yonekawa T, Ohyagi Y, Kira J. Wall-eyed bilateral internuclear ophthalmoplegia (WEBINO) syndrome in a patient with neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder and anti-aquaporin-4 antibody. Mult Scler. 2011;17:885–887.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pittock SJ, Weinshenker BG, Lucchinetti CF, Wingerchuk DM, Corboy JR, Lennon VA. Neuromyelitis optica brain lesions localized at sites of high aquaporin 4 expression. Arch Neurol. 2006;63:964–968.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roemer SF, Parisi JE, Lennon VA, Benarroch EE, Lassmann H, Bruck W, Mandler RN, Weinshenker BG, Pittock SJ, Wingerchuk DM, Lucchinetti CF. Pattern-specific loss of aquaporin-4 immunoreactivity distinguishes neuromyelitis optica from multiple sclerosis. Brain. 2007;130(pt 5):1194–1205.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jarius S, Paul F, Franciotta D, Waters P, Zipp F, Hohlfeld R, Vincent A, Wildemann B. Mechanisms of disease: aquaporin-4 antibodies in neuromyelitis optica. Nat Clin Pract Neurol. 2008;4:202–214.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zou Z, Chen W. Can Wernekink commissure syndrome and wall-eyed bilateral internuclear ophthalmoplegia be ascribed to neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder? Neurol Sci. 2017;38:2053–2055.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaufman MD, Johnson SK, Moyer D, Bivens J, Norton HJ. Multiple sclerosis: severity and progression rate in African Americans compared with whites. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2003;82:582–590.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rivas-Rodriguez E, Amezcua L. Ethnic considerations and multiple sclerosis disease variability in the United States. Neurol Clin. 2018;36:151–162.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim SH, Mealy MA, Levy M, Schmidt F, Ruprecht K, Paul F, Ringelstein M, Aktas O, Hartung HP, Asgari N, Tsz-Ching JL, Siritho S, Prayoonwiwat N, Shin HJ, Hyun JW, Han M, Leite MI, Palace J, Kim HJ. Racial differences in neuromyelitis optica spectrum disorder. Neurology. 2018;91:e2089–e2099.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Flanagan EP, Cabre P, Weinshenker BG, Sauver JS, Jacobson DJ, Majed M, Lennon VA, Lucchinetti CF, McKeon A, Matiello M, Kale N, Wingerchuk DM, Mandrekar J, Sagen JA, Fryer JP, Robinson AB, Pittock SJ. Epidemiology of aquaporin-4 autoimmunity and neuromyelitis optica spectrum. Ann Neurol. 2016;79:775–783.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Papais-Alvarenga RM, Carellos SC, Alvarenga MP, Holander C, Bichara RP, Thuler LC. Clinical course of optic neuritis in patients with relapsing neuromyelitis optica. Arch Ophthalmol. 2008;126:12–16.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sellner J, Boggild M, Clanet M, Hintzen RQ, Illes Z, Montalban X, Du Pasquier RA, Polman CH, Sorensen PS, Hemmer B. EFNS guidelines on diagnosis and management of neuromyelitis optica. Eur J Neurol. 2010;17:1019–1032.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kira J. Neuromyelitis optica and asian phenotype of multiple sclerosis. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2008;1142:58–71.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Popa GL, Papa MI. Salmonella spp. infection–a continuous threat worldwide. Germs. 2021;11:88–96.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
