<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35426607</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">2193-8210</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>12</Volume>
            <Issue>5</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Dermatology and therapy</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Dermatol Ther (Heidelb)</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Parapsoriasis-A Diagnosis with an Identity Crisis: A Narrative Review.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>1091</StartPage>
          <EndPage>1102</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>1091-1102</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s13555-022-00716-y</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Parapsoriasis is an uncommon inflammatory skin disease characterized by chronic patches that may be resistant to therapy. It was primarily introduced and classified 120 years ago, and the original classification incorporated parapsoriasis and pityriasis lichenoides under the umbrella term parapsoriasis. After a major change in classification, parapsoriasis now exclusively refers to small plaque parapsoriasis (SPP) and large plaque parapsoriasis (LPP). However, debates still frequently occur regarding various nomenclatures and classifications used by different authors. Moreover, parapsoriasis may progress to overt cutaneous lymphoma, most commonly mycosis fungoides (MF), and it is very difficult to distinguish these two conditions despite modern histologic and molecular testing techniques.As parapsoriasis is a rare disease, there is a lack of studies and clinical guidelines to assist physicians in clinical practice. In our comprehensive review, we review several aspects of parapsoriasis, from the history of nomenclature and classification, clinical characteristics, immunohistopathology, and advanced molecular techniques for the diagnosis of this condition, to the most current treatments. We also propose a scheme for distinguishing parapsoriasis from early-stage MF in this review.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chairatchaneeboon</LastName>
            <ForeName>Manasmon</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Faculty of Medicine Siriraj Hospital, Mahidol University, Bangkok, Thailand.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Thanomkitti</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kanchalit</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Faculty of Medicine Siriraj Hospital, Mahidol University, Bangkok, Thailand.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kim</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ellen J</ForeName>
            <Initials>EJ</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9099-7614</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Perelman School of Medicine at the University of Pennsylvania, 3400 Civic Center Boulevard, Philadelphia, PA, 19104, USA. ellen.kim@pennmedicine.upenn.edu.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>04</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Dermatol Ther (Heidelb)</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101590450</NlmUniqueID>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Digitate dermatosis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Large plaque parapsoriasis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mycosis fungoides</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Parapsoriasis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Poikiloderma vasculare atrophicans</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Premycotic dermatosis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Small plaque parapsoriasis</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>5</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35426607</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9110571</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13555-022-00716-y</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s13555-022-00716-y</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brocq L. Les parapsoriases. Ann Dermatol Syphiligr (Paris) 1902;3:433–468.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Unna PGSF, Pollitzer D. Über die Parakeratosen im allgemeinen und eine neue Form derselben (Parakeratosis variegata) Monatschr Prakt Dermatol. 1890;10:404–412.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Neisser A. Zur Frage der lichenoiden Eruptionen. Verh Dtsch Dermatol Ges. 1894;4:495–506.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jadassohn J. Über ein eigenartiges psoriasiformes und lichenoides Exanthem. Verh Dtsch Dermatol Ges. 1894;4:524–529.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brocq L. Les erythrodermies pityriasques en plaques disseminees. Rev Gen J Practiciens. 1897;11:577–590.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Juliusberg F. Über die pityriasis lichenoides chronica (Psoriasiform lichenoides Exanthem) Arch Dermatol Syphilol (Wien) 1899;50:359–374. doi: 10.1007/BF02002046.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF02002046</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mucha V. Über einen der Parakeratosis variegate (UNNA) bzw: Pityriasis lichenoides chronica (Neisser-Juliusberg) nahestehenden eigentumlichen Fall. Arch Dermatol Syphil (Wien) 1916;123:586–592. doi: 10.1007/BF01825905.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF01825905</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Habermann R. Über die akut verlaufende, nekrotisierende Unterart der Pityriasis lichenoides (Pityriasis lichenoides et varioliformis acuta) Dermatol Zeitschr (Berlin) 1925;45:42–48. doi: 10.1159/000251260.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000251260</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lambert WC, Everett MA. The nosology of parapsoriasis. J Am Acad Dermatol. 1981;5:373–395. doi: 10.1016/S0190-9622(81)70100-2.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0190-9622(81)70100-2</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7026622</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schieke SM, Wood GS, et al.   Parapsoriasis and Pityriasis Lichenoides. In: Kang S, Amagai M, Bruckner AL, Enk AH, Margolis DJ, McMichael AJ, et al., editors. Fitzpatrick's Dermatology. 9. New York: McGraw-Hill Education; 2019. pp. 505–517.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bluefarb SM. The clinical implications of parapsoriasis. Int J Dermatol. 1980;19:556–557. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-4362.1980.tb00804.x.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-4362.1980.tb00804.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7451004</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Patterson JW.  Weedon's skin pathology. 4. Philadelphia: Elsevier Churchill Livingstone; 2016. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vakeva L, Sarna S, Vaalasti A, Pukkala E, Kariniemi AL, Ranki A. A retrospective study of the probability of the evolution of parapsoriasis en plaques into mycosis fungoides. Acta Derm Venereol. 2005;85:318–323. doi: 10.1080/00015550510030087.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00015550510030087</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16191852</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hu CH, Winkelmann RK. Digitate dermatosis. A new look at symmetrical, small plaque parapsoriasis. Arch Dermatol. 1973;107:65–69. doi: 10.1001/archderm.1973.01620160037010.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archderm.1973.01620160037010</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4682544</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cerroni L.  Skin lymphoma: the illustrated guide. 4. Oxford: Wiley Blackwell; 2014. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vasconcelos Berg R, Valente NYS, Fanelli C, et al.  Poikilodermatous mycosis fungoides: comparative study of clinical histopathological and immunohistochemical features. Dermatology. 2020;236:117–122. doi: 10.1159/000502027.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000502027</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31550709</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Calonje E, Lazar A, Brenn T, McKee PH.  McKee's pathology of the skin with clinical correlations. 4. Saint Louis: Elsevier Saunders; 2012. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elder DE.  Lever's histopathology of the skin. 11. Philadelphia: Wolters Kluwer Health; 2015. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Belousova IE, Vanecek T, Samtsov AV, Michal M, Kazakov DV. A patient with clinicopathologic features of small plaque parapsoriasis presenting later with plaque-stage mycosis fungoides: report of a case and comparative retrospective study of 27 cases of "nonprogressive" small plaque parapsoriasis. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2008;59:474–482. doi: 10.1016/j.jaad.2008.05.028.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2008.05.028</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18694680</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sibbald C, Pope E. Systematic review of cases of cutaneous T-cell lymphoma transformation in pityriasis lichenoides and small plaque parapsoriasis. Br J Dermatol. 2016;175:807–809. doi: 10.1111/bjd.14605.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bjd.14605</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27031678</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sarveswari KN, Yesudian P. The conundrum of parapsoriasis versus patch stage of mycosis fungoides. Indian J Dermatol Venereol Leprol. 2009;75:229–235. doi: 10.4103/0378-6323.51239.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/0378-6323.51239</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19439874</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miyagaki T. Diagnosis of early mycosis fungoides. Diagnostics (Basel). 2021;11(9):1721. doi: 10.3390/diagnostics11091721.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/diagnostics11091721</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8465146</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34574062</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schachter O, Tabibian-Keissar H, Debby A, Segal O, Baum S, Barzilai A. Evaluation of the polymerase chain reaction-based T-cell receptor beta clonality test in the diagnosis of early mycosis fungoides. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2020;83:1400–1405. doi: 10.1016/j.jaad.2020.05.110.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2020.05.110</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32526320</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kikuchi A, Naka W, Harada T, Sakuraoka K, Harada R, Nishikawa T. Parapsoriasis en plaques: its potential for progression to malignant lymphoma. J Am Acad Dermatol. 1993;29:419–422. doi: 10.1016/0190-9622(93)70204-7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0190-9622(93)70204-7</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8394392</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muche JM, Lukowsky A, Heim J, Friedrich M, Audring H, Sterry W. Demonstration of frequent occurrence of clonal T cells in the peripheral blood but not in the skin of patients with small plaque parapsoriasis. Blood. 1999;94:1409–1417. doi: 10.1182/blood.V94.4.1409.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/blood.V94.4.1409</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10438729</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Simon M, Flaig MJ, Kind P, Sander CA, Kaudewitz P. Large plaque parapsoriasis: clinical and genotypic correlations. J Cutan Pathol. 2000;27:57–60. doi: 10.1034/j.1600-0560.2000.027002057.x.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1034/j.1600-0560.2000.027002057.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10678699</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Klemke CD, Dippel E, Dembinski A, et al.  Clonal T cell receptor gamma-chain gene rearrangement by PCR-based GeneScan analysis in the skin and blood of patients with parapsoriasis and early-stage mycosis fungoides. J Pathol. 2002;197:348–354. doi: 10.1002/path.1133.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/path.1133</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12115881</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pimpinelli N, Olsen EA, Santucci M, et al.  Defining early mycosis fungoides. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2005;53:1053–1063. doi: 10.1016/j.jaad.2005.08.057.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2005.08.057</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16310068</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zimmermann C, Boisson M, Ram-Wolff C, et al.  Diagnostic performance of high-throughput sequencing of the T-cell receptor beta gene for the diagnosis of cutaneous T-cell lymphoma. Br J Dermatol. 2021;185:679–680. doi: 10.1111/bjd.20432.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bjd.20432</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33942285</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xavier JCCJ, Ocanha-Xavier JP, Marques MEA. Shall we exclude parapsoriasis from the medical vocabulary? J Cutan Pathol. 2021;48:833–836. doi: 10.1111/cup.13990.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cup.13990</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33605464</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>King-Ismael D, Ackerman AB. Guttate parapsoriasis/digitate dermatosis (small plaque parapsoriasis) is mycosis fungoides. Am J Dermatopathol. 1992;14:518–530. doi: 10.1097/00000372-199212000-00005.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00000372-199212000-00005</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1345135</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Agar NS, Wedgeworth E, Crichton S, et al.  Survival outcomes and prognostic factors in mycosis fungoides/Sezary syndrome: validation of the revised International Society for Cutaneous Lymphomas/European Organisation for Research and Treatment of Cancer staging proposal. J Clin Oncol. 2010;28:4730–4739. doi: 10.1200/JCO.2009.27.7665.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2009.27.7665</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20855822</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lindahl LM, Schmidt M, Farkas DK, Sorensen HT, Iversen L. Risk of venous thromboembolism in patients with mycosis fungoides and parapsoriasis: a Danish nationwide population-based cohort study. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2018;78:1077–1083. doi: 10.1016/j.jaad.2017.11.043.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2017.11.043</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29203438</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lindahl LM, Heide-Jorgensen U, Pedersen L, Sorensen HT, Iversen L. Risk of acute myocardial infarction or stroke in patients with mycosis fungoides and parapsoriasis. Acta Derm Venereol. 2016;96:530–534. doi: 10.2340/00015555-2294.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2340/00015555-2294</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26576854</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lindahl LM, Fenger-Gron M, Iversen L. Subsequent cancers, mortality, and causes of death in patients with mycosis fungoides and parapsoriasis: a Danish nationwide, population-based cohort study. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2014;71:529–535. doi: 10.1016/j.jaad.2014.03.044.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaad.2014.03.044</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24836079</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lessin SR, Ross EA, Wu H. Treatment of parapsoriasis with bexarotene 1% gel. Int J Dermatol. 2008;47:1325–1327. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-4632.2008.03740.x.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-4632.2008.03740.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19126035</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lindahl LM, Fenger-Gron M, Iversen L. Topical nitrogen mustard therapy in patients with mycosis fungoides or parapsoriasis. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 2013;27:163–168. doi: 10.1111/j.1468-3083.2011.04433.x.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1468-3083.2011.04433.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22229501</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zackheim HS, Epstein EH, Jr, McNutt NS, Grekin DA, Crain WR. Topical carmustine (BCNU) for mycosis fungoides and related disorders: a 10-year experience. J Am Acad Dermatol. 1983;9:363–374. doi: 10.1016/S0190-9622(83)70143-X.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0190-9622(83)70143-X</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6630597</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhu Q, Wu Y, Li Y, et al.  Positive effects of hydrogen-water bathing in patients of psoriasis and parapsoriasis en plaques. Sci Rep. 2018;8:8051. doi: 10.1038/s41598-018-26388-3.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-018-26388-3</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5966409</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29795283</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Urosevic M, Dummer R. Role of imiquimod in skin cancer treatment. Am J Clin Dermatol. 2004;5:453–458. doi: 10.2165/00128071-200405060-00010.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/00128071-200405060-00010</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15663342</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aydogan K, Karadogan SK, Tunali S, Adim SB, Ozcelik T. Narrowband UVB phototherapy for small plaque parapsoriasis. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 2006;20:573–577. doi: 10.1111/j.1468-3083.2006.01567.x.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1468-3083.2006.01567.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16684286</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hofer A, Cerroni L, Kerl H, Wolf P. Narrowband (311-nm) UV-B therapy for small plaque parapsoriasis and early-stage mycosis fungoides. Arch Dermatol. 1999;135:1377–1380.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10566837</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Herzinger T, Degitz K, Plewig G, Rocken M. Treatment of small plaque parapsoriasis with narrow-band (311 nm) ultraviolet B: a retrospective study. Clin Exp Dermatol. 2005;30:379–381. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2230.2005.01752.x.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2230.2005.01752.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15953075</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Powell FC, Spiegel GT, Muller SA. Treatment of parapsoriasis and mycosis fungoides: the role of psoralen and long-wave ultraviolet light A (PUVA) Mayo Clin Proc. 1984;59:538–546. doi: 10.1016/S0025-6196(12)61492-X.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0025-6196(12)61492-X</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6748744</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kreuter JA, Gambichler T, Jansen T, Hoffmann K, Altmeyer P, von Kobyletzki G. UVA1 cold-light phototherapy of small plaque parapsoriasis. Acta Derm Venereol. 2000;80:390–391.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11200849</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aydogan K, Yazici S, Balaban Adim S, et al.  Efficacy of low-dose ultraviolet a-1 phototherapy for parapsoriasis/early-stage mycosis fungoides. Photochem Photobiol. 2014;90:873–877.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24502428</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rosenbaum MM, Roenigk HH, Jr, Caro WA, Esker A. Photochemotherapy in cutaneous T cell lymphoma and parapsoriasis en plaques. Long-term follow-up in forty-three patients. J Am Acad Dermatol. 1985;13:613–622. doi: 10.1016/S0190-9622(85)70206-X.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0190-9622(85)70206-X</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3878369</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Inaoki M, Kawabata C, Yagishita M, Nishijima C. Large plaque parapsoriasis with the "deck-chair" sign successfully treated with bath psoralen and ultraviolet A therapy. J Dermatol. 2010;37:570–572. doi: 10.1111/j.1346-8138.2010.00832.x.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1346-8138.2010.00832.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20536677</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morita A, Takashima A, Nagai M, Dall'Acqua F. Treatment of a case of mycosis fungoides and one of parapsoriasis en plaque with topical PUVA using a monofunctional furocoumarin derivative, 4,6,4'-trimethylangelicin. J Dermatol. 1990;17:545–549. doi: 10.1111/j.1346-8138.1990.tb01692.x.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1346-8138.1990.tb01692.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2277144</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gebert S, Raulin C, Ockenfels HM, Gundogan C, Greve B. Excimer-laser (308 nm) treatment of large plaque parapsoriasis and long-term follow-up. Eur J Dermatol. 2006;16:198–199.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16613751</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gambichler T, Manke-Heimann A. Balneophototherapy in small plaque parapsoriasis—four case reports. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 1998;10:179–181.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9553920</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
