<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35420251</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>14</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2053-1095</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Apr</Month>
              <Day>14</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Veterinary medicine and science</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Vet Med Sci</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Characterization of Brucella spp. and other abortigenic pathogens from aborted tissues of cattle and goats in Rwanda.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/vms3.805</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Abortions cause tremendous economic losses in food-producing animals and may lead to food insecurity.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">This study aimed to characterize Brucella spp. and other abortigenic pathogens from aborted tissues of cattle.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">For cattle, aborted tissues (n = 19) were cultured, and Brucella spp. were detected using the genus-specific 16S-23S ribosomal DNA interspacer region (ITS) assay and speciated using Brucella abortus, Brucella melitensis, Brucella ovis, and Brucella suis (AMOS) and Bruce-ladder PCR assays. Brucella negative samples were screened using the eight abortigenic pathogens PCR panel. Samples from an abortion outbreak that occurred within a goat tribe were included in this investigation. Sera of females (n = 8) and males (n = 2) were analyzed using the Rose Bengal Test (RBT) and indirect enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (i-ELISA), while vaginal swabs (n = 3) and aborted tissues (n = 1) were cultured and characterized.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The ITS-PCR detected Brucella DNA in cultures from two aborted tissues of cattle (10.5%, [2/19]), which were identified as B. melitensis (n = 1), and B. abortus (n = 1) using AMOS and Bruce-ladder PCR assays. Campylobacter fetus (n = 7) and Leptospira spp. (n = 4) including co-infections (n = 2) of C. fetus and Leptospira spp. were identified from the Brucella negative samples of cattle. Goats (100.0%, 10/10) were brucellosis seropositive on RBT and i-ELISA. Mixed infections caused by B. melitensis and B. abortus were isolated from the vaginal swabs (n = 3) and aborted tissues (n = 1).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION AND CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This is the first identification of abortion-associated pathogens in aborted cattle indicating the enormous financial losses and a threat to public health. It is therefore essential to include these identified pathogens in the surveillance scheme of veterinary and human services.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Authors. Veterinary Medicine and Science published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ntivuguruzwa</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jean Bosco</ForeName>
            <Initials>JB</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9404-2214</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Veterinary Tropical Diseases, Faculty of Veterinary Science, University of Pretoria, Pretoria, South Africa.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Veterinary Medicine, College of Veterinary Medicine, University of Rwanda, Kigali, Rwanda.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kolo</LastName>
            <ForeName>Francis Babaman</ForeName>
            <Initials>FB</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2872-8864</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Veterinary Tropical Diseases, Faculty of Veterinary Science, University of Pretoria, Pretoria, South Africa.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mwikarago</LastName>
            <ForeName>Emil Ivan</ForeName>
            <Initials>EI</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Human Medicine and Device assessment and Registration, Rwanda Food and Drug Administration, Kigali, Rwanda.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>vanHeerden</LastName>
            <ForeName>Henriette</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Veterinary Tropical Diseases, Faculty of Veterinary Science, University of Pretoria, Pretoria, South Africa.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>04</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Vet Med Sci</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101678837</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2053-1095</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">abortigenic pathogens</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cattle</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">characterization</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">goats</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
          <Hour>8</Hour>
          <Minute>38</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35420251</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/vms3.805</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Acha, P., &amp; Szyfres, B. (2003). Zoonoses and communicable diseases common to man and animals. Vol. I. Bacterioses and mycoses. Scientific and Technical Publication No. 580. Pan American Health Organization, Regional Office of the WHO, Washington, USA.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Akar, Y., &amp; Yildiz, H. (2005). Concentrations of some minerals in cows with retained placenta and abortion. Turkish Journal of Veterinary and Animal Sciences, 29, 1157-1162.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alinaitwe, L., Kankya, C., Allan, K. J., Rodriguez-Campos, S., Torgerson, P., &amp; Dreyfus, A. (2019). Bovine leptospirosis in abattoirs in Uganda: Molecular detection and risk of exposure among workers. Zoonoses and Public Health, 66, 636-646.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Allan, K. J., Maze, M. J., Galloway, R. L., Rubach, M. P., Biggs, H. M., Halliday, J. E., Cleaveland, S., Saganda, W., Lwezaula, B. F., &amp; Kazwala, R. R. (2020). Molecular detection and typing of pathogenic Leptospira in febrile patients and phylogenetic comparison with Leptospira detected among animals in Tanzania. The American Journal of Tropical Medicine and Hygiene, 103, 1427-1434.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Austin, F. W. (2021). Infectious agents: Mycotic abortion. Bovine Reproduction, 1, 809-813.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bang, B. (1897). Die aetiologie des seuchenhaften (‘Infectiosen’) verwerfens. Zeit Tiermed, 1, 241-278.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barkallah, M., Gharbi, Y., Hassena, A. B., Slima, A. B., Mallek, Z., Gautier, M., Greub, G., Gdoura, R., &amp; Fendri, I. (2014). Survey of infectious etiologies of bovine abortion during mid- to late gestation in dairy herds. PLoS One, 9, e91549.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blaser, M. J., Newell, D. G., Thompson, S. A., &amp; Zechner, E. L. (2008). Pathogenesis of campylobacter fetus. In I. Nachamkin, C. M. Szymanski, &amp; M. J. Blaser (Eds.) Campylobacter (pp. 401-428). ASM Press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bricker, B. J., &amp; Halling, S. M. (1994). Differentiation of Brucella abortus bv. 1, 2, and 4, Brucella melitensis, Brucella-ovis, and Brucella suis bv. 1 by PCR. Journal of Clinical Microbiology, 32, 2660-2666.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bruce, S. D., Hamerton, A., Bateman, H., &amp; Mackie, F. (1910). “Muhinyo,” a disease of natives in Uganda. Proceedings of the Royal Society of London. Series B, Containing Papers of a Biological Character, 82, 485-490.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bruce, S. D. (1887). Note on the discovery of a microorganism in Malta fever. The Practitioner, 39, 161-170.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cabell, E. (2007). Bovine abortion: Aetiology and investigations. In Practice, 29, 455-463.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chatikobo, P., Manzi, M., Kagarama, J., Rwemarika, J., &amp; Umunezero, O. (2009). Benchmark study on husbandry factors affecting reproductive performance of smallholder dairy cows in the Eastern Province of Rwanda. Livestock Research for Rural Development, 21, 1-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Corbel, M. J. (2006). Brucellosis in humans and animals: WHO.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Corner, L., Alton, G., Mcnichol, L., Streeten, T., &amp; Trueman, K. (1983). An evaluation of the anamnestic test for brucellosis in cattle of the northern pastoral area. Australian Veterinary Journal, 60, 1-3.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>da SILVA, T. M. A., de Oliveira, R. G., Mol, J. P. S., Xavier, M. N., da Paixão, T. A., Cortez, A., Heinemann, M. B., Richtzenhain, L. J., Lage, A. P., &amp; Santos, R. L. (2009). Etiologic diagnosis of bovine infectious abortion by PCR. Ciencia Rural, 39, 2563-2570.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deresa, B., Tulu, D., &amp; Deressa, F. B. (2020). Epidemiological investigation of cattle abortion and its association with brucellosis in Jimma zone, Ethiopia. Veterinary Medicine: Research and Reports, 11, 87.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gahamanyi, N., Mboera, L. E., Matee, M. I., Mutangana, D., Amachawadi, R. G., Yoon, K.-Y., Mabwi, H. A., Pan, C.-H., &amp; Komba, E. V. (2021). Molecular detection of Campylobacter species from human and cattle faecal samples in Kilosa district, Tanzania. East African Journal of Science, Technology and Innovation.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garcia-Yoldi, D., Marin, C. M., De Miguel, M. J., Munoz, P. M., Vizmanos, J. L., &amp; Lopez-Goni, I. (2006). Multiplex PCR assay for the identification and differentiation of all Brucella species and the vaccine strains Brucella abortus S19 and RB51 and Brucella melitensis Rev1. Clinical Chemistry, 52, 779-781.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garcia-Ispierto, I., &amp; López-Gatius, F. (2019). Abortion in dairy cattle with advanced twin pregnancies: Incidence and timing. Reproduction in Domestic Animals, 54, 50-53.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ishtifaq, A., Qureshi, S., Farooq, S., Kashoo, Z. A., Malik, M. Z., Alam, M. R., Wani, S., Bhat, M. A., Hussain, M., &amp; Dar, R. A. (2020). Genotyping and antibiotic resistance patterns of Campylobacter fetus subsp. venerealis from cattle farms in India. Letters in Applied Microbiology, 71, 627-636.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaufmann, A. F., Fox, M. D., Boyce, J. M., Anderson, D. C., Potter, M. E., Martone, W. J., &amp; Patton, C. M. (1980). Airborne spread of brucellosis. Annals of the New York Academy of Sciences, 353, 105-114.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Keid, L. B., Soares, R. M., Vasconcellos, S. A., Chiebao, D. P., Salgado, V. R., Megid, J., &amp; Richtzenhain, L. J. (2007). A polymerase chain reaction for detection of Brucella canis in vaginal swabs of naturally infected bitches. Theriogenology, 68, 1260-1270.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Keppie, J., Williams, A., Witt, K., &amp; Smith, H. (1965). The role of erythritol in the tissue localization of the brucellae. British Journal of Experimental Pathology, 46, 104.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kimberling, C. V., Luchsinger, D. W., &amp; Anderson, R. (1966). Three cases of canine brucellosis. Journal of the American Veterinary Medical Association, 148, 900-901.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leal-Klevezas, D. S., martínez-vázquez, I. O., garcía-cantú, J., López-Merino, A., &amp; Martínez-Soriano, J. P. (2000). Use of polymerase chain reaction to detect Brucella abortus biovar 1 in infected goats. Veterinary Microbiology, 75, 91-97.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leaver, D., &amp; Hart, I. (1960). The etiology of abortion in dairy cattle in Victoria. Australian Veterinary Journal, 36, 46-48.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ledwaba, M. B., Gomo, C., Lekota, K. E., Le Flèche, P., Hassim, A., Vergnaud, G., &amp; Van Heerden, H. (2019). Molecular characterization of Brucella species from Zimbabwe. PLoS Neglected Tropical Diseases, 13, e0007311.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ledwaba, M. B., Matle, I., Van Heerden, H., Ndumnego, O. C., &amp; Gelaw, A. K. (2020). Investigating selective media for optimal isolation of Brucella spp. in South Africa. Onderstepoort Journal of Veterinary Research, 87, 1-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lopez-Goni, I., Garcia-Yoldi, D., Marin, C. M., De Miguel, M. J., Munoz, P. M., Blasco, J. M., Jacques, I., Grayon, M., Cloeckaert, A., Ferreira, A. C., Cardoso, R., Correa de Sa, M. I., Walravens, K., Albert, D., &amp; Garin-Bastuji, B. (2008). Evaluation of a multiplex PCR assay (Bruce-ladder) for molecular typing of all Brucella species, including the vaccine strains. Journal of Clinical Microbiology, 46, 3484-3487.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mcdermott, J., Deng, K., Jayatileka, T., &amp; El Jack, M. (1987). A cross-sectional cattle disease study in Kongor Rural Council, southern Sudan. I. Prevalence estimates and age, sex and breed associations for brucellosis and contagious bovine pleuropneumonia. Preventive Veterinary Medicine, 5, 111-123.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mcdermott, J., Grace, D., &amp; Zinsstag, J. (2013). Economics of brucellosis impact and control in low-income countries. Revue Scientifique Et Technique-Office International Des Epizooties, 32, 249-261.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Megersa, B., Biffa, D., Abunna, F., Regassa, A., Godfroid, J., &amp; Skjerve, E. (2011). Seroprevalence of brucellosis and its contribution to abortion in cattle, camel, and goat kept under pastoral management in Borana, Ethiopia. Tropical Animal Health and Production, 43, 651-656.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miller, R., Nakavuma, J. L., Ssajjakambwe, P., Vudriko, P., Musisi, N., &amp; Kaneene, J. B. (2016). The prevalence of brucellosis in cattle, goats and humans in rural Uganda: A comparative study. Transboundary and Emerging Diseases, 63, e197-e210.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Momtaz, H., &amp; Moshkelani, S. (2012). Detection and characterization of Leptospira spp. isolated from aborted bovine clinical samples. Acta Veterinaria Brno, 81, 21-25.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morgan, W. B., &amp; Mcdiarmid, A. (1960). The excretion of Brucella abortus in the milk of experimentally infected cattle. Research in Veterinary Science, 1, 53-57.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muendo, E. N., Mbatha, P. M., Macharia, J., Abdoel, T. H., Janszen, P. V., Pastoor, R., &amp; Smits, H. L. (2012). Infection of cattle in Kenya with Brucella abortus biovar 3 and Brucella melitensis biovar 1 genotypes. Tropical Animal Health and Production, 44, 17-20.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muma, J. B., Godfroid, J., Samui, K. L., &amp; Skjerve, E. (2007). The role of Brucella infection in abortions among traditional cattle reared in proximity to wildlife on the Kafue flats of Zambia. Revue Scientifique et Technique (International Office of Epizootics), 26, 721-30.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ndazigaruye, G., Mushonga, B., Kandiwa, E., Samkange, A., &amp; Segwagwe, B. E. (2018). Prevalence and risk factors for brucellosis seropositivity in cattle in Nyagatare District, Eastern Province, Rwanda. Journal of the South African Veterinary Association, 89, e1-e8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nicoletti, P., &amp; Muraschi, T. (1966). Bacteriologic evaluation of serologic test procedures for the diagnosis of brucellosis in problem cattle herds. American Journal of Veterinary Research, 27, 689-694.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ntivuguruzwa, J. B., Kolo, F. B., Gashururu, R. S., Umurerwa, L., Byaruhanga, C., &amp; Van Heerden, H. (2020). Seroprevalence and associated risk factors of bovine brucellosis at the wildlife-livestock-human interface in Rwanda. Microorganisms, 8, 1553.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ocholi, R., Kwaga, J., Ajogi, I., &amp; Bale, J. (2005). Abortion due to Brucella abortus in sheep in Nigeria. Revue Scientifique et Technique-Office International des Epizooties, 24, 973.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>OIE (2021). Brucellosis (Brucella abortus, Brucella melitensis, and Brucella suis) manual of diagnostic tests and vaccines for terrestrial animals 2021. Terrestrial Manual 8th Edition. World Organisation for Animal Health.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pearce, J., Williams, A., Harris-Smith, P. W., Fitzgeorge, R., &amp; Smith, H. (1962). The chemical basis of the virulence of Brucella abortus: II. Erythritol, a constituent of bovine foetal fluids which stimulates the growth of Br. Abortus in bovine phagocytes. British Journal of Experimental Pathology, 43, 31.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pesca, C., Cruciani, D., Agostini, L., Rossi, E., Pavone, S., Stazi, M., Mangili, P., &amp; Crotti, S. (2020). Simultaneous detection of Aspergillus nidulans, Aspergillus luchuensis and Lichtheimia spp. in a bovine abortion. Journal de Mycologie Medicale, 30, 100923.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Philpott, M., &amp; Auko, O. (1972). Caprine brucellosis in Kenya. British Veterinary Journal, 128, 642-651.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roth, Z. (2020). Influence of heat stress on reproduction in dairy cows-Physiological and practical aspects. Journal of Animal Science, 98, S80-S87.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Samartino, L. E., &amp; Enright, F. M. (1993). Pathogenesis of abortion of bovine brucellosis. Comparative Immunology, Microbiology and Infectious Diseases, 16, 95-101.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singh, B. B., Dhand, N. K., &amp; Gill, J. P. (2015). Economic losses occurring due to brucellosis in Indian livestock populations. Preventive Veterinary Medicine, 119, 211-5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Traum, J. (1914). Report of the Chief of the Bureau of Animal Industry. US Department of agriculture. Washington. DC. https://www.archives.gov/research/guide-fed-records/groups/017.html</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tremblay, C., Gaudreau, C., &amp; Lorange, M. (2003). Epidemiology and antimicrobial susceptibilities of 111 Campylobacter fetus subsp. fetus strains isolated in Quebec, Canada, from 1983 to 2000. Journal of Clinical Microbiology, 41, 463-466.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verma, S., Katoch, R. C., Sharma, M., &amp; Nigam, P. (2000). Abortions and infertility in livestock due to brucellosis in Himachal Pradesh, India. Veterinarski Arhiv, 70, 75-82.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Véron, M., &amp; Chatelain, R. (1973). Taxonomic study of the genus Campylobacter Sebald and Véron and designation of the neotype strain for the type species, Campylobacter fetus (Smith and Taylor) Sebald and Véron. International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology, 23, 122-134.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wallach, J. C., Samartino, L. E., Efron, A., &amp; Baldi, P. C. (1997). Human infection by Brucella melitensis: An outbreak attributed to contact with infected goats. FEMS Immunology &amp; Medical Microbiology, 19, 315-321.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wareth, G., Melzer, F., Tomaso, H., Roesler, U., &amp; Neubauer, H. (2015). Detection of Brucella abortus DNA in aborted goats and sheep in Egypt by real-time PCR. BMC Research Notes, 8, 1-5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zammit, T. (1905). A preliminary note on the susceptibility of goats to Malta fever. Proceedings of the Royal Society of London: Containing papers of a Biological Character. Series B, 76, 367.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zowghi, E., Ebadi, A., &amp; Mohseni, B. (1990). Isolation of Brucella organisms from the milk of seronegative cows. Revue scientifique et technique (International Office of Epizootics), 9, 1175-1178.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
