<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35421022</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>18</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>21</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-5687</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>34</Volume>
            <Issue>5</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>01</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>European journal of gastroenterology &amp; hepatology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Gastroenterol Hepatol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Acamprosate may be safer than baclofen for the treatment of alcohol use disorder in patients with cirrhosis: a first description of use in real-world clinical practice.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>567</StartPage>
          <EndPage>575</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>567-575</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MEG.0000000000002304</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Patients with alcohol use disorder (AUD) and liver cirrhosis benefit from stopping alcohol intake. Baclofen has been trialled for AUD in cirrhosis and appears to be effective. However, in patients without cirrhosis acamprosate is safer and more efficacious. Acamprosate is rarely used in cirrhosis due to safety concerns: the only published report was for 24 h in a controlled setting. Our centre uses both medications off-label in cirrhotic patients. We performed an audit to pragmatically compare the safety of acamprosate to baclofen in these patients.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The electronic records of patients prescribed acamprosate or baclofen between 01/04/17 and 31/03/20 were retrospectively reviewed. Adverse events and abstinence at last follow-up were compared by Student's t-test, Mann-Whitney U or chi-square test. Confounding variables were evaluated by logistic regression.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">In total 48 cirrhotic patients taking acamprosate (median 84 days, range 2-524); 44 baclofen (247 days, 8-910) met inclusion criteria. At baseline, 41% had Childs-Pugh B or C cirrhosis. More patients taking baclofen had an unplanned hospital admission or attendance (23 vs 13; P = 0.013) and the mean number per patient was higher (1.6 vs 0.6; P = 0.032). Sub-group analysis revealed increased admissions in actively drinking patients prescribed baclofen to achieve abstinence (mean 2.4 vs 0.6; P = 0.020); acamprosate use was associated with a reduced chance of admission or attendance (OR, 0.284; 0.095-0.854; P = 0.025) independent of treatment length. No difference in efficacy was observed.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">In patients with cirrhosis, acamprosate was associated with fewer unplanned admissions than baclofen, hence may be safer despite historical concerns.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2021 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tyson</LastName>
            <ForeName>Luke David</ForeName>
            <Initials>LD</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Hepatology, Imperial College National Health Service Healthcare Trust.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Metabolism, Digestion and Reproduction, Section of Hepatology and Gastroenterology, Liver Unit, Imperial College London, St Mary's Hospital, London, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Cheng</LastName>
            <ForeName>Alexandra</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Hepatology, Imperial College National Health Service Healthcare Trust.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kelleher</LastName>
            <ForeName>Charles</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Hepatology, Imperial College National Health Service Healthcare Trust.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Strathie</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kirstin</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Hepatology, Imperial College National Health Service Healthcare Trust.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lovendoski</LastName>
            <ForeName>James</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Hepatology, Imperial College National Health Service Healthcare Trust.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Habtemariam</LastName>
            <ForeName>Zebib</ForeName>
            <Initials>Z</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Hepatology, Imperial College National Health Service Healthcare Trust.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lewis</LastName>
            <ForeName>Heather</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Hepatology, Imperial College National Health Service Healthcare Trust.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Eur J Gastroenterol Hepatol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9000874</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0954-691X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>H789N3FKE8</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D001418">Baclofen</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>N4K14YGM3J</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000077443">Acamprosate</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000077443" MajorTopicYN="N">Acamprosate</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000428" MajorTopicYN="N">Alcohol Drinking</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000437" MajorTopicYN="Y">Alcoholism</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001418" MajorTopicYN="Y">Baclofen</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008103" MajorTopicYN="N">Liver Cirrhosis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
          <Hour>17</Hour>
          <Minute>12</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35421022</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MEG.0000000000002304</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">00042737-202205000-00013</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>World Health Organization. (2018). Global status report on alcohol and health 2018. World Health Organization.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>European Association for the Study of the Liver. EASL Clinical Practice Guidelines: management of alcohol-related liver disease. J Hepatol 2018; 69:154–181.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dandaba M, Serra W, Harika-Germaneau G, Silvain C, Langbour N, Solinas M, et al. Predicting relapse in patients with severe alcohol use disorder: the role of alcohol insight and implicit alcohol associations. Addict Behav 2020; 107:106433.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Espiridion ED. A retrospective study of hospital recidivism among patients with alcohol use disorders treated with intramuscular naltrexone. Cureus 2019; 11:e6287.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thursz MR, Richardson P, Allison M, Austin A, Bowers M, Day CP, et al.; STOPAH Trial. Prednisolone or pentoxifylline for alcoholic hepatitis. N Engl J Med 2015; 372:1619–1628.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schellekens AF, de Jong CA, Buitelaar JK, Verkes RJ. Co-morbid anxiety disorders predict early relapse after inpatient alcohol treatment. Eur Psychiatry 2015; 30:128–136.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Degré D, Stauber RE, Englebert G, Sarocchi F, Verset L, Rainer F, et al. Long-term outcomes in patients with decompensated alcohol-related liver disease, steatohepatitis and Maddrey’s discriminant function &lt;32. J Hepatol 2020; 72:636–642.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thursz M, Kamath PS, Mathurin P, Szabo G, Shah VH. Alcohol-related liver disease: areas of consensus, unmet needs and opportunities for further study. J Hepatol 2019; 70:521–530.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Avila MA, Dufour JF, Gerbes AL, Zoulim F, Bataller R, Burra P, et al. Recent advances in alcohol-related liver disease (ALD): summary of a Gut round table meeting. Gut 2020; 69:764–780.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>L’Agence nationale de sécurité du médicament et des produits de santé (French National Agency for Medicines and Health Products Safety, ANSM). Recommandation Temporaire d’Utilisation du baclofène dans la prise en charge des patients alcoolo-dépendants—2014. Available at: http://ansm.sante.fr/S-informer/Points-d-information-Points-d-information/Une-recommandation-temporaire-d-utilisation-RTU-est-accordee-pour-le-baclofene-Point-d-information. [Accessed 1 July 2020]</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rösner S, Hackl-Herrwerth A, Leucht S, Lehert P, Vecchi S, Soyka M. Acamprosate for alcohol dependence. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 2010a; 9:CD004332.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Minozzi S, Saulle R, Rösner S. Baclofen for alcohol use disorder. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 2018; 11:CD012557.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reynoard J, Schmitt C, Torrents R, Simon N. Toxicological considerations in the prescription of baclofen for the treatment of substance use disorders. Expert Opin Drug Metab Toxicol 2020; 16:309–317.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beraha EM, Salemink E, Goudriaan AE, Bakker A, de Jong D, Smits N, et al. Efficacy and safety of high-dose baclofen for the treatment of alcohol dependence: a multicentre, randomised, double-blind controlled trial. Eur Neuropsychopharmacol 2016; 26:1950–1959.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rigal L, Sidorkiewicz S, Tréluyer JM, Perrodeau E, Le Jeunne C, Porcher R, Jaury P. Titrated baclofen for high-risk alcohol consumption: a randomized placebo-controlled trial in out-patients with 1-year follow-up. Addiction 2020; 115:1265–1276.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chaignot C, Zureik M, Rey G, Dray-Spira R, Coste J, Weill A. Risk of hospitalisation and death related to baclofen for alcohol use disorders: Comparison with nalmefene, acamprosate, and naltrexone in a cohort study of 165 334 patients between 2009 and 2015 in France. Pharmacoepidemiol Drug Saf 2018; 27:1239–1248.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Addolorato G, Leggio L, Ferrulli A, Cardone S, Vonghia L, Mirijello A, et al. Effectiveness and safety of baclofen for maintenance of alcohol abstinence in alcohol-dependent patients with liver cirrhosis: randomised, double-blind controlled study. Lancet 2007; 370:1915–1922.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morley KC, Baillie A, Fraser I, Furneaux-Bate A, Dore G, Roberts M, et al. Baclofen in the treatment of alcohol dependence with or without liver disease: multisite, randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Br J Psychiatry 2018; 212:362–369.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hauser P, Fuller B, Ho SB, Thuras P, Kern S, Dieperink E. The safety and efficacy of baclofen to reduce alcohol use in veterans with chronic hepatitis C: a randomized controlled trial. Addiction 2017; 112:1173–1183.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yamini D, Lee SH, Avanesyan A, Walter M, Runyon B. Utilization of baclofen in maintenance of alcohol abstinence in patients with alcohol dependence and alcoholic hepatitis with or without cirrhosis. Alcohol Alcohol 2014; 49:453–456.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barrault C, Lison H, Roudot-Thoraval F, Garioud A, Costentin C, Béhar V, et al. One year of baclofen in 100 patients with or without cirrhosis: a French real-life experience. Eur J Gastroenterol Hepatol 2017; 29:1155–1160.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Owens L, Thompson A, Rose A, Gilmore I, Pirmohamed M, Richardson P. A prospective cohort study examining the effectiveness of baclofen in the maintenance of abstinence in alcohol use disorder patients attending a joint liver and alcohol treatment clinic. Alcohol 2017; 62:11–15.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heydtmann M, Macdonald B, Lewsey J, Masson N, Cunningham L, Irnazarow A, et al. Tailored dose baclofen in patients with alcoholic liver disease: a case series with 2-year follow-up of hospitalisation. Addict Res Theory, 2015; 23:510–517.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elfert AA, Abo Ali L, Soliman S, Zakaria S, Shehab El-Din I, Elkhalawany W, Abd-Elsalam S. Randomized placebo-controlled study of baclofen in the treatment of muscle cramps in patients with liver cirrhosis. Eur J Gastroenterol Hepatol 2016; 28:1280–1284.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Caputo F, Domenicali M, Bernardi M. Diagnosis and treatment of alcohol use disorder in patients with end-stage alcoholic liver disease. Hepatology 2019; 70:410–417.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Delgrange T, Khater J, Capron D, Duron B, Capron JP. [Effect of acute administration of acamprosate on the risk of encephalopathy and on arterial pressure in patients with alcoholic cirrhosis]. Gastroenterol Clin Biol 1992; 16:687–691.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tyson LD, Lewis H. How I treat… alcohol-related liver disease. Clin Med (Lond) 2019; 19:43–46.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Beaurepaire R, Sinclair JMA, Heydtmann M, Addolorato G, Aubin HJ, Beraha EM, et al. The use of baclofen as a treatment for alcohol use disorder: a clinical practice perspective. Front Psychiatry 2018; 9:708.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fairbanks J, Umbreit A, Kolla BP, Karpyak VM, Schneekloth TD, Loukianova LL, Sinha S. Evidence-based pharmacotherapies for alcohol use disorder: clinical pearls. Mayo Clin Proc 2020; 95:1964–1977.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iasi MS, Vieira A, Añez CI, Trindade R, Codovani NT, Favero SS, et al. Recurrence of alcohol ingestion in liver transplantation candidates. Transplant Proc 2003; 35:1123–1124.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Erim Y, Böttcher M, Dahmen U, Beck O, Broelsch CE, Helander A. Urinary ethyl glucuronide testing detects alcohol consumption in alcoholic liver disease patients awaiting liver transplantation. Liver Transpl 2007; 13:757–761.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
