<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35430736</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>17</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1556-4029</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Apr</Month>
              <Day>16</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of forensic sciences</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Forensic Sci</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Portable Raman spectroscopy applied to the study of drugs of abuse.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/1556-4029.15011</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The use of drugs of abuse has grown significantly in recent decades. In forensic chemistry, methods of identifying and characterizing illicit drugs contribute to the interests of researchers, experts, and public security authorities. Among existing methods, portable Raman spectroscopy is notable for performing rapid, non-destructive, and highly selective analysis in the laboratory or on-site. When the resulting spectral data are paired with chemometric tools, methods of exploratory analysis and multivariate calibration can be developed. Thus, this work describes the application of Raman spectroscopy associated with principal component analysis (PCA) and interval principal component analysis (iPCA) to assessing trends in samples of cocaine (n = 40), crack (n = 33), and their main adulterants (n = 5) and diluents (n = 5), tablets of ecstasy (n = 14), designer drugs papers (n = 27), and alcoholic solutions adulterated with benzodiazepines (alprazolam and diazepam). In addition, competitive adaptive reweighted sampling (CARS) combined with partial least squares (PLS) regression (CARSPLS) was used to quantify adulterants (benzocaine, lidocaine, and procaine) in binary mixtures with crack (n = 21) and solutions of cachaça adulterated with bromazepam (n = 11).</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 American Academy of Forensic Sciences.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Santos</LastName>
            <ForeName>Layla P</ForeName>
            <Initials>LP</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Laboratório de Petroleômica e Forense, Universidade Federal do Espírito Santo (UFES), Vitória, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Instituto Nacional de Ciência e Tecnologia Forense (INCT Forense), Vila Velha, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nascimento</LastName>
            <ForeName>Marcia H C</ForeName>
            <Initials>MHC</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Laboratório de Petroleômica e Forense, Universidade Federal do Espírito Santo (UFES), Vitória, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Barros</LastName>
            <ForeName>Iago H A S</ForeName>
            <Initials>IHAS</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Laboratório de Petroleômica e Forense, Universidade Federal do Espírito Santo (UFES), Vitória, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Santos</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nayara A</ForeName>
            <Initials>NA</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Laboratório de Petroleômica e Forense, Universidade Federal do Espírito Santo (UFES), Vitória, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Instituto Nacional de Ciência e Tecnologia Forense (INCT Forense), Vila Velha, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lacerda</LastName>
            <ForeName>Valdemar</ForeName>
            <Initials>V</Initials>
            <Suffix>Jr</Suffix>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Laboratório de Petroleômica e Forense, Universidade Federal do Espírito Santo (UFES), Vitória, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Filgueiras</LastName>
            <ForeName>Paulo R</ForeName>
            <Initials>PR</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Laboratório de Petroleômica e Forense, Universidade Federal do Espírito Santo (UFES), Vitória, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Romão</LastName>
            <ForeName>Wanderson</ForeName>
            <Initials>W</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2254-6683</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Laboratório de Petroleômica e Forense, Universidade Federal do Espírito Santo (UFES), Vitória, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Instituto Nacional de Ciência e Tecnologia Forense (INCT Forense), Vila Velha, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Instituto Federal do Espírito Santo (IFES), Vila Velha, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Academia Brasileira de Ciências (ABC), Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>04</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Forensic Sci</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0375370</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0022-1198</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CARSPLS</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">NPS</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">beverages</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cocaine</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">iPCA</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">new psychoactive substances</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">portable analysis</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>21</Hour>
          <Minute>5</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35430736</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1556-4029.15011</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>World drug report 2020 (United Nations publication, Sales No. E.20.XI.6). [cited 2020 Aug 01]. Available from: https://www.unodc.org/unodc/en/data-and-analysis/wdr2021.html</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Romão W, Schwab NV, Bueno MIMS, Sparrapan R, Eberlin MN, Martiny A, et al. Forensic chemistry: perspectives on new analytical methods applied to documentoscopy, ballistics, and drugs of abuse. Quim Nova. 2011;34(10):1717-28. https://doi.org/10.1590/s0100-40422011001000005</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dias F. Amidst the pandemic and with closed borders, drug seizures in MS rise by 101% in the last 2 months. May 13, 2020. [cited 2020 Jul 5]. Available from: https://g1.globo.com/ms/mato-grosso-do-sul/noticia/2020/05/13/em-meio-a-pandemia-e-com-fronteiras-fechadas-apreensao-de-drogas-em-ms-cresce-101percent-nos-ultimos-2-meses.ghtmladas-apreensao-de-drogas-em-ms-cresce-101percent-nos-ultimos-2-meses.ghtml</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>The amount of drugs used in ES in 2020 is five times higher than last year. 2020 Dec 19. [cited 2020 Jul 5]. Available from: https://g1.globo.com/es/espirito-santo/noticia/2020/12/19/quantidade-de-droga-apreendida-no-es-em-2020-e-cinco-vezes-maior-que-no-ano-passado.ghtml</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martinis BS, Oliveira MF. Experimental forensic chemistry. Vol 117. São Paulo, Brazil: Cengage Learning; 2015. p. 135-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Passagli MF. Forensic toxicology: theory and practice. 2nd ed. São Paulo, Brazil: Millennium; 2018. p. 119-20 125-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Santos NA, Souza LM, Domingos E, França HS, Lacerda V, Beatriz A, et al. Evaluating the selectivity of colorimetric test (fast blue BB salt) for the cannabinoids identification in marijuana street samples by UV-vis, TLC, ESI(+)FT-ICR MS and ESI(+)MS/MS. Forensic Chem. 2016;1:13-21. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.forc.2016.07.001</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Conceição VN, Souza LM, Merlo BB, Filgueiras PR, Poppi RJ, Romão W. Study of Scott’s test via spectroscopic techniques: An alternative method to differentiate cocaine hydrochloride and its adulterants. Quim Nova. 2014;37(9):1538-44. https://doi.org/10.5935/0100-4042.20140240</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lanaro R, Costa JL, Zanolli Filho LA, Cazenave SOS. Chemical identification of chlorophenylpiperazine (CPP) in confiscated tablets. Quim Nova. 2010;33(3):725-9. https://doi.org/10.1590/s0100-40422010000300042</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kelly K, Bell S. Evaluation of the reproducibility and repeatability of GCMS retention indices and mass spectra of novel psychoactive substances. Forensic Chem. 2018;7:10-8. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.forc.2017.11.002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>López-García E, Mastroianni N, Postigo C, Barceló D, López de Alda M. A fully automated approach for the analysis of 37 psychoactive substances in raw wastewater based on on-line solid phase extraction-liquid chromatography-tandem mass spectrometry. J Chromatogr A. 2018;1576:80-9. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chroma.2018.09.038</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Santos NA, Macrino CJ, Allochio Filho JF, Gonçalves FF, Almeida CM, Agostini F, et al. Exploring the chemical profile of designer drugs by ESI (+) and PSI (+) mass spectrometry - An approach on the fragmentation mechanisms and chemometric analysis. J Mass Spectrom. 2020;55(10):e4596. https://doi.org/10.1002/jms.4596</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coelho Neto J, Andrade AFB, Lordeiro RA, Machado Y, Elie M, Ferrari Júnior E, et al. Preventing misidentification of 25I-NBOH as 2C-I on routine GC-MS analyses. Forensic Toxicol. 2017;35(2):415-20. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11419-017-0362-0</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bordin DC, Messias M, Lanaro R, Cazenave SOS, Costa JL. Forensic analysis: research of interfering plant drugs in colorimetric tests for the identification of cannabinoids in marijuana (Cannabis sativa L.). Quim Nova. 2012;35(10):2040-3. https://doi.org/10.1590/S0100-40422012001000025</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tsumura Y, Mitome T, Kimoto S. False positives and false negatives with a cocaine-specific field test and modification of test protocol to reduce false decision. Forensic Sci Int. 2005;155(2-3):158-64. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.forsciint.2004.11.011</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Doty KC, Muro CK, Bueno J, Halámková L, Lednev IK. What can Raman spectroscopy do for criminalistics? J Raman Spectrosc. 2016;47(1):39-50. https://doi.org/10.1002/jrs.4826</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>West MJ, Went MJ. Detection of drugs of abuse by Raman spectroscopy. Drug Test Anal. 2011;3(9):532-8. https://doi.org/10.1002/dta.217</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bumbrah GS, Sharma RM. Raman spectroscopy - basic principle, instrumentation and selected applications for the characterization of drugs of abuse. Egypt J Forensic Sci. 2016;6(3):209-15. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ejfs.2015.06.001</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oliveira Penido CAF, Pacheco MTT, Lednev IK, Silveira L. Raman spectroscopy in forensic analysis: identification of cocaine and other illegal drugs of abuse. J Raman Spectrosc. 2016;47(1):28-38. https://doi.org/10.1002/jrs.4864</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fikiet MA, Khandasammy SR, Mistek E, Ahmed Y, Halámková L, Bueno J, et al. Forensics: evidence examination via Raman spectroscopy. Phys Sci Rev. 2018;4(2):1-16. https://doi.org/10.1515/psr-2017-0049</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>SWGDRUG. Recommendations for code of professional practice, education and training, methods of analysis, and quality assurance. Sci Work Gr Anal Seized Drugs. 2019;1(6):26-42. https://www.swgdrug.org/Documents/SWGDRUG%20Recommendations%206.pdf</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Downes A. Wide area Raman spectroscopy. Appl Spectrosc Rev. 2019;54(5):445-56. https://doi.org/10.1080/05704928.2019.1576190</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harvey SD, Vucelick ME, Lee RN, Wright BW. Blind field test evaluation of Raman spectroscopy as a forensic tool. Forensic Sci Int. 2002;125(1):12-21. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0379-0738(01)00615-6</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Crocombe RA. Portable spectroscopy. Appl Spectrosc. 2018;72(12):1701-51. https://doi.org/10.1177/0003702818809719</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Crocombe RA. Handheld spectrometers: the state of the art. Next-Generation Spectrosc Technol VI. 2013;8726(978):87260R. https://doi.org/10.1117/12.2017892</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lanzarotta A, Witkowski M, Batson JC. Identification of opioids and related substances using handheld Raman spectrometers. J Forensic Sci. 2019;65(2):421-7. https://doi.org/10.1111/1556-4029.14217</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnson CS, Stansfield CR, Hassan VR. Festival testing: a survey of suspected drugs seized from New Zealand music festivals, December 2018 to march 2019. Forensic Sci Int. 2020;313:110367. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.forsciint.2020.110367</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu CM, Xu L, He HY, Jia W, Hua ZD. Discrimination of phenethylamine regioisomers and structural analogues by Raman spectroscopy. J Forensic Sci. 2021;66(1):365-74. https://doi.org/10.1111/1556-4029.14563</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khandasammy SR, Fikiet MA, Mistek E, Ahmed Y, Halámková L, Bueno J, et al. Bloodstains, paintings, and drugs: Raman spectroscopy applications in forensic science. Forensic Chem. 2018;8:111-33. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.forc.2018.02.002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pelletier MJ. Quantitative analysis using Raman methods. Appl Spectrosc. 2003;57(1):19-42. https://doi.org/10.1366/000370203321165133</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Omar J, Slowikowski B, Guillou C, Reniero F, Holland M, Boix A. Identification of new psychoactive substances (NPS) by Raman spectroscopy. J Raman Spectrosc. 2018;50(1):41-51. https://doi.org/10.1002/jrs.5496</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bedward TM, Xiao L, Fu S. Application of Raman spectroscopy in the detection of cocaine in food matrices. Aust J Forensic Sci. 2019;51(2):209-19. https://doi.org/10.1080/00450618.2017.1356867</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Metternich S, Fischmann S, Münster-Müller S, Pütz M, Westphal F, Schönberger T, et al. Discrimination of synthetic cannabinoids in herbal matrices and of cathinone derivatives by portable and laboratory-based Raman spectroscopy. Forensic Chem. 2020;19:100241. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.forc.2020.100241</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Braz A, Santos Silva C, Peixoto AC, Pimentel MF, Pereira G, Braga CCS, et al. Preliminary study on the identification of synthetic cathinones in street seized samples by Raman spectroscopy and chemometrics. J Raman Spectrosc. 2021;52(4):901-13. https://doi.org/10.1002/jrs.6074</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Silva CS, Braz A, Pimentel MF. Vibrational spectroscopy and chemometrics in forensic chemistry: critical review, current trends and challenges. J Braz Chem Soc. 2019;30(11):2259-90. https://doi.org/10.21577/0103-5053.20190140</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kumar R, Sharma V. Chemometrics in forensic science. Trends Analyt Chem. 2018;105:191-201. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.trac.2018.05.010</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sabin GP, De Souza AM, Breitkreitz MC, Poppi RJ. Desenvolvimento de um algoritmo Para identificação e correção de spikes em espectroscopia raman de imagem [development of algorithm for the identification and correction of spikes in image Raman spectroscopy]. Quim Nova. 2012;35(3):612-5. https://doi.org/10.1590/S0100-40422012000300030</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang ZM, Chen S, Liang YZ. Baseline correction using adaptive iteratively reweighted penalized least squares. Analyst. 2010;135(5):1138-46. https://doi.org/10.1039/b922045c</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ballabio D. A MATLAB toolbox for principal component analysis and unsupervised exploration of data structure. Chemom Intel Lab Syst. 2015;149:1-9. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemolab.2015.10.003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nérgaard L, Saudland A, Wagner J, Nielsen JP, Munck L, Engelsen SB. Interval partial least-squares regression (iPLS): a comparative chemometric study with an example from near-infrared spectroscopy. Appl Spectrosc. 2000;54(3):413-9. https://doi.org/10.1366/0003702001949500</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Andersson M. A comparison of nine PLS1 algorithms. J Chemometr. 2009;23(10):518-29. https://doi.org/10.1002/cem.1248</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li H, Liang Y, Xu Q, Cao D. Key wavelengths screening using competitive adaptive reweighted sampling method for multivariate calibration. Anal Chim Acta. 2009;648(1):77-84. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.aca.2009.06.046</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Westad F, Marini F. Validation of chemometric models - a tutorial. Anal Chim Acta. 2015;893:14-24. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.aca.2015.06.056</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ferreira MMC. Chemometric: Concepts, methods and applications. Vol 346. São Paulo, Brazil: Editora da Unicamp; 2015 378-80.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Geladi P, Bruce RK. Partial least-squares regression: a tutorial. Anal Chim Acta. 1986;185:1-17. https://doi.org/10.1016/0003-2670(86)80028-9</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Souza LM, Rodrigues RRT, Santos H, Costa HB, Merlo BB, Filgueiras PR, et al. A survey of adulterants used to cut cocaine in samples seized in the Espírito Santo state by GC-MS allied to chemometric tools. Sci Justice. 2016;56(2):73-9. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scijus.2015.11.006</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haddad A, Green O, Lombardi JR. Detection of fentanyl in binary mixtures with cocaine by use of surface-enhanced Raman spectroscopy. Spectrosc Lett. 2019;52(8):462-72. https://doi.org/10.1080/00387010.2019.1671871</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Penido CAFDO, Silveira L, Pacheco MTT. Quantification of binary mixtures of cocaine and adulterants using dispersive Raman and ft-ir spectroscopy and principal component regression. Instrum Sci Technol. 2012;40(5):441-56. https://doi.org/10.1080/10739149.2012.686356</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Penido CAFO, Pacheco MTT, Zângaro RA, Silveira L. Identification of different forms of cocaine and substances used in adulteration using near-infrared Raman spectroscopy and infrared absorption spectroscopy. J Forensic Sci. 2015;60(1):171-8. https://doi.org/10.1111/1556-4029.12666</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oliveira Penido CAF, Pacheco MTT, Novotny EH, Lednev IK, Silveira L. Quantification of cocaine in ternary mixtures using partial least squares regression applied to Raman and Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy. J Raman Spectrosc. 2017;48(12):1732-43. https://doi.org/10.1002/jrs.5231</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abdulazeez I, Popoola SA, Saleh TA, Al-Saadi AA. Spectroscopic, DFT and trace detection study of procaine using surface-enhanced Raman scattering technique. Chem Phys Lett. 2019;730:617-22. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2019.06.067</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>D’Elia V, Montalvo G, Ruiz CG. Analysis of street cocaine samples in nasal fluid by Raman spectroscopy. Talanta. 2016;154:367-73. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.talanta.2016.03.077</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shende C, Smith W, Brouillette C, Farquharson S. Drug stability analysis by Raman spectroscopy. Pharmaceutics. 2014;6(4):651-62. https://doi.org/10.3390/pharmaceutics6040651</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moreira RV, da Costa JL, Menezes MR, de Faria DLA. Accessing the chemical profile of ecstasy tablets seized in São Paulo (Brazil) by FT-Raman spectroscopy. Vib Spectrosc. 2016;87:104-10. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vibspec.2016.09.015</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Inscore F, Shende C, Sengupta A, Huang H, Farquharson S. Detection of drugs of abuse in saliva by surface-enhanced Raman spectroscopy (SERS). Appl Spectrosc. 2011;65(9):1004-8. https://doi.org/10.1366/11-06310</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lobo Vicente J, Chassaigne H, Holland MV, Reniero F, Kolář K, Tirendi S, et al. Systematic analytical characterization of new psychoactive substances: a case study. Forensic Sci Int. 2016;265:107-15. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.forsciint.2016.01.024</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thirakul P, Hair LS, Bergen KL, Pearson JM. Clinical presentation, autopsy results and toxicology findings in an acute N-ethylpentylone fatality. J Anal Toxicol. 2017;41(4):342-6. https://doi.org/10.1093/jat/bkx004</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lin Z, Wang H, Hu L, Li J, Lin J, Liu B, et al. Simultaneous determination of N -ethylpentylone, dopamine, 5-hydroxytryptamine and their metabolites in rat brain microdialysis by liquid chromatography tandem mass spectrometry. Biomed Chromatogr. 2019;33(10):1-8. https://doi.org/10.1002/bmc.4626</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Christie R, Horan E, Fox J, O’Donnell C, Byrne HJ, Mcdermott S, et al. Discrimination of cathinone regioisomers, sold as “legal highs”, by Raman spectroscopy. Drug Test Anal. 2014;6(7-8):651-7. https://doi.org/10.1002/dta.1518</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Milhazes N, Borges F, Calheiros R, Marques MPM. Identification of synthetic precursors of amphetamine-like drugs using Raman spectroscopy and ab initio calculations: β-methyl-β-nitrostyrene derivatives. Analyst. 2004;129(11):1106-17. https://doi.org/10.1039/b405290k</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Han Z, Liu H, Meng J, Yang L, Liu J, Liu J. Portable kit for identification and detection of drugs in human urine using surface-enhanced Raman spectroscopy. Anal Chem. 2015;87(18):9500-6. https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.analchem.5b02899</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hargreaves MD, Burnett AD, Munshi T, Cunningham JE, Linfield EH, Davies AG, et al. Comparison of near infrared laser excitation wavelengths and its influence on the interrogation of seized drugs-of-abuse by Raman spectroscopy. J Raman Spectrosc. 2009;40(12):1974-83. https://doi.org/10.1002/jrs.2352</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gunasekaran S, Varadluin SR, Manoharan K. Fourier transform infrared and laser Raman spectroscopic investigations on 2-N-(benzoylamino) pyridine. J Phys. 1993;101(13):95-101.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Togni LR, Lanaro R, Resende RR, Costa JL. The variability of ecstasy tablets composition in Brazil. J Forensic Sci. 2015;60(1):147-51. https://doi.org/10.1111/1556-4029.12584</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Segawa H, Fukuoka T, Itoh T, Imai Y, Iwata YT, Yamamuro T, et al. Rapid detection of hypnotics using surface-enhanced Raman scattering based on gold nanoparticle co-aggregation in a wet system. Analyst. 2019;144(6):2158-65. https://doi.org/10.1039/c8an01829d</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ali EMA, Edwards HGM. The detection of flunitrazepam in beverages using portable Raman spectroscopy. Drug Test Anal. 2016;9(2):256-9. https://doi.org/10.1002/dta.1969</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sha XS, An SH, Hao HZ, Nan LI, Hang CZ, Asi WH. A rapid detection method for on-site screening of estazolam in beverages with au@ag core-shell nanoparticles paper-based SERS substrate. Anal Sci. 2020;36(6):667-74. https://doi.org/10.2116/analsci.19P361</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
