<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35436011</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>08</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-6860</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>36</Volume>
            <Issue>5</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>FASEB journal : official publication of the Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>FASEB J</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Midbody plays an active role in fibroblast-myofibroblast transition by mediating TGF-β signaling.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e22272</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e22272</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1096/fj.202101613R</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The transition of fibroblasts into myofibroblasts is a crucial step in kidney fibrosis. However, the biological processes involved in this transdifferentiation are incompletely understood. In this study, we discovered that the midbody plays a role in the fibroblast-myofibroblast transition by mediating TGF-β/Smad signaling. Combining bulk RNA-seq, histology, and the western blot of unilateral ureteral obstruction kidneys, we demonstrated that the pathway related to microtubules is implicated in kidney fibrosis, and the blocking of microtubule dynamics by colchicine improved kidney fibrosis. Subsequently, to explore microtubule-based organelles in detail, we cultured NRK-49F (rat kidney fibroblast cell line) and HKC-8 (human proximal tubule cell line) under transforming growth factor-β1 (TGF-β1) stimulation, which caused deciliation in both cell lines during epithelial-mesenchymal and fibroblast-myofibroblast transition. We identified another microtubule-based organelle, the midbody, whose formation is promoted by TGF-β1 in fibroblasts as a result of proliferation in contrast to tubular cells. Notably, TGF-β receptors were present in the midbody of both cell lines. In TGF-β1-treated fibroblasts, colchicine or Hedgehog pathway inhibitor 4 impaired the midbody formation, and attenuated the upregulation of canonical TGF-β/Smad signaling and α-SMA expression. These findings offer novel insight into the midbody as an active organelle involved in fibroblast-myofibroblast transition by mediating TGF-β/Smad signaling, which could be a potential therapeutic target.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Jung</LastName>
            <ForeName>Su Woong</ForeName>
            <Initials>SW</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9053-924X</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Nephrology, Department of Internal Medicine, Kyung Hee University Hospital at Gangdong, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kim</LastName>
            <ForeName>Su-Mi</ForeName>
            <Initials>SM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Nephrology, Department of Internal Medicine, Kyung Hee University Hospital at Gangdong, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kim</LastName>
            <ForeName>Arum</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Nephrology, Department of Internal Medicine, Kyung Hee University Hospital at Gangdong, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Park</LastName>
            <ForeName>Seon Hwa</ForeName>
            <Initials>SH</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5652-2524</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Nephrology, Department of Internal Medicine, Kyung Hee University Hospital at Gangdong, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Moon</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ju-Young</ForeName>
            <Initials>JY</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Nephrology, Department of Internal Medicine, Kyung Hee University Hospital at Gangdong, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lee</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sang-Ho</ForeName>
            <Initials>SH</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9915-6221</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Nephrology, Department of Internal Medicine, Kyung Hee University Hospital at Gangdong, Seoul, Republic of Korea.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>FASEB J</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8804484</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0892-6638</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D053823">Hedgehog Proteins</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D053773">Transforming Growth Factor beta1</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>SML2Y3J35T</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D003078">Colchicine</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003078" MajorTopicYN="N">Colchicine</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D058750" MajorTopicYN="N">Epithelial-Mesenchymal Transition</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005347" MajorTopicYN="N">Fibroblasts</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005355" MajorTopicYN="N">Fibrosis</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D053823" MajorTopicYN="N">Hedgehog Proteins</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007674" MajorTopicYN="Y">Kidney Diseases</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D058628" MajorTopicYN="Y">Myofibroblasts</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D051381" MajorTopicYN="N">Rats</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015398" MajorTopicYN="N">Signal Transduction</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D053773" MajorTopicYN="N">Transforming Growth Factor beta1</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">TGF-β/Smad signaling</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">fibroblast-myofibroblast transition</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">midbody</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">renal fibroblasts</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>13</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35436011</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1096/fj.202101613R</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leaf IA, Duffield JS. What can target kidney fibrosis? Nephrol Dial Transplant. 2017;32:i89-i97.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Duffield JS. Cellular and molecular mechanisms in kidney fibrosis. J Clin Invest. 2014;124:2299-2306.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hu B, Wu Z, Phan SH. Smad3 mediates transforming growth factor-beta-induced alpha-smooth muscle actin expression. Am J Respir Cell Mol Biol. 2003;29:397-404.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Evans RA, Tian YC, Steadman R, Phillips AO. TGF-beta1-mediated fibroblast-myofibroblast terminal differentiation-the role of Smad proteins. Exp Cell Res. 2003;282:90-100.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Itano S, Satoh M, Kadoya H, et al. Colchicine attenuates renal fibrosis in a murine unilateral ureteral obstruction model. Mol Med Rep. 2017;15:4169-4175.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim S, Jung ES, Lee J, Heo NJ, Na KY, Han JS. Effects of colchicine on renal fibrosis and apoptosis in obstructed kidneys. Korean J Intern Med. 2018;33:568-576.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sobh M, Sabry A, Moustafa F, Foda MA, Sally S, Ghoneim M. Effect of colchicine on chronic ciclosporin nephrotoxicity in Sprague-Dawley rats. Nephron. 1998;79:452-457.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Han SJ, Kim JH, Kim JI, Park KM. Inhibition of microtubule dynamics impedes repair of kidney ischemia/reperfusion injury and increases fibrosis. Sci Rep. 2016;6:27775.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Han SJ, Jung JK, Im SS, et al. Deficiency of primary cilia in kidney epithelial cells induces epithelial to mesenchymal transition. Biochem Biophys Res Commun. 2018;496:450-454.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Villalobos E, Criollo A, Schiattarella GG, et al. Fibroblast primary cilia are required for cardiac fibrosis. Circulation. 2019;139:2342-2357.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dionne LK, Wang XJ, Prekeris R. Midbody: from cellular junk to regulator of cell polarity and cell fate. Curr Opin Cell Biol. 2015;35:51-58.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peterman E, Gibieza P, Schafer J, et al. The post-abscission midbody is an intracellular signaling organelle that regulates cell proliferation. Nat Commun. 2019;10:3181.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chikina M, Zaslavsky E, Sealfon SC. CellCODE: a robust latent variable approach to differential expression analysis for heterogeneous cell populations. Bioinformatics. 2015;31:1584-1591.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim J, Lee JE, Heynen-Genel S, et al. Functional genomic screen for modulators of ciliogenesis and cilium length. Nature. 2010;464:1048-1051.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Green RA, Paluch E, Oegema K. Cytokinesis in animal cells. Annu Rev Cell Dev Biol. 2012;28:29-58.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hu CK, Coughlin M, Mitchison TJ. Midbody assembly and its regulation during cytokinesis. Mol Biol Cell. 2012;23:1024-1034.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnson CA, Wright CE, Ghashghaei HT. Regulation of cytokinesis during corticogenesis: focus on the midbody. FEBS Lett. 2017;591:4009-4026.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>D'Avino PP, Capalbo L. Regulation of midbody formation and function by mitotic kinases. Semin Cell Dev Biol. 2016;53:57-63.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Silverman-Gavrila RV, Silverman-Gavrila LB. Septins: new microtubule interacting partners. Sci World J. 2008;8:611-620.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Takahashi K, Nagai T, Chiba S, Nakayama K, Mizuno K. Glucose deprivation induces primary cilium formation through mTORC1 inactivation. J Cell Sci. 2018;131:jcs208769.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tucker RW, Scher CD, Stiles CD. Centriole deciliation associated with the early response of 3T3 cells to growth factors but not to SV40. Cell. 1979;18:1065-1072.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rozycki M, Lodyga M, Lam J, et al. The fate of the primary cilium during myofibroblast transition. Mol Biol Cell. 2014;25:643-657.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmierer B, Hill CS. TGFbeta-SMAD signal transduction: molecular specificity and functional flexibility. Nat Rev Mol Cell Biol. 2007;8:970-982.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Firestone AJ, Weinger JS, Maldonado M, et al. Small-molecule inhibitors of the AAA+ ATPase motor cytoplasmic dynein. Nature. 2012;484:125-129.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huang Z, Ma L, Wang Y, et al. MiCroKiTS 4.0: a database of midbody, centrosome, kinetochore, telomere and spindle. Nucleic Acids Res. 2015;43:D328-D334.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fumoto K, Kikuchi K, Gon H, Kikuchi A. Wnt5a signaling controls cytokinesis by correctly positioning ESCRT-III at the midbody. J Cell Sci. 2012;125:4822-4832.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Capalbo L, Bassi ZI, Geymonat M, et al. The midbody interactome reveals unexpected roles for PP1 phosphatases in cytokinesis. Nat Commun. 2019;10:4513.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Willard FS, Crouch MF. MEK, ERK, and p90RSK are present on mitotic tubulin in Swiss 3T3 cells: a role for the MAP kinase pathway in regulating mitotic exit. Cell Signal. 2001;13:653-664.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peterman E, Prekeris R. The postmitotic midbody: regulating polarity, stemness, and proliferation. J Cell Biol. 2019;218:3903-3911.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kuo TC, Chen CT, Baron D, et al. Midbody accumulation through evasion of autophagy contributes to cellular reprogramming and tumorigenicity. Nat Cell Biol. 2011;13:1214-1223.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bernabe-Rubio M, Andres G, Casares-Arias J, et al. Novel role for the midbody in primary ciliogenesis by polarized epithelial cells. J Cell Biol. 2016;214:259-273.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Crowell EF, Gaffuri AL, Gayraud-Morel B, Tajbakhsh S, Echard A. Engulfment of the midbody remnant after cytokinesis in mammalian cells. J Cell Sci. 2014;127:3840-3851.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clement CA, Ajbro KD, Koefoed K, et al. TGF-beta signaling is associated with endocytosis at the pocket region of the primary cilium. Cell Rep. 2013;3:1806-1814.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vestergaard ML, Awan A, Warzecha CB, Christensen ST, Andersen CY. Immunofluorescence Microscopy and mRNA Analysis of Human Embryonic Stem Cells (hESCs) Including Primary Cilia Associated Signaling Pathways. Methods Mol Biol. 2016;1307:123-140.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Skop AR, Liu H, Yates J 3rd, Meyer BJ, Heald R. Dissection of the mammalian midbody proteome reveals conserved cytokinesis mechanisms. Science. 2004;305:61-66.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Horgan CP, Hanscom SR, McCaffrey MW. Dynein LIC1 localizes to the mitotic spindle and midbody and LIC2 localizes to spindle poles during cell division. Cell Biol Int. 2011;35:171-178.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Estey MP, Di Ciano-Oliveira C, Froese CD, Bejide MT, Trimble WS. Distinct roles of septins in cytokinesis: SEPT9 mediates midbody abscission. J Cell Biol. 2010;191:741-749.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Madhivanan K, Aguilar RC. Ciliopathies: the trafficking connection. Traffic. 2014;15:1031-1056.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim JI, Kim J, Jang HS, Noh MR, Lipschutz JH, Park KM. Reduction of oxidative stress during recovery accelerates normalization of primary cilia length that is altered after ischemic injury in murine kidneys. Am J Physiol Renal Physiol. 2013;304:F1283-F1294.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jung SW, Kim DJ, Kim YG, Moon JY, Jeong KH, Lee SH. Renal aging resembles a continuum between normal and diseased kidneys that potentiates inflammatory response to injury. J Gerontol A Biol Sci Med Sci. 2021;76:385-392.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
