<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35435421</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>08</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-9912</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>12</Volume>
            <Issue>4</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Season>Oct-Dec</Season>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Medical gas research</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Med Gas Res</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Looking for more than hot air: how experimental design can enhance clinical evidence for hyperbaric oxygen therapy.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>116</StartPage>
          <EndPage>124</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>116-124</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/2045-9912.337992</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Hyperbaric oxygen therapy is emerging as a potential treatment for critical medical and psychological issues, including mild traumatic brain injury, traumatic brain injury, and post-traumatic stress disorder. Based on the promising results from numerous case studies, randomized clinical trials generated conflicting interpretations despite frequent improvements in patient symptoms. The primary debate concerns whether the therapeutic benefits could be attributed to placebo effects or sham conditions that actually induce a therapeutic state. In part, the contention has been exacerbated by experimental designs which could not properly account for extraneous variables, such as the potential for differing patient expectations to influence the outcome. The current discussion addresses five methodological challenges that complicate any determination of clinical significance due to experimental design. These challenges include: 1) not properly addressing or controlling patient expectations prior to the experimental sessions; 2) the challenge of experimental masking in clinical designs that require pressurized environments; 3) patient subjectivity in the primary dependent variables; 4) potential fluidity in patient symptoms or data, such as regression to the mean; and 5) the potential for nocebo effects to exaggerate treatment benefits by lowering performance expectations during pre-treatment assessments. Each factor provides an influential means by which placebo effects could complicate results and prevent the combined data from reaching a threshold of clinical significance. The discussion concludes with methodological best practices with which future research could minimize placebo effects and produce more conclusive results.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Biggs</LastName>
            <ForeName>Adam T</ForeName>
            <Initials>AT</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Naval Special Warfare Command, Coronado, CA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Littlejohn</LastName>
            <ForeName>Lanny F</ForeName>
            <Initials>LF</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Naval Special Warfare Command, Coronado, CA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Med Gas Res</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101564536</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2045-9912</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000070642" MajorTopicYN="Y">Brain Injuries, Traumatic</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006931" MajorTopicYN="Y">Hyperbaric Oxygenation</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012107" MajorTopicYN="N">Research Design</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013313" MajorTopicYN="Y">Stress Disorders, Post-Traumatic</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">best practices</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">brain health</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cognitive</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hyperbaric oxygen therapy</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mild traumatic brain injury</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">placebo</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">post-traumatic stress disorder</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">research design</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement><b>Conflicts of interest</b>. The views expressed in this article are those of the authors and do not necessarily reflect the official policy or position of the Department of the Navy, Department of Defense, nor the U.S. Government. The author is a military service member or employee of the U.S. government. This work was prepared as part of their official duties. Title 17 U.S.C. §105 provides that “Copyright protection under this title is not available for any work of the United States Government.” Title 17 U.S.C. §101 defines a U.S. Government work as a work prepared by a military service member or employee of the U.S. Government as part of that person's official duties. The authors have no financial or non-financial competing interests in this manuscript.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>8</Hour>
          <Minute>42</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35435421</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9074977</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/2045-9912.337992</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">MedGasRes_2022_12_4_116_337992</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>TRICARE. TRICARE Policy Manual 6010.60-M. 2015 </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peterson K, Bourne D, Anderson J, Boundy E, Helfand M.  Washington (DC): Department of Veterans Affairs (US); 2011. Evidence brief: Hyperbaric oxygen therapy (HBOT) for traumatic brain injury and/or post-traumatic stress disorder. VA Evidence Synthesis Program Evidence Briefs.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hyperbaric Oxygen Therapy: Don’t Be Misled. Washington, DC: FDA Consumer Health Information, U.S. Food and Drug Administration; 2013. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miller RS, Weaver LK, Bahraini N, et al.  Effects of hyperbaric oxygen on symptoms and quality of life among service members with persistent postconcussion symptoms: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Intern Med. 2015;175:43–52.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25401463</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Figueroa XA, Wright JK. Hyperbaric oxygen: B-level evidence in mild traumatic brain injury clinical trials. Neurology. 2016;87:1400–1406.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27581219</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Litz BT, Stein N, Delaney E, et al.  Moral injury and moral repair in war veterans: a preliminary model and intervention strategy. Clin Psychol Rev. 2009;29:695–706.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19683376</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nash WP, Marino Carper TL, Mills MA, Au T, Goldsmith A, Litz BT. Psychometric evaluation of the Moral Injury Events Scale. Mil Med. 2013;178:646–652.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23756071</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Holbrook TL, Galarneau MR, Dye JL, Quinn K, Dougherty AL. Morphine use after combat injury in Iraq and post-traumatic stress disorder. N Engl J Med. 2010;362:110–117.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20071700</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gama Sosa MA, De Gasperi R, Janssen PL, et al.  Selective vulnerability of the cerebral vasculature to blast injury in a rat model of mild traumatic brain injury. Acta Neuropathol Commun. 2014;2:67.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4229875</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24938728</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matchett GA, Martin RD, Zhang JH. Hyperbaric oxygen therapy and cerebral ischemia: neuroprotective mechanisms. Neurol Res. 2009;31:114–121.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19298750</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baratz-Goldstein R, Toussia-Cohen S, Elpaz A, Rubovitch V, Pick CG. Immediate and delayed hyperbaric oxygen therapy as a neuroprotective treatment for traumatic brain injury in mice. Mol Cell Neurosci. 2017;83:74–82.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28690173</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen X, Duan XS, Xu LJ, et al.  Interleukin-10 mediates the neuroprotection of hyperbaric oxygen therapy against traumatic brain injury in mice. Neuroscience. 2014;266:235–243.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24291771</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lin KC, Niu KC, Tsai KJ, et al.  Attenuating inflammation but stimulating both angiogenesis and neurogenesis using hyperbaric oxygen in rats with traumatic brain injury. J Trauma Acute Care Surg. 2012;72:650–659.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22491549</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xing P, Ma K, Li L, Wang D, Hu G, Long W. The protection effect and mechanism of hyperbaric oxygen therapy in rat brain with traumatic injury. Acta Cir Bras. 2018;33:341–353.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29768537</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harch PG, Andrews SR, Rowe CJ, et al.  Hyperbaric oxygen therapy for mild traumatic brain injury persistent postconcussion syndrome: a randomized controlled trial. Med Gas Res. 2020;10:8–20.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7871939</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32189664</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Biggs AT, Littlejohn LF, Dainer HM. Alternative uses of hyperbaric oxygen therapy in military medicine: current positions and future directions. Mil Med. 2022;187:e40–e46.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33564849</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hart BB, Weaver LK, Gupta A, et al.  Hyperbaric oxygen for mTBI-associated PCS and PTSD: Pooled analysis of results from Department of Defense and other published studies. Undersea Hyperb Med. 2019;46:353–383.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31394604</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kazdin AE. The meanings and measurement of clinical significance. J Consult Clin Psychol. 1999;67:332–339.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10369053</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kraemer HC, Morgan GA, Leech NL, Gliner JA, Vaske JJ, Harmon RJ. Measures of clinical significance. J Am Acad Child Adolesc Psychiatry. 2003;42:1524–1529.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14627890</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bain Barbara A, Dollaghan Christine A. The notion of clinically significant change. Lang Speech Hear Serv Sch. 1991;22:264–270.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hindmarch I, Quinlan PT, Moore KL, Parkin C. The effects of black tea and other beverages on aspects of cognition and psychomotor performance. Psychopharmacology (Berl) 1998;139:230–238.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9784078</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hardy P, Johnston KM, De Beaumont L, et al.  Pilot case study of the therapeutic potential of hyperbaric oxygen therapy on chronic brain injury. J Neurol Sci. 2007;253:94–105.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17234213</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Neubauer RA, Gottlieb SF, Pevsner NH. Hyperbaric oxygen for treatment of closed head injury. South Med J. 1994;87:933–936.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8091261</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wright JK, Zant E, Groom K, Schlegel RE, Gilliland K. Case report: Treatment of mild traumatic brain injury with hyperbaric oxygen. Undersea Hyperb Med. 2009;36:391–399.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20112530</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eovaldi B, Zanetti C. Hyperbaric oxygen ameliorates worsening signs and symptoms of post-traumatic stress disorder. Neuropsychiatr Dis Treat. 2010;6:785–789.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3012456</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21212826</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stoller KP. Hyperbaric oxygen therapy (1.5 ATA) in treating sports related TBI/CTE: two case reports. Med Gas Res. 2011;1:17.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3231948</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22146303</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Golden ZL, Neubauer R, Golden CJ, Greene L, Marsh J, Mleko A. Improvement in cerebral metabolism in chronic brain injury after hyperbaric oxygen therapy. Int J Neurosci. 2002;112:119–131.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12325401</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shytle RD, Eve DJ, Kim SH, Spiegel A, Sanberg PR, Borlongan CV. Retrospective case series of traumatic brain injury and post-traumatic stress disorder treated with hyperbaric oxygen therapy. Cell Transplant. 2019;28:885–892.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6719491</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31134828</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Solomon J. Case studies: more than simple anecdotes. Nat Clin Pract Nephrol. 2006;2:657.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17124517</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lin JW, Tsai JT, Lee LM, et al.  Effect of hyperbaric oxygen on patients with traumatic brain injury. Acta Neurochir Suppl. 2008;101:145–149.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18642650</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boussi-Gross R, Golan H, Fishlev G, et al.  Hyperbaric oxygen therapy can improve post concussion syndrome years after mild traumatic brain injury - randomized prospective trial. PLoS One. 2013;8:e79995.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3829860</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24260334</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weaver LK, Wilson SH, Lindblad AS, et al.  Hyperbaric oxygen for post-concussive symptoms in United States military service members: a randomized clinical trial. Undersea Hyperb Med. 2018;45:129–156.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29734566</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wolf G, Cifu D, Baugh L, Carne W, Profenna L. The effect of hyperbaric oxygen on symptoms after mild traumatic brain injury. J Neurotrauma. 2012;29:2606–2612.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23031217</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cifu DX, Hart BB, West SL, Walker W, Carne W. The effect of hyperbaric oxygen on persistent postconcussion symptoms. J Head Trauma Rehabil. 2014;29:11–20.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24052094</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marois P, Mukherjee A, Ballaz L. Hyperbaric oxygen treatment for persistent postconcussion symptoms--a placebo effect? JAMA Intern Med. 2015;175:1239–1240.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26146912</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Biggs AT, Dainer HM, Littlejohn LF. Effect sizes for symptomatic and cognitive improvements in traumatic brain injury following hyperbaric oxygen therapy. J Appl Physiol (1985) 2021;130:1594–1603.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8354823</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33792399</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Finniss DG, Kaptchuk TJ, Miller F, Benedetti F. Biological, clinical, and ethical advances of placebo effects. Lancet. 2010;375:686–695.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2832199</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20171404</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Annoni M. The Ethics of placebo effects in clinical practice and research. Int Rev Neurobiol. 2018;139:463–484.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30146058</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reynolds T. The ethics of placebo-controlled trials. Ann Intern Med. 2000;133:491.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10975985</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Simon R. Are placebo-controlled clinical trials ethical or needed when alternative treatment exists? Ann Intern Med. 2000;133:474–475.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10975967</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bok S. The ethics of giving placebos. Sci Am. 1974;231:17–23.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4432060</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Benedetti F.  Placebo effects: Understanding the mechanisms in health and disease. Oxford: Oxford University Press; 2008. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Foroughi CK, Monfort SS, Paczynski M, McKnight PE, Greenwood PM. Placebo effects in cognitive training. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2016;113:7470–7474.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4941515</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27325761</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weaver LK, Churchill SK, Bell J, Deru K, Snow GL. A blinded trial to investigate whether ‘pressure-familiar’ individuals can determine chamber pressure. Undersea Hyperb Med. 2012;39:801–805.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22908836</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harch PG. Department of Defense trials for hyperbaric oxygen and TBI: issues of study design and questionable conclusions. Undersea Hyperb Med. 2013;40:469–470.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24224289</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wampold BE, Minami T, Tierney SC, Baskin TW, Bhati KS. The placebo is powerful: estimating placebo effects in medicine and psychotherapy from randomized clinical trials. J Clin Psychol. 2005;61:835–854.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15827993</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wampold BE, Imel ZE, Minami T. The story of placebo effects in medicine: evidence in context. J Clin Psychol. 2007;63:379.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17279527</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beecher HK. The powerful placebo. J Am Med Assoc. 1955;159:1602–1606.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13271123</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kienle GS, Kiene H. The powerful placebo effect: fact or fiction? J Clin Epidemiol. 1997;50:1311–1318.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9449934</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McDonald CJ, Mazzuca SA, McCabe GP., Jr How much of the placebo ’effect’ is really statistical regression? Stat Med. 1983;2:417–427.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6369471</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boot WR, Simons DJ, Stothart C, Stutts C. The pervasive problem with placebos in psychology: why active control groups are not sufficient to rule out placebo effects. Perspect Psychol Sci. 2013;8:445–454.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26173122</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Colloca L, Finniss D. Nocebo effects, patient-clinician communication, and therapeutic outcomes. JAMA. 2012;307:567–568.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6909539</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22318275</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tracey I. Getting the pain you expect: mechanisms of placebo, nocebo and reappraisal effects in humans. Nat Med. 2010;16:1277–1283.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20948533</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Colloca L, Miller FG. The nocebo effect and its relevance for clinical practice. Psychosom Med. 2011;73:598–603.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3167012</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21862825</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scott DJ, Stohler CS, Egnatuk CM, Wang H, Koeppe RA, Zubieta JK. Placebo and nocebo effects are defined by opposite opioid and dopaminergic responses. Arch Gen Psychiatry. 2008;65:220–231.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18250260</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carey JC. The importance of case reports in advancing scientific knowledge of rare diseases. Adv Exp Med Biol. 2010;686:77–86.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20824440</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blacker KJ, Hamilton J, Roush G, Pettijohn KA, Biggs AT. Cognitive training for military application: a review of the literature and practical guide. J Cogn Enhanc. 2019;3:30–51.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
