<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35430731</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>04</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1469-7793</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Apr</Month>
              <Day>17</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>The Journal of physiology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Physiol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>When healing turns into killing - the pathophysiology of pancreatic and hepatic fibrosis.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1113/JP281135</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Disorders such as pancreatic or hepatic fibrosis are a cruel reminder that disruption of the delicate physiological balance could result in severe pathological consequences. Fibrosis is usually associated with chronic diseases and manifests itself as excessive deposition of the extracellular matrix, which gradually leads to the replacement of the cellular components by fibrotic lesions, significantly compromising normal tissue functions. The main cellular mediators of fibrosis are different populations of tissue fibroblasts, predominantly hepatic and pancreatic stellate cells in the liver and pancreas, respectively. These cells undergo a phenotypic switch in response to (bio)chemical or physical stimuli and acquire a myofibroblast-like phenotype characterised by increased contractile and adhesive properties, elevated expression of certain cytoskeletal and membrane proteins, and prominent production of extracellular matrix components. In the past few decades, a substantial scientific effort has been undertaken to investigate the pathogenesis of fibrosis. Here, cellular mechanisms of hepatic and pancreatic fibrosis, their aetiological factors, associated diseases and prospective therapies are discussed. New therapies against fibrosis are likely to be focused on regulation of hepatic/pancreatic stellate cell physiology as well as normalisation of the organ mechanostasis.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Authors. The Journal of Physiology © 2022 The Physiological Society.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ferdek</LastName>
            <ForeName>Pawel E</ForeName>
            <Initials>PE</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5582-6588</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cell Biology, Faculty of Biochemistry, Biophysics and Biotechnology, Jagiellonian University, Krakow, Poland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Krzysztofik</LastName>
            <ForeName>Daria</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1626-0849</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Malopolska Centre of Biotechnology, Jagiellonian University, Krakow, Poland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Stopa</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kinga B</ForeName>
            <Initials>KB</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7150-8990</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Malopolska Centre of Biotechnology, Jagiellonian University, Krakow, Poland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kusiak</LastName>
            <ForeName>Agnieszka A</ForeName>
            <Initials>AA</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cell Biology, Faculty of Biochemistry, Biophysics and Biotechnology, Jagiellonian University, Krakow, Poland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Paw</LastName>
            <ForeName>Milena</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3325-7916</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cell Biology, Faculty of Biochemistry, Biophysics and Biotechnology, Jagiellonian University, Krakow, Poland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wnuk</LastName>
            <ForeName>Dawid</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5807-2440</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cell Biology, Faculty of Biochemistry, Biophysics and Biotechnology, Jagiellonian University, Krakow, Poland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Jakubowska</LastName>
            <ForeName>Monika A</ForeName>
            <Initials>MA</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9334-3798</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Malopolska Centre of Biotechnology, Jagiellonian University, Krakow, Poland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>04</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Physiol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0266262</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0022-3751</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fibroblasts</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fibrosis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">liver</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pancreas</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">stellate cells</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>21</Hour>
          <Minute>5</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35430731</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/JP281135</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abbas, G., Silveira, M. G., &amp; Lindor, K. D. (2011). Hepatic fibrosis and the renin-angiotensin system. American Journal of Therapeutics, 18(6), e202-e208.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Acharya, P., Chouhan, K., Weiskirchen, S., &amp; Weiskirchen, R. (2021). Cellular mechanisms of liver fibrosis. Frontiers in Pharmacology, 12, 671640.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Adler, G., Hupp, T., &amp; Kern, H. F. (1979). Course and spontaneous regression of acute pancreatitis in the rat. Virchows Archiv A, Pathological Anatomy and Histology, 382(1), 31-47.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Amer, J., Salhab, A., Doron, S., Morali, G., &amp; Safadi, R. (2018). A novel flow cytometry tool for fibrosis scoring through hepatic stellate cell differentiation. Cytometry Part A: The journal of the International Society for Analytical Cytology, 93(4), 427-435.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>An, P., Wei, L. L., Zhao, S., Sverdlov, D. Y., Vaid, K. A., Miyamoto, M., Kuramitsu, K., Lai, M., &amp; Popov, Y. V. (2020). Hepatocyte mitochondria-derived danger signals directly activate hepatic stellate cells and drive progression of liver fibrosis. Nature Communication, 11(1), 2362.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aoki, H., Ohnishi, H., Hama, K., Shinozaki, S., Kita, H., Yamamoto, H., Osawa, H., Sato, K., Tamada, K., &amp; Sugano, K. (2006). Existence of autocrine loop between interleukin-6 and transforming growth factor-beta1 in activated rat pancreatic stellate cells. Journal of Cellular Biochemistry, 99(1), 221-228.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Apte, M., Pirola, R. C., &amp; Wilson, J. S. (2015). Pancreatic stellate cell: Physiologic role, role in fibrosis and cancer. Current Opinion in Gastroenterology, 31(5), 416-423.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Apte, M. V., Haber, P. S., Applegate, T. L., Norton, I. D., McCaughan, G. W., Korsten, M. A., Pirola, R. C., &amp; Wilson, J. S. (1998). Periacinar stellate shaped cells in rat pancreas: Identification, isolation, and culture. Gut, 43(1), 128-133.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Apte, M. V., Haber, P. S., Darby, S. J., Rodgers, S. C., McCaughan, G. W., Korsten, M. A., Pirola, R. C., &amp; Wilson, J. S. (1999). Pancreatic stellate cells are activated by proinflammatory cytokines: Implications for pancreatic fibrogenesis. Gut, 44(4), 534-541.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Apte, M. V., Park, S., Phillips, P. A., Santucci, N., Goldstein, D., Kumar, R. K., Ramm, G. A., Buchler, M., Friess, H., McCarroll, J. A., Keogh, G., Merrett, N., Pirola, R., &amp; Wilson, J. S. (2004). Desmoplastic reaction in pancreatic cancer: Role of pancreatic stellate cells. Pancreas, 29(3), 179-187.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Apte, M. V., Phillips, P. A., Fahmy, R. G., Darby, S. J., Rodgers, S. C., McCaughan, G. W., Korsten, M. A., Pirola, R. C., Naidoo, D., &amp; Wilson, J. S. (2000). Does alcohol directly stimulate pancreatic fibrogenesis? Studies with rat pancreatic stellate cells. Gastroenterology, 118(4), 780-794.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Armstrong, T., Packham, G., Murphy, L. B., Bateman, A. C., Conti, J. A., Fine, D. R., Johnson, C. D., Benyon, R. C., &amp; Iredale, J. P. (2004). Type I collagen promotes the malignant phenotype of pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma. Clinical Cancer Research, 10(21), 7427-7437.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Asahina, K., Zhou, B., Pu, W. T., &amp; Tsukamoto, H. (2011). Septum transversum-derived mesothelium gives rise to hepatic stellate cells and perivascular mesenchymal cells in developing mouse liver. Hepatology, 53(3), 983-995.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Athanazio, R. A., Silva Filho, L., Vergara, A. A., Ribeiro, A. F., Riedi, C. A., Procianoy, E., Adde, F. V., Reis, F. J. C., Ribeiro, J. D., Torres, L. A., Fuccio, M. B., Epifanio, M., Firmida, M. C., Damaceno, N., Ludwig-Neto, N., Maróstica, P. J. C., Rached, S. Z., &amp; Melo, S. F. O. (2017). Brazilian guidelines for the diagnosis and treatment of cystic fibrosis. Jornal Brasileiro De Pneumologia: Publicacao Oficial da Sociedade Brasileira de Pneumologia e Tisilogia, 43(3), 219-245.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bachem, M. G., Schneider, E., Gross, H., Weidenbach, H., Schmid, R. M., Menke, A., Siech, M., Beger, H., Grunert, A., &amp; Adler, G. (1998). Identification, culture, and characterization of pancreatic stellate cells in rats and humans. Gastroenterology, 115(2), 421-432.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bachem, M. G., Schunemann, M., Ramadani, M., Siech, M., Beger, H., Buck, A., Zhou, S., Schmid-Kotsas, A., &amp; Adler, G. (2005). Pancreatic carcinoma cells induce fibrosis by stimulating proliferation and matrix synthesis of stellate cells. Gastroenterology, 128(4), 907-921.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bacon, B. R. (2011). Clinical trial report: Treatment of nonalcoholic steatohepatitis with vitamin E. Current Gastroenterology Reports, 13(1), 1-2.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bai, F., Huang, Q., Nie, J., Lu, S., Lu, C., Zhu, X., Wang, Y., Zhuo, L., Lu, Z., &amp; Lin, X. (2017). Trolline ameliorates liver fibrosis by inhibiting the NF-κB pathway, promoting HSC apoptosis and suppressing autophagy. Cellular Physiology and Biochemistry, 44(2), 436-446.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bansal, R., Nagórniewicz, B., &amp; Prakash, J. (2016). Clinical advancements in the targeted therapies against liver fibrosis. Mediators of Inflammation, 2016, 7629724.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bataller, R., Ginès, P., Nicolás, J. M., Görbig, M. N., Garcia-Ramallo, E., Gasull, X., Bosch, J., Arroyo, V., &amp; Rodés, J. (2000). Angiotensin II induces contraction and proliferation of human hepatic stellate cells. Gastroenterology, 118(6), 1149-1156.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bataller, R., Nicolás, J. M., Gineès, P., Görbig, M. N., Garcia-Ramallo, E., Lario, S., Tobías, E., Pinzani, M., Thomas, A. P., Arroyo, V., &amp; Rodés, J. (1998). Contraction of human hepatic stellate cells activated in culture: A role for voltage-operated calcium channels. Journal of Hepatology, 29(3), 398-408.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bataller, R., Schwabe, R. F., Choi, Y. H., Yang, L., Paik, Y. H., Lindquist, J., Qian, T., Schoonhoven, R., Hagedorn, C. H., Lemasters, J. J., &amp; Brenner, D. A. (2003). NADPH oxidase signal transduces angiotensin II in hepatic stellate cells and is critical in hepatic fibrosis. Journal of Clinical Investigation, 112(9), 1383-1394.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Benali-Furet, N. L., Chami, M., Houel, L., De Giorgi, F., Vernejoul, F., Lagorce, D., Buscail, L., Bartenschlager, R., Ichas, F., Rizzuto, R., &amp; Paterlini-Bréchot, P. (2005). Hepatitis C virus core triggers apoptosis in liver cells by inducing ER stress and ER calcium depletion. Oncogene, 24(31), 4921-4933.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Benedetti, A., Di Sario, A., Casini, A., Ridolfi, F., Bendia, E., Pigini, P., Tonnini, C., D'Ambrosio, L., Feliciangeli, G., Macarri, G., &amp; Svegliati-Baroni, G. (2001). Inhibition of the NA(+)/H(+) exchanger reduces rat hepatic stellate cell activity and liver fibrosis: An in vitro and in vivo study. Gastroenterology, 120(2), 545-556.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bernard, K., Logsdon, N. J., Ravi, S., Xie, N., Persons, B. P., Rangarajan, S., Zmijewski, J. W., Mitra, K., Liu, G., Darley-Usmar, V. M., &amp; Thannickal, V. J. (2015). Metabolic reprogramming is required for myofibroblast contractility and differentiation. Journal of Biological Chemistry, 290(42), 25427-25438.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berumen, J., Baglieri, J., Kisseleva, T., &amp; Mekeel, K. (2021). Liver fibrosis: Pathophysiology and clinical implications. Wiley Interdisciplinary Reviews: Systems Biology and Medicine, 13, e1499.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Betapudi, B., Aleem, A., &amp; Kothadia, J. P. (2022). Cystic fibrosis and liver disease. In StatPearls. StatPearls Publishing LLC.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beyer, G., Habtezion, A., Werner, J., Lerch, M. M., &amp; Mayerle, J. (2020). Chronic pancreatitis. Lancet, 396(10249), 499-512.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bhatia, M. (2004). Apoptosis of pancreatic acinar cells in acute pancreatitis: Is it good or bad? Journal of Cellular and Molecular Medicine, 8(3), 402-409.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Botello-Smith, W. M., Jiang, W., Zhang, H., Ozkan, A. D., Lin, Y. C., Pham, C. N., Lacroix, J. J., &amp; Luo, Y. (2019). A mechanism for the activation of the mechanosensitive Piezo1 channel by the small molecule Yoda1. Nature Communication, 10(1), 4503.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boxhoorn, L., Voermans, R. P., Bouwense, S. A., Bruno, M. J., Verdonk, R. C., Boermeester, M. A., van Santvoort, H. C., &amp; Besselink, M. G. (2020). Acute pancreatitis. Lancet, 396(10252), 726-734.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Braganza, J. M., Lee, S. H., McCloy, R. F., &amp; McMahon, M. J. (2011). Chronic pancreatitis. Lancet, 377(9772), 1184-1197.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Buckley, C. D. (2021). Fibroblast cells reveal their ancestry. Nature, 593(7860), 511-512.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Buzzetti, E., Pinzani, M., &amp; Tsochatzis, E. A. (2016). The multiple-hit pathogenesis of non-alcoholic fatty liver disease (NAFLD). Metabolism, 65(8), 1038-1048.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cai, X., Li, Z., Zhang, Q., Qu, Y., Xu, M., Wan, X., &amp; Lu, L. (2018). CXCL6-EGFR-induced Kupffer cells secrete TGF-β1 promoting hepatic stellate cell activation via the SMAD2/BRD4/C-MYC/EZH2 pathway in liver fibrosis. Journal of Cellular and Molecular Medicine, 22(10), 5050-5061.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Calabro, S. R., Maczurek, A. E., Morgan, A. J., Tu, T., Wen, V. W., Yee, C., Mridha, A., Lee, M., d'Avigdor, W., Locarnini, S. A., McCaughan, G. W., Warner, F. J., McLennan, S. V., &amp; Shackel, N. A. (2014). Hepatocyte produced matrix metalloproteinases are regulated by CD147 in liver fibrogenesis. Plos One, 9(7), e90571.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Caliari, S. R., Perepelyuk, M., Cosgrove, B. D., Tsai, S. J., Lee, G. Y., Mauck, R. L., Wells, R. G., &amp; Burdick, J. A. (2016). Stiffening hydrogels for investigating the dynamics of hepatic stellate cell mechanotransduction during myofibroblast activation. Science Reports, 6(1), 21387.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cardone, R. A., Casavola, V., &amp; Reshkin, S. J. (2005). The role of disturbed pH dynamics and the Na+/H+ exchanger in metastasis. Nature Reviews Cancer, 5(10), 786-795.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Casini, A., Ceni, E., Salzano, R., Biondi, P., Parola, M., Galli, A., Foschi, M., Caligiuri, A., Pinzani, M., &amp; Surrenti, C. (1997). Neutrophil-derived superoxide anion induces lipid peroxidation and stimulates collagen synthesis in human hepatic stellate cells: Role of nitric oxide. Hepatology, 25(2), 361-367.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Casini, A., Galli, A., Pignalosa, P., Frulloni, L., Grappone, C., Milani, S., Pederzoli, P., Cavallini, G., &amp; Surrenti, C. (2000). Collagen type I synthesized by pancreatic periacinar stellate cells (PSC) co-localizes with lipid peroxidation-derived aldehydes in chronic alcoholic pancreatitis. Journal of Pathology, 192(1), 81-89.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cassiman, D., Barlow, A., Vander Borght, S., Libbrecht, L., &amp; Pachnis, V. (2006). Hepatic stellate cells do not derive from the neural crest. Journal of Hepatology, 44(6), 1098-1104.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cave, D. D., Di Guida, M., Costa, V., Sevillano, M., Ferrante, L., Heeschen, C., Corona, M., Cucciardi, A., &amp; Lonardo, E. (2020). TGF-beta1 secreted by pancreatic stellate cells promotes stemness and tumourigenicity in pancreatic cancer cells through L1CAM downregulation. Oncogene, 39(21), 4271-4285.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chang, M. L. (2016). Metabolic alterations and hepatitis C: From bench to bedside. World Journal of Gastroenterology, 22(4), 1461-1476.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cheng, Q., Li, C., Yang, C. F., Zhong, Y. J., Wu, D., Shi, L., Chen, L., Li, Y. W., &amp; Li, L. (2019). Methyl ferulic acid attenuates liver fibrosis and hepatic stellate cell activation through the TGF-β1/Smad and NOX4/ROS pathways. Chemico-Biological Interactions, 299, 131-139.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Choi, H. K., Pokharel, Y. R., Lim, S. C., Han, H. K., Ryu, C. S., Kim, S. K., Kwak, M. K., &amp; Kang, K. W. (2009). Inhibition of liver fibrosis by solubilized coenzyme Q10: Role of Nrf2 activation in inhibiting transforming growth factor-beta1 expression. Toxicology and Applied Pharmacology, 240(3), 377-384.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chronopoulos, A., Robinson, B., Sarper, M., Cortes, E., Auernheimer, V., Lachowski, D., Attwood, S., Garcia, R., Ghassemi, S., Fabry, B., &amp; Del Rio Hernandez, A. (2016). ATRA mechanically reprograms pancreatic stellate cells to suppress matrix remodelling and inhibit cancer cell invasion. Nature Communications, 7(1), 12630.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chung, S. I., Moon, H., Ju, H. L., Cho, K. J., Kim, D. Y., Han, K. H., Eun, J. W., Nam, S. W., Ribback, S., Dombrowski, F., Calvisi, D. F., &amp; Ro, S. W. (2016). Hepatic expression of Sonic Hedgehog induces liver fibrosis and promotes hepatocarcinogenesis in a transgenic mouse model. Journal of Hepatology, 64(3), 618-627.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coll, M., Perea, L., Boon, R., Leite, S. B., Vallverdú, J., Mannaerts, I., Smout, A., El Taghdouini, A., Blaya, D., Rodrigo-Torres, D., Graupera, I., Aguilar-Bravo, B., Chesne, C., Najimi, M., Sokal, E., Lozano, J. J., van Grunsven, L. A., Verfaillie, C. M., &amp; Sancho-Bru, P. (2018). Generation of hepatic stellate cells from human pluripotent stem cells enables in vitro modeling of liver fibrosis. Cell Stem Cell, 23(1), 101-113.e7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Corbett, L., Mann, J., &amp; Mann, D. A. (2015). Non-canonical wnt predominates in activated rat hepatic stellate cells, influencing HSC survival and paracrine stimulation of kupffer cells. Plos One, 10(11), e0142794.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Corey, K. E., &amp; Rinella, M. E. (2016). Medical and surgical treatment options for nonalcoholic steatohepatitis. Digestive Diseases and Sciences, 61(5), 1387-1397.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Corey, K. E., Shah, N., Misdraji, J., Abu Dayyeh, B. K., Zheng, H., Bhan, A. K., &amp; Chung, R. T. (2009). The effect of angiotensin-blocking agents on liver fibrosis in patients with hepatitis C. Liver International, 29(5), 748-753.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cortes, E., Sarper, M., Robinson, B., Lachowski, D., Chronopoulos, A., Thorpe, S. D., Lee, D. A., &amp; Del Rio Hernandez, A. E. (2019). GPER is a mechanoregulator of pancreatic stellate cells and the tumor microenvironment. Embo Reports, 20(1).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Criddle, D. N. (2015). The role of fat and alcohol in acute pancreatitis: A dangerous liaison. Pancreatology, 15(4), S6-S12.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Criscimanna, A., Speicher, J. A., Houshmand, G., Shiota, C., Prasadan, K., Ji, B., Logsdon, C. D., Gittes, G. K., &amp; Esni, F. (2011). Duct cells contribute to regeneration of endocrine and acinar cells following pancreatic damage in adult mice. Gastroenterology, 141(4), 1451-1462.e6, 1462.e1451-1456.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Czerny, C., Kholmukhamedov, A., Theruvath, T. P., Maldonado, E. N., Ramshesh, V. K., Lehnert, M., Marzi, I., Zhong, Z., &amp; Lemasters, J. J. (2012). Minocycline decreases liver injury after hemorrhagic shock and resuscitation in mice. Hpb Surgery, 2012, 259512.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dangi-Garimella, S., Krantz, S. B., Barron, M. R., Shields, M. A., Heiferman, M. J., Grippo, P. J., Bentrem, D. J., &amp; Munshi, H. G. (2011). Three-dimensional collagen I promotes gemcitabine resistance in pancreatic cancer through MT1-MMP-mediated expression of HMGA2. Cancer Research, 71(3), 1019-1028.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Das, D., Sarkar, N., Sengupta, I., Pal, A., Saha, D., Bandopadhyay, M., Das, C., Narayan, J., Singh, S. P., &amp; Chakravarty, R. (2016). Anti-viral role of toll like receptor 4 in hepatitis B virus infection: An in vitro study. World Journal of Gastroenterology, 22(47), 10341-10352.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Das, S. L., Singh, P. P., Phillips, A. R., Murphy, R., Windsor, J. A., &amp; Petrov, M. S. (2014). Newly diagnosed diabetes mellitus after acute pancreatitis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Gut, 63(5), 818-831.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Debray, D., Kelly, D., Houwen, R., Strandvik, B., &amp; Colombo, C. (2011). Best practice guidance for the diagnosis and management of cystic fibrosis-associated liver disease. Journal of Cystic Fibrosis, 10(Suppl 2), S29-S36.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deleve, L. D., Wang, X., &amp; Guo, Y. (2008). Sinusoidal endothelial cells prevent rat stellate cell activation and promote reversion to quiescence. Hepatology, 48(3), 920-930.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Demeyer, S., De Boeck, K., Witters, P., &amp; Cosaert, K. (2016). Beyond pancreatic insufficiency and liver disease in cystic fibrosis. European Journal of Pediatrics, 175(7), 881-894.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deng, C. -C., Hu, Y. -F., Zhu, D. -H., Cheng, Q., Gu, J. -J., Feng, Q. -L., Zhang, L. -X., Xu, Y. -P., Wang, D., Rong, Z., &amp; Yang, B. (2021). Single-cell RNA-seq reveals fibroblast heterogeneity and increased mesenchymal fibroblasts in human fibrotic skin diseases. Nature Communications, 12(1), 3709.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Desai, B. M., Oliver-Krasinski, J., De Leon, D. D., Farzad, C., Hong, N., Leach, S. D., &amp; Stoffers, D. A. (2007). Preexisting pancreatic acinar cells contribute to acinar cell, but not islet beta cell, regeneration. Journal of Clinical Investigation, 117(4), 971-977.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Desmoulière, A., Redard, M., Darby, I., &amp; Gabbiani, G. (1995). Apoptosis mediates the decrease in cellularity during the transition between granulation tissue and scar. American Journal of Pathology, 146, 56-66.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dewidar, B., Meyer, C., Dooley, S., &amp; Meindl-Beinker, A. N. (2019). TGF-β in hepatic stellate cell activation and liver fibrogenesis-updated 2019. Cells, 8(11), 1419.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Di Maggio, F., Arumugam, P., Delvecchio, F. R., Batista, S., Lechertier, T., Hodivala-Dilke, K., &amp; Kocher, H. M. (2016). Pancreatic stellate cells regulate blood vessel density in the stroma of pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma. Pancreatology, 16(6), 995-1004.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Di Sario, A., Bendia, E., Taffetani, S., Marzioni, M., Candelaresi, C., Pigini, P., Schindler, U., Kleemann, H. W., Trozzi, L., Macarri, G., &amp; Benedetti, A. (2003). Selective Na+/H+ exchange inhibition by cariporide reduces liver fibrosis in the rat. Hepatology, 37(2), 256-266.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dieguez-Castillo, C., Jimenez-Luna, C., Martin-Ruiz, J. L., Martinez-Galan, J., Prados, J., Torres, C., Gonzalez-Ramirez, A. R., &amp; Caba, O. (2020). Role of exocrine and endocrine insufficiency in the management of patients with chronic pancreatitis. Journal of Clinical Medicine 2014, 9.(6),</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Do, N. N., &amp; Eming, S. A. (2016). Skin fibrosis: Models and mechanisms. Current Research in Translational Medicine, 64(4), 185-193.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dong, J., Viswanathan, S., Adami, E., Singh, B. K., Chothani, S. P., Ng, B., Lim, W. W., Zhou, J., Tripathi, M., Ko, N. S. J., Shekeran, S. G., Tan, J., Lim, S. Y., Wang, M., Lio, P. M., Yen, P. M., Schafer, S., Cook, S. A., &amp; Widjaja, A. A. (2021). Hepatocyte-specific IL11 cis-signaling drives lipotoxicity and underlies the transition from NAFLD to NASH. Nature Communication, 12(1), 66.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dranoff, J. A., Ogawa, M., Kruglov, E. A., Gaca, M. D., Sevigny, J., Robson, S. C., &amp; Wells, R. G. (2004). Expression of P2Y nucleotide receptors and ectonucleotidases in quiescent and activated rat hepatic stellate cells. American Journal of Physiology Gastrointestinal and Liver Physiology, 287(2), G417-G424.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Drifka, C. R., Tod, J., Loeffler, A. G., Liu, Y., Thomas, G. J., Eliceiri, K. W., &amp; Kao, W. J. (2015). Periductal stromal collagen topology of pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma differs from that of normal and chronic pancreatitis. Modern Pathology, 28(11), 1470-1480.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Duong, H. T., Dong, Z., Su, L., Boyer, C., George, J., Davis, T. P., &amp; Wang, J. (2015). The use of nanoparticles to deliver nitric oxide to hepatic stellate cells for treating liver fibrosis and portal hypertension. Small, 11(19), 2291-2304.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Duval, M. (1889). Atlas d'embryologie. G. Masson.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dvorak, H. F. (2015). Tumors: Wounds that do not heal-redux. Cancer Immunology Research, 3(1), 1-11.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dwyer, B. J., Macmillan, M. T., Brennan, P. N., &amp; Forbes, S. J. (2021). Cell therapy for advanced liver diseases: Repair or rebuild. Journal of Hepatology, 74(1), 185-199.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Edenberg, H. J. (2007). The genetics of alcohol metabolism: Role of alcohol dehydrogenase and aldehyde dehydrogenase variants. Alcohol Research &amp; Health, 30, 5-13.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>El-Karef, A., Kaito, M., Tanaka, H., Ikeda, K., Nishioka, T., Fujita, N., Inada, H., Adachi, Y., Kawada, N., Nakajima, Y., Imanaka-Yoshida, K., &amp; Yoshida, T. (2007). Expression of large tenascin-C splice variants by hepatic stellate cells/myofibroblasts in chronic hepatitis C. Journal of Hepatology, 46(4), 664-673.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elsässer, H. P., Adler, G., &amp; Kern, H. F. (1986). Time course and cellular source of pancreatic regeneration following acute pancreatitis in the rat. Pancreas, 1(5), 421-429.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Erkan, M., Reiser-Erkan, C., Michalski, C. W., Deucker, S., Sauliunaite, D., Streit, S., Esposito, I., Friess, H., &amp; Kleeff, J. (2009). Cancer-stellate cell interactions perpetuate the hypoxia-fibrosis cycle in pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma. Neoplasia, 11(5), 497-508.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fang, Y. L., Chen, H., Wang, C. L., &amp; Liang, L. (2018). Pathogenesis of non-alcoholic fatty liver disease in children and adolescence: From “two hit theory” to “multiple hit model”. World Journal of Gastroenterology, 24(27), 2974-2983.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Farhangi, M. A., Alipour, B., Jafarvand, E., &amp; Khoshbaten, M. (2014). Oral coenzyme Q10 supplementation in patients with nonalcoholic fatty liver disease: Effects on serum vaspin, chemerin, pentraxin 3, insulin resistance and oxidative stress. Archives of Medical Research, 45(7), 589-595.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Farsi, F., Mohammadshahi, M., Alavinejad, P., Rezazadeh, A., Zarei, M., &amp; Engali, K. A. (2016). Functions of coenzyme Q10 supplementation on liver enzymes, markers of systemic inflammation, and adipokines in patients affected by nonalcoholic fatty liver disease: A double-blind, placebo-controlled, randomized clinical trial. Journal of the American College of Nutrition, 35(4), 346-353.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fels, B., Nielsen, N., &amp; Schwab, A. (2016). Role of TRPC1 channels in pressure-mediated activation of murine pancreatic stellate cells. European Biophysics Journal, 45(7), 657-670.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ferdek, P. E., &amp; Jakubowska, M. A. (2017). Biology of pancreatic stellate cells - More than pancreatic cancer. Pflugers Archiv: European Journal of Physiology, 469(9),1039-1050,</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ferdek, P. E., Jakubowska, M. A., Gerasimenko, J. V., Gerasimenko, O. V., &amp; Petersen, O. H. (2016). Bile acids induce necrosis in pancreatic stellate cells dependent on calcium entry and sodium-driven bile uptake. Journal of Physiology, 594(21), 6147-6164.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ferenci, P., Członkowska, A., Merle, U., Ferenc, S., Gromadzka, G., Yurdaydin, C., Vogel, W., Bruha, R., Schmidt, H. T., &amp; Stremmel, W. (2007). Late-onset Wilson's disease. Gastroenterology, 132(4), 1294-1298.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Foglia, B., Cannito, S., Bocca, C., Parola, M., &amp; Novo, E. (2019). ERK pathway in activated, myofibroblast-like, hepatic stellate cells: A critical signaling crossroad sustaining liver fibrosis. International Journal of Molecular Sciences, 20(11), 2700.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Friedman, S. L. (2003). Liver fibrosis - From bench to bedside. Journal of Hepatology, 38, 38-53.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Friedman, S. L. (2008). Hepatic stellate cells: Protean, multifunctional, and enigmatic cells of the liver. Physiological Reviews, 88(1), 125-172.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gabbiani, G., Ryan, G. B., &amp; Majne, G. (1971). Presence of modified fibroblasts in granulation tissue and their possible role in wound contraction. Experientia, 27(5), 549-550.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gan, C., Chen, Y. H., Liu, L., Gao, J. H., Tong, H., Tang, C. W., &amp; Liu, R. (2017). Efficacy and safety of pancreatic enzyme replacement therapy on exocrine pancreatic insufficiency: A meta-analysis. Oncotarget, 8(55), 94920-94931.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gao, R., &amp; Brigstock, D. R. (2005). Connective tissue growth factor (CCN2) in rat pancreatic stellate cell function: Integrin alpha5beta1 as a novel CCN2 receptor. Gastroenterology, 129(3), 1019-1030.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gao, T. T., Qin, Z. L., Ren, H., Zhao, P., &amp; Qi, Z. T. (2015). Inhibition of IRS-1 by hepatitis C virus infection leads to insulin resistance in a PTEN-dependent manner. Virology Journal, 12(1), 12.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ge, X., Antoine, D. J., Lu, Y., Arriazu, E., Leung, T. M., Klepper, A. L., Branch, A. D., Fiel, M. I., &amp; Nieto, N. (2014). High mobility group box-1 (HMGB1) participates in the pathogenesis of alcoholic liver disease (ALD). Journal of Biological Chemistry, 289(33), 22672-22691.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Georgescu, E. F., &amp; Georgescu, M. (2007). Therapeutic options in non-alcoholic steatohepatitis (NASH). Are all agents alike? Results of a preliminary study. Journal of Gastrointestinal and Liver Diseases: JGLD, 16, 39-46.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gerasimenko, J. V., Flowerdew, S. E., Voronina, S. G., Sukhomlin, T. K., Tepikin, A. V., Petersen, O. H., &amp; Gerasimenko, O. V. (2006). Bile acids induce Ca2+ release from both the endoplasmic reticulum and acidic intracellular calcium stores through activation of inositol trisphosphate receptors and ryanodine receptors. Journal of Biological Chemistry, 281(52), 40154-40163.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gerasimenko, J. V., Lur, G., Sherwood, M. W., Ebisui, E., Tepikin, A. V., Mikoshiba, K., Gerasimenko, O. V., &amp; Petersen, O. H. (2009). Pancreatic protease activation by alcohol metabolite depends on Ca2+ release via acid store IP3 receptors. PNAS, 106(26), 10758-10763.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gibo, J., Ito, T., Kawabe, K., Hisano, T., Inoue, M., Fujimori, N., Oono, T., Arita, Y., &amp; Nawata, H. (2005). Camostat mesilate attenuates pancreatic fibrosis via inhibition of monocytes and pancreatic stellate cells activity. Laboratory Investigation, 85(1), 75-89.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gibson-Corley, K. N., Meyerholz, D. K., &amp; Engelhardt, J. F. (2016). Pancreatic pathophysiology in cystic fibrosis. Journal of Pathology, 238(2), 311-320.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gillessen, A., &amp; Schmidt, H. H. (2020). Silymarin as supportive treatment in liver diseases: A narrative review. Advances in Therapy, 37(4), 1279-1301.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gissen, P., &amp; Arias, I. M. (2015). Structural and functional hepatocyte polarity and liver disease. Journal of Hepatology, 63(4), 1023-1037.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gómez Dumm, C. L., Semino, M. C., &amp; Gagliardino, J. J. (1990). Sequential morphological changes in pancreatic islets of spontaneously diabetic rats. Pancreas, 5(5), 533-539.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Granato, M., Zompetta, C., Vescarelli, E., Rizzello, C., Cardi, A., Valia, S., Antonelli, G., Marchese, C., Torrisi, M. R., Faggioni, A., &amp; Cirone, M. (2016). HCV derived from sera of HCV-infected patients induces pro-fibrotic effects in human primary fibroblasts by activating GLI2. Scientific Reports, 6(1), 30649.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Graus-Nunes, F., &amp; Souza-Mello, V. (2019). The renin-angiotensin system as a target to solve the riddle of endocrine pancreas homeostasis. Biomedicine &amp; Pharmacotherapy, 109, 639-645.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gryshchenko, O., Gerasimenko, J. V., Gerasimenko, O. V., &amp; Petersen, O. H. (2016a). Ca2+ signals mediated by bradykinin type 2 receptors in normal pancreatic stellate cells can be inhibited by specific Ca2+ channel blockade. Journal of Physiology, 594(2), 281-293.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gryshchenko, O., Gerasimenko, J. V., Gerasimenko, O. V., &amp; Petersen, O. H. (2016b). Calcium signalling in pancreatic stellate cells: Mechanisms and potential roles. Cell Calcium, 59(2-3), 140-144.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guixe-Muntet, S., Ortega-Ribera, M., Wang, C., Selicean, S., Andreu, I., Kechagia, J. Z., Fondevila, C., Roca-Cusachs, P., Dufour, J. F., Bosch, J., Berzigotti, A., &amp; Gracia-Sancho, J. (2020). Nuclear deformation mediates liver cell mechanosensing in cirrhosis. JHEP Reports, 2(5), 100145.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gukovskaya, A. S., Gukovsky, I., Zaninovic, V., Song, M., Sandoval, D., Gukovsky, S., &amp; Pandol, S. J. (1997). Pancreatic acinar cells produce, release, and respond to tumor necrosis factor-alpha. Role in regulating cell death and pancreatitis. Journal of Clinical Investigation, 100(7), 1853-1862.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gunawan, B., &amp; Kaplowitz, N. (2004). Clinical perspectives on xenobiotic-induced hepatotoxicity. Drug Metabolism Reviews, 36(2), 301-312.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guo, Y., Wu, X. Q., Zhang, C., Liao, Z. X., Wu, Y., Xia, Z. Y., &amp; Wang, H. (2010). Effect of indole-3-carbinol on ethanol-induced liver injury and acetaldehyde-stimulated hepatic stellate cells activation using precision-cut rat liver slices. Clinical and Experimental Pharmacology &amp; Physiology, 37, 1107-1113.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haber, P. S., Keogh, G. W., Apte, M. V., Moran, C. S., Stewart, N. L., Crawford, D. H., Pirola, R. C., McCaughan, G. W., Ramm, G. A., &amp; Wilson, J. S. (1999). Activation of pancreatic stellate cells in human and experimental pancreatic fibrosis. American Journal of Pathology, 155(4), 1087-1095.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Han, Q. J., Mu, Y. L., Zhao, H. J., Zhao, R. R., Guo, Q. J., Su, Y. H., &amp; Zhang, J. (2021). Fasudil prevents liver fibrosis via activating natural killer cells and suppressing hepatic stellate cells. World Journal of Gastroenterology, 27(24), 3581-3594.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Han, W., Chen, S., Yuan, W., Fan, Q., Tian, J., Wang, X., Chen, L., Zhang, X., Wei, W., Liu, R., Qu, J., Jiao, Y., Austin, R. H., &amp; Liu, L. (2016). Oriented collagen fibers direct tumor cell intravasation. PNAS, 113(40), 11208-11213.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hanumegowda, U. M., Copple, B. L., Shibuya, M., Malle, E., Ganey, P. E., &amp; Roth, R. A. (2003). Basement membrane and matrix metalloproteinases in monocrotaline-induced liver injury. Toxicological Sciences, 76(1), 237-246.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harjumaki, R., Pridgeon, C. S., &amp; Ingelman-Sundberg, M. (2021). CYP2E1 in alcoholic and non-alcoholic liver injury. Roles of ROS, reactive intermediates and lipid overload. International Journal of Molecular Sciences, 22(15), 8221.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hart, P. A., Bellin, M. D., Andersen, D. K., Bradley, D., Cruz-Monserrate, Z., Forsmark, C. E., Goodarzi, M. O., Habtezion, A., Korc, M., Kudva, Y. C., Pandol, S. J., Yadav, D., &amp; Chari, S. T. (2016). Type 3c (pancreatogenic) diabetes mellitus secondary to chronic pancreatitis and pancreatic cancer. The Lancet Gastroenterology and Hepatology, 1(3), 226-237.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hartmann, N., Giese, N. A., Giese, T., Poschke, I., Offringa, R., Werner, J., &amp; Ryschich, E. (2014). Prevailing role of contact guidance in intrastromal T-cell trapping in human pancreatic cancer. Clinical Cancer Research, 20(13), 3422-3433.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hayden, M. R. (2007). Islet amyloid and fibrosis in the cardiometabolic syndrome and type 2 diabetes mellitus. Journal of the Cardiometabolic Syndrome, 2(1), 70-75.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hegyi, P. (2016). Bile as a key aetiological factor of acute but not chronic pancreatitis: A possible theory revealed. Journal of Physiology, 594(21), 6073-6074.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hemmann, S., Graf, J., Roderfeld, M., &amp; Roeb, E. (2007). Expression of MMPs and TIMPs in liver fibrosis - A systematic review with special emphasis on anti-fibrotic strategies. Journal of Hepatology, 46(5), 955-975.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Henderson, N. C., Rieder, F., &amp; Wynn, T. A. (2020). Fibrosis: from mechanisms to medicines. Nature, 587(7835), 555-566.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hennigs, J. K., Seiz, O., Spiro, J., Berna, M. J., Baumann, H. J., Klose, H., &amp; Pace, A. (2011). Molecular basis of P2-receptor-mediated calcium signaling in activated pancreatic stellate cells. Pancreas, 40(5), 740-746.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hezel, A. F., Deshpande, V., Zimmerman, S. M., Contino, G., Alagesan, B., O'Dell, M. R., Rivera, L. B., Harper, J., Lonning, S., Brekken, R. A., &amp; Bardeesy, N. (2012). TGF-β and αvβ6 integrin act in a common pathway to suppress pancreatic cancer progression. Cancer Research, 72(18), 4840-4845.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hiraga, R., Kato, M., Miyagawa, S., &amp; Kamata, T. (2013). Nox4-derived ROS signaling contributes to TGF-β-induced epithelial-mesenchymal transition in pancreatic cancer cells. Anticancer Research, 33, 4431-4438.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hong, O. K., Lee, S. H., Rhee, M., Ko, S. H., Cho, J. H., Choi, Y. H., Song, K. H., Son, H. Y., &amp; Yoon, K. H. (2007). Hyperglycemia and hyperinsulinemia have additive effects on activation and proliferation of pancreatic stellate cells: Possible explanation of islet-specific fibrosis in type 2 diabetes mellitus. Journal of Cellular Biochemistry, 101(3), 665-675.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hou, W., &amp; Syn, W. K. (2018). Role of metabolism in hepatic stellate cell activation and fibrogenesis. Frontiers in Cell and Developmental Biology, 6, 150.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hu, C., Yang, J., Su, H. Y., Waldron, R. T., Zhi, M., Li, L., Xia, Q., Pandol, S. J., &amp; Lugea, A. (2019). Yes-associated protein 1 plays major roles in pancreatic stellate cell activation and fibroinflammatory responses. Frontiers in Physiology, 10, 1467.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huang, C., Gan, D., Luo, F., Wan, S., Chen, J., Wang, A., Li, B., &amp; Zhu, X. (2019). Interaction mechanisms between the NOX4/ROS and RhoA/ROCK1 signaling pathways as new anti-fibrosis targets of ursolic acid in hepatic stellate cells. Frontiers in Pharmacology, 10, 431.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huang, H., Zhang, Y., Gallegos, V., Sorrelle, N., Zaid, M. M., Toombs, J., Du, W., Wright, S., Hagopian, M., Wang, Z., Hosein, A. N., Sathe, A. A., Xing, C., Koay, E. J., Driscoll, K. E., &amp; Brekken, R. A. (2019). Targeting TGFbetaR2-mutant tumors exposes vulnerabilities to stromal TGFbeta blockade in pancreatic cancer. EMBO Molecular Medicine, 11(11), e10515.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hyun, J., Wang, S., Kim, J., Rao, K. M., Park, S. Y., Chung, I., Ha, C. S., Kim, S. W., Yun, Y. H., &amp; Jung, Y. (2016). MicroRNA-378 limits activation of hepatic stellate cells and liver fibrosis by suppressing Gli3 expression. Nature Communication, 7(1), 10993.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iansante, V., Mitry, R. R., Filippi, C., Fitzpatrick, E., &amp; Dhawan, A. (2018). Human hepatocyte transplantation for liver disease: Current status and future perspectives. Pediatric Research, 83(1-2), 232-240.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ignotz, R. A., &amp; Massagué, J. (1986). Transforming growth factor-beta stimulates the expression of fibronectin and collagen and their incorporation into the extracellular matrix. Journal of Biological Chemistry, 261(9), 4337-4345.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iimuro, Y., Nishio, T., Morimoto, T., Nitta, T., Stefanovic, B., Choi, S. K., Brenner, D. A., &amp; Yamaoka, Y. (2003). Delivery of matrix metalloproteinase-1 attenuates established liver fibrosis in the rat. Gastroenterology, 124(2), 445-458.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iizuka, M., Murata, T., Hori, M., &amp; Ozaki, H. (2011). Increased contractility of hepatic stellate cells in cirrhosis is mediated by enhanced Ca2+-dependent and Ca2+-sensitization pathways. American Journal of Physiology Gastrointestinal and Liver Physiology, 300(6), G1010-G1021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Imrie, J. R., Fagan, D. G., &amp; Sturgess, J. M. (1979). Quantitative evaluation of the development of the exocrine pancreas in cystic fibrosis and control infants. American Journal of Pathology, 95, 697-708.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Institute of Medicine (2010). Hepatitis and liver cancer: A national strategy for prevention and control of hepatitis B and C. The National Academies Press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iredale, J. P., Thompson, A., &amp; Henderson, N. C. (2013). Extracellular matrix degradation in liver fibrosis: Biochemistry and regulation. Biochimica Et Biophysica Acta, 1832(7), 876-883.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ito, T., &amp; Nemoto, M. (1952). Kupfer's cells and fat storing cells in the capillary wall of human liver. Okajimas Folia Anatomica Japonica, 24(4), 243-258.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jakubowska, M. A., Pyka, J., Michalczyk-Wetula, D., Baczynski, K., Ciesla, M., Susz, A., Ferdek, P. E., Plonka, B. K., Fiedor, L., &amp; Plonka, P. M. (2020). Electron paramagnetic resonance spectroscopy reveals alterations in the redox state of endogenous copper and iron complexes in photodynamic stress-induced ischemic mouse liver. Redox Biology, 34, 101566.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jaster, R., Sparmann, G., Emmrich, J., &amp; Liebe, S. (2002). Extracellular signal regulated kinases are key mediators of mitogenic signals in rat pancreatic stellate cells. Gut, 51(4), 579-584.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jeong, W. I., Park, O., Radaeva, S., &amp; Gao, B. (2006). STAT1 inhibits liver fibrosis in mice by inhibiting stellate cell proliferation and stimulating NK cell cytotoxicity. Hepatology, 44(6), 1441-1451.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jiang, B., Zhou, L., Lu, J., Wang, Y., Liu, C., You, L., &amp; Guo, J. (2020). Stroma-targeting therapy in pancreatic cancer: One coin with two sides? Frontiers in Oncology, 10, 576399.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jiang, J. X., Chen, X., Serizawa, N., Szyndralewiez, C., Page, P., Schröder, K., Brandes, R. P., Devaraj, S., &amp; Török, N. J. (2012). Liver fibrosis and hepatocyte apoptosis are attenuated by GKT137831, a novel NOX4/NOX1 inhibitor in vivo. Free Radical Biology &amp; Medicine, 53, 289-296.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jin, L., Gao, H., Wang, J., Yang, S., Wang, J., Liu, J., Yang, Y., Yan, T., Chen, T., Zhao, Y., &amp; He, Y. (2017). Role and regulation of autophagy and apoptosis by nitric oxide in hepatic stellate cells during acute liver failure. Liver International, 37(11), 1651-1659.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jończy, A., Lipiński, P., Ogórek, M., Starzyński, R. R., Krzysztofik, D., Bednarz, A., Krzeptowski, W., Szudzik, M., Haberkiewicz, O., Miłoń, A., Grzmil, P., &amp; Lenartowicz, M. (2019). Functional iron deficiency in toxic milk mutant mice (tx-J) despite high hepatic ferroportin: A critical role of decreased GPI-ceruloplasmin expression in liver macrophages. Metallomics, 11(6), 1079-1092.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kabir, N., Ali, H., Ateeq, M., Bertino, M. F., Shah, M. R., &amp; Franzel, L. (2014). Silymarin coated gold nanoparticles ameliorates CCl4-induced hepatic injury and cirrhosis through down regulation of hepatic stellate cells and attenuation of Kupffer cells. RSC Advances, 4(18), 9012-9020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kang, N. (2020). Mechanotransduction in liver diseases. Seminars in Liver Disease, 40, 84-90.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kanno, K., Tazuma, S., &amp; Chayama, K. (2003). AT1A-deficient mice show less severe progression of liver fibrosis induced by CCl(4). Biochemical and Biophysical Research Communications, 308(1), 177-183.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kappler, M., Espach, C., Schweiger-Kabesch, A., Lang, T., Hartl, D., Hector, A., Glasmacher, C., &amp; Griese, M. (2012). Ursodeoxycholic acid therapy in cystic fibrosis liver disease - A retrospective long-term follow-up case-control study. Alimentary Pharmacology &amp; Therapeutics, 36, 266-273.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Karaa, A., Thompson, K. J., McKillop, I. H., Clemens, M. G., &amp; Schrum, L. W. (2008). S-adenosyl-L-methionine attenuates oxidative stress and hepatic stellate cell activation in an ethanol-LPS-induced fibrotic rat model. Shock (Augusta, GA), 30(2), 197-205.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Karlmark, K. R., Weiskirchen, R., Zimmermann, H. W., Gassler, N., Ginhoux, F., Weber, C., Merad, M., Luedde, T., Trautwein, C., &amp; Tacke, F. (2009). Hepatic recruitment of the inflammatory Gr1+ monocyte subset upon liver injury promotes hepatic fibrosis. Hepatology, 50(1), 261-274.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kawaguchi, T., Yoshida, T., Harada, M., Hisamoto, T., Nagao, Y., Ide, T., Taniguchi, E., Kumemura, H., Hanada, S., Maeyama, M., Baba, S., Koga, H., Kumashiro, R., Ueno, T., Ogata, H., Yoshimura, A., &amp; Sata, M. (2004). Hepatitis C virus down-regulates insulin receptor substrates 1 and 2 through up-regulation of suppressor of cytokine signaling 3. American Journal of Pathology, 165(5), 1499-1508.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Keating, S. M., Heitman, J. D., Wu, S., Deng, X., Stramer, S. L., Kuhns, M. C., Mullen, C., Norris, P. J., &amp; Busch, M. P. (2014). Cytokine and chemokine responses in the acute phase of hepatitis B virus replication in naive and previously vaccinated blood and plasma donors. Journal of Infectious Diseases, 209(6), 845-854.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kendall, R. T., &amp; Feghali-Bostwick, C. A. (2014). Fibroblasts in fibrosis: Novel roles and mediators. Frontiers in Pharmacology, 5, 123.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kennedy, R. H., Bockman, D. E., Uscanga, L., Choux, R., Grimaud, J. A., &amp; Sarles, H. (1987). Pancreatic extracellular matrix alterations in chronic pancreatitis. Pancreas, 2(1), 61-72.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khatun, M., &amp; Ray, R. B. (2019). Mechanisms underlying hepatitis C virus-associated hepatic fibrosis. Cells, 8(10), 1249.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kiagiadaki, F., Kampa, M., Voumvouraki, A., Castanas, E., Kouroumalis, E., &amp; Notas, G. (2018). Activin-A causes Hepatic stellate cell activation via the induction of TNFα and TGFβ in Kupffer cells. Biochimica et Biophysica Acta - Molecular Basis of Disease, 1864(3), 891-899.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim, J. W., Ko, S. H., Cho, J. H., Sun, C., Hong, O. K., Lee, S. H., Kim, J. H., Lee, K. W., Kwon, H. S., Lee, J. M., Song, K. H., Son, H. Y., &amp; Yoon, K. H. (2008). Loss of beta-cells with fibrotic islet destruction in type 2 diabetes mellitus. Frontiers in Bioscience, 13, 6022-6033.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim, J. W., Park, S. Y., You, Y. H., Ham, D. S., Lee, S. H., Yang, H. K., Jeong, I. K., Ko, S. H., &amp; Yoon, K. H. (2016). Suppression of ROS production by exendin-4 in PSC attenuates the high glucose-induced islet fibrosis. Plos One, 11(12), e0163187.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kirkegård, J., Cronin-Fenton, D., Heide-Jørgensen, U., &amp; Mortensen, F. V. (2018). Acute pancreatitis and pancreatic cancer risk: A nationwide matched-cohort study in Denmark. Gastroenterology, 154(6), 1729-1736.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kisseleva, T., &amp; Brenner, D. (2021). Molecular and cellular mechanisms of liver fibrosis and its regression. Nature Reviews Gastroenterology &amp; Hepatology, 18, 151-166.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Klöppel, G. (1999). Progression from acute to chronic pancreatitis. A pathologist's view. Surgical Clinics of North America, 79(4), 801-814.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Klöppel, G., Detlefsen, S., &amp; Feyerabend, B. (2004). Fibrosis of the pancreas: the initial tissue damage and the resulting pattern. Virchows Archiv, 444(1), 1-2.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ko, S. H., Hong, O. K., Kim, J. W., Ahn, Y. B., Song, K. H., Cha, B. Y., Son, H. Y., Kim, M. J., Jeong, I. K., &amp; Yoon, K. H. (2006). High glucose increases extracellular matrix production in pancreatic stellate cells by activating the renin-angiotensin system. Journal of Cellular Biochemistry, 98(2), 343-355.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ko, S. H., Kwon, H. S., Kim, S. R., Moon, S. D., Ahn, Y. B., Song, K. H., Son, H. S., Cha, B. Y., Lee, K. W., Son, H. Y., Kang, S. K., Park, C. G., Lee, I. K., &amp; Yoon, K. H. (2004). Ramipril treatment suppresses islet fibrosis in Otsuka Long-Evans Tokushima fatty rats. Biochemical and Biophysical Research Communications, 316(1), 114-122.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kocher, H. M., Basu, B., Froeling, F. E. M., Sarker, D., Slater, S., Carlin, D., deSouza, N. M., De Paepe, K. N., Goulart, M. R., Hughes, C., Imrali, A., Roberts, R., Pawula, M., Houghton, R., Lawrence, C., Yogeswaran, Y., Mousa, K., Coetzee, C., Sasieni, P., … Propper D. J. (2020). Phase I clinical trial repurposing all-trans retinoic acid as a stromal targeting agent for pancreatic cancer. Nature Communication, 11(1), 4841.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koenig, A., Mueller, C., Hasel, C., Adler, G., &amp; Menke, A. (2006). Collagen type I induces disruption of E-cadherin-mediated cell-cell contacts and promotes proliferation of pancreatic carcinoma cells. Cancer Research, 66(9), 4662-4671.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Komar, H. M., Serpa, G., Kerscher, C., Schwoegl, E., Mace, T. A., Jin, M., Yang, M. C., Chen, C. S., Bloomston, M., Ostrowski, M. C., Hart, P. A., Conwell, D. L., &amp; Lesinski, G. B. (2017). Inhibition of Jak/STAT signaling reduces the activation of pancreatic stellate cells in vitro and limits caerulein-induced chronic pancreatitis in vivo. Science Reports, 7(1), 1787.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kondo, Y., Ueno, Y., &amp; Shimosegawa, T. (2011). Toll-like receptors signaling contributes to immunopathogenesis of HBV infection. Gastroenterology Research and Practice, 2011, 810939.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kong, P., Christia, P., &amp; Frangogiannis, N. G. (2014). The pathogenesis of cardiac fibrosis. Cellular and Molecular Life Sciences, 71(4), 549-574.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kong, S. C., Giannuzzo, A., Novak, I., &amp; Pedersen, S. F. (2014). Acid-base transport in pancreatic cancer: Molecular mechanisms and clinical potential. Biochemistry and Cell Biology, 92(6), 449-459.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Konishi, K., Izumi, R., Kato, O., Yamaguchi, A., &amp; Miyazaki, I. (1981). Experimental pancreatolithiasis in the dog. Surgery, 89, 687-691.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kopelman, H., Corey, M., Gaskin, K., Durie, P., Weizman, Z., &amp; Forstner, G. (1988). Impaired chloride secretion, as well as bicarbonate secretion, underlies the fluid secretory defect in the cystic fibrosis pancreas. Gastroenterology, 95(2), 349-355.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kopelman, H., Durie, P., Gaskin, K., Weizman, Z., &amp; Forstner, G. (1985). Pancreatic fluid secretion and protein hyperconcentration in cystic fibrosis. New England Journal of Medicine, 312(6), 329-334.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kostallari, E., Wei, B., Sicard, D., Li, J., Cooper, S. A., Gao, J., Dehankar, M., Li, Y., Cao, S., Yin, M., Tschumperlin, D. J., &amp; Shah, V. H. (2022). Stiffness is associated with hepatic stellate cell heterogeneity during liver fibrosis. American Journal of Physiology Gastrointestinal and Liver Physiology, 322(2), G234-G246.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kotlinowski, J., Hutsch, T., Czyzynska-Cichon, I., Wadowska, M., Pydyn, N., Jasztal, A., Kij, A., Dobosz, E., Lech, M., Miekus, K., Pośpiech, E., Fu, M., Jura, J., Koziel, J., &amp; Chlopicki, S. (2021). Deletion of Mcpip1 in Mcpip1(fl/fl)Alb(Cre) mice recapitulates the phenotype of human primary biliary cholangitis. Biochimica et Biophysica Acta - Molecular Basis of Disease, 1867(5), 166086.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kruglov, E. A., Correa, P. R., Arora, G., Yu, J., Nathanson, M. H., &amp; Dranoff, J. A. (2007). Molecular basis for calcium signaling in hepatic stellate cells. American Journal of Physiology Gastrointestinal and Liver Physiology, 292(4), G975-G982.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kuntze, A., Goetsch, O., Fels, B., Najder, K., Unger, A., Wilhelmi, M., Sargin, S., Schimmelpfennig, S., Neumann, I., Schwab, A., &amp; Petho, Z. (2020). Protonation of Piezo1 impairs cell-matrix interactions of pancreatic stellate cells. Frontiers in Physiology, 11, 89.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kuppe, C., Ibrahim, M. M., Kranz, J., Zhang, X., Ziegler, S., Perales-Paton, J., Jansen, J., Reimer, K. C., Smith, J. R., Dobie, R., Wilson-Kanamori, J. R., Halder, M., Xu, Y., Kabgani, N., Kaesler, N., Klaus, M., Gernhold, L., Puelles, V. G., Huber, T. B., … Kramann R. (2021). Decoding myofibroblast origins in human kidney fibrosis. Nature, 589(7841), 281-286.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kusiak, A. A., Szopa, M. D., Jakubowska, M. A., &amp; Ferdek, P. E. (2020). Signaling in the physiology and pathophysiology of pancreatic stellate cells - A brief review of recent advances. Frontiers in Physiology, 11, 78.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kutney, K., Donnola, S. B., Flask, C. A., Gubitosi-Klug, R., O'Riordan, M., McBennett, K., Sferra, T. J., &amp; Kaminski, B. (2019). Lumacaftor/ivacaftor therapy is associated with reduced hepatic steatosis in cystic fibrosis patients. World Journal of Hepatology, 11(12), 761-772.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lachowski, D., Cortes, E., Pink, D., Chronopoulos, A., Karim, S. A., J, P. M., &amp; Del Río Hernández, A. E. (2017). Substrate rigidity controls activation and durotaxis in pancreatic stellate cells. Science Reports, 7(1), 2506.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Landi, A., Weismuller, T. J., Lankisch, T. O., Santer, D. M., Tyrrell, D. L., Manns, M. P., &amp; Houghton, M. (2014). Differential serum levels of eosinophilic eotaxins in primary sclerosing cholangitis, primary biliary cirrhosis, and autoimmune hepatitis. Journal of Interferon &amp; Cytokine Research, 34, 204-214.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lardon, J., De Breuck, S., Rooman, I., Van Lommel, L., Kruhøffer, M., Orntoft, T., Schuit, F., &amp; Bouwens, L. (2004). Plasticity in the adult rat pancreas: transdifferentiation of exocrine to hepatocyte-like cells in primary culture. Hepatology, 39(6), 1499-1507.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee, E., Ryu, G. R., Ko, S. H., Ahn, Y. B., &amp; Song, K. H. (2017). A role of pancreatic stellate cells in islet fibrosis and β-cell dysfunction in type 2 diabetes mellitus. Biochemical and Biophysical Research Communications, 485(2), 328-334.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee, U. E., &amp; Friedman, S. L. (2011). Mechanisms of hepatic fibrogenesis. Best Practice &amp; Research Clinical Gastroenterology, 25, 195-206.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee, Y. A., &amp; Friedman, S. L. (2020). Stellate cells and Fibrosis. In The Liver, pp. 444-454.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li, B., Cong, M., Zhu, Y., Xiong, Y., Jin, W., Wan, Y., Zhou, Y., Ao, Y., &amp; Wang, H. (2017). Indole-3-carbinol induces apoptosis of hepatic stellate cells through K63 De-Ubiquitination of RIP1 in rats. Cellular Physiology and Biochemistry, 41(4), 1481-1490.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li, J., Bessho, K., Shivakumar, P., Mourya, R., Mohanty, S. K., Dos Santos, J. L., Miura, I. K., Porta, G., &amp; Bezerra, J. A. (2011). Th2 signals induce epithelial injury in mice and are compatible with the biliary atresia phenotype. Journal of Clinical Investigation, 121(11), 4244-4256.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li, J., Zeng, C., Zheng, B., Liu, C., Tang, M., Jiang, Y., Chang, Y., Song, W., Wang, Y., &amp; Yang, C. (2018). HMGB1-induced autophagy facilitates hepatic stellate cells activation: A new pathway in liver fibrosis. Clinical Science (London, England: 1979), 132(15), 1645-1667.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li, J. T., Liao, Z. X., Ping, J., Xu, D., &amp; Wang, H. (2008). Molecular mechanism of hepatic stellate cell activation and antifibrotic therapeutic strategies. Journal of Gastroenterology, 43(6), 419-428.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li, M., Sun, R., Xu, L., Yin, W., Chen, Y., Zheng, X., Lian, Z., Wei, H., &amp; Tian, Z. (2015). Kupffer cells support hepatitis B virus-mediated CD8+ T cell exhaustion via hepatitis B core antigen-TLR2 interactions in mice. Journal of Immunology, 195(7), 3100-3109.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li, W., Yu, X., Zhu, C., Wang, Z., Zhao, Z., Li, Y., &amp; Zhang, Y. (2019). Notum attenuates HBV-related liver fibrosis through inhibiting Wnt 5a mediated non-canonical pathways. Biological Research, 52(1), 10.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li, X., Wang, Z., Ma, Q., Xu, Q., Liu, H., Duan, W., Lei, J., Ma, J., Wang, X., Lv, S., Han, L., Li, W., Guo, J., Guo, K., Zhang, D., Wu, E., &amp; Xie, K. (2014). Sonic hedgehog paracrine signaling activates stromal cells to promote perineural invasion in pancreatic cancer. Clinical Cancer Research, 20(16), 4326-4338.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li, Y., Liu, F., Ding, F., Chen, P., &amp; Tang, M. (2015). Inhibition of liver fibrosis using vitamin A-coupled liposomes to deliver matrix metalloproteinase-2 siRNA in vitro. Molecular Medicine Reports, 12(3), 3453-3461.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li, Z., Lu, D., Jin, T., Liu, X., &amp; Hao, J. (2021). Nicotine facilitates pancreatic fibrosis by promoting activation of pancreatic stellate cells via alpha7nAChR-mediated JAK2/STAT3 signaling pathway in rats. Toxicology Letters, 349, 84-91.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lindblad, A., Glaumann, H., &amp; Strandvik, B. (1998). A two-year prospective study of the effect of ursodeoxycholic acid on urinary bile acid excretion and liver morphology in cystic fibrosis-associated liver disease. Hepatology, 27(1), 166-174.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liou, G. Y., Döppler, H., Necela, B., Krishna, M., Crawford, H. C., Raimondo, M., &amp; Storz, P. (2013). Macrophage-secreted cytokines drive pancreatic acinar-to-ductal metaplasia through NF-κB and MMPs. Journal of Cell Biology, 202(3), 563-577.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu, Y., Wen, X. M., Lui, E. L., Friedman, S. L., Cui, W., Ho, N. P., Li, L., Ye, T., Fan, S. T., &amp; Zhang, H. (2009). Therapeutic targeting of the PDGF and TGF-beta-signaling pathways in hepatic stellate cells by PTK787/ZK22258. Laboratory Investigation, 89(10), 1152-1160.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Logsdon, C. D., &amp; Ji, B. (2013). The role of protein synthesis and digestive enzymes in acinar cell injury. Nature Reviews Gastroenterology &amp; hepatology, 10, 362-370.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Long, K. B., Gladney, W. L., Tooker, G. M., Graham, K., Fraietta, J. A., &amp; Beatty, G. L. (2016). IFNγ and CCL2 cooperate to redirect tumor-infiltrating monocytes to degrade fibrosis and enhance chemotherapy efficacy in pancreatic carcinoma. Cancer Discovery, 6(4), 400-413.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Luo, J., Zhang, Z., Zeng, Y., Dong, Y., &amp; Ma, L. (2021). Co-encapsulation of collagenase type I and silibinin in chondroitin sulfate coated multilayered nanoparticles for targeted treatment of liver fibrosis. Carbohydrate Polymers, 263, 117964.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lupi, R., Del Guerra, S., Bugliani, M., Boggi, U., Mosca, F., Torri, S., Del Prato, S., &amp; Marchetti, P. (2006). The direct effects of the angiotensin-converting enzyme inhibitors, zofenoprilat and enalaprilat, on isolated human pancreatic islets. European Journal of Endocrinology, 154(2), 355-361.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Madácsy, T., Pallagi, P., &amp; Maleth, J. (2018). Cystic fibrosis of the pancreas: The role of CFTR channel in the regulation of intracellular Ca(2+) signaling and mitochondrial function in the exocrine pancreas. Frontiers in Physiology, 9, 1585.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Majno, G., Gabbiani, G., Hirschel, B. J., Ryan, G. B., &amp; Statkov, P. R. (1971). Contraction of granulation tissue in vitro: Similarity to smooth muscle. Science, 173(3996), 548-550.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Malaguarnera, G., Cataudella, E., Giordano, M., Nunnari, G., Chisari, G., &amp; Malaguarnera, M. (2012). Toxic hepatitis in occupational exposure to solvents. World Journal of Gastroenterology, 18(22), 2756-2766.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marino, C. R., Matovcik, L. M., Gorelick, F. S., &amp; Cohn, J. A. (1991). Localization of the cystic fibrosis transmembrane conductance regulator in pancreas. Journal of Clinical Investigation, 88(2), 712-716.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marrache, F., Pendyala, S., Bhagat, G., Betz, K. S., Song, Z., &amp; Wang, T. C. (2008). Role of bone marrow-derived cells in experimental chronic pancreatitis. Gut, 57(8), 1113-1120.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Masamune, A., Kikuta, K., Satoh, M., Kume, K., &amp; Shimosegawa, T. (2003). Differential roles of signaling pathways for proliferation and migration of rat pancreatic stellate cells. The Tohoku Journal of Experimental Medicine, 199(2), 69-84.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Masamune, A., Kikuta, K., Watanabe, T., Satoh, K., Hirota, M., &amp; Shimosegawa, T. (2008). Hypoxia stimulates pancreatic stellate cells to induce fibrosis and angiogenesis in pancreatic cancer. American Journal of Physiology Gastrointestinal and Liver Physiology, 295(4), G709-G717.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Masamune, A., &amp; Shimosegawa, T. (2009). Signal transduction in pancreatic stellate cells. Journal of Gastroenterology, 44(4), 249-260.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mateus Goncalves, L., Pereira, E., Werneck de Castro, J. P., Bernal-Mizrachi, E., &amp; Almaca, J. (2020). Islet pericytes convert into profibrotic myofibroblasts in a mouse model of islet vascular fibrosis. Diabetologia, 63(8), 1564-1575.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mato, J. M., Cámara, J., Fernández de Paz, J., Caballería, L., Coll, S., Caballero, A., García-Buey, L., Beltrán, J., Benita, V., Caballería, J., Solà, R., Moreno-Otero, R., Barrao, F., Martín-Duce, A., Correa, J. A., Parés, A., Barrao, E., García-Magaz, I., Puerta, J. L., … Rodés, J. (1999). S-adenosylmethionine in alcoholic liver cirrhosis: A randomized, placebo-controlled, double-blind, multicenter clinical trial. Journal of Hepatology, 30(6), 1081-1089.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McCarroll, J. A., Phillips, P. A., Kumar, R. K., Park, S., Pirola, R. C., Wilson, J. S., &amp; Apte, M. V. (2004). Pancreatic stellate cell migration: Role of the phosphatidylinositol 3-kinase(PI3-kinase) pathway. Biochemical Pharmacology, 67(6), 1215-1225.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meng, D., Li, Z., Wang, G., Ling, L., Wu, Y., &amp; Zhang, C. (2018). Carvedilol attenuates liver fibrosis by suppressing autophagy and promoting apoptosis in hepatic stellate cells. Biomedicine &amp; Pharmacotherapy, 108, 1617-1627.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mews, P., Phillips, P., Fahmy, R., Korsten, M., Pirola, R., Wilson, J., &amp; Apte, M. (2002). Pancreatic stellate cells respond to inflammatory cytokines: Potential role in chronic pancreatitis. Gut, 50(4), 535-541.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meyerholz, D. K., Stoltz, D. A., Pezzulo, A. A., &amp; Welsh, M. J. (2010). Pathology of gastrointestinal organs in a porcine model of cystic fibrosis. American Journal of Pathology, 176(3), 1377-1389.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Michalik, M., Wojcik-Pszczola, K., Paw, M., Wnuk, D., Koczurkiewicz, P., Sanak, M., Pekala, E., &amp; Madeja, Z. (2018). Fibroblast-to-myofibroblast transition in bronchial asthma. Cellular and Molecular Life Sciences, 75(21), 3943-3961.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Michalopoulos, G. K., &amp; Bhushan, B. (2021). Liver regeneration: Biological and pathological mechanisms and implications. Nature Reviews Gastroenterology &amp; Hepatology, 18, 40-55.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Michl, J., Wang, Y., Monterisi, S., Blaszczak, W., Beveridge, R., Bridges, E. M., Koth, J., Bodmer, W. F., &amp; Swietach, P. (2022). CRISPR-Cas9 screen identifies oxidative phosphorylation as essential for cancer cell survival at low extracellular pH. Cell Reports, 38(10), 110493.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mittal, M., Siddiqui, M. R., Tran, K., Reddy, S. P., &amp; Malik, A. B. (2014). Reactive oxygen species in inflammation and tissue injury. Antioxidants &amp; Redox Signaling, 20(7), 1126-1167.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mohapatra, S., Majumder, S., Smyrk, T. C., Zhang, L., Matveyenko, A., Kudva, Y. C., &amp; Chari, S. T. (2016). Diabetes mellitus is associated with an exocrine pancreatopathy: Conclusions from a review of literature. Pancreas, 45(8), 1104-1110.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muhl, L., Genove, G., Leptidis, S., Liu, J., He, L., Mocci, G., Sun, Y., Gustafsson, S., Buyandelger, B., Chivukula, I. V., Segerstolpe, A., Raschperger, E., Hansson, E. M., Bjorkegren, J. L. M., Peng, X. R., Vanlandewijck, M., Lendahl, U., &amp; Betsholtz, C. (2020). Single-cell analysis uncovers fibroblast heterogeneity and criteria for fibroblast and mural cell identification and discrimination. Nature Communication, 11(1), 3953.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Munce, D., Lim, M., &amp; Akong, K. (2020). Persistent recovery of pancreatic function in patients with cystic fibrosis after ivacaftor. Pediatric Pulmonology, 55(12), 3381-3383.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nagamoto, Y., Takayama, K., Ohashi, K., Okamoto, R., Sakurai, F., Tachibana, M., Kawabata, K., &amp; Mizuguchi, H. (2016). Transplantation of a human iPSC-derived hepatocyte sheet increases survival in mice with acute liver failure. Journal of Hepatology, 64(5), 1068-1075.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nakamura, T., Arii, S., Monden, K., Furutani, M., Takeda, Y., Imamura, M., Tominaga, M., &amp; Okada, Y. (1998). Expression of the Na+/Ca2+ exchanger emerges in hepatic stellate cells after activation in association with liver fibrosis. PNAS, 95(9), 5389-5394.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Neesse, A., Krug, S., Gress, T. M., Tuveson, D. A., &amp; Michl, P. (2013). Emerging concepts in pancreatic cancer medicine: Targeting the tumor stroma. Onco Targets Ther, 7, 33-43.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nelson, D. R., Lauwers, G. Y., Lau, J. Y., &amp; Davis, G. L. (2000). Interleukin 10 treatment reduces fibrosis in patients with chronic hepatitis C: A pilot trial of interferon nonresponders. Gastroenterology, 118(4), 655-660.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nicolas-Boluda, A., Vaquero, J., Vimeux, L., Guilbert, T., Barrin, S., Kantari-Mimoun, C., Ponzo, M., Renault, G., Deptula, P., Pogoda, K., Bucki, R., Cascone, I., Courty, J., Fouassier, L., Gazeau, F., &amp; Donnadieu, E. (2021). Tumor stiffening reversion through collagen crosslinking inhibition improves T cell migration and anti-PD-1 treatment. Elife, 10.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nielsen, N., Kondratska, K., Ruck, T., Hild, B., Kovalenko, I., Schimmelpfennig, S., Welzig, J., Sargin, S., Lindemann, O., Christian, S., Meuth, S. G., Prevarskaya, N., &amp; Schwab, A. (2017). TRPC6 channels modulate the response of pancreatic stellate cells to hypoxia. Pflugers Archiv: European Journal of Physiology, 469(12), 1567-1577.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nieto, N. (2006). Oxidative-stress and IL-6 mediate the fibrogenic effects of [corrected] Kupffer cells on stellate cells. Hepatology, 44(6), 1487-1501.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nieto, N., Friedman, S. L., Greenwel, P., &amp; Cederbaum, A. I. (1999). CYP2E1-mediated oxidative stress induces collagen type I expression in rat hepatic stellate cells. Hepatology, 30(4), 987-996.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Njoku, D. B. (2010). Suppressive and pro-inflammatory roles for IL-4 in the pathogenesis of experimental drug-induced liver injury: A review. Expert Opinion on Drug Metabolism &amp; Toxicology, 6, 519-531.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nomiyama, Y., Tashiro, M., Yamaguchi, T., Watanabe, S., Taguchi, M., Asaumi, H., Nakamura, H., &amp; Otsuki, M. (2007). High glucose activates rat pancreatic stellate cells through protein kinase C and p38 mitogen-activated protein kinase pathway. Pancreas, 34(3), 364-372.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oh, Y. J., Kim, S. M., Shin, B. C., Kim, H. L., Chung, J. H., Kim, A. J., Ro, H., Chang, J. H., Lee, H. H., Chung, W., Lee, C., &amp; Jung, J. Y. (2017). The impact of renin-angiotensin system blockade on renal outcomes and mortality in pre-dialysis patients with advanced chronic kidney disease. Plos One, 12(1), e0170874.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ohnishi, H., Miyata, T., Yasuda, H., Satoh, Y., Hanatsuka, K., Kita, H., Ohashi, A., Tamada, K., Makita, N., Iiri, T., Ueda, N., Mashima, H., &amp; Sugano, K. (2004). Distinct roles of Smad2-, Smad3-, and ERK-dependent pathways in transforming growth factor-beta1 regulation of pancreatic stellate cellular functions. Journal of Biological Chemistry, 279(10), 8873-8878.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oide, H., Tateyama, M., Wang, X. E., Hirose, M., Itatsu, T., Watanabe, S., Ochi, R., &amp; Sato, N. (1999). Activated stellate (Ito) cells possess voltage-activated calcium current. Biochimica Et Biophysica Acta, 1418(1), 158-164.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ostapoff, K. T., Cenik, B. K., Wang, M., Ye, R., Xu, X., Nugent, D., Hagopian, M. M., Topalovski, M., Rivera, L. B., Carroll, K. D., &amp; Brekken, R. A. (2014). Neutralizing murine TGFβR2 promotes a differentiated tumor cell phenotype and inhibits pancreatic cancer metastasis. Cancer Research, 74(18), 4996-5007.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ota, S., Nishimura, M., Murakami, Y., Birukawa, N. K., Yoneda, A., Nishita, H., Fujita, R., Sato, Y., Minomi, K., Kajiwara, K., Miyazaki, M., Uchiumi, M., Mikuni, S., Tamura, Y., Mizuguchi, T., Imamura, M., Meguro, M., Kimura, Y., Hirata, K., &amp; Niitsu, Y. (2016). Involvement of pancreatic stellate cells in regeneration of remnant pancreas after partial pancreatectomy. Plos One, 11(12), e0165747.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ou, H., Fu, Y., Liao, W., Zheng, C., &amp; Wu, X. (2019). Association between smoking and liver fibrosis among patients with nonalcoholic fatty liver disease. Canadian Journal of Gastroenterology &amp; Hepatology, 2019, 6028952.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ozdemir, B. C., Pentcheva-Hoang, T., Carstens, J. L., Zheng, X., Wu, C. C., Simpson, T. R., Laklai, H., Sugimoto, H., Kahlert, C., Novitskiy, S. V., De Jesus-Acosta, A., Sharma, P., Heidari, P., Mahmood, U., Chin, L., Moses, H. L., Weaver, V. M., Maitra, A., Allison, J. P., … Kalluri, R. (2014). Depletion of carcinoma-associated fibroblasts and fibrosis induces immunosuppression and accelerates pancreas cancer with reduced survival. Cancer Cell, 25(6), 719-734.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pang, T. C. Y., Wilson, J. S., &amp; Apte, M. V. (2017). Pancreatic stellate cells: What's new? Current Opinion in Gastroenterology, 33(5), 366-373.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pardali, K., &amp; Moustakas, A. (2007). Actions of TGF-beta as tumor suppressor and pro-metastatic factor in human cancer. Biochimica Et Biophysica Acta, 1775, 21-62.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Park, S., In Hwang, S., Kim, J., Hwang, S., Kang, S., Yang, S., Kim, J., Kang, W., Kim, K. H., Han, D. W., &amp; Paik, Y. H. (2019). The therapeutic potential of induced hepatocyte-like cells generated by direct reprogramming on hepatic fibrosis. Current Stem Cell Research &amp; Therapy, 10, 21.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Park, W., Chawla, A., &amp; O'Reilly, E. M. (2021). Pancreatic cancer: A review. Jama, 326(9), 851-862.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parvaiz, F., Manzoor, S., Iqbal, J., McRae, S., Javed, F., Ahmed, Q. L., &amp; Waris, G. (2014). Hepatitis C virus nonstructural protein 5A favors upregulation of gluconeogenic and lipogenic gene expression leading towards insulin resistance: A metabolic syndrome. Archives of Virology, 159(5), 1017-1025.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Patel, A. G., Toyama, M. T., Alvarez, C., Nguyen, T. N., Reber, P. U., Ashley, S. W., &amp; Reber, H. A. (1995). Pancreatic interstitial pH in human and feline chronic pancreatitis. Gastroenterology, 109(5), 1639-1645.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paulo, J. A., Kadiyala, V., Banks, P. A., Conwell, D. L., &amp; Steen, H. (2013). Mass spectrometry-based quantitative proteomic profiling of human pancreatic and hepatic stellate cell lines. Genomics, Proteomics &amp; Bioinformatics, 11, 105-113.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peana, A. T., Sánchez-Catalán, M. J., Hipólito, L., Rosas, M., Porru, S., Bennardini, F., Romualdi, P., Caputi, F. F., Candeletti, S., Polache, A., Granero, L., &amp; Acquas, E. (2017). Mystic acetaldehyde: The never-ending story on alcoholism. Frontiers in Behavioral Neuroscience, 11, 81.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pereira Tde, A., Witek, R. P., Syn, W. K., Choi, S. S., Bradrick, S., Karaca, G. F., Agboola, K. M., Jung, Y., Omenetti, A., Moylan, C. A., Yang, L., Fernandez-Zapico, M. E., Jhaveri, R., Shah, V. H., Pereira, F. E., &amp; Diehl, A. M. (2010). Viral factors induce Hedgehog pathway activation in humans with viral hepatitis, cirrhosis, and hepatocellular carcinoma. Laboratory Investigation, 90(12), 1690-1703.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Perillo, B., Di Donato, M., Pezone, A., Di Zazzo, E., Giovannelli, P., Galasso, G., Castoria, G., &amp; Migliaccio, A. (2020). ROS in cancer therapy: The bright side of the moon. Experimental &amp; Molecular Medicine, 52, 192-203.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Petersen, O. H. (2014). Calcium signalling and secretory epithelia. Cell Calcium, 55(6), 282-289.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Petersen, O. H., Gerasimenko, J. V., Gerasimenko, O. V., Gryshchenko, O., &amp; Peng, S. (2021). The roles of calcium and ATP in the physiology and pathology of the exocrine pancreas. Physiological Reviews, 101(4), 1691-1744.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Petrasek, J., Iracheta-Vellve, A., Csak, T., Satishchandran, A., Kodys, K., Kurt-Jones, E. A., Fitzgerald, K. A., &amp; Szabo, G. (2013). STING-IRF3 pathway links endoplasmic reticulum stress with hepatocyte apoptosis in early alcoholic liver disease. PNAS, 110(41), 16544-16549.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Petrov, V. V., Fagard, R. H., &amp; Lijnen, P. J. (2002). Stimulation of collagen production by transforming growth factor-beta1 during differentiation of cardiac fibroblasts to myofibroblasts. Hypertension, 39(2), 258-263.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Petta, S., Eslam, M., Valenti, L., Bugianesi, E., Barbara, M., Cammà, C., Porzio, M., Rosso, C., Fargion, S., George, J., &amp; Craxì, A. (2017). Metabolic syndrome and severity of fibrosis in nonalcoholic fatty liver disease: An age-dependent risk profiling study. Liver International, 37(9), 1389-1396.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Phillips, P. A., McCarroll, J. A., Park, S., Wu, M. J., Pirola, R., Korsten, M., Wilson, J. S., &amp; Apte, M. V. (2003). Rat pancreatic stellate cells secrete matrix metalloproteinases: Implications for extracellular matrix turnover. Gut, 52(2), 275-282.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Piao, J., Jeong, J., Jung, J., Yoo, K., &amp; Hong, H. S. (2019). Substance P promotes liver sinusoidal endothelium-mediated hepatic regeneration by NO/HGF regulation. Journal of Interferon &amp; Cytokine Research, 39, 147-154.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Poilil Surendran, S., George Thomas, R., Moon, M. J., &amp; Jeong, Y. Y. (2017). Nanoparticles for the treatment of liver fibrosis. International Journal of Nanomedicine, 12, 6997-7006.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Poniachik, J., Baraona, E., Zhao, J., &amp; Lieber, C. S. (1999). Dilinoleoylphosphatidylcholine decreases hepatic stellate cell activation. Journal of Laboratory and Clinical Medicine, 133(4), 342-348.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Poulsen, J. H., Fischer, H., Illek, B., &amp; Machen, T. E. (1994). Bicarbonate conductance and pH regulatory capability of cystic fibrosis transmembrane conductance regulator. PNAS, 91(12), 5340-5344.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Povero, D., Pinatel, E. M., Leszczynska, A., Goyal, N. P., Nishio, T., Kim, J., Kneiber, D., de Araujo Horcel, L., Eguchi, A., Ordonez, P. M., Kisseleva, T., &amp; Feldstein, A. E. (2019). Human induced pluripotent stem cell-derived extracellular vesicles reduce hepatic stellate cell activation and liver fibrosis. JCI Insight, 5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Provenzano, P. P., Cuevas, C., Chang, A. E., Goel, V. K., Von Hoff, D. D., &amp; Hingorani, S. R. (2012). Enzymatic targeting of the stroma ablates physical barriers to treatment of pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma. Cancer Cell, 21(3), 418-429.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Przybyłkowski, A., Szeligowska, J., Januszewicz, M., Raszeja-Wyszomirska, J., Szczepankiewicz, B., Nehring, P., Górnicka, B., Litwin, T., &amp; Członkowska, A. (2021). Evaluation of liver fibrosis in patients with Wilson's disease. European Journal of Gastroenterology &amp; Hepatology, 33, 535-540.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Qadri, I., Iwahashi, M., Capasso, J. M., Hopken, M. W., Flores, S., Schaack, J., &amp; Simon, F. R. (2004). Induced oxidative stress and activated expression of manganese superoxide dismutase during hepatitis C virus replication: Role of JNK, p38 MAPK and AP-1. Biochemical Journal, 378(3), 919-928.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ramachandran, P., &amp; Iredale, J. P. (2009). Reversibility of liver fibrosis. Annals of Hepatology, 8(4), 283-291.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ramli, M. N. B., Lim, Y. S., Koe, C. T., Demircioglu, D., Tng, W., Gonzales, K. A. U., Tan, C. P., Szczerbinska, I., Liang, H., Soe, E. L., Lu, Z., Ariyachet, C., Yu, K. M., Koh, S. H., Yaw, L. P., Jumat, N. H. B., Lim, J. S. Y., Wright, G., Shabbir, A., … Chan, Y. S. (2020). Human pluripotent stem cell-derived organoids as models of liver disease. Gastroenterology, 159(4), 1471-1486.e12.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rankin, M. M., &amp; Kushner, J. A. (2009). Adaptive beta-cell proliferation is severely restricted with advanced age. Diabetes, 58(6), 1365-1372.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rehm, J., Kanteres, F., &amp; Lachenmeier, D. W. (2010). Unrecorded consumption, quality of alcohol and health consequences. Drug and Alcohol Review, 29(4), 426-436.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reshkin, S. J., Bellizzi, A., Caldeira, S., Albarani, V., Malanchi, I., Poignee, M., Alunni-Fabbroni, M., Casavola, V., &amp; Tommasino, M. (2000). Na+/H+ exchanger-dependent intracellular alkalinization is an early event in malignant transformation and plays an essential role in the development of subsequent transformation-associated phenotypes. Faseb Journal, 14(14), 2185-2197.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rhim, A. D., Oberstein, P. E., Thomas, D. H., Mirek, E. T., Palermo, C. F., Sastra, S. A., Dekleva, E. N., Saunders, T., Becerra, C. P., Tattersall, I. W., Westphalen, C. B., Kitajewski, J., Fernandez-Barrena, M. G., Fernandez-Zapico, M. E., Iacobuzio-Donahue, C., Olive, K. P., &amp; Stanger, B. Z. (2014). Stromal elements act to restrain, rather than support, pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma. Cancer Cell, 25(6), 735-747.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rinderknecht, H. (1986). Activation of pancreatic zymogens. Normal activation, premature intrapancreatic activation, protective mechanisms against inappropriate activation. Digestive Diseases and Sciences, 31(3), 314-321.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Riopel, M. M., Li, J., Liu, S., Leask, A., &amp; Wang, R. (2013). β1 integrin-extracellular matrix interactions are essential for maintaining exocrine pancreas architecture and function. Laboratory Investigation, 93(1), 31-40.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Robert, S., Gicquel, T., Bodin, A., Lagente, V., &amp; Boichot, E. (2016). Characterization of the MMP/TIMP imbalance and collagen production induced by IL-1β or TNF-α release from human hepatic stellate cells. Plos One, 11(4), e0153118.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roberts, A. B., Sporn, M. B., Assoian, R. K., Smith, J. M., Roche, N. S., Wakefield, L. M., Heine, U. I., Liotta, L. A., Falanga, V., &amp; Kehrl, J. H. (1986). Transforming growth factor type beta: Rapid induction of fibrosis and angiogenesis in vivo and stimulation of collagen formation in vitro. PNAS, 83(12), 4167-4171.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Robles, L., Vaziri, N. D., Li, S., Masuda, Y., Takasu, C., Takasu, M., Vo, K., Farzaneh, S. H., Stamos, M. J., &amp; Ichii, H. (2014). Dimethyl fumarate protects pancreatic islet cells and non-endocrine tissue in L-arginine-induced chronic pancreatitis. Plos One, 9(9), e107111.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rodrigues, M., Kosaric, N., Bonham, C. A., &amp; Gurtner, G. C. (2019). Wound healing: A cellular perspective. Physiological Reviews, 99(1), 665-706.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roehlen, N., Crouchet, E., &amp; Baumert, T. F. (2020). Liver fibrosis: Mechanistic concepts and therapeutic perspectives. Cells, 9(4), 875.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ryu, G. R., Lee, E., Chun, H. J., Yoon, K. H., Ko, S. H., Ahn, Y. B., &amp; Song, K. H. (2013). Oxidative stress plays a role in high glucose-induced activation of pancreatic stellate cells. Biochemical and Biophysical Research Communications, 439(2), 258-263.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sancho-Bru, P., &amp; Ginès, P. (2016). Targeting the renin-angiotensin system in liver fibrosis. Hepatology International, 10(5), 730-732.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sankaran, S. J., Xiao, A. Y., Wu, L. M., Windsor, J. A., Forsmark, C. E., &amp; Petrov, M. S. (2015). Frequency of progression from acute to chronic pancreatitis and risk factors: A meta-analysis. Gastroenterology, 149(6), 1490-1500.e1491.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sanyal, A. J., Chalasani, N., Kowdley, K. V., McCullough, A., Diehl, A. M., Bass, N. M., Neuschwander-Tetri, B. A., Lavine, J. E., Tonascia, J., Unalp, A., Van Natta, M., Clark, J., Brunt, E. M., Kleiner, D. E., Hoofnagle, J. H., &amp; Robuck, P. R. (2010). Pioglitazone, vitamin E, or placebo for nonalcoholic steatohepatitis. New England Journal of Medicine, 362(18), 1675-1685.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sasaki, R., Devhare, P. B., Steele, R., Ray, R., &amp; Ray, R. B. (2017). Hepatitis C virus-induced CCL5 secretion from macrophages activates hepatic stellate cells. Hepatology, 66(3), 746-757.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scaffidi, P., Misteli, T., &amp; Bianchi, M. E. (2002). Release of chromatin protein HMGB1 by necrotic cells triggers inflammation. Nature, 418(6894), 191-195.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scarlett, C. J., Colvin, E. K., Pinese, M., Chang, D. K., Morey, A. L., Musgrove, E. A., Pajic, M., Apte, M., Henshall, S. M., Sutherland, R. L., Kench, J. G., &amp; Biankin, A. V. (2011). Recruitment and activation of pancreatic stellate cells from the bone marrow in pancreatic cancer: a model of tumor-host interaction. Plos One, 6(10), e26088.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schneider, E., Schmid-Kotsas, A., Zhao, J., Weidenbach, H., Schmid, R. M., Menke, A., Adler, G., Waltenberger, J., Grunert, A., &amp; Bachem, M. G. (2001). Identification of mediators stimulating proliferation and matrix synthesis of rat pancreatic stellate cells. American Journal of Physiology Cell Physiology, 281(2), C532-C543.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schwabe, R. F., Tabas, I., &amp; Pajvani, U. B. (2020). Mechanisms of fibrosis development in nonalcoholic steatohepatitis. Gastroenterology, 158(7), 1913-1928.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sebastiani, G., Gkouvatsos, K., &amp; Pantopoulos, K. (2014). Chronic hepatitis C and liver fibrosis. World Journal of Gastroenterology, 20(32), 11033-11053.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Seitz, H. K., Bataller, R., Cortez-Pinto, H., Gao, B., Gual, A., Lackner, C., Mathurin, P., Mueller, S., Szabo, G., &amp; Tsukamoto, H. (2018). Alcoholic liver disease. Nature Reviews Disease Primers, 4(1), 16.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Serini, G., Bochaton-Piallat, M. L., Ropraz, P., Geinoz, A., Borsi, L., Zardi, L., &amp; Gabbiani, G. (1998). The fibronectin domain ED-A is crucial for myofibroblastic phenotype induction by transforming growth factor-beta1. Journal of Cell Biology, 142(3), 873-881.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shen, C. N., Slack, J. M., &amp; Tosh, D. (2000). Molecular basis of transdifferentiation of pancreas to liver. Nature Cell Biology, 2(12), 879-887.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sherman, M. H., Yu, R. T., Engle, D. D., Ding, N., Atkins, A. R., Tiriac, H., Collisson, E. A., Connor, F., Van Dyke, T., Kozlov, S., Martin, P., Tseng, T. W., Dawson, D. W., Donahue, T. R., Masamune, A., Shimosegawa, T., Apte, M. V., Wilson, J. S., Ng, B., … Evans, R. M. (2014). Vitamin D receptor-mediated stromal reprogramming suppresses pancreatitis and enhances pancreatic cancer therapy. Cell, 159(1), 80-93.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shields, M. A., Dangi-Garimella, S., Krantz, S. B., Bentrem, D. J., &amp; Munshi, H. G. (2011). Pancreatic cancer cells respond to type I collagen by inducing snail expression to promote membrane type 1 matrix metalloproteinase-dependent collagen invasion. Journal of Biological Chemistry, 286(12), 10495-10504.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shields, M. A., Dangi-Garimella, S., Redig, A. J., &amp; Munshi, H. G. (2012). Biochemical role of the collagen-rich tumour microenvironment in pancreatic cancer progression. Biochemical Journal, 441(2), 541-552.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shih, H. P., Wang, A., &amp; Sander, M. (2013). Pancreas organogenesis: From lineage determination to morphogenesis. Annual Review of Cell and Developmental Biology, 29(1), 81-105.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shim, J. H., Yu, J. S., Chung, J. J., Kim, J. H., &amp; Kim, K. W. (2011). Segmental difference of the hepatic fibrosis from chronic viral hepatitis due to hepatitis B versus C virus infection: Comparison using dual contrast material-enhanced MRI. Korean Journal of Radiology, 12(4), 431-438.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shrivastava, S., Mukherjee, A., Ray, R., &amp; Ray, R. B. (2013). Hepatitis C virus induces interleukin-1β (IL-1β)/IL-18 in circulatory and resident liver macrophages. Journal of Virology, 87(22), 12284-12290.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Si-Tayeb, K., Lemaigre, F. P., &amp; Duncan, S. A. (2010). Organogenesis and development of the liver. Developmental Cell, 18(2), 175-189.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sparmann, G., Kruse, M. L., Hofmeister-Mielke, N., Koczan, D., Jaster, R., Liebe, S., Wolff, D., &amp; Emmrich, J. (2010). Bone marrow-derived pancreatic stellate cells in rats. Cell Research, 20(3), 288-298.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stassen, O., Ristori, T., &amp; Sahlgren, C. M. (2020). Notch in mechanotransduction - From molecular mechanosensitivity to tissue mechanostasis. Journal of Cell Science, 133.(24),</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stock, C., &amp; Pedersen, S. F. (2017). Roles of pH and the Na(+)/H(+) exchanger NHE1 in cancer: From cell biology and animal models to an emerging translational perspective? Seminars in Cancer Biology, 43, 5-16.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stopa, K. B., Kusiak, A. A., Szopa, M. D., Ferdek, P. E., &amp; Jakubowska, M. A. (2020). Pancreatic cancer and its microenvironment-recent advances and current controversies. International Journal of Molecular Sciences, 21(9), 3218.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sturgess, J. M. (1984). Structural and developmental abnormalities of the exocrine pancreas in cystic fibrosis. Journal of Pediatric Gastroenterology and Nutrition, 3(Suppl 1), S55-S66.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Suda, K., Akai, J., &amp; Nakamura, T. (1993). Pancreatic fibrosis in patients with alcoholic dependence syndrome. Archives of Pathology &amp; Laboratory Medicine, 117, 1013-1016.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sun, Q. F., Ding, J. G., Wang, X. F., Fu, R. Q., Yang, J. X., Hong, L., Xu, X. J., Wang, J. R., Wu, J. G., &amp; Xu, D. Z. (2010). Efficacy and safety of intravenous stronger neo-minophagen C and S-adenosyl-L-methionine in treatment of pregnant woman with chronic hepatitis B: A pilot study. Medical Science Monitor, 16, Pr9-14.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Svegliati-Baroni, G., Saccomanno, S., van Goor, H., Jansen, P., Benedetti, A., &amp; Moshage, H. (2001). Involvement of reactive oxygen species and nitric oxide radicals in activation and proliferation of rat hepatic stellate cells. Liver, 21(1), 1-12.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swietach, P., Vaughan-Jones, R. D., Harris, A. L., &amp; Hulikova, A. (2014). The chemistry, physiology and pathology of pH in cancer. Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society of London Series B: Biological Sciences, 369(1638), 20130099.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tahkola, K., Ahtiainen, M., Mecklin, J. P., Kellokumpu, I., Laukkarinen, J., Tammi, M., Tammi, R., Väyrynen, J. P., &amp; Böhm, J. (2021). Stromal hyaluronan accumulation is associated with low immune response and poor prognosis in pancreatic cancer. Science Reports, 11(1), 12216.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Takahara, T., Furui, K., Yata, Y., Jin, B., Zhang, L. P., Nambu, S., Sato, H., Seiki, M., &amp; Watanabe, A. (1997). Dual expression of matrix metalloproteinase-2 and membrane-type 1-matrix metalloproteinase in fibrotic human livers. Hepatology, 26(6), 1521-1529.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tanwar, S., Rhodes, F., Srivastava, A., Trembling, P. M., &amp; Rosenberg, W. M. (2020). Inflammation and fibrosis in chronic liver diseases including non-alcoholic fatty liver disease and hepatitis C. World Journal of Gastroenterology, 26(2), 109-133.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Teli, M. R., Day, C. P., Burt, A. D., Bennett, M. K., &amp; James, O. F. (1995). Determinants of progression to cirrhosis or fibrosis in pure alcoholic fatty liver. Lancet, 346(8981), 987-990.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Teta, M., Long, S. Y., Wartschow, L. M., Rankin, M. M., &amp; Kushner, J. A. (2005). Very slow turnover of beta-cells in aged adult mice. Diabetes, 54(9), 2557-2567.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thannickal, V. J., Toews, G. B., White, E. S., Lynch, J. P., 3rd, &amp; Martinez, F. J. (2004). Mechanisms of pulmonary fibrosis. Annual Review of Medicine, 55(1), 395-417.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thapa, M., Chinnadurai, R., Velazquez, V. M., Tedesco, D., Elrod, E., Han, J. H., Sharma, P., Ibegbu, C., Gewirtz, A., Anania, F., Pulendran, B., Suthar, M. S., &amp; Grakoui, A. (2015). Liver fibrosis occurs through dysregulation of MyD88-dependent innate B-cell activity. Hepatology, 61(6), 2067-2079.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thomas, D., &amp; Radhakrishnan, P. (2019). Tumor-stromal crosstalk in pancreatic cancer and tissue fibrosis. Molecular cancer, 18(1), 14.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tomasek, J. J., Gabbiani, G., Hinz, B., Chaponnier, C., &amp; Brown, R. A. (2002). Myofibroblasts and mechano-regulation of connective tissue remodelling. Nature Reviews Molecular Cell Biology, 3(5), 349-363.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tschen, S. I., Dhawan, S., Gurlo, T., &amp; Bhushan, A. (2009). Age-dependent decline in beta-cell proliferation restricts the capacity of beta-cell regeneration in mice. Diabetes, 58(6), 1312-1320.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tschumperlin, D. J., Ligresti, G., Hilscher, M. B., &amp; Shah, V. H. (2018). Mechanosensing and fibrosis. Journal of Clinical Investigation, 128(1), 74-84.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tuncer, I., Ozbek, H., Ugras, S., &amp; Bayram, I. (2003). Anti-fibrogenic effects of captopril and candesartan cilexetil on the hepatic fibrosis development in rat. The effect of AT1-R blocker on the hepatic fibrosis. Experimental and Toxicologic Pathology, 55, 159-166.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tune, J. D., Goodwill, A. G., Sassoon, D. J., &amp; Mather, K. J. (2017). Cardiovascular consequences of metabolic syndrome. Translational Research, 183, 57-70.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ufuk, A., Garner, T., Stevens, A., &amp; Latif, A. (2022). Monocarboxylate transporters are involved in extracellular matrix remodelling in pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma. Cancers (Basel), 14(5), 1298.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Van Cutsem, E., Tempero, M. A., Sigal, D., Oh, D. Y., Fazio, N., Macarulla, T., Hitre, E., Hammel, P., Hendifar, A. E., Bates, S. E., Li, C. P., Hingorani, S. R., de la Fouchardiere, C., Kasi, A., Heinemann, V., Maraveyas, A., Bahary, N., Layos, L., Sahai, V., … Bullock, A. J. (2020). Randomized phase III trial of pegvorhyaluronidase alfa with nab-paclitaxel plus gemcitabine for patients with hyaluronan-high metastatic pancreatic adenocarcinoma. Journal of Clinical Oncology, 38(27), 3185-3194.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van de Peppel, I. P., Doktorova, M., Berkers, G., de Jonge, H. R., Houwen, R. H. J., Verkade, H. J., Jonker, J. W., &amp; Bodewes, F. (2019). IVACAFTOR restores FGF19 regulated bile acid homeostasis in cystic fibrosis patients with an S1251N or a G551D gating mutation. Journal of Cystic Fibrosis, 18(2), 286-293.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van Geenen, E. J., Smits, M. M., Schreuder, T. C., van der Peet, D. L., Bloemena, E., &amp; Mulder, C. J. (2011). Smoking is related to pancreatic fibrosis in humans. American Journal of Gastroenterology, 106(6), 1161-1166; quiz 1167.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Van Lint, P., Wielockx, B., Puimège, L., Noël, A., López-Otin, C., &amp; Libert, C. (2005). Resistance of collagenase-2 (matrix metalloproteinase-8)-deficient mice to TNF-induced lethal hepatitis. Journal of Immunology, 175(11), 7642-7649.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Van Linthout, S., Miteva, K., &amp; Tschope, C. (2014). Crosstalk between fibroblasts and inflammatory cells. Cardiovascular Research, 102(2), 258-269.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Virchow, R. (1858). Die cellularpathologie in ihrer begrundung auf physiologische und pathologische gewebelehre. August Hirschwald.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vonlaufen, A., Phillips, P. A., Xu, Z., Zhang, X., Yang, L., Pirola, R. C., Wilson, J. S., &amp; Apte, M. V. (2011). Withdrawal of alcohol promotes regression while continued alcohol intake promotes persistence of LPS-induced pancreatic injury in alcohol-fed rats. Gut, 60(2), 238-246.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang, L., Liu, X., Zhou, Q., Sui, M., Lu, Z., Zhou, Z., Tang, J., Miao, Y., Zheng, M., Wang, W., &amp; Shen, Y. (2017). Terminating the criminal collaboration in pancreatic cancer: Nanoparticle-based synergistic therapy for overcoming fibroblast-induced drug resistance. Biomaterials, 144, 105-118.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Watari, N., Hotta, Y., &amp; Mabuchi, Y. (1982). Morphological studies on a vitamin A-storing cell and its complex with macrophage observed in mouse pancreatic tissues following excess vitamin A administration. Okajimas Folia Anatomica Japonica, 58(4-6), 837-857.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weiss, F. U., Laemmerhirt, F., &amp; Lerch, M. M. (2019). Etiology and risk factors of acute and chronic pancreatitis. Visceral Medicine, 35(2), 73-81.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weng, H., Mertens, P. R., Gressner, A. M., &amp; Dooley, S. (2007). IFN-gamma abrogates profibrogenic TGF-beta signaling in liver by targeting expression of inhibitory and receptor Smads. Journal of Hepatology, 46(2), 295-303.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weng, H. L., Feng, D. C., Radaeva, S., Kong, X. N., Wang, L., Liu, Y., Li, Q., Shen, H., Gao, Y. P., Müllenbach, R., Munker, S., Huang, T., Chen, J. L., Zimmer, V., Lammert, F., Mertens, P. R., Cai, W. M., Dooley, S., &amp; Gao, B. (2013). IFN-γ inhibits liver progenitor cell proliferation in HBV-infected patients and in 3,5-diethoxycarbonyl-1,4-dihydrocollidine diet-fed mice. Journal of Hepatology, 59(4), 738-745.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Werner, C. M., &amp; Böhm, M. (2008). The therapeutic role of RAS blockade in chronic heart failure. Therapeutic Advances in Cardiovascular Disease, 2(3), 167-177.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Whatcott, C. J., Diep, C. H., Jiang, P., Watanabe, A., LoBello, J., Sima, C., Hostetter, G., Shepard, H. M., Von Hoff, D. D., &amp; Han, H. (2015). Desmoplasia in primary tumors and metastatic lesions of pancreatic cancer. Clinical Cancer Research, 21(15), 3561-3568.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Whitcomb, D. C., Gorry, M. C., Preston, R. A., Furey, W., Sossenheimer, M. J., Ulrich, C. D., Martin, S. P., Gates, L. K., Jr., Amann, S. T., Toskes, P. P., Liddle, R., McGrath, K., Uomo, G., Post, J. C., &amp; Ehrlich, G. D. (1996). Hereditary pancreatitis is caused by a mutation in the cationic trypsinogen gene. Nature Genetics, 14(2), 141-145.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wilschanski, M., &amp; Novak, I. (2013). The cystic fibrosis of exocrine pancreas. Cold Spring Harbor Perspectives in Medicine, 3(5), a009746.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Witt, H., Luck, W., Hennies, H. C., Classen, M., Kage, A., Lass, U., Landt, O., &amp; Becker, M. (2000). Mutations in the gene encoding the serine protease inhibitor, Kazal type 1 are associated with chronic pancreatitis. Nature Genetics, 25(2), 213-216.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wobser, H., Dorn, C., Weiss, T. S., Amann, T., Bollheimer, C., Büttner, R., Schölmerich, J., &amp; Hellerbrand, C. (2009). Lipid accumulation in hepatocytes induces fibrogenic activation of hepatic stellate cells. Cell Research, 19(8), 996-1005.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Won, J. H., Zhang, Y., Ji, B., Logsdon, C. D., &amp; Yule, D. I. (2011). Phenotypic changes in mouse pancreatic stellate cell Ca2+ signaling events following activation in culture and in a disease model of pancreatitis. Molecular Biology of the Cell, 22(3), 421-436.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>World Health Organization (2021). Hepatitis C, World Health Organization.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu, X., Shu, L., Zhang, Z., Li, J., Zong, J., Cheong, L. Y., Ye, D., Lam, K. S. L., Song, E., Wang, C., Xu, A., &amp; Hoo, R. L. C. (2021). Adipocyte fatty acid binding protein promotes the onset and progression of liver fibrosis via mediating the crosstalk between liver sinusoidal endothelial cells and hepatic stellate cells. Advancement of Science (Weinh), 8, e2003721.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wynn, T. A. (2007). Common and unique mechanisms regulate fibrosis in various fibroproliferative diseases. Journal of Clinical Investigation, 117(3), 524-529.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xiao, A. Y., Tan, M. L., Wu, L. M., Asrani, V. M., Windsor, J. A., Yadav, D., &amp; Petrov, M. S. (2016). Global incidence and mortality of pancreatic diseases: A systematic review, meta-analysis, and meta-regression of population-based cohort studies. The Lancet Gastroenterology and Hepatology, 1(1), 45-55.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yamada, S., Fuchs, B. C., Fujii, T., Shimoyama, Y., Sugimoto, H., Nomoto, S., Takeda, S., Tanabe, K. K., Kodera, Y., &amp; Nakao, A. (2013). Epithelial-to-mesenchymal transition predicts prognosis of pancreatic cancer. Surgery, 154(5), 946-954.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yan, B., Cheng, L., Jiang, Z., Chen, K., Zhou, C., Sun, L., Cao, J., Qian, W., Li, J., Shan, T., Lei, J., Ma, Q., &amp; Ma, J. (2018). Resveratrol inhibits ROS-promoted activation and glycolysis of pancreatic stellate cells via suppression of miR-21. Oxidative Medicine and Cellular Longevity, 2018, 1346958.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang, L., Bataller, R., Dulyx, J., Coffman, T. M., Ginès, P., Rippe, R. A., &amp; Brenner, D. A. (2005). Attenuated hepatic inflammation and fibrosis in angiotensin type 1a receptor deficient mice. Journal of Hepatology, 43(2), 317-323.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang, X., Yao, L., Fu, X., Mukherjee, R., Xia, Q., Jakubowska, M. A., Ferdek, P. E., &amp; Huang, W. (2020). Experimental acute pancreatitis models: History, current status, and role in translational research. Frontiers in Physiology, 11, 614591.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang, Y., Kim, J. W., Park, H. S., Lee, E. Y., &amp; Yoon, K. H. (2020). Pancreatic stellate cells in the islets as a novel target to preserve the pancreatic β-cell mass and function. Journal of Diabetes Investigation, 11(2), 268-280.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yanguas, S. C., Cogliati, B., Willebrords, J., Maes, M., Colle, I., van den Bossche, B., de Oliveira, C., Andraus, W., Alves, V. A. F., Leclercq, I., &amp; Vinken, M. (2016). Experimental models of liver fibrosis. Archives of Toxicology, 90(5), 1025-1048.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ye, Q., Zhou, Y., Zhao, C., Xu, L., &amp; Ping, J. (2021). Salidroside inhibits CCl(4)-induced liver fibrosis in mice by reducing activation and migration of HSC induced by liver sinusoidal endothelial cell-derived exosomal SphK1. Frontiers in Pharmacology, 12, 677810.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yokohama, S., Yoneda, M., Haneda, M., Okamoto, S., Okada, M., Aso, K., Hasegawa, T., Tokusashi, Y., Miyokawa, N., &amp; Nakamura, K. (2004). Therapeutic efficacy of an angiotensin II receptor antagonist in patients with nonalcoholic steatohepatitis. Hepatology, 40(5), 1222-1225.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zein, C. O., Unalp, A., Colvin, R., Liu, Y. C., &amp; McCullough, A. J. (2011). Smoking and severity of hepatic fibrosis in nonalcoholic fatty liver disease. Journal of Hepatology, 54(4), 753-759.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zha, M., Li, F., Xu, W., Chen, B., &amp; Sun, Z. (2014). Isolation and characterization of islet stellate cells in rat. Islets, 6(2), e28701.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zha, M., Xu, W., Jones, P. M., &amp; Sun, Z. (2016). Isolation and characterization of human islet stellate cells. Experimental Cell Research, 341(1), 61-66.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang, L. P., Ma, F., Abshire, S. M., &amp; Westlund, K. N. (2013). Prolonged high fat/alcohol exposure increases TRPV4 and its functional responses in pancreatic stellate cells. American Journal of Physiology Regulatory, Integrative and Comparative Physiology, 304(9), R702-R711.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang, W., Zhang, S., Zhang, W., Yue, Y., Qian, W., &amp; Wang, Z. (2021). Matrix stiffness and its influence on pancreatic diseases. Biochimica et Biophysica Acta - Reviews on Cancer, 1876(1), 188583.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhao, Z., Lin, C. Y., &amp; Cheng, K. (2019). siRNA- and miRNA-based therapeutics for liver fibrosis. Translational Research, 214, 17-29.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhou, D., Wang, W., Cheng, X., Wei, J., &amp; Zheng, S. (2015). Antioxidant therapy for patients with chronic pancreatitis: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Clinical Nutrition, 34(4), 627-634.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhou, Y., Wang, S., Ma, J. W., Lei, Z., Zhu, H. F., Lei, P., Yang, Z. S., Zhang, B., Yao, X. X., Shi, C., Sun, L. F., Wu, X. W., Ning, Q., Shen, G. X., &amp; Huang, B. (2010). Hepatitis B virus protein X-induced expression of the CXC chemokine IP-10 is mediated through activation of NF-kappaB and increases migration of leukocytes. Journal of Biological Chemistry, 285(16), 12159-12168.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhou, Z., Xu, M. J., Cai, Y., Wang, W., Jiang, J. X., Varga, Z. V., Feng, D., Pacher, P., Kunos, G., Torok, N. J., &amp; Gao, B. (2018). Neutrophil-hepatic stellate cell interactions promote fibrosis in experimental steatohepatitis. Cellular and Molecular Gastroenterology and Hepatology, 5(3), 399-413.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zimmermann, A., Gloor, B., Kappeler, A., Uhl, W., Friess, H., &amp; Büchler, M. W. (2002). Pancreatic stellate cells contribute to regeneration early after acute necrotising pancreatitis in humans. Gut, 51(4), 574-578.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zion, O., Genin, O., Kawada, N., Yoshizato, K., Roffe, S., Nagler, A., Iovanna, J. L., Halevy, O., &amp; Pines, M. (2009). Inhibition of transforming growth factor beta signaling by halofuginone as a modality for pancreas fibrosis prevention. Pancreas, 38(4), 427-435.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
