<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35434817</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>29</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1099-0801</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Apr</Month>
              <Day>17</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Biomedical chromatography : BMC</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Biomed Chromatogr</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Stability-indicating HPLC method development and validation for simultaneous estimation of metformin, dapagliflozin, and saxagliptin in bulk drug and pharmaceutical dosage form.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e5384</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e5384</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/bmc.5384</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>A simple, precise, and rapid stability-indicating reversed-phase-HPLC method was developed and validated for the estimation of metformin (MET), dapagliflozin (DAP), and saxagliptin (SAX) combination in bulk and tablet dosage forms. The proposed method uses a Kromasil C18 column (150 × 4.6 mm, 5 μm) with column oven temperature of 30°C and mobile phase containing a mixture of 60% phosphate buffer (pH = 3) and 40% acetonitrile. The flow rate was set at 1.0 mL/min, and the injection volume was 10 μL. The detection was carried out at 230 nm using a photodiode array detector, and the total run time was 4 min. The proposed method was validated according to International Council for Harmonisation (ICH) guidelines for specificity, linearity, precision, accuracy, robustness, and solution stability. The method is linear over the range of 125-750 μg/mL for MET, 1.25-7.5 μg/mL for DAP, and 0.625-3.75 μg/mL for SAX. The observed correlation coefficients (R<sup>2</sup> ) for MET, DAP, and SAX are &gt;0.999. The proposed method is precise, and the percentage relative standard deviation was found to be between 0.4 and 0.8. The observed percentage recoveries were between 98.51 and 100.80 for all three compounds. The product was subjected to stress conditions of acid, base, oxidative, thermal, and photolytic degradation. The product was found to degrade significantly in oxidative, acid, and base hydrolysis degradation conditions, and the degradation products were well determined from the active peaks, thus proving the stability-indicating power of the method. The developed and validated stability-indicating reversed-phase-HPLC method was appropriate for quantitative determination of these drugs in pharmaceutical preparations and also for quality control in bulk manufacturing.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Vankalapati</LastName>
            <ForeName>Krishna Rao</ForeName>
            <Initials>KR</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, JNTUH University College of Engineering Jagtial, Jagtial, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Alegete</LastName>
            <ForeName>Pallavi</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, JNTUH University College of Engineering Jagtial, Jagtial, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Boodida</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sathyanarayana</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3034-8609</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, JNTUH University College of Engineering Jagtial, Jagtial, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>04</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Biomed Chromatogr</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8610241</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0269-3879</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dapagliflozin</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">metformin</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">reversed-phase-HPLC</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">saxagliptin</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">stability indicating</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tablet dosage form</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>44</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35434817</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/bmc.5384</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abdelrahman, A. E., Maher, H. M., &amp; Alzoman, N. Z. (2020). HPTLC method for the determination of metformin hydrochloride, Saxagliptin hydrochloride, and Dapagliflozin in pharmaceuticals. Current Analytical Chemistry, 16(5), 609-619. https://doi.org/10.2174/1573407215666190131123029</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abeer, H., &amp; Hoda, M. (2016). A validated HPLC method for the determination of Linagliptin in RatPlasma. Application to a pharmacokinetic study. Journal of Chromatographic Science, 54(9), 1573-1577.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ayoub, B. M. (2015). UPLC simultaneous determination of empagliflozin, linagliptin and metformin. RSC Advances, 5, 95703-95709. https://doi.org/10.1039/C5RA17231D</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dongala, T., Katari, N. K., Ettaboina, S. K., Krishnan, A., Tambuwala, M. M., &amp; Dua, K. (2021). In vitro dissolution profile at different biological pH conditions of hydroxychloroquine sulfate tablets is available for the treatment of COVID-19. Frontiers in Molecular Biosciences, 7, 613393. https://doi.org/10.3389/fmolb.2020.613393</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Geetha Susmita, A., Rajitha, G., Ramya Yadav, Y., &amp; Uma, P. (2019). Analytical method development and validation of new stability-indicating reverse-phase high-performance liquid chromatography method for simultaneous estimation of metformin hydrochloride and Empagliflozin in tablet dosage form. Asian Journal of Pharmaceutical and Clinical Research, 12(1), 241-244. https://doi.org/10.22159/ajpcr.2019.v12i1.26537</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>International conference on harmonization. (2005). ICH Q2 (R1): Validation of analytical procedures: Text and methodology. ICH Secretariat.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Janardhan Swamy, A., &amp; Harinadha Baba, K. (2013). Analytical method development and method validation for the simultaneous estimation of metformin HCL and Linagliptin in bulk and tablet dosage form by RP-HPLC method. International Journal of Pharmaceutics, 3(3), 594-600.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Joy Chandra, R., Mahbubul Alam, M. D., Shahadat Hossain, M. D., &amp; Samiul Islam, M. D. (2018). Development and validation of a RP-HPLC method for quantitative analysis of Linagliptin in bulk and dosage forms. Journal of Pharmaceutical Sciences, 17(2), 175-182.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Katakam, L. N. R., Dongala, T., &amp; Ettaboina, S. K. (2020). Novel stability indicating UHPLC method development and validation for simultaneous quantification of hydrocortisone acetate, pramoxine hydrochloride, potassium sorbate and sorbic acid in topical cream formulation. Talanta Open, 1, 100004. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.talo.2020.100004</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Katakam, L. N. R., Ettaboina, S. K., &amp; Dongala, T. (2021). A simple and rapid HPLC method for determination of parabens and their degradation products in pharmaceutical dosage forms. Biomedical Chromatography, 35(10), e5152. https://doi.org/10.1002/bmc.5152</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lakshman Raju, B. (2012). A validated RP-HPLC method for the determination of Linagliptin. American Journal of PharmTech Research, 2(4), 1-5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Madan Mohan Reddy, M., Gowri Sankar, D., &amp; SeshagiriRao, J. (2017). Stress degradation studies and development of validated stability indicating assay method by RP-HPLC for simultaneous estimation of metformin and Empagliflozin in presence of degradation products as per ICH guidelines. Journal of Scientific Research in Pharmacy, 6(2), 20-33.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mallavarapu, R., Katari, N. K., Dongala, T., &amp; Rekulapally, V. K. (2022). A validated stability-indicating reversed-phase-HPLC method for dipyridamole in the presence of degradation products and its process-related impurities in pharmaceutical dosage forms. Biomedical Chromatography, 36, e5247. https://doi.org/10.1002/bmc.5247</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mokhtar, M. M., Suzan, M. S., Heba, M. E., &amp; Fotouh, R. M. (2019). A HPLC/DAD method for simultaneous determination of empagliflozin and three related substances in spiked human plasma. BMC Chemistry, 13(83), 1-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mounika, P., Hemant, T. K., Srinivasa, Y. R., &amp; Vara Prasad, K. R. (2019). RP-HPLC method for quantification of Empagliflozin in pharmaceutical formulation. Asian Journal of Pharmacy and Technology, 9(3), 208-211. https://doi.org/10.5958/2231-5713.2019.00035.7</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nachiket, S. D., Ganesh, S. S., &amp; Jyoti, J. V. (2019). Simultaneous estimation, validation and force degradation study of metformin hydrochloride and Empagliflozin by RP-HPLC method. Research Journal of Science and Technology, 11(2), 1-5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nenavath, P., &amp; Guttena, V. (2017). A novel stability indicating Rp-HPLC-dad method for determination of metformin and Empagliflozin in bulk and tablet dosage form. Oriental Journal of Chemistry, 33(4), 1949-1958. https://doi.org/10.13005/ojc/330441</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Padmaja, N., &amp; Veerabhadram, G. (2015). Development and validation of analytical method for simultaneous estimation of Empagliflozin and Linagliptin in bulk drugs and combined dosage forms using UV-visible spectroscopy. Der Pharmacia Lettre, 7(12), 306-312.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Patel, D. K., Kumar, R., Laloo, D., &amp; Hemalatha, S. (2012). Diabetes mellitus: An overview on its pharmacological aspects and reported medicinal plants having antidiabetic activity. Asian Pacific Journal of Tropical Biomedicine, 2(5), 411-420. https://doi.org/10.1016/S2221-1691(12)60067-7</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rekulapally, V. K., &amp; Rao, V. U. (2014). Stability Indicating RPHPLC Method Development and validation for simultaneous estimation of aliskiren, amlodipine and hydrochlorthiazide in tablet dosage form. International Journal of Pharmacy and Pharmaceutical Sciences, 6(1), 724-730.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rekulapally, V. K., &amp; Rao, V. U. (2015). A novel stability indicating RP-HPLC method development and validation for simultaneous estimation of phenylephrine, acetaminophen, guaifenesine, and dextromethorphan in tablet dosage form. Der Pharmacia Lettre, 7(7), 329-339.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ritesh, P. B., &amp; Faiyyaj, R. T. (2018). Development and validation of stability indicating HPTLC-MS method for estimation of Empagliflozin in pharmaceutical dosage form. Analytical Chemistry Letters, 8(2), 244-256. https://doi.org/10.1080/22297928.2017.1404929</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rupasi Pratyusha, C., &amp; Bhagavan Raju, M. (2016). Development and validation of stability indicating RP-HPLC method for the simultaneous estimation of metformin hydrochloride and Empagliflozin in bulk and in a synthetic mixture. International Journal of Pharmaceutics, 6(4), 138-147.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sharmila, D., &amp; Suneetha, A. (2018). Validated HPLC-UV method for simultaneous estimation of linagliptin and Empagliflozin in human plasma. International Journal of Applied Pharmaceutics, 10(3), 56-61.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shyamala Soumika, M., Sangeetha, E., &amp; Mahender, L. (2016). Method development and validation of Empagliflozin by Rp-Hplc in bulk and pharmaceutical dosage form. An International Journal of Advances in Pharmaceutical Sciences, 7(1), 1-5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Song, R. (2016). Mechanism of metformin: A tale of two sites. Diabetes Care, 39(2), 187-189. https://doi.org/10.2337/dci15-0013</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Subhashini, E., &amp; Syama Sundhar, B. (2014). New analytical method development and validation for the simultaneous estimation of metformin and Glibenclamide in bulk and tablet dosage form using RP-HPLC. Journal of Chemistry, 7(1), 55-63.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sujan, B., MasudKaisar, M. D., &amp; Salim, M. H. (2013). Development and validation of a simple and rapid UV spectrophotometer method for assay of Linagliptin in bulk and marketed dosage form. Indian Journal of Novel Drug Delivery, 5(4), 221-224.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Surya Prakash Rao, P., Vijay Kumar, C., &amp; Ranga Reddy, V. (2013). Stability -indicating UPLC method for determining related substances and degradants in Dronedarone. Journal of Chromatographic Science, 52, 665-675.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Surya Prakash Rao, P., Vijay Kumar, C., &amp; Ranga Reddy, V. (2014). Rapid quantitative determination of related substances and degradants in Milnacipran. Journal of Chromatographic Science, 52, 42-51. https://doi.org/10.1093/chromsci/bms202</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Surya Prakash Rao, P., Vijay Kumar, C., &amp; Ranga Reddy, V. (2015). Stability -indicating UPLC method for determining related substances and degradants in rivaroxaban. International Journal of Research in Pharmacy and Science, 5(2), 17-24.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vinay Kumar, D., &amp; Seshagiri Rao, J. (2018). A new validated stability indicating RP-HPLC method for simultaneous estimation of metformin hydrochloride and Empagliflozin in tablet dosage forms. International Research Journal of Pharmacy and Medical Sciences, 1(5), 16-22.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zalte Amar, G., Saudagar Ravindranath, B., &amp; Pramod, K. (2016). Validated UV-spectroscopic estimation of Linagliptin concentration in bulk and dosage form. Research Journal of Pharmacy and Technology, 9(5), 490-492. https://doi.org/10.5958/0974-360X.2016.00090.1</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
