<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35435142</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>29</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1087-2981</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>27</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Dec</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Medical education online</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Med Educ Online</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Development and psychometric testing of a scale measuring caring behaviors for healthcare students and providers.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>2066496</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>2066496</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2066496</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1080/10872981.2022.2066496</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>This study intended to develop and assess the psychometric properties of a caring behavior scale on healthcare students and providers (CBS-HSP) in a Taiwanese population. After a literature review was conducted and an expert panel was consulted for item generation, 104 items for the CBS-HSP scale were derived on a nine-point Likert scale, with 9 indicating 'extremely important' and 1 indicating 'extremely unimportant.' A pilot study was then conducted with seven hundred forty-eight healthcare students and providers in Taiwan for further data analysis. The statistic software used in the study was SPSS for the exploratory factor analysis (EFA) and AMOS for the confirmatory factor analysis (CFA). Also, to examine the psychometric properties of the scale, internal consistency, convergent validities, discriminant validities, and model fit indices were calculated in the study. The EFA results derived 31 items in four factors, with 65.742% of the total variance explained: 'support and attentiveness' (11 items; 48.714% of the variance explained), 'professional knowledge and skills' (8 items; 8.226% of the variance explained), 'gratifying needs and responsiveness' (7 items; 5.236% of the variance explained), and 'confidentiality and trust' (5 items; 3.566% of the variance explained). The Cronbach's alphas for the four subscales and the overall scale ranged from 0.894 to 0.964. The CFA results yielded the same 31 items, with the same four factors. The CFA results demonstrated good to excellent model fit in the χ2/df ratio (1.242), GFI (0.988), CFI (0.988), TFI (0.985), and RMSEA (0.031). The Cronbach's alphas ranged between 0.866 and 0.971; the composite alphas ranged between 0.854 and 0.964. The convergent and discriminant validities also proved the stability of the CBS-HSP scale. The research results indicated that the developed CBS-HSP appeared to be a reliable instrument to measure healthcare students' and providers' caring behaviors.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Liao</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hung-Chang</ForeName>
            <Initials>HC</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Health Policy and Management, Chung Shan Medical University, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medical Management, Chung Shan Medical University Hospital, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Huang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Cheng-Yi</ForeName>
            <Initials>CY</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Nursing, Chung Shan Medical University, Taichung, Taiwan; Department of Nursing, Chung Shan Medical University Hospital, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ya-Huei</ForeName>
            <Initials>YH</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Applied Foreign Languages, Chung Shan Medical University, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medical Education, Chung Shan Medical University Hospital, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Med Educ Online</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9806550</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1087-2981</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003695" MajorTopicYN="Y">Delivery of Health Care</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005163" MajorTopicYN="N">Factor Analysis, Statistical</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D010865" MajorTopicYN="N">Pilot Projects</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011594" MajorTopicYN="N">Psychometrics</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015203" MajorTopicYN="N">Reproducibility of Results</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013334" MajorTopicYN="Y">Students</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011795" MajorTopicYN="N">Surveys and Questionnaires</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Caring behavior</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">compassion</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">healthcare students and providers</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">psychometric properties</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">scale development</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>No potential conflict of interest was reported by the author(s).</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>8</Hour>
          <Minute>40</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35435142</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9037200</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10872981.2022.2066496</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fan VY, Lin SC.. 
It is time to include compassion in medical training. Acad Med. 2013;88:11.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sinclair S, Norris JM, McConnell SJ, et al. Compassion: a scoping review of the healthcare literature. BMC Palliat Care. 2016;15:6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4717626</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26786417</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singer T, Klimecki OM.. 
Empathy and compassion. Curr Biol. 2014;24:R875–R878.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25247366</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lown BA, Rosen J, Marttila J. An agenda for improving compassionate care: a survey shows about half of patients say such care is missing. Health Affairs (Millwood). 2011;30:1772–11.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Trzeciak S, Roberts BW, Mazzarelli AJ. Compassionomics: hypothesis and experimental approach. Med Hypotheses. 2017;107:92–97.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28915973</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Santo-Novak DA. Older adults’ descriptions of their role expectations of nursing. J Gerontol Nurs. 1997;23:32–40.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hogg R, Hanley J, Smith P. Learning lessons from the analysis of patient complaints relating to staff attitudes, behaviour and communication, using the concept of emotional labour. J Clin Nurs. 2018;27:e1004–12.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29052343</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Watson J. Caring theory as an ethical guide to administrative and clinical practices. Nurs Adm Q. 2006;30:48–55.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16449884</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bertakis KD, Azari R. Patient-centered care is associated with decreased health care utilization. J Am Board Fam Med. 2011;24:229–239.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21551394</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tonges M, Ray J. Translating caring theory into practice: the Carolina care model. J Nurs Adm. 2011;4:374–381.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Larson PJ. Cancer nurses’ perceptions of caring. Cancer Nurs. 1986;9:86–91.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3635439</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Larson PJ, Ferketich SL. Patients’ satisfaction with nurses caring during hospitalization. West J Nurs Res. 1993;15:690Y707.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8284928</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Watson J. Nursing: the philosophy and science of caring. Boulder/Colorado: University Press of Colorado; 2008.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Latham C. Predictors of patient outcomes following interactions with nurses. West J Nurs Res. 1996;18:548–564.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8918207</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wolf ZR, Miller PA, Devine M. Relationship between nurse caring and patient satisfaction in patients undergoing invasive cardiac procedures. MedSurg Nursing J. 2003;12:391–396.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Neumann M, Wirtz M, Bollschweiler E, et al. Determinants and patient-reported long-term outcomes of physician empathy in oncology: a structural equation modelling approach. Patient Educ Couns. 2007;69:63–75.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17851016</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>West CP, Huschka MM, Novotny PJ, et al. Association of perceived medical errors with resident distress and empathy: a prospective longitudinal study. JAMA. 2006;296:1071–1078.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16954486</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stewart M, Brown JB, Donner A, et al. The impact of patient-centered care on outcomes. J Fam Pract. 2000;49:796–804.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11032203</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weissmann PF, Branch WT, Gracey CF, et al. Role modeling humanistic behavior: learning bedside manner from the experts. Acad Med. 2006;82:661–667.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Burnell L, Agan DL. Compassionate care: can it be defined and measured? the development of the compassionate care assessment tool. Int J Caring Sci. 2013;6:180–187.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lown BA, Muncer SJ, Chadwick R. Can compassionate healthcare be measured? the Schwartz center compassionate care scale. Patient Educ Couns. 2015;98:1005–1010.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25921380</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mercer SW, Maxwell M, Heaney D, et al. The Consultation and Relational Empathy (CARE) measure: development and preliminary validation and reliability of an empathy-based consultation process measure. Fam Pract. 2004;21:699–705.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15528286</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roberts BW, Roberts MB, Yao J, et al. Development and validation of a tool to measure patient assessment of clinical compassion. JAMA Network Open. 2019;2:e193976.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6537812</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31099870</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee-Hsieh J, Kuo CL, Tsai YH. An action research on the development of a caring curriculum in Taiwan. J Nurs Educ. 2004;43:391–400.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15478691</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Slavec A, Drnovšek M. Perspective on scale development in entrepreneurship research. Econ Bus Rev. 2012;14:39–62.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>TSA . Research ethics framework of society institute in Taiwan. Available online: http://proj3.sinica.edu.tw/~tsa/modules/tadnews/index.php?nsn=43 (accessed on 2016 Nov
26).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>IBM Corp . IBM SPSS statistics for windows, version 24.0. Armonk/NY: IBM Corp; 2016.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaiser HF. An index of factorial simplicity. Psychometrika. 1974;39:31–36.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bartlett MS. A further note on tests of significance in factor analysis. Br J Psychol. 1951;4:1–2.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arbuckle JL. IBM SPSS Amos 24 User’s Guide. New York/NY: IBM; 2015.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hooper D, Coughlan J, Mullen M. Structural equation modelling: guidelines for determining model fit. Electron J Business Res Methods. 2008;6:53–60.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bentler PM. Comparative fit indexes in structural models. Psychol Bull. 1990;107:238–246.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2320703</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hu L, Bentler PM. Cutoff criteria for fit indexes in covariance structure analysis: conventional criteria versus new alternatives. Struct Equ Modeling. 1999;6:1–55.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hair J, Black W, Babin B, et al. Multivariate data analysis. 7th ed. Upper Saddle River/NJ: Prentice-Hall; 2010.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gefen D, Straub D, Boudreau MC. Structural equation modeling and regression: guidelines for research practice. Commun AIS. 2000;4:1–78.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cronbach LJ. Coefficient alpha and the internal structure of tests. Psychometrika. 1951;16(3):297–334.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nunnally JC. Psychometric Theory. 2nd ed. New York/NY: McGraw-Hill; 1978.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tabachnick BG, Fidell LS. Using multivariate statistics. 5th ed. New York/NY/USD: Allyn and Bacon; 2007.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sharma S, Mukherjee S, Kumar A, et al. A simulation study to investigate the use of cutoff values for assessing model fit in covariance structure models. J Bus Res. 2005;58:935–943.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ma Z. Application of structural equation modeling to evaluate customer satisfaction in the China internet bank sector. In Proceedings of the International Conference on Instrumentation, Measurement, Circuits and Systems (ICIMCS 2011), Hong Kong, China, 2011 Dec
12–13; ASME International, 2011; pp. 975–978.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schermelleh-Engel K, Moosbrugger H. Evaluating the fit of structural equation models: tests of significance and descriptive goodness-of-fit measures. Methods Psychol Res Online. 2003;8:23–74.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Malhotra NK. Pesquisa de Marketing: uma Orientação Aplicada. 6th ed. São Paulo/Brazil: Bookman; 2011.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bartlett MS. A note on the multiplying factors for various chi-square approximations. J R Stat Soc. 1954;16:296–298.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cinar D, Yava A. Validity and reliability of functional assessment of chronic illness treatment-fatigue scale in Turkish patients with type 2 diabetes. Endocrinología, Diabetes y Nutrición. 2018;65:409–417.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yalçiner N, Türkmen SN, Irmak H, et al. The validity and reliability of the Turkish Form of Recovery Process Inventory. Anatolian J Psychiatry. 2019;20:32–40.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Menezes MS, Gusmão MM, Santana RM, et al. Translation, transcultural adaptation, and validation of the role-modeling cost-conscious behaviors scale. BMC Med Educ. 2019;19:151.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6524215</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31096964</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fornell C, Larcker DF. Evaluating structural equation models with unobservable variables and measurement error. J Marketing Res. 1981;18:39.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stevens JP. Applied multivariate statistics for the social sciences. 5th ed. New York/NY: Routledge; 2009.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35435142</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>29</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1087-2981</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>27</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Dec</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Medical education online</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Med Educ Online</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Development and psychometric testing of a scale measuring caring behaviors for healthcare students and providers.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>2066496</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>2066496</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2066496</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1080/10872981.2022.2066496</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>This study intended to develop and assess the psychometric properties of a caring behavior scale on healthcare students and providers (CBS-HSP) in a Taiwanese population. After a literature review was conducted and an expert panel was consulted for item generation, 104 items for the CBS-HSP scale were derived on a nine-point Likert scale, with 9 indicating 'extremely important' and 1 indicating 'extremely unimportant.' A pilot study was then conducted with seven hundred forty-eight healthcare students and providers in Taiwan for further data analysis. The statistic software used in the study was SPSS for the exploratory factor analysis (EFA) and AMOS for the confirmatory factor analysis (CFA). Also, to examine the psychometric properties of the scale, internal consistency, convergent validities, discriminant validities, and model fit indices were calculated in the study. The EFA results derived 31 items in four factors, with 65.742% of the total variance explained: 'support and attentiveness' (11 items; 48.714% of the variance explained), 'professional knowledge and skills' (8 items; 8.226% of the variance explained), 'gratifying needs and responsiveness' (7 items; 5.236% of the variance explained), and 'confidentiality and trust' (5 items; 3.566% of the variance explained). The Cronbach's alphas for the four subscales and the overall scale ranged from 0.894 to 0.964. The CFA results yielded the same 31 items, with the same four factors. The CFA results demonstrated good to excellent model fit in the χ2/df ratio (1.242), GFI (0.988), CFI (0.988), TFI (0.985), and RMSEA (0.031). The Cronbach's alphas ranged between 0.866 and 0.971; the composite alphas ranged between 0.854 and 0.964. The convergent and discriminant validities also proved the stability of the CBS-HSP scale. The research results indicated that the developed CBS-HSP appeared to be a reliable instrument to measure healthcare students' and providers' caring behaviors.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Liao</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hung-Chang</ForeName>
            <Initials>HC</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Health Policy and Management, Chung Shan Medical University, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medical Management, Chung Shan Medical University Hospital, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Huang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Cheng-Yi</ForeName>
            <Initials>CY</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Nursing, Chung Shan Medical University, Taichung, Taiwan; Department of Nursing, Chung Shan Medical University Hospital, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ya-Huei</ForeName>
            <Initials>YH</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Applied Foreign Languages, Chung Shan Medical University, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medical Education, Chung Shan Medical University Hospital, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Med Educ Online</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9806550</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1087-2981</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003695" MajorTopicYN="Y">Delivery of Health Care</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005163" MajorTopicYN="N">Factor Analysis, Statistical</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D010865" MajorTopicYN="N">Pilot Projects</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011594" MajorTopicYN="N">Psychometrics</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015203" MajorTopicYN="N">Reproducibility of Results</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013334" MajorTopicYN="Y">Students</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011795" MajorTopicYN="N">Surveys and Questionnaires</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Caring behavior</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">compassion</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">healthcare students and providers</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">psychometric properties</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">scale development</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>No potential conflict of interest was reported by the author(s).</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>8</Hour>
          <Minute>40</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35435142</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9037200</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10872981.2022.2066496</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fan VY, Lin SC.. 
It is time to include compassion in medical training. Acad Med. 2013;88:11.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sinclair S, Norris JM, McConnell SJ, et al. Compassion: a scoping review of the healthcare literature. BMC Palliat Care. 2016;15:6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4717626</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26786417</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singer T, Klimecki OM.. 
Empathy and compassion. Curr Biol. 2014;24:R875–R878.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25247366</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lown BA, Rosen J, Marttila J. An agenda for improving compassionate care: a survey shows about half of patients say such care is missing. Health Affairs (Millwood). 2011;30:1772–11.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Trzeciak S, Roberts BW, Mazzarelli AJ. Compassionomics: hypothesis and experimental approach. Med Hypotheses. 2017;107:92–97.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28915973</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Santo-Novak DA. Older adults’ descriptions of their role expectations of nursing. J Gerontol Nurs. 1997;23:32–40.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hogg R, Hanley J, Smith P. Learning lessons from the analysis of patient complaints relating to staff attitudes, behaviour and communication, using the concept of emotional labour. J Clin Nurs. 2018;27:e1004–12.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29052343</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Watson J. Caring theory as an ethical guide to administrative and clinical practices. Nurs Adm Q. 2006;30:48–55.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16449884</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bertakis KD, Azari R. Patient-centered care is associated with decreased health care utilization. J Am Board Fam Med. 2011;24:229–239.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21551394</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tonges M, Ray J. Translating caring theory into practice: the Carolina care model. J Nurs Adm. 2011;4:374–381.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Larson PJ. Cancer nurses’ perceptions of caring. Cancer Nurs. 1986;9:86–91.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3635439</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Larson PJ, Ferketich SL. Patients’ satisfaction with nurses caring during hospitalization. West J Nurs Res. 1993;15:690Y707.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8284928</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Watson J. Nursing: the philosophy and science of caring. Boulder/Colorado: University Press of Colorado; 2008.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Latham C. Predictors of patient outcomes following interactions with nurses. West J Nurs Res. 1996;18:548–564.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8918207</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wolf ZR, Miller PA, Devine M. Relationship between nurse caring and patient satisfaction in patients undergoing invasive cardiac procedures. MedSurg Nursing J. 2003;12:391–396.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Neumann M, Wirtz M, Bollschweiler E, et al. Determinants and patient-reported long-term outcomes of physician empathy in oncology: a structural equation modelling approach. Patient Educ Couns. 2007;69:63–75.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17851016</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>West CP, Huschka MM, Novotny PJ, et al. Association of perceived medical errors with resident distress and empathy: a prospective longitudinal study. JAMA. 2006;296:1071–1078.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16954486</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stewart M, Brown JB, Donner A, et al. The impact of patient-centered care on outcomes. J Fam Pract. 2000;49:796–804.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11032203</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weissmann PF, Branch WT, Gracey CF, et al. Role modeling humanistic behavior: learning bedside manner from the experts. Acad Med. 2006;82:661–667.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Burnell L, Agan DL. Compassionate care: can it be defined and measured? the development of the compassionate care assessment tool. Int J Caring Sci. 2013;6:180–187.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lown BA, Muncer SJ, Chadwick R. Can compassionate healthcare be measured? the Schwartz center compassionate care scale. Patient Educ Couns. 2015;98:1005–1010.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25921380</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mercer SW, Maxwell M, Heaney D, et al. The Consultation and Relational Empathy (CARE) measure: development and preliminary validation and reliability of an empathy-based consultation process measure. Fam Pract. 2004;21:699–705.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15528286</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roberts BW, Roberts MB, Yao J, et al. Development and validation of a tool to measure patient assessment of clinical compassion. JAMA Network Open. 2019;2:e193976.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6537812</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31099870</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee-Hsieh J, Kuo CL, Tsai YH. An action research on the development of a caring curriculum in Taiwan. J Nurs Educ. 2004;43:391–400.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15478691</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Slavec A, Drnovšek M. Perspective on scale development in entrepreneurship research. Econ Bus Rev. 2012;14:39–62.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>TSA . Research ethics framework of society institute in Taiwan. Available online: http://proj3.sinica.edu.tw/~tsa/modules/tadnews/index.php?nsn=43 (accessed on 2016 Nov
26).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>IBM Corp . IBM SPSS statistics for windows, version 24.0. Armonk/NY: IBM Corp; 2016.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaiser HF. An index of factorial simplicity. Psychometrika. 1974;39:31–36.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bartlett MS. A further note on tests of significance in factor analysis. Br J Psychol. 1951;4:1–2.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arbuckle JL. IBM SPSS Amos 24 User’s Guide. New York/NY: IBM; 2015.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hooper D, Coughlan J, Mullen M. Structural equation modelling: guidelines for determining model fit. Electron J Business Res Methods. 2008;6:53–60.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bentler PM. Comparative fit indexes in structural models. Psychol Bull. 1990;107:238–246.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2320703</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hu L, Bentler PM. Cutoff criteria for fit indexes in covariance structure analysis: conventional criteria versus new alternatives. Struct Equ Modeling. 1999;6:1–55.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hair J, Black W, Babin B, et al. Multivariate data analysis. 7th ed. Upper Saddle River/NJ: Prentice-Hall; 2010.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gefen D, Straub D, Boudreau MC. Structural equation modeling and regression: guidelines for research practice. Commun AIS. 2000;4:1–78.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cronbach LJ. Coefficient alpha and the internal structure of tests. Psychometrika. 1951;16(3):297–334.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nunnally JC. Psychometric Theory. 2nd ed. New York/NY: McGraw-Hill; 1978.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tabachnick BG, Fidell LS. Using multivariate statistics. 5th ed. New York/NY/USD: Allyn and Bacon; 2007.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sharma S, Mukherjee S, Kumar A, et al. A simulation study to investigate the use of cutoff values for assessing model fit in covariance structure models. J Bus Res. 2005;58:935–943.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ma Z. Application of structural equation modeling to evaluate customer satisfaction in the China internet bank sector. In Proceedings of the International Conference on Instrumentation, Measurement, Circuits and Systems (ICIMCS 2011), Hong Kong, China, 2011 Dec
12–13; ASME International, 2011; pp. 975–978.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schermelleh-Engel K, Moosbrugger H. Evaluating the fit of structural equation models: tests of significance and descriptive goodness-of-fit measures. Methods Psychol Res Online. 2003;8:23–74.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Malhotra NK. Pesquisa de Marketing: uma Orientação Aplicada. 6th ed. São Paulo/Brazil: Bookman; 2011.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bartlett MS. A note on the multiplying factors for various chi-square approximations. J R Stat Soc. 1954;16:296–298.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cinar D, Yava A. Validity and reliability of functional assessment of chronic illness treatment-fatigue scale in Turkish patients with type 2 diabetes. Endocrinología, Diabetes y Nutrición. 2018;65:409–417.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yalçiner N, Türkmen SN, Irmak H, et al. The validity and reliability of the Turkish Form of Recovery Process Inventory. Anatolian J Psychiatry. 2019;20:32–40.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Menezes MS, Gusmão MM, Santana RM, et al. Translation, transcultural adaptation, and validation of the role-modeling cost-conscious behaviors scale. BMC Med Educ. 2019;19:151.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6524215</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31096964</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fornell C, Larcker DF. Evaluating structural equation models with unobservable variables and measurement error. J Marketing Res. 1981;18:39.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stevens JP. Applied multivariate statistics for the social sciences. 5th ed. New York/NY: Routledge; 2009.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
