<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35431916</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>06</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">1663-9812</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>13</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Frontiers in pharmacology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Front Pharmacol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Asthma Therapies on Pulmonary Tuberculosis Pneumonia in Predominant Bronchiectasis-Asthma Combination.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>790031</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>790031</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">790031</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fphar.2022.790031</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText><b>Background:</b> It is sometimes difficult to distinguish between asthma and bronchiectasis as their symptoms overlap, and these two diseases are associated with pulmonary tuberculosis (PTB) or pneumonia. <b>Objective:</b> The purpose of this study is to determine the effects of bronchodilator drugs, steroids, antidepressants drugs, and antianxiety drugs on the risks of PTB or pneumonia in patients with bronchiectasis-asthma combination or bronchiectasis-asthma-chronic obstructive pulmonary disease combination-BCAS cohort. <b>Methods:</b> After propensity score matching, we retrospectively studied patients with BCAS (<i>N</i> = 620) and without BCAS (<i>N</i> = 2,314) through an analysis. The cumulative incidence of PTB or pneumonia was analyzed through Cox proportional regression. After adjustment for sex, age, comorbidities, and medications [including long-acting beta2 agonist/muscarinic antagonists (LABAs/LAMAs), short-acting beta2 agonist/muscarinic antagonists (SABAs/SAMAs), leukotriene receptor antagonist, montelukast, steroids (inhaled corticosteroids, ICSs; oral steroids, OSs), anti-depressants (fluoxetine), and anti-anxiety drugs (benzodiazepines, BZDs)], we calculated the adjusted hazard ratios (aHR) and their 95% confidence intervals (95% CI) for these risks. Similar to OSs, ICSs are associated with an increased risk of PTB or pneumonia, lumping these two as steroids (ICSs/OSs). <b>Results:</b> For the aHR (95% CI), with non-LABAs/non-OSs as the reference 1, the use of LABAs [0.70 (0.52-0.94)]/OSs [0.35 (0.29-0.44)] was associated with a lower risk of PTB or pneumonia. However, the current use of LABAs [2.39 (1.31-4.34)]/SABAs [1.61 (1.31-1.96)], steroids [ICSs 3.23 (1.96-5.29)]/OSs 1.76 (1.45-2.14)], and BZDs [alprazolam 1.73 (1.08-2.75)/fludiazepam 7.48 (1.93-28.9)] was associated with these risks. The current use of LAMAs [0.52 (0.14-1.84)]/SAMAs [1.45 (0.99-2.11)] was not associated with these risks. <b>Conclusion:</b> The current use of LAMAs/SAMAs is relatively safe with respect to PTB or pneumonia risks, but LABAs/SABAs, steroids, and BZDs could be used after evaluation of the benefit for the BCAS cohort. However, we must take the possible protopathic bias into account.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022 Yeh, Lin, Yang, Hsu and Kao.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yeh</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jun-Jun</ForeName>
            <Initials>JJ</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Family Medicine, Geriatric Medicine, Chest Medicine and Medical Research, Ditmanson Medical Foundation Chia-Yi Christian Hospital, Chiayi, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>College of Medicine, China Medical University, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lin</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hui-Chuan</ForeName>
            <Initials>HC</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pharmacy, Ditmanson Medical Foundation Chia-Yi Christian Hospital, Chiayi, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yu-Cih</ForeName>
            <Initials>YC</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Management Office for Health Data, China Medical University Hospital, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>College of Medicine, China Medical University, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hsu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Chung-Y</ForeName>
            <Initials>CY</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>College of Medicine, China Medical University, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kao</LastName>
            <ForeName>Chia-Hung</ForeName>
            <Initials>CH</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Graduate Institute of Biomedical Sciences, College of Medicine, China Medical University, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Nuclear Medicine and PET Center, China Medical University Hospital, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Bioinformatics and Medical Engineering, Asia University, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Center of Augmented Intelligence in Healthcare, China Medical University Hospital, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Front Pharmacol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101548923</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1663-9812</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">and benzodiazepines</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">beta2 agonist/muscarinic antagonists</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bronchiectasis‐asthma combination</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pneumonia</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pulmonary tuberculosis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">steroids</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>32</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35431916</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9006509</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fphar.2022.790031</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">790031</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Antony S., Kumar P., George N., Chinthu R., Paulose C. (2010). Hypoglycemia Induced Behavioral Deficit and Decreased GABA Receptor, CREB Expression in the Cerebellum of Streptozoticin Induced Diabetic Rats. Brain Res. Bull.
83, 360–366. 10.1016/j.brainresbull.2010.09.004
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.brainresbull.2010.09.004</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20851745</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Arfè A., Corrao G. (2016). The Lag-Time Approach Improved Drug-Outcome Association Estimates in Presence of Protopathic Bias. J. Clin. Epidemiol.
78, 101–107. 10.1016/j.jclinepi.2016.03.003
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jclinepi.2016.03.003</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26976053</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Basham C. A., Karim M. E., Cook V. J., Patrick D. M., Johnston J. C. (2021). Post-tuberculosis Airway Disease: A Population-Based Cohort Study of People Immigrating to British Columbia, Canada, 1985-2015. EClinicalMedicine.
33, 100752. 10.1016/j.eclinm.2021.100752
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eclinm.2021.100752</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7933261</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33718847</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Bashir A., Abdallah I. E., Musa O. (2016). TB Infection Decreases Asthma Prevalence and Severity of Symptoms. Eur. Respir. J.
48, PA2706. 10.1183/13993003.congress-2016.PA2706
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.congress-2016.PA2706</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Chan P. C., Yang C. H., Chang F. Y. (2011). Scaling up of Latent Tuberculosis Infection Treatment for Close Contacts of Tuberculosis in Taiwan. J. Formos. Med. Assoc.
110, 733–736. 10.1016/j.jfma.2011.11.001
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jfma.2011.11.001</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22351971</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Chang T. M., Mou C. H., Shen T. C., Yang C. L., Yang M. H., Wu F. Y., et al.  (2016). Retrospective Cohort Evaluation on Risk of Pneumonia in Patients with Pulmonary Tuberculosis. Medicine (Baltimore)
95, e4000. 10.1097/MD.0000000000004000
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000004000</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4937923</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27368009</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Coman I., Pola-Bibián B., Barranco P., Vila-Nadal G., Dominguez-Ortega J., Romero D., et al.  (2018). Bronchiectasis in Severe Asthma: Clinical Features and Outcomes. Ann. Allergy Asthma Immunol.
120, 409–413. 10.1016/j.anai.2018.02.016
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.anai.2018.02.016</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29496464</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Domon H., Nagai K., Maekawa T., Oda M., Yonezawa D., Takeda W., et al.  (2018). Neutrophil Elastase Subverts the Immune Response by Cleaving Toll-like Receptors and Cytokines in Pneumococcal Pneumonia. Front. Immunol.
9, 732. 10.3389/fimmu.2018.00732
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2018.00732</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5996908</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29922273</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Duko B., Gebeyehu A., Ayano G. (2015). Prevalence and Correlates of Depression and Anxiety Among Patients with Tuberculosis at WolaitaSodo University Hospital and Sodo Health Center, WolaitaSodo, South Ethiopia, Cross Sectional Study. BMC Psychiatry.
15, 214. 10.1186/s12888-015-0598-3
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12888-015-0598-3</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4570612</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26370894</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Falcón C. R., Hurst N. F., Vivinetto A. L., López P. H. H., Zurita A., Gatti G., et al.  (2021). Diazepam Impairs Innate and Adaptive Immune Responses and Ameliorates Experimental Autoimmune Encephalomyelitis. Front. Immunol.
12, 682612. 10.3389/fimmu.2021.682612
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2021.682612</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8329586</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34354703</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Feng J. Y., Fang W. F., Wu C. L., Yu C. J., Lin M. C., Ku S. C., et al.  (2012). Concomitant Pulmonary Tuberculosis in Hospitalized Healthcare-Associated Pneumonia in a Tuberculosis Endemic Area: a Multi-center Retrospective Study. PLoS One
7, e36832. 10.1371/journal.pone.0036832
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0036832</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3358294</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22629334</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Gao Y. H., Guan W. J., Zhu Y. N., Chen R. C., Zhang G. J. (2018). Anxiety and Depression in Adult Outpatients with Bronchiectasis: Associations with Disease Severity and Health-Related Quality of Life. Clin. Respir. J.
12, 1485–1494. 10.1111/crj.12695
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/crj.12695</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28842946</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Hill A. T., Sullivan A. L., Chalmers J. D., De Soyza A., Elborn S. J., Floto A. R., et al.  (2019). British Thoracic Society Guideline for Bronchiectasis in Adults. Thorax
74, 1–69. 10.1136/thoraxjnl-2018-212463
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/thoraxjnl-2018-212463</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30545985</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Hsieh C. Y., Su C. C., Shao S. C., Sung S. F., Lin S. J., Kao Yang Y. H., et al.  (2019). Taiwan's National Health Insurance Research Database: Past and Future. Clin. Epidemiol.
11, 349–358. 10.2147/CLEP.S196293
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/CLEP.S196293</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6509937</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31118821</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Huang H. Y., Chung F. T., Lo C. Y., Lin H. C., Huang Y. T., Yeh C. H., et al.  (2020). Etiology and Characteristics of Patients with Bronchiectasis in Taiwan: a Cohort Study from 2002 to 2016. BMC Pulm. Med.
20, 45. 10.1186/s12890-020-1080-7
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12890-020-1080-7</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7029505</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32070324</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Huang K. H., Tai C. J., Kuan Y. H., Chang Y. C., Tsai T. H., Lee C. Y. (2021). Pneumonia Risk Associated with the Use of Individual Benzodiazepines and Benzodiazepine Related Drugs Among the Elderly with Parkinson's Disease. Int. J. Environ. Res. Public Health
18, 9410. 10.3390/ijerph18179410
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph18179410</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8431585</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34501996</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Hung C.-T., Li S. F., Chung W. S. (2018). Increased Risk of Acute Coronary Syndrome in Patients with Bronchiectasis: A Population-Based Cohort Study. Respirology
23, 828–834. 10.1111/resp.13298
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/resp.13298</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29641845</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Kapnadak S. G., Dimango E., Hadjiliadis D., Hempstead S. E., Tallarico E., Pilewski J. M., et al.  (2020). Cystic Fibrosis Foundation Consensus Guidelines for the Care of Individuals with Advanced Cystic Fibrosis Lung Disease. J. Cyst Fibros.
19, 344–354. 10.1016/j.jcf.2020.02.015
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcf.2020.02.015</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32115388</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Lai C. C., Tan C. K., Lin S. H., Liao C. H., Huang Y. T., Hsueh P. R. (2011). Diagnostic Performance of Whole-Blood Interferon-γ Assay and Enzyme-Linked Immunospot Assay for Active Tuberculosis'. Diagn. Microbiol. Infect. Dis.
71, 139–143. 10.1016/j.diagmicrobio.2011.05.013
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.diagmicrobio.2011.05.013</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21840675</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Lee C. M., Heo J., Han S. S., Moon K. W., Lee S. H., Kim Y. J., et al.  (2019). Inhaled Corticosteroid-Related Tuberculosis in the Real World Among Patients with Asthma and COPD: A 10-Year Nationwide Population-Based Study. J. Allergy Clin. Immunol. Pract.
7, 1197. 10.1016/j.jaip.2018.10.007
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaip.2018.10.007</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30339858</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Lehrer P. M., Karavidas M. K., Lu S. E., Feldman J., Kranitz L., Abraham S., et al.  (2008). Psychological Treatment of Comorbid Asthma and Panic Disorder: a Pilot Study. J. Anxiety Disord.
22, 671–683. 10.1016/j.janxdis.2007.07.001
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.janxdis.2007.07.001</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2517172</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17693054</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Martínez-García M. Á., Máiz L., Olveira C., Girón R. M., de la Rosa D., Blanco M., et al.  (2018). Spanish Guidelines on Treatment of Bronchiectasis in Adults. Arch. Bronconeumol
54, 88–98. 10.1016/j.arbres.2017.07.016
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arbres.2017.07.016</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29128129</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Mihălțan F., Constantin A. (2019). Asthma–COPD–Bronchiectasis Combination: an Unstudied Triplet. Pneumologia
68, 58–60. 10.2478/pneum-2019-0015
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/pneum-2019-0015</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Mincham K. T., Bruno N., Singanayagam A., Snelgrove R. J. (2021). Our Evolving View of Neutrophils in Defining the Pathology of Chronic Lung Disease. Immunology
164, 701–721. 10.1111/imm.13419
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/imm.13419</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8561104</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34547115</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Obiora E., Hubbard R., Sanders R. D., Myles P. R. (2013). The Impact of Benzodiazepines on Occurrence of Pneumonia and Mortality from Pneumonia: a Nested Case-Control and Survival Analysis in a Population-Based Cohort. Thorax
68, 163–170. 10.1136/thoraxjnl-2012-202374
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/thoraxjnl-2012-202374</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23220867</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Patel S., Cole A. D., Nolan C. M., Barker R. E., Jones S. E., Kon S., et al.  (2019). Pulmonary Rehabilitation in Bronchiectasis: a Propensity-Matched Study. Eur. Respir. J.
53, PA663. 10.1183/13993003.01264-2018
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.01264-2018</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30578381</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Polverino E., Dimakou K., Hurst J., Martinez-Garcia M. A., Miravitlles M., Paggiaro P., et al.  (2018). The Overlap between Bronchiectasis and Chronic Airway Diseases: State of the Art and Future Directions. Eur. Respir. J.
52, 1800328. 10.1183/13993003.00328-2018
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.00328-2018</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30049739</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Porto B. N., Stein R. T. (2016). Neutrophil Extracellular Traps in Pulmonary Diseases: Too Much of a Good Thing?
Front. Immunol.
7, 311. 10.3389/fimmu.2016.00311
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2016.00311</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4983612</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27574522</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Redondo M., Keyt H., Dhar R., Chalmers J. D. (2016). Global Impact of Bronchiectasis and Cystic Fibrosis. Breathe (Sheff)
12, 222–235. 10.1183/20734735.007516
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/20734735.007516</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5298141</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28210295</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Sanders R. D., Godlee A., Fujimori T., Goulding J., Xin G., Salek-Ardakani S., et al.  (2013). Benzodiazepine Augmented γ-amino-butyric Acid Signaling Increases Mortality from Pneumonia in Mice. Crit. Care Med.
41, 1627–1636. 10.1097/CCM.0b013e31827c0c8d
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CCM.0b013e31827c0c8d</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5774585</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23478657</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Shantakumar S., Pwu R. F., D'Silva L., Wurst K., Kuo Y. W., Yang Y. Y., et al.  (2018). Burden of Asthma and COPD Overlap (ACO) in Taiwan: a Nationwide Population-Based Study. BMC Pulm. Med.
18, 16. 10.1186/s12890-017-0571-7
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12890-017-0571-7</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5784537</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29368608</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Su V. Y., Yang K. Y., Yang Y. H., Tsai Y. H., Perng D. W., Su W. J., et al.  (2018). Use of ICS/LABA Combinations or LAMA Is Associated with a Lower Risk of Acute Exacerbation in Patients with Coexistent COPD and Asthma. J. Allergy Clin. Immunol. Pract.
6, 1927. 10.1016/j.jaip.2018.01.035
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaip.2018.01.035</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29432960</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Su V. Y., Yen Y. F., Pan S. W., Chuang P. H., Feng J. Y., Chou K. T., et al.  (2016). Latent Tuberculosis Infection and the Risk of Subsequent Cancer. Medicine (Baltimore)
95, e2352. 10.1097/MD.0000000000002352
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000002352</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5291550</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26825880</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Suissa S., Ernst P. (2020). Avoiding Immortal Time Bias in Observational Studies. Eur. Respir. J.
55, 2000138. 10.1183/13993003.00138-2020
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/13993003.00138-2020</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32198272</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Truong T. (2013). The Overlap of Bronchiectasis and Immunodeficiency with Asthma. Immunol. Allergy Clin. North. Am.
33, 61–78. 10.1016/j.iac.2012.10.007
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.iac.2012.10.007</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23337065</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
van der Meer A. J., Zeerleder S., Blok D. C., Kager L. M., Lede I. O., Rahman W., et al.  (2017). Neutrophil Extracellular Traps in Patients with Pulmonary Tuberculosis. Respir. Res.
18, 181. 10.1186/s12931-017-0663-1
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12931-017-0663-1</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5663039</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29084563</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Vanfleteren L. E. (2016). Asymptomatic COPD, until You Take it to Exertion. Thorax.
71, 781–782. 10.1136/thoraxjnl-2016-208863
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/thoraxjnl-2016-208863</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27440141</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Veith M., Tüffers J., Peychev E., Klemmer A., Kotke V., Janciauskiene S., et al.  (2020). The Distribution of Alpha-1 Antitrypsin Genotypes between Patients with COPD/Emphysema, Asthma and Bronchiectasis. Int. J. Chron. Obstruct Pulmon Dis.
15, 2827–2836. 10.2147/COPD.S271810
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/COPD.S271810</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7654539</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33192056</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Vynnycky E., Fine P. E. (1997). The Natural History of Tuberculosis: the Implications of Age-dependent Risks of Disease and the Role of Reinfection. Epidemiol. Infect.
119, 183–201. 10.1017/s0950268897007917
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/s0950268897007917</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2808840</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9363017</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Wynne S. C., Patel S., Barker R. E., Jones S. E., Walsh J. A., Kon S. S., et al.  (2020). Anxiety and Depression in Bronchiectasis: Response to Pulmonary Rehabilitation and Minimal Clinically Important Difference of the Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale. Chron. Respir. Dis.
17, 1479973120933292. 10.1177/1479973120933292
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1479973120933292</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7301664</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32545998</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Yeh J. J., Lin C. L., Hsu C. Y., Shae Z., Kao C. H. (2019). Associations between Statins and Coronary Artery Disease and Stroke Risks in Patients with Asthma-Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease Overlap Syndrome: A Time-dependent Regression Study. Atherosclerosis
283, 61–68. 10.1016/j.atherosclerosis.2019.02.007
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.atherosclerosis.2019.02.007</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30782562</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Yeh J. J., Lin C. L., Hsu C. Y., Shae Z., Kao C. H. (2018). Statin for Tuberculosis and Pneumonia in Patients with Asthma–Chronic Pulmonary Disease Overlap Syndrome: A Time-dependent Population-Based Cohort Study. J. Clin. Med.
7, 381. 10.3390/jcm7110381
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm7110381</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6262333</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30355982</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Yeh J. J. (2019). Predictors of Initial Smear-Negative Active Pulmonary Tuberculosis with Acute Early Stage Lung Injury by High-Resolution Computed Tomography and Clinical Manifestations: An Auxiliary Model in Critical Patients. Sci. Rep.
9, 4527. 10.1038/s41598-019-40799-w
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-019-40799-w</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6418143</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30872774</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Yeh J. J., Lin C. L., Kao C. H. (2020). Associations Among Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease with Asthma, Pneumonia, and Corticosteroid Use in the General Population. PLOS ONE
15, e0229484. 10.1371/journal.pone.0229484
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0229484</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7039502</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32092112</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Zhang P., Li J., Liu H., Han N., Ju J., Kou Y., et al.  (2020). Long-term Bone and Lung Consequences Associated with Hospital-Acquired Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome: a 15-year Follow-Up from a Prospective Cohort Study. Bone Res.
8, 8. 10.1038/s41413-020-0084-5
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41413-020-0084-5</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7018717</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32128276</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
