<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35431390</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>22</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">0264-2751</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>126</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jul</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Cities (London, England)</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Cities</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>COVID-19 effects on urban driving, walking, and transit usage trends: Evidence from Indian metropolitan cities.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>103697</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>103697</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.cities.2022.103697</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The outbreak of the COVID-19 pandemic disrupted all walks of life, including the transportation sector. Fear of the contagion coupled with government regulations to restrict mobility altered the travel behavior of the public. This study proposes integrating freely accessible aggregate mobility datasets published by tech giants Apple and Google, which opens a broader avenue for mobility research in the light of difficult data collection circumstances. A comparative analysis of the changes in usage of different mobility modes during the national lockdown and unlock policy periods across 6 Indian cities (Bangalore, Chennai, Delhi, Hyderabad, Mumbai, and Pune) explain the spatio-temporal differences in mode usages. The study shows a preference for individual travel modes (walking and driving) over public transit. Comparisons with pre-pandemic mode shares present evidence of inertia in the choice of travel modes. Association investigations through generalized linear mixed-effects models identify income, vehicle registrations, and employment rates at the city level to significantly impact the community mobility trends. The methods and interpretations from this study benefit government, planners, and researchers to boost informed policymaking and implementation during a future emergency demanding mobility regulations in the high-density urban conglomerations.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Padmakumar</LastName>
            <ForeName>Athul</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Civil Engineering, Indian Institute of Technology Bombay, Mumbai 400076, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Patil</LastName>
            <ForeName>Gopal R</ForeName>
            <Initials>GR</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Civil Engineering, Indian Institute of Technology Bombay, Mumbai 400076, India.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>04</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Cities</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101085015</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0264-2751</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Generalized linear mixed effects mode</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Google and Apple mobility data</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Indian cities</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Travel modes</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>31</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35431390</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8995256</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cities.2022.103697</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">S0264-2751(22)00136-6</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aaditya B., Rahul T.M. A comprehensive analysis of the trip frequency behavior in COVID scenario. Transportation Letters. 2021;13(5–6):395–403. doi: 10.1080/19427867.2021.1906478.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/19427867.2021.1906478</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abdullah M., Ali N., Javid M.A., Dias C., Campisi T. Public transport versus solo travel mode choices during the COVID-19 pandemic: Self-reported evidence from a developing country. Transportation Engineering. 2021;5 doi: 10.1016/J.TRENG.2021.100078.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.TRENG.2021.100078</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>AbouKorin S.A.A., Han H., Mahran M.G.N. Role of urban planning characteristics in forming pandemic resilient cities – Case study of Covid-19 impacts on European cities within England, Germany and Italy. Cities. 2021;118 doi: 10.1016/J.CITIES.2021.103324.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.CITIES.2021.103324</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aloi A., Alonso B., Benavente J., Cordera R., Echániz E., González F.…Álvaro L.-P. Effects of the COVID-19 lockdown on urban mobility: Empirical evidence from the city of Santander (Spain) Sustainability (Switzerland) 2020;12(9) doi: 10.3390/su12093870.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su12093870</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Apple COVID-19 mobility trends reports Apple. 2020. https://covid19.apple.com/mobility Retrieved 8 November 2020, from.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beria P., Lunkar V. Presence and mobility of the population during the first wave of Covid-19 outbreak and lockdown in Italy. Sustainable Cities and Society. 2021;65 doi: 10.1016/j.scs.2020.102616.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scs.2020.102616</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bhaduri E., Manoj B.S., Wadud Z., Goswami A.K., Choudhury C.F. Modelling the effects of COVID-19 on travel mode choice behaviour in India. Transportation Research Interdisciplinary Perspectives. 2020;8 doi: 10.1016/j.trip.2020.100273.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.trip.2020.100273</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boisjoly G., Grisé E., Maguire M., Veillette M.P., Deboosere R., Berrebi E., El-Geneidy A. Invest in the ride: A 14 year longitudinal analysis of the determinants of public transport ridership in 25 north American cities. Transportation Research Part A: Policy and Practice. 2018;116:434–445. doi: 10.1016/j.tra.2018.07.005.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tra.2018.07.005</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Buckee C., Balsari S., Chan J., Crosas M., Dominici F., Gasser U., Grad Y., Grenfell B., Halloran M.E., Kraemer M., Lipsitch M., Metcalf J., Meyers L.A., Perkins A., Santillana M., Scarpino S., Viboud C., Wesolowski A., Schroeder A. Aggregated mobility data could help fight COVID-19. Science. 2020;23(March) (Letters)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bucsky P. Modal share changes due to COVID-19: The case of Budapest. Transportation Research Interdisciplinary Perspectives. 2020;8 doi: 10.1016/j.trip.2020.100141.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.trip.2020.100141</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cacciapaglia G., Cot C., Sannino F. Mining Google and apple mobility data: Temporal anatomy for COVID-19 social distancing. Scientific Reports. 2020;11(1):4150. http://arxiv.org/abs/2008.02117</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cartenì A., Di Francesco L., Martino M. How mobility habits influenced the spread of the COVID-19 pandemic: Results from the italian case study. Science of the Total Environment. 2020;741 doi: 10.1016/j.scitotenv.2020.140489.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scitotenv.2020.140489</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chakrabarti S. How can public transit get people out of their cars? An analysis of transit mode choice for commute trips in Los Angeles. Transport Policy. 2017;54:80–89. doi: 10.1016/j.tranpol.2016.11.005.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tranpol.2016.11.005</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Christidis P., Christodoulou A., Navajas-Cawood E., Ciuffo B. The post-pandemic recovery of transport activity: emerging mobility patterns and repercussions on future evolution. Sustainability. 2021;13(11):6359. doi: 10.3390/SU13116359.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/SU13116359</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cirianni F., Monterosso C., Panuccio P., Rindone C. A review methodology of sustainable urban mobility plans: Objectives and actions to promote cycling and pedestrian mobility. Green Energy and Technology. 2017:685–697. doi: 10.1007/978-3-319-75774-2_46. 9783319757735.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-3-319-75774-2_46</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Croce A.I., Musolino G., Rindone C., Vitetta A. Estimation of travel demand models with limited information: floating car data for parameters'’ calibration. Sustainability. 2021;13(16):8838. doi: 10.3390/SU13168838.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/SU13168838</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Darsena D., Gelli G., Iudice I., Verde F.  2021. Enabling and emerging sensing technologies for crowd management in public transportation systems: A review.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.36227/TECHRXIV.16811191.V2</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Das S., Boruah A., Banerjee A., Raoniar R., Nama S., Maurya A.K. Impact of COVID-19: A radical modal shift from public to private transport mode. Transport Policy. 2021;109:1–11. doi: 10.1016/j.tranpol.2021.05.005.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tranpol.2021.05.005</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Vos J. The effect of COVID-19 and subsequent social distancing on travel behavior. Transportation Research Interdisciplinary Perspectives. 2020;5 doi: 10.1016/j.trip.2020.100121.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.trip.2020.100121</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dev S.M., Sengupta R. Covid-19: Impact on the Indian economy. Indira Gandhi Institute of Development Research, Mumbai working papers. 2020. https://ideas.repec.org/p/ind/igiwpp/2020-013.html</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dingil A.E., Esztergár-Kiss D. The influence of the Covid-19 pandemic on mobility patterns: The first Wave’s results. Transportation Letters. 2021;13(5–6):434–446. doi: 10.1080/19427867.2021.1901011.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/19427867.2021.1901011</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dueñas M., Campi M., Olmos L.E. Changes in mobility and socioeconomic conditions during the COVID-19 outbreak. Humanities and Social Sciences Communications. 2021;8(1):1–10. doi: 10.1057/s41599-021-00775-0.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1057/s41599-021-00775-0</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eisenmann C., Nobis C., Kolarova V., Lenz B., Winkler C. Transport mode use during the COVID-19 lockdown period in Germany: The car became more important, public transport lost ground. Transport Policy. 2021;103:60–67. doi: 10.1016/j.tranpol.2021.01.012.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tranpol.2021.01.012</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Facebook Facebook data for good. 2020. https://dataforgood.fb.com/ Retrieved 9 November, 2020, from.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fuller G., McGuinness K., Waitt G., Buchanan I., Lea T. The reactivated bike: Self-reported cycling activity during the 2020 COVID-19 pandemic in Australia. Transportation Research Interdisciplinary Perspectives. 2021;10 doi: 10.1016/J.TRIP.2021.100377.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.TRIP.2021.100377</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Galeazzi A., Cinelli M., Bonaccorsi G., Pierri F., Schmidt A.L., Scala A., Pammolli F., Quattrociocchi W.  2020. Human mobility in response to COVID-19 in France, Italy and UK.http://arxiv.org/abs/2005.06341</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garnier R., Benetka J.R., Kraemer J., Bansal S. Socioeconomic disparities in social distancing during the COVID-19 pandemic in the United States: Observational study. Journal of Medical Internet Research. 2021;23(1) doi: 10.2196/24591.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2196/24591</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gascon M., Marquet O., Gràcia-Lavedan E., Ambròs A., Götschi T., de Nazelle A., Panis L.I., Gerike R., Brand C., Dons E., Eriksson U., Iacorossi F., Ávila-Palència I., Cole-Hunter T., Nieuwenhuisjen M.J. What explains public transport use? Evidence from seven European cities. Transport Policy. 2020;99:362–374. doi: 10.1016/J.TRANPOL.2020.08.009.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.TRANPOL.2020.08.009</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gensini G.F., Yacoub M.H., Conti A.A. The concept of quarantine in history: From plague to SARS. Journal of Infection. 2004;49(4):257–261. doi: 10.1016/j.jinf.2004.03.002.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jinf.2004.03.002</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gkiotsalitis K. A model for modifying the public transport service patterns to account for the imposed COVID-19 capacity. Transportation Research Interdisciplinary Perspectives. 2021;9 doi: 10.1016/J.TRIP.2021.100336.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.TRIP.2021.100336</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gkiotsalitis K., Cats O.  Public transport planning adaption under the COVID-19 pandemic crisis: Literature review of research needs and directions. Vol. 41. 2020. pp. 374–392. (3)</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/01441647.2020.1857886</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Google COVID-19 community mobility reports. 2020. https://www.google.com/covid19/mobility/ Retrieved November 8, 2020, from.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta M., Pawar N.M., Velaga N.R. Impact of lockdown and change in mobility patterns on road fatalities during COVID-19 pandemic. Transportation Letters. 2021 doi: 10.1080/19427867.2021.1892937.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/19427867.2021.1892937</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hadjidemetriou G.M., Sasidharan M., Kouyialis G., Parlikad A.K. The impact of government measures and human mobility trend on COVID-19 related deaths in the UK. Transportation Research Interdisciplinary Perspectives. 2020;6 doi: 10.1016/J.TRIP.2020.100167.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.TRIP.2020.100167</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hale T., Angrist N., Goldszmidt R., Kira B., Petherick A., Phillips T., Webster S., Cameron-Blake E., Hallas L., Majumdar S., Tatlow H. A global panel database of pandemic policies (Oxford COVID-19 government response Tracker) Nature Human Behaviour. 2021 doi: 10.1038/s41562-021-01079-8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41562-021-01079-8</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hasselwander M., Tamagusko T., Bigotte J.F., Ferreira A., Mejia A., Ferranti E.J.S. Building back better: The COVID-19 pandemic and transport policy implications for a developing megacity. Sustainable Cities and Society. 2021;69 doi: 10.1016/j.scs.2021.102864.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scs.2021.102864</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huang X., Li Z., Jiang Y., Ye X., Deng C., Zhang J., Li X. The characteristics of multi-source mobility datasets and how they reveal the luxury nature of social distancing in the U.S. During the COVID-19 pandemic. International Journal of Digital Earth. 2021;14(4):424–442. doi: 10.1080/17538947.2021.1886358.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17538947.2021.1886358</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jeffrey B., Walters C.E., Ainslie K.E.C., Eales O., Ciavarella C., Bhatia S., Hayes S., Baguelin M., Boonyasiri A., Brazeau N.F., Cuomo-Dannenburg G., FitzJohn R.G., Gaythorpe K., Green W., Imai N., Mellan T.A., Mishra S., Nouvellet P., Unwin H.J.T., Riley S.… Anonymised and aggregated crowd level mobility data from mobile phones suggests that initial compliance with covid-19 social distancing interventions was high and geographically consistent across the UK. Wellcome Open Research. 2020;5:1–10. doi: 10.12688/WELLCOMEOPENRES.15997.1.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12688/WELLCOMEOPENRES.15997.1</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8474101</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34632082</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kissler S.M., Kishore N., Prabhu M., Goffman D., Beilin Y., Landau R., Gyamfi-Bannerman C., Bateman B.T., Snyder J., Razavi A.S., Katz D., Gal J., Bianco A., Stone J., Larremore D., Buckee C.O., Grad Y.H. Reductions in commuting mobility correlate with geographic differences in SARS-CoV-2 prevalence in New York City. NatureCommunications. 2020;11(1) doi: 10.1038/s41467-020-18271-5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-020-18271-5</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kraemer M.U.G., Yang C.H., Gutierrez B., Wu C.H., Klein B., Pigott D.M., du Plessis L., Faria N.R., Li R., Hanage W.P., Brownstein J.S., Layan M., Vespignani A., Tian H., Dye C., Pybus O.G., Scarpino S.V. The effect of human mobility and control measures on the COVID-19 epidemic in China. Science. 2020;368(6490):493–497. doi: 10.1126/science.abb4218.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.abb4218</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7146642</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32213647</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee W.D., Qian M., Schwanen T. The association between socioeconomic status and mobility reductions in the early stage of England’s COVID-19 epidemic. Health &amp; Place. 2021;69 doi: 10.1016/J.HEALTHPLACE.2021.102563.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.HEALTHPLACE.2021.102563</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leung K., Wu J.T., Leung G.M.  MedRxiv; 2020. Real-time tracking and prediction of COVID-19 infection using digital proxies of population mobility and mixing. 020.10.17.20214155.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2020.10.17.20214155</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu Z., Stern R. Quantifying the traffic impacts of the COVID-19 shutdown. Journal of Transportation Engineering, Part A: Systems. 2021;147(5):04021014. doi: 10.1061/jtepbs.0000527.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/jtepbs.0000527</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lou J., Shen X., Niemeier D. Are stay-at-home orders more difficult to follow for low-income groups? Journal of Transport Geography. 2020;89 doi: 10.1016/j.jtrangeo.2020.102894.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jtrangeo.2020.102894</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mannering F.L., Shankar V., Bhat C.R. Unobserved heterogeneity and the statistical analysis of highway accident data. Analytic Methods in Accident Research. 2016;11:1–16. doi: 10.1016/j.amar.2016.04.001.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.amar.2016.04.001</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martínez L., Short J.R. The pandemic city: Urban issues in the time of COVID-19. Sustainability. 2021;13(6):3295. doi: 10.3390/SU13063295.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/SU13063295</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mbunge E., Akinnuwesi B., Fashoto S.G., Metfula A.S., Mashwama P. A critical review of emerging technologies for tackling COVID-19 pandemic. Human Behavior and Emerging Technologies. 2021;3(1):25–39. doi: 10.1002/hbe2.237.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hbe2.237</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ministry of Health and Family Welfare  Social distancing advisory. 2020. https://www.mohfw.gov.in/pdf/SocialDistancingAdvisorybyMOHFW.pdf Retrieved 21 May, 2021, from.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ministry of Urban Development  . Government of India; 2019. Handbook of urban statistics.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Molloy J., Schatzmann T., Schoeman B., Tchervenkov C., Hintermann B., Axhausen K.W. Observed impacts of the Covid-19 first wave on travel behavior in Switzerland based on a large GPS panel. Transport Policy. 2021;104:43–51. doi: 10.1016/J.TRANPOL.2021.01.009.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.TRANPOL.2021.01.009</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Munawar H.S., Khan S.I., Qadir Z., Kouzani A.Z., Mahmud M.A.P. Insight into the impact of COVID-19 on Australian transportation sector: An economic and community-based perspective. Sustainability. 2021;13(3):1276. doi: 10.3390/SU13031276.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/SU13031276</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nikitas A., Tsigdinos S., Karolemeas C., Kourmpa E., Bakogiannis E. Cycling in the era of COVID-19: Lessons learnt and best practice policy recommendations for a more bike-centric future. Sustainability. 2021;13(9):4620. doi: 10.3390/SU13094620.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/SU13094620</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nouvellet P., Bhatia S., Cori A., Ainslie K.E.C., Baguelin M., Bhatt S., Boonyasiri A., Brazeau N.F., Cattarino L., Cooper L.V., Coupland H., Cucunuba Z.M., Cuomo-Dannenburg G., Dighe A., Djaafara B.A., Dorigatti I., Eales O.D., van Elsland S.L., Nascimento F.F., Donnelly C.A.… Reduction in mobility and COVID-19 transmission. Nature Communications. 2021;12(1):1–9. doi: 10.1038/s41467-021-21358-2.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-021-21358-2</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nurse A., Dunning R. Is COVID-19 a turning point for active travel in cities? Cities &amp; Health. 2020;1–3 doi: 10.1080/23748834.2020.1788769.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/23748834.2020.1788769</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Padmakumar Athul, Patil Gopal R., Gadiya Kirtesh. Did mobility affect the spread of COVID-19 during the first pandemic wave? An investigation for Indian states using dynamic regression. Journal of Transportation Engineering, Part A: Systems. 2022 doi: 10.1061/JTEPBS.0000707. In press.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/JTEPBS.0000707</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parady G., Taniguchi A., Takami K. Travel behavior changes during the COVID-19 pandemic in Japan: Analyzing the effects of risk perception and social influence on going-out self-restriction. Transportation Research Interdisciplinary Perspectives. 2020;7 doi: 10.1016/j.trip.2020.100181.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.trip.2020.100181</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parashar L., Cheriyan C.A. Application of mobility related data during pandemic: Opportunities, issues and challenges in India. Transport Policy. 2021;111:74–81. doi: 10.1016/J.TRANPOL.2021.07.009.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.TRANPOL.2021.07.009</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Park J., Kim G. Risk of COVID-19 infection in public transportation: The development of a model. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health. 2021;18(23):12790. doi: 10.3390/IJERPH182312790.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/IJERPH182312790</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8657409</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34886516</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parr S., Wolshon B., Murray-Tuite P., Lomax T. Multistate assessment of roadway travel, social separation, and COVID-19 cases. Journal of Transportation Engineering, Part A: Systems. 2021;147(5):04021012. doi: 10.1061/jtepbs.0000528.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/jtepbs.0000528</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Patil G.R., Dhore R., Bhavathrathan B.K., Pawar D.S., Sahu P., Mulani A. Consumer responses towards essential purchases during COVID-19 pan-India lockdown. Research in Transportation Business &amp; Management. 2021;100768 doi: 10.1016/J.RTBM.2021.100768.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.RTBM.2021.100768</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paul B., Sarkar S.  COVID-19 pandemic trajectory in the developing worldexploring the changing environmental and economic milieus in India. 2020. The contagion effects of COVID-19 and public transportation system: Conceptualizing the shifting paradigm in India; pp. 231–255.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-981-33-6440-0_10</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pawar D.S., Yadav A.K., Choudhary P., Velaga N.R. Modelling work- and non-work-based trip patterns during transition to lockdown period of COVID-19 pandemic in India. Travel Behaviour and Society. 2021;24:46–56. doi: 10.1016/j.tbs.2021.02.002.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tbs.2021.02.002</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8561416</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34745888</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paydar M., Fard A.K. The hierarchy of walking needs and the COVID-19 pandemic. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health. 2021;18(14):7461. doi: 10.3390/IJERPH18147461. Retrieved 21 May, 2021, from.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/IJERPH18147461</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8307307</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34299913</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peak C.M., Wesolowski A., Erbach-Schoenberg E.Z., Tatem A.J., Wetter E., Lu X.…Bengtsson L. Population mobility reductions associated with travel restrictions during the Ebola epidemic in Sierra Leone: Use of mobile phone data. International Journal of Epidemiology. 2018;47(5):1562–1570. doi: 10.1093/ije/dyy095.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ije/dyy095</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6208277</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29947788</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Politis I., Georgiadis G., Papadopoulos E., Fyrogenis I., Nikolaidou A., Kopsacheilis A., Sdoukopoulos A., Verani E. COVID-19 lockdown measures and travel behavior: The case of Thessaloniki, Greece. Transportation Research Interdisciplinary Perspectives. 2021;10:100345. doi: 10.1016/j.trip.2021.100345.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.trip.2021.100345</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pullano G., Valdano E., Scarpa N., Rubrichi S., Colizza V. Evaluating the effect of demographic factors, socioeconomic factors, and risk aversion on mobility during the COVID-19 epidemic in France under lockdown: a population-based study. The Lancet Digital Health. 2020;0(0) doi: 10.1016/S2589-7500(20)30243-0.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2589-7500(20)30243-0</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Russo F., Rindone C. Regional transport plans: From direction role denied to common rules identified. Sustainability. 2021;13(16):9052. doi: 10.3390/SU13169052.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/SU13169052</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saha J., Barman B., Chouhan P. Lockdown for COVID-19 and its impact on community mobility in India: An analysis of the COVID-19 community mobility reports, 2020. Children and Youth Services Review. 2020;116 doi: 10.1016/j.childyouth.2020.105160.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.childyouth.2020.105160</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shakibaei S., de Jong G.C., Alpkökin P., Rashidi T.H. Impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on travel behavior in Istanbul: A panel data analysis. Sustainable Cities and Society. 2021;65 doi: 10.1016/j.scs.2020.102619.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scs.2020.102619</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Snoeijer B.T., Burger M., Sun S., Dobson R.J.B., Folarin A.A. Measuring the effect of non-pharmaceutical interventions (NPIs) on mobility during the COVID-19 pandemic using global mobility data. Npj Digital Medicine. 2021;4(1):1–12. doi: 10.1038/s41746-021-00451-2.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41746-021-00451-2</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7782845</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33398041</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sulyok M., Walker M. Community movement and covid-19: A global study using google’s community mobility reports. Epidemiology and Infection. 2020;148 doi: 10.1017/S0950268820002757.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0950268820002757</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tamagusko T., Ferreira A. Mobility patterns of the Portuguese population during the COVID-19 pandemic. Sustainability (Switzerland) 2020;12(22):1–12. doi: 10.3390/su12229775.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/su12229775</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thombre A., Agarwal A. A paradigm shift in urban mobility: Policy insights from travel before and after COVID-19 to seize the opportunity. Transport Policy. 2021 doi: 10.1016/j.tranpol.2021.06.010.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tranpol.2021.06.010</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tirachini A., Cats O. COVID-19 and public transportation: Current assessment, prospects, and research needs. Journal of Public Transportation. 2020;22(1):1–34. doi: 10.5038/2375-0901.22.1.1.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5038/2375-0901.22.1.1</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tom Tom. Traffic congestion ranking. 2021. https://www.tomtom.com/en_gb/traffic-index/ranking/ Retrieved March 17, 2022, from.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wen L., Sheng M., Sharp B.  2021. The impact of COVID-19 on changes in community mobility and variation in transport modes.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/00779954.2020.1870536</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>WHO Advice for the public. 2020. https://www.who.int/emergencies/diseases/novel-coronavirus-2019/advice-for-public Retrieved November 8, 2020, from.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wilder-Smith A., Freedman D.O.  2020. Isolation, quarantine, social distancing and community containment: Pivotal role for old-style public health measures in the novel coronavirus (2019-nCoV) outbreak.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jtm/taaa020</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang J., Hayashi Y., Frank L.D. COVID-19 and transport: Findings from a world-wide expert survey. Transport Policy. 2021;103:68–85. doi: 10.1016/j.tranpol.2021.01.011.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tranpol.2021.01.011</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7838579</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33519127</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang N., Jia W., Wang P., Dung C.H., Zhao P., Leung K., Su B., Cheng R., Li Y. Changes in local travel behaviour before and during the COVID-19 pandemic in Hong Kong. Cities. 2021;112 doi: 10.1016/J.CITIES.2021.103139.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/J.CITIES.2021.103139</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhu D., Mishra S.R., Han X., Santo K. Social distancing in Latin America during the COVID-19 pandemic: An analysis using the stringency index and Google Community mobility reports. Journal of Travel Medicine. 2020;27(8):1–3. doi: 10.1093/JTM/TAAA125.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/JTM/TAAA125</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
