<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35434053</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">2307-8960</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>10</Volume>
            <Issue>8</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Mar</Month>
              <Day>16</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>World journal of clinical cases</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>World J Clin Cases</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Fatal community-acquired bloodstream infection caused by <i>Klebsiella variicola</i>: A case report.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>2474</StartPage>
          <EndPage>2483</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>2474-2483</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.12998/wjcc.v10.i8.2474</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND"><i>Klebsiella pneumoniae</i> (<i>K. pneumoniae</i>) is an infective microorganism of worldwide concern because of its varied manifestations and life-threatening potential. Genetic analyses have revealed that subspecies of <i>K. pneumoniae</i> exhibit higher virulence and mortality. However, infections with <i>Klebsiella</i> subspecies are often misdiagnosed and underestimated in the clinic because of difficulties in distinguishing <i>K. pneumoniae</i> from its subspecies using routine tests. This case study reports the rapid and fatal effects of <i>K. pneumoniae</i> subspecies.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CASE SUMMARY" NlmCategory="METHODS">A 52-year-old male patient was febrile and admitted to hospital. Examinations excluded viral and fungal causes along with mycoplasma/chlamydia and parasitic infections. Bacterial cultures revealed blood-borne <i>K. pneumoniae</i> sensitive to carbapenem antibiotics, although corresponding treatment failed to improve the patient's symptoms. His condition worsened and death occurred within 72 h of symptom onset from sepsis shock. Application of the PMseq-DNA Pro high throughput gene detection assay was implemented with results obtained after death showing a mixed infection of <i>K. pneumoniae</i> and <i>Klebsiella variicola</i> (<i>K. variicola</i>). Clinical evidence suggested that <i>K. variicola</i> rather than <i>K. pneumoniae</i> contributed to the patient's poor prognosis.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This is the first case report to show patient death from <i>Klebsiella</i> subspecies infection within a short period of time. This case provides a timely reminder of the clinical hazards posed by <i>Klebsiella</i> subspecies and highlights the limitations of classical laboratory methods in guiding anti-infective therapies for complex cases. Moreover, this report serves as reference for physicians diagnosing similar diseases and provides a recommendation to employ early genetic detection to aid patient diagnosis and management.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>©The Author(s) 2022. Published by Baishideng Publishing Group Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Long</LastName>
            <ForeName>Da-Li</ForeName>
            <Initials>DL</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Intensive Care Unit, Guizhou Provincial People's Hospital, Guiyang 550000, Guizhou Province, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yu-Hui</ForeName>
            <Initials>YH</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Intensive Care Unit, Guizhou Provincial People's Hospital, Guiyang 550000, Guizhou Province, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jin-Long</ForeName>
            <Initials>JL</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Intensive Care Unit, Guizhou Provincial People's Hospital, Guiyang 550000, Guizhou Province, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Si-Jie</ForeName>
            <Initials>SJ</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Intensive Care Unit, Guizhou Provincial People's Hospital, Guiyang 550000, Guizhou Province, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Li</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Intensive Care Unit, Guizhou Provincial People's Hospital, Guiyang 550000, Guizhou Province, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Shi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xian-Qing</ForeName>
            <Initials>XQ</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Intensive Care Unit, Guizhou Provincial People's Hospital, Guiyang 550000, Guizhou Province, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Li</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jian-Quan</ForeName>
            <Initials>JQ</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Intensive Care Unit, Guizhou Provincial People's Hospital, Guiyang 550000, Guizhou Province, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>World J Clin Cases</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101618806</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2307-8960</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Case report</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Community-acquired bloodstream infection</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">High throughput gene detection</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Klebsiella pneumoniae</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Klebsiella variicola</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mixed infection</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>Conflict-of-interest statement: All authors declare that they have no competing interests to disclose.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>40</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35434053</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8968595</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12998/wjcc.v10.i8.2474</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martin RM, Bachman MA. Colonization, Infection, and the Accessory Genome of Klebsiella pneumoniae. Front Cell Infect Microbiol. 2018;8:4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5786545</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29404282</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Holt KE, Wertheim H, Zadoks RN, Baker S, Whitehouse CA, Dance D, Jenney A, Connor TR, Hsu LY, Severin J, Brisse S, Cao H, Wilksch J, Gorrie C, Schultz MB, Edwards DJ, Nguyen KV, Nguyen TV, Dao TT, Mensink M, Minh VL, Nhu NT, Schultsz C, Kuntaman K, Newton PN, Moore CE, Strugnell RA, Thomson NR. Genomic analysis of diversity, population structure, virulence, and antimicrobial resistance in Klebsiella pneumoniae, an urgent threat to public health. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2015;112:E3574–E3581.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4500264</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26100894</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shi Q, Lan P, Huang D, Hua X, Jiang Y, Zhou J, Yu Y. Diversity of virulence level phenotype of hypervirulent Klebsiella pneumoniae from different sequence type lineage. BMC Microbiol. 2018;18:94.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6116568</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30157774</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Seki M, Gotoh K, Nakamura S, Akeda Y, Yoshii T, Miyaguchi S, Inohara H, Horii T, Oishi K, Iida T, Tomono K. Fatal sepsis caused by an unusual Klebsiella species that was misidentified by an automated identification system. J Med Microbiol. 2013;62:801–803.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23449877</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Podschun R, Pietsch S, Höller C, Ullmann U. Incidence of Klebsiella species in surface waters and their expression of virulence factors. Appl Environ Microbiol. 2001;67:3325–3327.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC93022</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11425763</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paczosa MK, Mecsas J. Klebsiella pneumoniae: Going on the Offense with a Strong Defense. Microbiol Mol Biol Rev. 2016;80:629–661.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4981674</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27307579</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu C, Shi J, Guo J. High prevalence of hypervirulent Klebsiella pneumoniae infection in the genetic background of elderly patients in two teaching hospitals in China. Infect Drug Resist. 2018;11:1031–1041.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6074765</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30104891</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li J, Ren J, Wang W, Wang G, Gu G, Wu X, Wang Y, Huang M, Li J. Risk factors and clinical outcomes of hypervirulent Klebsiella pneumoniae induced bloodstream infections. Eur J Clin Microbiol Infect Dis. 2018;37:679–689.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29238932</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hodgson K, Morris J, Bridson T, Govan B, Rush C, Ketheesan N. Immunological mechanisms contributing to the double burden of diabetes and intracellular bacterial infections. Immunology. 2015;144:171–185.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4298412</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25262977</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Potter RF, Lainhart W, Twentyman J, Wallace MA, Wang B, Burnham CA, Rosen DA, Dantas G. Population Structure, Antibiotic Resistance, and Uropathogenicity of Klebsiella variicola. mBio. 2018;9</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6299229</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30563902</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rodríguez-Medina N, Martínez-Romero E, De la Cruz MA, Ares MA, Valdovinos-Torres H, Silva-Sánchez J, Lozano-Aguirre L, Martínez-Barnetche J, Andrade V, Garza-Ramos U. A Klebsiella variicola Plasmid Confers Hypermucoviscosity-Like Phenotype and Alters Capsule Production and Virulence. Front Microbiol. 2020;11:579612.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7772424</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33391198</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lat A, Clock SA, Wu F, Whittier S, Della-Latta P, Fauntleroy K, Jenkins SG, Saiman L, Kubin CJ. Comparison of polymyxin B, tigecycline, cefepime, and meropenem MICs for KPC-producing Klebsiella pneumoniae by broth microdilution, Vitek 2, and Etest. J Clin Microbiol. 2011;49:1795–1798.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3122677</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21367993</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bassetti M, Giacobbe DR, Giamarellou H, Viscoli C, Daikos GL, Dimopoulos G, De Rosa FG, Giamarellos-Bourboulis EJ, Rossolini GM, Righi E, Karaiskos I, Tumbarello M, Nicolau DP, Viale PL, Poulakou G Critically Ill Patients Study Group of the European Society of Clinical Microbiology and Infectious Disease (ESCMID);  Hellenic Society of Chemotherapy (HSC) and Società Italiana di Terapia Antinfettiva (SITA) Management of KPC-producing Klebsiella pneumoniae infections. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2018;24:133–144.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28893689</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Agyeman AA, Bergen PJ, Rao GG, Nation RL, Landersdorfer CB. A systematic review and meta-analysis of treatment outcomes following antibiotic therapy among patients with carbapenem-resistant Klebsiella pneumoniae infections. Int J Antimicrob Agents. 2020;55:105833.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31730892</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
