<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35435152</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>29</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1555-8592</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>18</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Dec</Month>
              <Day>31</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Organogenesis</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Organogenesis</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Hepatocyte Differentiation from iPSCs or MSCs in Decellularized Liver Scaffold: Cell-ECM Adhesion, Spatial Distribution, and Hepatocyte Maturation Profile.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>2061263</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>2061263</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2061263</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1080/15476278.2022.2061263</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Mesenchymal stem cells (MSC) and induced pluripotent stem cells (iPSC) have been reported to be able to differentiate to hepatocyte in vitro with varying degree of hepatocyte maturation. A simple method to decellularize liver scaffold has been established by the Department of Histology, Faculty of Medicine, Universitas Indonesia, in SCTE IMERI lab.<sup>15</sup> This study aims to evaluate hepatocyte differentiation from iPSCs compared to MSCs derived in our decellularized liver scaffold. The research stages started with iPSC culture, decellularization, seeding cell culture into the scaffold, and differentiation into hepatocytes for 21 days. Hepatocyte differentiation from iPSCs and MSCs in the scaffolds was characterized using hematoxylin-eosin, Masson Trichrome, and immunohistochemistry staining to determine the fraction of the differentiation area. RNA samples were isolated on days 7 and 21. Expression of albumin, CYP450, and CK-19 genes were analyzed using the qRT-PCR method. Electron microscopy images were obtained by SEM. Immunofluorescence examination was done using HNF4-α and CEBPA markers. The results of this study in hepatocyte-differentiated iPSCs compared with hepatocyte-differentiated MSCs in decellularized liver scaffold showed lower adhesion capacity, single-cell-formation and adhered less abundant, decreased trends of albumin, and lower CYP450 expression. Several factors contribute to this result: lower initial seeding number, which causes only a few iPSCs to attach to certain parts of decellularized liver scaffold, and manual syringe injection for recellularization, which abruptly and unevenly creates pattern of single-cell-formation by hepatocyte-differentiated iPSC in the scaffold. Hepatocyte-differentiated MSCs have the advantage of higher adhesion capacity to collagen fiber decellularized liver scaffold. This leads to positive result: increase trends of albumin and higher CYP450 expression. Hepatocyte maturation is shown by diminishing CK-19, which is more prominent in hepatocyte-differentiated iPSCs in decellularized liver scaffold. Confirmation of mature hepatocyte-differentiated iPSCs in decellularized liver scaffold maturation is positive for HNF4-a and CEBPA. The conclusion of this study is hepatocyte-differentiated iPSCs in decellularized liver scaffold is mature with lower cell-ECM adhesion, spatial cell distribution, albumin, and CYP450 expression than hepatocyte-differentiated MSCs in decellularized liver scaffold.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Antarianto</LastName>
            <ForeName>Radiana Dhewayani</ForeName>
            <Initials>RD</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8578-7505</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Histology, Faculty of Medicine, Universitas Indonesia, Jakarta, Indonesia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Stem cell and tissue engineering research cluster, (IMERI) Indonesian Medical Education and Research Institute, Jakarta Indonesia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Program Doktor Ilmu Biomedik, Faculty of Medicine, Universitas Indonesia, Jakarta, Indonesia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Pragiwaksana</LastName>
            <ForeName>Adrian</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Program Master Ilmu Biomedik, Faculty of Medicine, Universitas Indonesia, Jakarta, Indonesia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Septiana</LastName>
            <ForeName>Wahyunia Likhayati</ForeName>
            <Initials>WL</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Program Doktor Ilmu Biomedik, Faculty of Medicine, Universitas Indonesia, Jakarta, Indonesia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Histology, Faculty of Medicine, Universitas Gunadarma, Depok, Indonesia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mazfufah</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nuzli Fahdia</ForeName>
            <Initials>NF</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Stem cell and tissue engineering research cluster, (IMERI) Indonesian Medical Education and Research Institute, Jakarta Indonesia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mahmood</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ameer</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Stem cell unit Department of Anatomy, King Saud University, Riyadh, Kingdom Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Organogenesis</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101253266</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1547-6278</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000418">Albumins</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000418" MajorTopicYN="N">Albumins</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002454" MajorTopicYN="N">Cell Differentiation</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D022781" MajorTopicYN="N">Hepatocytes</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D057026" MajorTopicYN="Y">Induced Pluripotent Stem Cells</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008099" MajorTopicYN="N">Liver</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D054457" MajorTopicYN="N">Tissue Scaffolds</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000737" MajorTopicYN="N">chemistry</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hepatocyte</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MSCs</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">decellularized-liver-scaffold</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">differentiation</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">iPSCs</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>No potential conflict of interest was reported by the author(s).</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>8</Hour>
          <Minute>40</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35435152</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9037523</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15476278.2022.2061263</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kwong A, Kim W, Lake J, Smith J, Schladt D, Skeans M, Noreen SM, Foutz J, Booker SE, Cafarella M, et al. OPTN/SRTR 2019 annual data report: liver. Am J Transplant. 2021;21(S2):208–15. doi:10.1111/ajt.16494.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ajt.16494</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iansante V, Mitry R, Filippi C, Fitzpatrick E, Dhawan A.. 
Human hepatocyte transplantation for liver disease: current status and future perspectives. Pediatr Res. 2017;83(1–2):232–40. doi:10.1038/pr.2017.284.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/pr.2017.284</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29149103</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alizadeh E, Eslaminejad MB, Akbarzadeh A, Sadeghi Z, Abasi M, Herizchi R, Zarghami N. Upregulation of MiR-122 via trichostatin a treatments in hepatocyte-like cells derived from mesenchymal stem cells. Chem Biol Drug Des. 2016;87(2):296–305. doi:10.1111/cbdd.12664.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cbdd.12664</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26360933</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Banas A, Teratani T, Yamamoto Y, Tokuhara M, Takeshita F, Osaki M, Kato T, Okochi H, Ochiya T. Rapid hepatic fate specification of adipose-derived stem cells and their therapeutic potential for liver failure. J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2009;24(1):70–77. doi:10.1111/j.1440-1746.2008.05496.x.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1440-1746.2008.05496.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18624899</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li J, Xing F, Chen F, He L, So K, Liu Y. Functional 3D human liver bud assembled from MSC-derived multiple liver cell lineages. Cell Transplant. 2018;27(1):1–12. doi:10.1177/0963689717745332.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0963689717745332</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6434474</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29562780</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ma X, Duan Y, Tschudy-Seney B, Roll G, Behbahan IS, Ahuja TP, Tolstikov V, Wang C, McGee J, Khoobyari S, et al. Highly efficient differentiation of functional hepatocytes from human induced pluripotent stem cells. Stem Cells Transl Med. 2013;2(6):409–19. doi:10.5966/sctm.2012-0160.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5966/sctm.2012-0160</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3673753</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23681950</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Banas A, Teratani T, Yamamoto Y, Tokuhara M, Takeshita F, Quinn G, Okochi H, Ochiya T. Adipose tissue-derived mesenchymal stem cells as a source of human hepatocytes. Hepatology. 2007;46(1):219–28. doi:10.1002/hep.21704.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hep.21704</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17596885</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Szkolnicka D, Zhou W, Lucendo-Villarin B, Hay DC. Pluripotent stem cell– derived hepatocytes: potential and challenges in pharmacology. Annu Rev Pharmacol Toxicol. 2013;53(1):147–59. doi:10.1146/annurev-pharmtox-011112-140306.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev-pharmtox-011112-140306</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23294308</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ang L, Tan A, Autio M, Goh S, Choo S, Lee K, Tan J, Pan B, Lee JJH, Lum JJ. A roadmap for human liver differentiation from pluripotent stem cells. Cell Rep. 2018;22(8):2190–205. doi:10.1016/j.celrep.2018.01.087.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.celrep.2018.01.087</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5854481</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29466743</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nakai S, Shibata I, Shitamichi T, Yamaguchi H, Takagi N, Inoue T, Nakagawa T, Kiyokawa J, Wakabayashi S, Miyoshi T, Higashi E, Ishida S, Shiraki N, Kume S, et al. Collagen vitrigel promotes hepatocytic differentiation of induced pluripotent stem cells into functional hepatocyte- like cells. Biol Open. 2019;8(7):1. doi:10.1242/bio.042192.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1242/bio.042192</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blackford SJI, Ng SS, Segal JM, King AJF, Austin AL, Kent D, Moore J, Sheldon M, Ilic D, Dhawan A, Mitry RR, Rashid ST, et al. Validation of current good manufacturing practice compliant human pluripotent stem cell-derived hepatocytes for cell-based therapy. Stem Cells Transl Med. 2018;1. doi:10.1002/sctm.18-0084.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/sctm.18-0084</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Si-Tayeb K, Lemaigre FP, Duncan SA. Organogenesis and development of the liver. Dev Cell. 2010;18(2):175–89. doi:10.1016/j.devcel.2010.01.011.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.devcel.2010.01.011</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20159590</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ober E, Lemaigre F. Development of the liver: insights into organ and tissue morphogenesis. J Hepatol. 2018;68(5):1049–62. doi:10.1016/j.jhep.2018.01.005.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhep.2018.01.005</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29339113</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Antarianto RD, Dewi AA, Pragiwaksana A, Pawitan JA. Decellularization of liver cubes using multiple site syringe injection for generating native liver scaffold: preliminary report. AIP Conf Proc. 2019;2193:040005.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dewi AAAAP, Antarianto RD, Pawitan JA. Characterization of Indonesia decellularized liver cubes scaffold using scanning electron microscopy. JBBBE. 2021;52:38–46. 10.4028/www.scientific.net/JBBBE.52.38.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen KG, Mallon BS, McKay RD, Robey PG. Human pluripotent stem cell culture: considerations for maintenance, expansion, and therapeutics. Cell Stem Cell. 2014;14(1):13–26. doi:10.1016/j.stem.2013.12.005.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.stem.2013.12.005</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3915741</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24388173</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Induced Pluripotent Stem Cell Culture Protocols  [Internet]. Sigmaaldrich.com. 2021.  [cited 20
June 2021]. Available from: https://www.sigmaaldrich.com/ID/en/technical-documents/protocol/cell-culture-and-cell-culture-analysis/stem-cell-culture/human-ipsc-culture-protocols.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mirdamadi E, Kalhori D, Zakeri N, Azarpira N, Solati-Hashjin M. Liver tissue engineering as an emerging alternative for liver disease treatment. Tissue Eng Part B Rev. 2020;26(2):145–63. doi:10.1089/ten.teb.2019.0233.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/ten.teb.2019.0233</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31797731</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Si-Tayeb K, Noto FK, Nagaoka M, Li J, Battle MA, Duris C, North PE, Dalton S, Duncan SA. Highly efficient generation of human hepatocyte–like cells from induced pluripotent stem cells. Hepatology. 2010;51(1):297–305. doi:10.1002/hep.23354.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hep.23354</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2946078</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19998274</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Minami T, Ishii T, Yasuchika K, Fukumitsu K, Ogiso S, Miyauchi Y, Kojima H, Kawai T, Yamaoka R, Oshima Y. Novel hybrid three-dimensional artificial liver using human induced pluripotent stem cells and a rat decellularized liver scaffold. Regen Ther. 2019;10:127–33. doi:10.1016/j.reth.2019.03.002.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.reth.2019.03.002</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6477477</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31032388</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Takeishi K, de L’hortet AC, Wang Y, Handa K, Guzman-Lepe J, Matsubara K, Morita K, Jang S, Haep N, Florentino RM, et al. Assembly and function of a bioengineered human liver for transplantation generated solely from induced pluripotent stem cells. Cell Rep. 2020;31(9):107711. doi:10.1016/j.celrep.2020.107711.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.celrep.2020.107711</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7734598</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32492423</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Debnath T, Shekar Mallarpu C, Kiran Chelluri L. Development of bioengineered organ using biological acellular rat liver scaffold and hepatocytes. Organogenesis. 2020;16(2):61–72. doi:10.1080/15476278.2020.1742534.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15476278.2020.1742534</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7531620</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32362216</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ogiso S, Yasuchika K, Fukumitsu K, Ishii T, Kojima H, Miyauchi Y, Yamaoka R, Komori J, Katayama H, Kawai T, et al. Efficient recellularisation of decellularised whole-liver grafts using biliary tree and foetal hepatocytes. Sci Rep. 2016 Oct
21;6(1):1–10. doi:10.1038/srep35887.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/srep35887</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5431369</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28442746</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hillebrandt KH, Everwien H, Haep N, Keshi E, Pratschke J, Sauer IM. Strategies based on organ decellularization and recellularization. Transpl Int. 2019. 
Jun;32(6):571–85. doi:10.1111/tri.13462.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/tri.13462</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31099920</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ong S-Y, Dai H, Leong KW. Inducing hepatic differentiation of human mesenchymal stem cells in pellet culture. Biomaterials. 2006;27(22):4087–97. doi:10.1016/j.biomaterials.2006.03.022.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biomaterials.2006.03.022</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16616366</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aleahmad F, Ebrahimi S, Salmannezhad M, Azarnia M, Jaberipour M, Hoseini M, Talaei-Khozani T. Heparin/Collagen 3D scaffold accelerates hepatocyte differentiation of Wharton’s Jelly-derived mesenchymal stem cells. Tissue Eng Regen Med. 2017;14(4):443–52. doi:10.1007/s13770-017-0048-z.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13770-017-0048-z</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6171614</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30603500</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khodabandeh Z, Vojdani Z, Talaei-Khozani T, Bahmanpour S. Hepatogenic differentiation capacity of human Wharton’s jelly mesenchymal stem cell in a co-culturing system with endothelial cells in matrigel/collagen scaffold in the presence of fetal liver extract. Int J Stem Cell. 2017;10(2):218. doi:10.15283/ijsc17003.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15283/ijsc17003</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Graffmann N, Ncube A, Wruck W, Adjaye J. Cell fate decisions of human iPSC-derived bipotential hepatoblasts depend on cell density. PLOS ONE. 2018;13(7):e0200416. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0200416.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0200416</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6039024</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29990377</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muncie JM, Weaver VM. The physical and biochemical properties of the extracellular matrix regulate cell fate. Curr Top Dev Biol. 2018;130:1–37.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6586474</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29853174</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang B, Jakus A, Baptista P, Soker S, Soto-Gutierrez A, Abecassis M, Shah RN, Wertheim JA. Functional maturation of induced pluripotent stem cell hepatocytes in extracellular matrix—A comparative analysis of bioartificial liver microenvironments. Stem Cells Transl Med. 2016;5(9):1257–67. doi:10.5966/sctm.2015-0235.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5966/sctm.2015-0235</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4996436</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27421950</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jaramillo M, Yeh H, Yarmush ML, Uygun BE. Decellularized human liver extracellular matrix (hDLM)‐mediated hepatic differentiation of human induced pluripotent stem cells (hIPSCs). J Tissue Eng Regen Med. 2018;12(4):e1962–73. doi:10.1002/term.2627.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/term.2627</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5906168</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29222839</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Luo Y, Lou C, Zhang S, Zhu Z, Xing Q, Wang P, Liu T, Liu H, Li C, Shi W, et al. Three-dimensional hydrogel culture conditions promote the differentiation of human induced pluripotent stem cells into hepatocytes. Cytotherapy. 2018 Jan
1;20(1):95–107. doi:10.1016/j.jcyt.2017.08.008.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcyt.2017.08.008</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28969895</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kehtari M, Beiki B, Zeynali B, Hosseini FS, Soleimanifar F, Kaabi M, Soleimani M, Enderami SE, Kabiri M, Mahboudi H. Decellularized Wharton’s jelly extracellular matrix as a promising scaffold for promoting hepatic differentiation of human induced pluripotent stem cells. J Cell Biochem. 2019;120(4):6683–97. doi:10.1002/jcb.27965.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcb.27965</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30417406</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sekine K, Tsuzuki S, Yasui R, Kobayashi T, Ikeda K, Hamada Y, Kanai E, Camp JG, Treutlein B, Ueno Y, et al. Robust detection of undifferentiated iPSC among differentiated cells. Sci Rep. 2020 Jun
24;10(1):1–9. doi:10.1038/s41598-020-66845-6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-020-66845-6</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6959339</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31913322</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schwartz RE, Fleming HE, Khetani SR, Bhatia SN. Pluripotent stem cell- derived hepatocyte-like cells. Biotechnol Adv. 2014;32(2):504–13. doi:10.1016/j.biotechadv.2014.01.003.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biotechadv.2014.01.003</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4043206</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24440487</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gieseck IIIRL, Hannan NR, Bort R, Hanley NA, Drake RA, Cameron GW, Wynn TA, Vallier L. Maturation of induced pluripotent stem cell derived hepatocytes by 3D-culture. PloS one. 2014 Jan
22;9(1):e86372. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0086372.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0086372</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3899231</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24466060</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Starokozhko V, Hemmingsen M, Larsen L, Mohanty S, Merema M, Pimentel RC, Wolff A, Emnéus J, Aspegren A, Groothuis G, et al. Differentiation of human‐induced pluripotent stem cell under flow conditions to mature hepatocytes for liver tissue engineering. J Tissue Eng Regen Med. 2018. 
May;12(5):1273–84. doi:10.1002/term.2659.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/term.2659</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5969064</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29499107</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Park K, Hussein K, Hong S, Ahn C, Yang S, Park S, Kweon O-K, Kim B-M, Woo H-M. Decellularized liver extracellular matrix as promising tools for transplantable bioengineered liver promotes hepatic lineage commitments of induced pluripotent stem cells. Tissue Eng Part A. 2016;22(5–6):449–60. doi:10.1089/ten.tea.2015.0313.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/ten.tea.2015.0313</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26801816</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bertucci T, Dai G. Biomaterial engineering for controlling pluripotent stem cell fate. Stem Cells Int. 2018;2018:1–12. doi:10.1155/2018/9068203.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2018/9068203</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cotovio J, Fernandes T. Production of human pluripotent stem cell-derived hepatic cell lineages and liver organoids: current status and potential applications. Bioengineering. 2020;7(2):36. doi:10.3390/bioengineering7020036.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/bioengineering7020036</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abbey D, Elwyn S, Hand N, Musunuru K, Rader D. Self‐organizing human induced pluripotent stem cell hepatocyte 3D organoids inform the biology of the pleiotropic TRIB1 gene. Hepatol Commun. 2020;4(9):1316–31. doi:10.1002/hep4.1538.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hep4.1538</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7471428</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32923835</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>DeLaForest A, Di Furio F, Jing R, Ludwig-Kubinski A, Twaroski K, Urick A, Pulakanti K, Rao S, Duncan SA. HNF4A regulates the formation of hepatic progenitor cells from human iPSC-derived endoderm by facilitating efficient recruitment of RNA Pol II. Genes. 2019;10(1):21. doi:10.3390/genes10010021.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/genes10010021</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Viiri LE, Rantapero T, Kiamehr M, Alexanova A, Oittinen M, Viiri K, Niskanen H, Nykter M, Kaikkonen MU, Aalto-Setälä K. Extensive reprogramming of the nascent transcriptome during iPSC to hepatocyte differentiation. Sci Rep. 2019;9(1):1–2. doi:10.1038/s41598-019-39215-0.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-019-39215-0</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6327027</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30626917</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tauran Y, Poulain S, Lereau-Bernier M, Danoy M, Shinohara M, Segard BD, Kato S, Kido T, Miyajima A, Sakai Y, et al. Analysis of the transcription factors and their regulatory roles during a step-by-step differentiation of induced pluripotent stem cells into hepatocyte-like cells. Molecular Omics. 2019;15(6):383–98. doi:10.1039/C9MO00122K.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/C9MO00122K</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31612883</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
