<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35437451</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>07</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">1865-5041</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Apr</Month>
              <Day>14</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Memo</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Memo</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Agony of choice-selecting chronic lymphocytic leukemia treatment in 2022.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>1</StartPage>
          <EndPage>4</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>1-4</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s12254-022-00804-x</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The treatment landscape of chronic lymphocytic leukemia (CLL) has undergone profound change in recent years. Targeted therapies have outnumbered chemotherapy-based treatment approaches demonstrating superior efficacy and tolerability profiles across nearly all CLL patient subgroups in the frontline and relapsed disease treatment setting. Individual selection of these novel agents is rather driven by patients' comorbidities and personal preferences than fitness and age. Given the high amount of currently licensed novel agents in both treatment-naïve as well as relapsed CLL patients and currently limited evidence from comparative clinical trials, clinicians sometimes appear spoilt for choice when selecting optimal therapy. This short review discusses recent clinical trial data focusing on treatment with targeted drugs and aims to help guide CLL treatment selection in individual patients.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© The Author(s) 2022.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bohn</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jan-Paul</ForeName>
            <Initials>JP</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2066-7377</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine V, Hematology and Oncology, Medical University of Innsbruck, Anichstr. 35, 6020 Innsbruck, Austria.</Affiliation>
              <Identifier Source="GRID">grid.5361.1</Identifier>
              <Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0000 8853 2677</Identifier>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>04</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Memo</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101467972</NlmUniqueID>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Acalabrutinib</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chemoimmunotherapy</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ibrutinib</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Venetoclax</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>Conflict of interestJ.-P. Bohn reports personal fees from AbbVie, Astra-Zeneca and Janssen for advisory board participation.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35437451</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9008377</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12254-022-00804-x</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">804</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shanafelt TD, Wang XV, Kay NE, Hanson CA, O’Brien S, Barrientos J, Jelinek DF, Braggio E, Leis JF, Zhang CC, et al.  Ibrutinib-Rituximab or chemoimmunotherapy for chronic lymphocytic leukemia. N Engl J Med. 2019;381:432–443. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1817073.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1817073</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6908306</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31365801</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eichhorst B, Robak T, Montserrat E, Ghia P, Niemann CU, Kater AP, Gregor M, Cymbalista F, Buske C, Hillmen P, et al.  Chronic lymphocytic leukaemia: ESMO clinical practice guidelines for diagnosis, treatment and follow-up. Ann Oncol. 2021;32:23–33. doi: 10.1016/j.annonc.2020.09.019.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.annonc.2020.09.019</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33091559</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eichhorst B, Niemann C, Kater AP, Fürstenau M, Von Tresckow J, Zhang C, Robrecht S, Gregor M, Juliusson G, Thornton P, et al.  A randomized phase III study of Venetoclax-based time-limited combination treatments (RVe, GVe, GIVe) vs standard chemoimmunotherapy (CIT: FCR/BR) in frontline chronic lymphocytic leukemia (CLL) of fit patients: first co-primary endpoint analysis of the international intergroup GAIA (CLL13) trial. Blood. 2021;138:71–71. doi: 10.1182/blood-2021-146161.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/blood-2021-146161</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koehler AB, Leung N, Call TG, Rabe KG, Achenbach SJ, Ding W, Kenderian SS, Leis JF, Wang Y, Muchtar E, et al.  Incidence and risk of tumor lysis syndrome in patients with relapsed chronic lymphocytic leukemia (CLL) treated with venetoclax in routine clinical practice. Leuk Lymphoma. 2020;61:2383–2388. doi: 10.1080/10428194.2020.1768384.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10428194.2020.1768384</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32449401</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Munir T, Brown JR, O’Brien S, Barrientos JC, Barr PM, Reddy NM, Coutre S, Tam CS, Mulligan SP, Jaeger U, et al.  Final analysis from RESONATE: Up to six years of follow-up on ibrutinib in patients with previously treated chronic lymphocytic leukemia or small lymphocytic lymphoma. Am J Hematol. 2019;94:1353–1363. doi: 10.1002/ajh.25638.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ajh.25638</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6899718</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31512258</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Burger JA, Barr PM, Robak T, Owen C, Ghia P, Tedeschi A, Bairey O, Hillmen P, Coutre SE, Devereux S, et al.  Long-term efficacy and safety of first-line ibrutinib treatment for patients with CLL/SLL: 5 years of follow-up from the phase 3 RESONATE-2 study. Leukemia. 2020;34:787–798. doi: 10.1038/s41375-019-0602-x.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41375-019-0602-x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7214263</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31628428</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coutre SE, Byrd JC, Hillmen P, Barrientos JC, Barr PM, Devereux S, Robak T, Kipps TJ, Schuh A, Moreno C, et al.  Long-term safety of single-agent ibrutinib in patients with chronic lymphocytic leukemia in 3 pivotal studies. Blood Adv. 2019;3:1799–1807. doi: 10.1182/bloodadvances.2018028761.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/bloodadvances.2018028761</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6595265</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31196847</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Munir T, Pitchford A, Bloor A, Broom A, Young M, Kennedy B, Walewska R, Furtado M, Preston G, Neilson JR, et al.  Sudden or cardiac deaths on Ibrutinib-based therapy were associated with a prior history of hypertension or cardiac disease and the use of ACE-inhibitors at study entry: analysis from the phase III NCRI FLAIR trial. Blood. 2021;138:2636–2636. doi: 10.1182/blood-2021-152167.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/blood-2021-152167</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Byrd JC, Hillmen P, Ghia P, Kater AP, Chanan-Khan A, Furman RR, O’Brien S, Yenerel MN, Illés A, Kay N, et al.  Acalabrutinib versus Ibrutinib in previously treated chronic lymphocytic leukemia: results of the first randomized phase III trial. J Clin Oncol. 2021;39:3441–3452. doi: 10.1200/jco.21.01210.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/jco.21.01210</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8547923</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34310172</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Woyach JA, Ruppert AS, Heerema NA, Zhao W, Booth AM, Ding W, Bartlett NL, Brander DM, Barr PM, Rogers K, et al.  Long-term results of alliance A041202 show continued advantage of Ibrutinib-based regimens compared with Bendamustine plus Rituximab (BR) chemoimmunotherapy. Blood. 2021;138:639–639. doi: 10.1182/blood-2021-153146.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/blood-2021-153146</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Al-Sawaf O, Zhang C, Tandon M, Sinha A, Fink AM, Robrecht S, Samoylova O, Liberati AM, Pinilla-Ibarz J, Opat S, et al.  Venetoclax plus obinutuzumab versus chlorambucil plus obinutuzumab for previously untreated chronic lymphocytic leukaemia (CLL14): follow-up results from a multicentre, open-label, randomised, phase 3 trial. Lancet Oncol. 2020;21:1188–1200. doi: 10.1016/s1470-2045(20)30443-5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s1470-2045(20)30443-5</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32888452</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kater AP, Wu JQ, Kipps T, Eichhorst B, Hillmen P, D’Rozario J, Assouline S, Owen C, Robak T, de la Serna J, et al.  Venetoclax plus Rituximab in relapsed chronic lymphocytic leukemia: 4-year results and evaluation of impact of genomic complexity and gene mutations from the MURANO phase III study. J Clin Oncol. 2020;38:4042–4054. doi: 10.1200/jco.20.00948.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/jco.20.00948</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7768340</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32986498</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jones JA, Mato AR, Wierda WG, Davids MS, Choi M, Cheson BD, Furman RR, Lamanna N, Barr PM, Zhou L, et al.  Venetoclax for chronic lymphocytic leukaemia progressing after ibrutinib: an interim analysis of a multicentre, open-label, phase 2 trial. Lancet Oncol. 2018;19:65–75. doi: 10.1016/S1470-2045(17)30909-9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1470-2045(17)30909-9</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6027999</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29246803</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mato AR, Roeker LE, Jacobs R, Hill BT, Lamanna N, Brander D, Shadman M, Ujjani CS, Yazdy MS, Perini GF, et al.  Assessment of the efficacy of therapies following Venetoclax discontinuation in CLL reveals BTK inhibition as an effective strategy. Clin Cancer Res. 2020;26:3589–3596. doi: 10.1158/1078-0432.Ccr-19-3815.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/1078-0432.Ccr-19-3815</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8588795</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32198151</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Furman RR, Sharman JP, Coutre SE, Cheson BD, Pagel JM, Hillmen P, Barrientos JC, Zelenetz AD, Kipps TJ, Flinn I, et al.  Idelalisib and Rituximab in relapsed chronic lymphocytic leukemia. N Engl J Med. 2014;370:997–1007. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1315226.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1315226</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4161365</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24450857</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Flinn IW, Hillmen P, Montillo M, Nagy Z, Illés Á, Etienne G, Delgado J, Kuss BJ, Tam CS, Gasztonyi Z, et al.  The phase 3 DUO trial: duvelisib vs ofatumumab in relapsed and refractory CLL/SLL. Blood. 2018;132:2446–2455. doi: 10.1182/blood-2018-05-850461.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/blood-2018-05-850461</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6284216</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30287523</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stilgenbauer S, Eichhorst B, Schetelig J, Hillmen P, Seymour JF, Coutre S, Jurczak W, Mulligan SP, Schuh A, Assouline S, et al.  Venetoclax for patients with chronic lymphocytic leukemia with 17p deletion: Results from the full population of a phase II pivotal trial. J Clin Oncol. 2018;36:1973–1980. doi: 10.1200/jco.2017.76.6840.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/jco.2017.76.6840</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29715056</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mato AR, Hill BT, Lamanna N, Barr PM, Ujjani CS, Brander DM, Howlett C, Skarbnik AP, Cheson BD, Zent CS, et al.  Optimal sequencing of ibrutinib, idelalisib, and venetoclax in chronic lymphocytic leukemia: results from a multicenter study of 683 patients. Ann Oncol. 2017;28:1050–1056. doi: 10.1093/annonc/mdx031.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/annonc/mdx031</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28453705</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hampel PJ, Call TG, Ding W, Muchtar E, Kenderian SS, Wang Y, Leis JF, Witzig TE, Koehler AB, Fonder AL, et al.  Addition of venetoclax at time of progression in ibrutinib-treated patients with chronic lymphocytic leukemia: Combination therapy to prevent ibrutinib flare. Am J Hematol. 2020;95:E57–E60. doi: 10.1002/ajh.25690.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ajh.25690</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31788844</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vijenthira A, Gong IY, Fox TA, Booth S, Cook G, Fattizzo B, Martín-Moro F, Razanamahery J, Riches JC, Zwicker J, et al.  Outcomes of patients with hematologic malignancies and COVID-19: a systematic review and meta-analysis of 3377 patients. Blood. 2020;136:2881–2892. doi: 10.1182/blood.2020008824.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/blood.2020008824</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7746126</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33113551</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Treon SP, Castillo JJ, Skarbnik AP, Soumerai JD, Ghobrial IM, Guerrera ML, Meid K, Yang G. The BTK inhibitor ibrutinib may protect against pulmonary injury in COVID-19-infected patients. Blood. 2020;135:1912–1915. doi: 10.1182/blood.2020006288.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/blood.2020006288</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7243149</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32302379</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fürstenau M, Langerbeins P, De Silva N, Fink AM, Robrecht S, von Tresckow J, Simon F, Hohloch K, Droogendijk J, van der Klift M, et al.  COVID-19 among fit patients with CLL treated with venetoclax-based combinations. Leukemia. 2020;34:2225–2229. doi: 10.1038/s41375-020-0941-7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41375-020-0941-7</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7323604</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32601378</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Buske C, Dreyling M, Alvarez-Larrán A, Apperley J, Arcaini L, Besson C, Bullinger L, Corradini P, Giovanni Della Porta M, Dimopoulos M, et al.  Managing hematological cancer patients during the COVID-19 pandemic: an ESMO-EHA interdisciplinary expert consensus. ESMO Open. 2022;7:100403. doi: 10.1016/j.esmoop.2022.100403.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.esmoop.2022.100403</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8795783</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35272130</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bagacean C, Letestu R, Al-Nawakil C, Brichler S, Lévy V, Sritharan N, Delmer A, Dartigeas C, Leblond V, Roos-Weil D, et al.  Humoral response to mRNA anti-COVID-19 vaccines BNT162b2 and mRNA-1273 in patients with chronic lymphocytic leukemia. Blood Adv. 2022;6:207–211. doi: 10.1182/bloodadvances.2021006215.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1182/bloodadvances.2021006215</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8632355</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34844264</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
