<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35446825</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>12</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1532-0987</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>41</Volume>
            <Issue>6</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
              <Day>01</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>The Pediatric infectious disease journal</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Pediatr Infect Dis J</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Late-onset Group B Streptococcus Bacteremia Evaluated in the Pediatric Emergency Department and Risk Factors for Severe Infection.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>455</StartPage>
          <EndPage>459</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>455-459</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/INF.0000000000003520</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND">To describe the infants presenting to pediatric emergency departments (PEDs) and diagnosed with group B Streptococcus (GBS) late-onset disease (LOD) bacteremia and identify risk factors for severe infection and pediatric intensive care unit (PICU) admission.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS">Observational study and subanalysis of a multicenter prospective registry. Setting: pediatric emergency department. Inclusion criteria: infants between 7 and 89 days of age with positive blood culture for GBS seen between 2011 and 2016 at any of 22 Spanish PEDs. Main outcome: risk factors (clinical and laboratory variables) for severe infection (sepsis/septic shock or meningitis) and PICU admission. Second, the prevalence of poor outcomes (acute complications, sequelae or death).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS">Among 118 patients with LOD, 74 (62.7%) presented a severe infection: 66 sepsis/septic shock (11 with associated meningitis) and 8 meningitis. Thirty-five patients (29.7%) were admitted to a PICU. An altered Pediatric Assessment Triangle (PAT) upon arrival and leukopenia were the only independent risk factors for severe infection [odds ratio (OR): 43.6; 95% confidence interval (CI): 8.1-235.7, P &lt; 0.01] and PICU admission (OR: 11.6; 95% CI: 1.5-91.4; P &lt; 0.019), respectively. Six patients (5.1%) developed a poor outcome, including 2 deaths (1.7%); all had an altered PAT, elevated procalcitonin (range 4.7-100 ng/ml), and were diagnosed with sepsis/septic shock and admitted to a PICU. Four developed leukopenia.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS">Infants with GBS LOD frequently develop sepsis/septic shock and bacterial meningitis, associated with non-negligible morbidity and mortality. Clinical appearance was the only risk factor for severe infection, whereas leukopenia was related to PICU admission.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ecclesia</LastName>
            <ForeName>Francesco Giuseppe</ForeName>
            <Initials>FG</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6173-9613</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Pediatric Emergency Department, Hospital Infantil Universitario Niño Jesús, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Alonso Cadenas</LastName>
            <ForeName>José Antonio</ForeName>
            <Initials>JA</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Pediatric Emergency Department, Hospital Infantil Universitario Niño Jesús, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gómez</LastName>
            <ForeName>Borja</ForeName>
            <Initials>B</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Pediatric Emergency Department, Hospital Cruces (Barakaldo), Vizcaya, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gangoiti</LastName>
            <ForeName>Iker</ForeName>
            <Initials>I</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Pediatric Emergency Department, Hospital Cruces (Barakaldo), Vizcaya, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hernández-Bou</LastName>
            <ForeName>Susanna</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Pediatric Emergency Department, Hospital Sant Joan de Déu (Esplugues de Llobregat), Barcelona, Spain Bacteremia Study Working Group from the Infectious Diseases Working Group, Spanish Society of Pediatric Emergencies (SEUP).</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>de la Torre Espí</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mercedes</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Pediatric Emergency Department, Hospital Infantil Universitario Niño Jesús, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <CollectiveName>Bacteremia Study Working Group from the Infectious Diseases Working Group, Spanish Society of Pediatric Emergencies</CollectiveName>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016448">Multicenter Study</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D064888">Observational Study</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>06</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Pediatr Infect Dis J</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8701858</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0891-3668</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016470" MajorTopicYN="Y">Bacteremia</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000382" MajorTopicYN="N">microbiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004636" MajorTopicYN="N">Emergency Service, Hospital</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007223" MajorTopicYN="N">Infant</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015278" MajorTopicYN="N">Intensive Care Units, Pediatric</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007970" MajorTopicYN="Y">Leukopenia</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012189" MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective Studies</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D018805" MajorTopicYN="Y">Sepsis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012772" MajorTopicYN="Y">Shock, Septic</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013292" MajorTopicYN="N">Streptococcus agalactiae</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors have no funding or conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>17</Hour>
          <Minute>11</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35446825</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/INF.0000000000003520</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">00006454-990000000-00060</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Greenhow TL, Hung YY, Herz AM. Changing epidemiology of bacteremia in infants aged 1 week to 3 months. Pediatrics. 2012;129:e590–e596.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Greenhow TL, Hung YY, Herz AM, et al. The changing epidemiology of serious bacterial infections in young infants. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2014;33:595–599.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Biondi E, Evans R, Mischler M, et al. Epidemiology of bacteremia in febrile infants in the United States. Pediatrics. 2013;132:990–996.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nanduri SA, Petit S, Smelser C, et al. Epidemiology of invasive early-onset and late-onset Group B Streptococcal Disease in the United States, 2006 to 2015: multistate laboratory and population-based surveillance. JAMA Pediatr. 2019;173:224–233.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schrag SJ, Zywicki S, Farley MM, et al. Group B streptococcal disease in the era of intrapartum antibiotic prophylaxis. N Engl J Med. 2000;342:15–20.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jordan HT, Farley MM, Craig A, et al.; Active Bacterial Core Surveillance (ABCs)/Emerging Infections Program Network, CDC. Revisiting the need for vaccine prevention of late-onset neonatal group B streptococcal disease: a multistate, population-based analysis. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2008;27:1057–1064.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gomez B, Hernandez-Bou S, Garcia-Garcia JJ, et al.; Bacteraemia Study Working Group from the Infectious Diseases Working Group, Spanish Society of Pediatric Emergencies (SEUP). Bacteremia in previously healthy children in emergency departments: clinical and microbiological characteristics and outcome. Eur J Clin Microbiol Infect Dis. 2015;34:453–460.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goldstein B, Giroir B, Randolph A; International Consensus Conference on Pediatric Sepsis. International pediatric sepsis consensus conference: definitions for sepsis and organ dysfunction in pediatrics. Pediatr Crit Care Med. 2005;6:2–8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de la Torre M, de Lucas N, Velasco R, et al.; [Aetiology and outcomes of potentially serious infections in febrile infants less than 3 months old]. An Pediatr (Barc). 2017;87:4249.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Powell EC, Mahajan PV, Roosevelt G, et al.; Febrile Infant Working Group of the Pediatric Emergency Care Applied Research Network (PECARN). Epidemiology of bacteremia in febrile infants aged 60 days and younger. Ann Emerg Med. 2018;71:211–216.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elgoibar B, Gangoiti I, Garcia-Garcia JJ, et al.; Bacteremia Study Working Group from the Infectious Diseases Working Group, Spanish Society of Pediatric Emergencies (SEUP). Paediatric Escherichia coli bacteraemia presentations and high-risk factors in the emergency department. Acta Paediatr. 2021;110:1032–1037.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berardi A, Rossi C, Lugli L, et al.; GBS Prevention Working Group, Emilia-Romagna. Group B streptococcus late-onset disease: 2003-2010. Pediatrics. 2013;131:e361–e368.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Puopolo KM, Lynfield R, Cummings JJ; Committee On Fetus And Newborn; Committee On Infectious Diseases. Management of infants at risk for group B streptococcal disease. Pediatrics. 2019;144:e20191881.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Madhi SA, Cutland CL, Jose L, et al. Safety and immunogenicity of an investigational maternal trivalent group B streptococcus vaccine in healthy women and their infants: a randomised phase 1b/2 trial. Lancet Infect Dis. 2016;16:923–934.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dzanibe S, Madhi SA. Systematic review of the clinical development of group B streptococcus serotype-specific capsular polysaccharide-based vaccines. Expert Rev Vaccines. 2018;17:635–651.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hillier SL, Ferrieri P, Edwards MS, et al. A Phase 2, Randomized, Control Trial of Group B Streptococcus (GBS) Type III Capsular Polysaccharide-tetanus Toxoid (GBS III-TT) vaccine to prevent vaginal colonization with GBS III. Clin Infect Dis. 2019;68:2079–2086.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kuppermann N, Dayan PS, Levine DA, et al.; Febrile Infant Working Group of the Pediatric Emergency Care Applied Research Network (PECARN). A clinical prediction rule to identify febrile infants 60 days and younger at low risk for serious bacterial infections. JAMA Pediatr. 2019;173:342–351.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gomez B, Mintegi S, Bressan S, et al.; European Group for Validation of the Step-by-Step Approach. Validation of the “Step-by-Step” approach in the management of young febrile infants. Pediatrics. 2016;138:e20154381.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gomez B, Bressan S, Mintegi S, et al. Diagnostic value of procalcitonin in well-appearing young febrile infants. Pediatrics. 2012;130:815–822.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hatherill M, Tibby SM, Sykes K, et al. Diagnostic markers of infection: comparison of procalcitonin with C reactive protein and leucocyte count. Arch Dis Child. 1999;81:417–421.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deis JN, Creech CB, Estrada CM, et al. Procalcitonin as a marker of severe bacterial infection in children in the emergency department. Pediatr Emerg Care. 2010;26:51–60; quiz 61.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gomez B, Mintegi S, Lopez E, et al. Diagnostic value of leukopenia in young febrile infants. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2012;31:92–95.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gomez B, Mintegi S, Benito J; Group for the Study of Febrile Infant of the RiSeuP-SPERG Network. A prospective multicenter study of leukopenia in infants younger than ninety days with fever without source. Pediatr Infect Dis J. 2016;35:25–29.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hernández-Bou S, Álvarez Álvarez C, Campo Fernández MN, et al. [Blood cultures in the paediatric emergency department. Guidelines and recommendations on their indications, collection, processing and interpretation]. An Pediatr (Barc). 2016;84:294.e1–e9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
