<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35444497</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>23</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">1535-7597</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>22</Volume>
            <Issue>2</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Season>Mar-Apr</Season>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Epilepsy currents</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Epilepsy Curr</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Stroke and Ischemic Heart Disease With Enzyme-inducing Antiseizure Medications: Time to Change Prescribing Habits.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>120</StartPage>
          <EndPage>122</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>120-122</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1177/15357597211070392</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText><b>Importance</b>: Enzyme-inducing antiseizure medications (eiASMs) have been hypothesized to be associated with long-term risks of cardiovascular disease. <b>Objective</b>: To quantify and model the putative hazard of cardiovascular disease secondary to eiASM use. <b>Design, Setting, and Participants</b>: This cohort study covered January 1990 to March 2019 (median [IQR] follow-up, 9 [4-15], years). The study linked primary care and hospital electronic health records at National Health Service hospitals in England. People aged 18 years or older diagnosed as having epilepsy after January 1, 1990, were included. All eligible patients were included with a waiver of consent. No patients were approached who withdrew consent. Analysis began January 2021 and ended August 2021. <b>Exposures</b>: Receipt of 4 consecutive EI ASMs (carbamazepine, eslicarbazepine, oxcarbazepine, phenobarbital, phenytoin, primidone, rufinamide, or topiramate) following an adult-onset (age &gt;/=18 years) epilepsy diagnosis or repeated exposure in a weighted cumulative exposure model. <b>Main Outcomes and Measures</b>: Three cohorts were isolated, 1 of which comprised all adults meeting a case definition for epilepsy diagnosed after 1990, 1 comprised incident cases diagnosed after 1998 (hospital linkage date), and 1 was limited to adults diagnosed with epilepsy at 65 years or older. Outcome was incident cardiovascular disease (ischemic heart disease or ischemic or hemorrhagic stroke). Hazard of incident cardiovascular disease was evaluated using adjusted propensity-matched survival analyses and weighted cumulative exposure models. <b>Results</b>: Of 10,916,166 adults, 50,888 (.6%) were identified as having period-prevalent cases (median [IQR] age, 32 [19-50] years; 16 584 [53%] female), of whom 31,479 (62%) were diagnosed on or after 1990 and were free of cardiovascular disease at baseline. In a propensity-matched Cox proportional hazards model adjusted for age, sex, baseline socioeconomic status, and cardiovascular risk factors, the hazard ratio for incident cardiovascular disease was 1.21 (95% CI, 1.06-1.39) for those receiving eiASMs. The absolute difference in cumulative hazard diverges by more than 1% and greater after 10 years. For those with persistent exposure beyond 4 prescriptions, the median hazard ratio increased from a median (IQR) of 1.54 (1.28-1.79) when taking a relative defined daily dose of an eiASM of 1 to 2.38 (1.52-3.56) with a relative defined daily dose of 2 throughout a maximum of 25 years' follow-up compared with those not receiving an eiASM. The hazard was elevated but attenuated when restricting analyses to incident cases or those diagnosed when older than 65 years. <b>Conclusions and Relevance</b>: The hazard of incident cardiovascular disease is higher in those receiving eiASMs. The association is dose dependent and the absolute difference in hazard seems to reach clinical significance by approximately 10 years from first exposure.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© The Author(s) 2022.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Vossler</LastName>
            <ForeName>David G</ForeName>
            <Initials>DG</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4823-0537</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>University of Washington Medicine, Renton, WA, USA.</Affiliation>
              <Identifier Source="RINGGOLD">384632</Identifier>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>01</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Epilepsy Curr</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101135954</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1535-7511</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>43</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35444497</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8988723</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/15357597211070392</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1177_15357597211070392</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Surges R, Shmuely S, Dietze C, Ryvlin P, Thijs RD. Identifying patients with epilepsy at high risk of cardiac death: signs, risk factors and initial management of high risk of cardiac death. Epileptic Disord. 2021;23(1):17-39. doi:10.1684/epd.2021.1254.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1684/epd.2021.1254</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33650492</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bardai A, Blom MT, van Noord C, Verhamme KM, Sturkenboom MCJM, Tan HL. Sudden cardiac death is associated both with epilepsy and with use of antiepileptic medications. Heart. 2015;101(1):17-22. doi:10.1136/heartjnl-2014-305664.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/heartjnl-2014-305664</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25031263</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee‐Lane E, Torabi F, Lacey A, et al.. Epilepsy, antiepileptic drugs, and the risk of major cardiovascular events. Epilepsia. 2021;62(7):1604-1616. doi:10.1111/epi.16930.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.16930</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34046890</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>French JA, Perucca E, Sander JW, et al.. FDA Safety Warning on the Cardiac Effects of Lamotrigine: An Advisory From the Ad Hoc ILAE/AES Task Force. Epilepsy Currents. 2021;21(3):150-153. doi:10.1177/1535759721996344.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1535759721996344</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8609589</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33641454</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Josephson CB, Wiebe S, Delgado-Garcia G, et al.. Association of Enzyme-Inducing Antiseizure Drug Use With Long-term Cardiovascular Disease. JAMA Neurol. 2021;78(11):1367-1374. doi:10.1001/jamaneurol.2021.3424.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaneurol.2021.3424</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34605857</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mintzer S, Skidmore CT, Abidin CJ, et al.. Effects of antiepileptic drugs on lipids, homocysteine, and C-reactive protein. Ann Neurol. 2009;65(4):448-456. doi:10.1002/ana.21615.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.21615</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19296463</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Isojärvi JIT, Pakarinen AJ, Myllyla VV. Serum Lipid Levels During Carbamazepine Medication. Arch Neurol. 1993;50(6):590-593. doi:10.1001/archneur.1993.00540060030012.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archneur.1993.00540060030012</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8099275</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vossler DG, Weingarten M, Gidal BE, American Epilepsy Society Treatments C. Summary of Antiepileptic Drugs Available in the United States of America. Epilepsy Currents. 2018;18(suppl 1-4):1-26. doi:10.5698/1535-7597.18.4s1.1.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5698/1535-7597.18.4s1.1</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6130739</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30233275</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mintzer S, Trinka E, Kraemer G, Chervoneva I, Werhahn KJ. Impact of carbamazepine, lamotrigine, and levetiracetam on vascular risk markers and lipid-lowering agents in the elderly. Epilepsia. 2018;59(10):1899-1907. doi:10.1111/epi.14554.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.14554</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30178473</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hookana E, Ansakorpi H, Kortelainen M-L, et al.. Antiepileptic medications and the risk for sudden cardiac death caused by an acute coronary event: a prospective case-control study. Ann Med. 2016;48(1-2):111-117. doi:10.3109/07853890.2016.1140225.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/07853890.2016.1140225</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26838936</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
