<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35445777</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>21</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2982</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Apr</Month>
              <Day>21</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Neurogastroenterology and motility : the official journal of the European Gastrointestinal Motility Society</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Neurogastroenterol Motil</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Systematic review: Clinical effectiveness of interventions for the treatment of nocturnal gastroesophageal reflux.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e14385</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e14385</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/nmo.14385</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Nocturnal gastroesophageal reflux symptoms have a major impact on sleep quality and are associated with complicated gastroesophageal reflux disease (GERD). We performed a systematic review to assess the data on the effectiveness of the currently available interventions for the treatment of nocturnal reflux symptoms.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We searched PubMed, EMBASE, and the Cochrane Library. All prospective, controlled, and uncontrolled clinical trials in adult patients describing interventions (lifestyle modifications, surgical and pharmacological) for nocturnal gastroesophageal reflux symptoms were assessed for eligibility. A narrative descriptive summary of findings is presented together with summary tables for study characteristics and quality assessment.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="KEY RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The initial reference search yielded 3067 citations; 66 citations were screened in full text, of which 31 articles were included. Studies on lifestyle modifications include head of bed elevation (n = 5), prolonging dinner-to-bed time (n = 2), and promoting left lateral decubitus position (n = 2). Placebo-controlled clinical trials investigating proton pump inhibitors (PPIs) (n = 11) show success rates ranging from 34.4% to 80.8% in the PPI group versus 10.4%-51.7% in the placebo group. Laparoscopic fundoplication is reserved for severe disease only. There is insufficient evidence for a recommendation on the use of nasal continuous positive airway pressure (nCPAP), hypnotics, baclofen and adding bedtime H2 receptor antagonists for reducing nocturnal reflux. CONCLUSION INFERENCES: A sequential treatment strategy, including head of bed elevation, prolonging dinner-to-bed time, promoting left lateral decubitus position and treatment with acid-suppressive medication is recommended for nocturnal gastroesophageal reflux symptoms. Currently, there is insufficient evidence for the use of nCPAP, hypnotics, baclofen and adding bedtime H2 receptor antagonists.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Authors. Neurogastroenterology &amp; Motility published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Schuitenmaker</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jeroen M</ForeName>
            <Initials>JM</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1213-3551</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology &amp; Hepatology, Amsterdam Gastroenterology and Metabolism, University Medical Centers Amsterdam, Amsterdam, The Netherlands.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kuipers</LastName>
            <ForeName>Thijs</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5503-5505</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology &amp; Hepatology, Amsterdam Gastroenterology and Metabolism, University Medical Centers Amsterdam, Amsterdam, The Netherlands.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Smout</LastName>
            <ForeName>André J P M</ForeName>
            <Initials>AJPM</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7796-6282</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology &amp; Hepatology, Amsterdam Gastroenterology and Metabolism, University Medical Centers Amsterdam, Amsterdam, The Netherlands.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Fockens</LastName>
            <ForeName>Paul</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2382-0672</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology &amp; Hepatology, Amsterdam Gastroenterology and Metabolism, University Medical Centers Amsterdam, Amsterdam, The Netherlands.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bredenoord</LastName>
            <ForeName>Albert J</ForeName>
            <Initials>AJ</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5918-2062</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology &amp; Hepatology, Amsterdam Gastroenterology and Metabolism, University Medical Centers Amsterdam, Amsterdam, The Netherlands.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>04</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Neurogastroenterol Motil</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9432572</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1350-1925</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lifestyle modification</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nocturnal</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">reflux</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">treatment</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>8</Hour>
          <Minute>47</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35445777</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/nmo.14385</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Revicki DA, Wood M, Maton PN, Sorensen S. The impact of gastroesophageal reflux disease on health-related quality of life. Am J Med. 1998;104(3):252-258.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shaker R, Castell DO, Schoenfeld PS, Spechler SJ. Nighttime heartburn is an under-appreciated clinical problem that impacts sleep and daytime function: the results of a Gallup survey conducted on behalf of the American Gastroenterological Association. Am J Gastroenterol. 2003;98(7):1487-1493.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dubois RW, Aguilar D, Fass R, et al. Consequences of frequent nocturnal gastro-oesophageal reflux disease among employed adults: symptom severity, quality of life and work productivity. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2007;25(4):487-500.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Orr WC. Sleep and gastroesophageal reflux: what are the risks?Am J Med. 2003;115(3 Suppl. 1):109-113.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Freidin N, Fisher MJ, Taylor W, et al. Sleep and nocturnal acid reflux in normal subjects and patients with reflux oesophagitis. Gut. 1991;32(11):1275-1279.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bredenoord AJ, Hemmink GJ, Smout AJ. Relationship between gastro-oesophageal reflux pattern and severity of mucosal damage. Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2009;21(8):807-812.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lagergren J, Bergstrom R, Lindgren A, Nyren O. Symptomatic gastroesophageal reflux as a risk factor for esophageal adenocarcinoma. N Engl J Med. 1999;340(11):825-831.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fass R, Achem SR, Harding S, et al. Review article: supra-oesophageal manifestations of gastro-oesophageal reflux disease and the role of night-time gastro-oesophageal reflux. Alimentary Pharmacology &amp; Therapeutics. 2004;20:26-38.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Poelmans J, Tack J. Extraoesophageal manifestations of gastro-oesophageal reflux. Gut. 2005;54(10):1492-1499.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tutuian R, Castell DO. Nocturnal acid breakthrough - approach to management. MedGenMed. 2004;6(4):11.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chey WD, Mody RR, Wu EQ, et al. Treatment patterns and symptom control in patients with GERD: US community-based survey. Curr Med Res Opin. 2009;25(8):1869-1878.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shibli F, Skeans J, Yamasaki T, Fass R. Nocturnal Gastroesophageal Reflux Disease (GERD) and sleep: an important relationship that is commonly overlooked. J Clin Gastroenterol. 2020;54(8):663-674.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gerson LB, Fass R. A systematic review of the definitions, prevalence, and response to treatment of nocturnal gastroesophageal reflux disease. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2009;7(4):372-378.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moher D, Shamseer L, Clarke M, et al. Preferred reporting items for systematic review and meta-analysis protocols (PRISMA-P) 2015 statement. Syst Rev. 2015;4(1):1.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ouzzani M, Hammady H, Fedorowicz Z, Elmagarmid A. Rayyan - a web and mobile app for systematic reviews. Syst Rev. 2016;5. doi:10.1186/s13643-016-0384-4</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>EndNote. Clarivate; 2013.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sterne JAC, Savović J, Page MJ, et al. RoB 2: a revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ. 2019;366:l4898.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sterne JAC, Hernán MA, Reeves BC, et al. ROBINS-I: a tool for assessing risk of bias in non-randomised studies of interventions. BMJ. 2016;355:i4919.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Villamil Morales IM, Gallego Ospina DM, Otero Regino WA. Impact of head of bed elevation in symptoms of patients with gastroesophageal reflux disease: a randomized single-blind study (IBELGA). Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2020;43(6):310-321.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huang H-C, Chang Y-J, Tseng Y-L, Fang S-Y. Effect of head-of-bed elevation on nocturnal reflux symptoms of esophageal cancer patients with esophagectomy and reconstruction. Cancer Nurs. 2019;44(3):244-250.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hamilton JW, Boisen RJ, Yamamoto DT, Wagner JL, Reichelderfer M. Sleeping on a wedge diminishes exposure of the esophagus to refluxed acid. Dig Dis Sci. 1988;33(5):518-522.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harvey RF, Hadley N, Gill TR, et al. Effects of sleeping with the bed-head raised and of ranitidine in patients with severe peptic oesophagitis. Lancet. 1987;2(8569):1200-1203.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khan BA, Sodhi JS, Zargar SA, et al. Effect of bed head elevation during sleep in symptomatic patients of nocturnal gastroesophageal reflux. J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2012;27(6):1078-1082.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Orr WC, Harnish MJ. Sleep-related gastro esophageal reflux: provocation with a late evening meal and treatment with acid suppression. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 1998;12(10):1033-1038.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Piesman M, Hwang I, Maydonovitch C, Wong RK. Nocturnal reflux episodes following the administration of a standardized meal. Does timing matter?Am J Gastroenterol. 2007;102(10):2128-2134.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schuitenmaker JM, vanDijk M, Oude Nijhuis RAB, Smout A, Bredenoord AJ. Associations between sleep position and nocturnal gastroesophageal reflux: a study using concurrent monitoring of sleep position and esophageal pH and impedance. Am J Gastroenterol. 2022;117(2):346-351.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tierney WS, Gabbard SL, Milstein CF, Benninger MS, Bryson PC. Treatment of laryngopharyngeal reflux using a sleep positioning device: a prospective cohort study. Am J Otolaryngol. 2017;38(5):603-607.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Epstein LJ, Kristo D, Strollo PJJr, et al. Clinical guideline for the evaluation, management and long-term care of obstructive sleep apnea in adults. J Clin Sleep Med. 2009;5(3):263-276.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kerr P, Shoenut JP, Millar T, Buckle P, Kryger MH. Nasal CPAP reduces gastroesophageal reflux in obstructive sleep apnea syndrome. Chest. 1992;101(6):1539-1544.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kerr P, Shoenut JP, Steens RD, Millar T, Micflikier AB, Kryger MH. Nasal continuous positive airway pressure. A new treatment for nocturnal gastroesophageal reflux?J Clin Gastroenterol. 1993;17(4):276-280.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>The effect of nasal CPAP on nocturnal reflux in patients with aperistaltic esophagus. Version 3. 1994. Accessed 9. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/8082351/</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Green BT, Broughton WA, O'Connor JB. Marked improvement in nocturnal gastroesophageal reflux in a large cohort of patients with obstructive sleep apnea treated with continuous positive airway pressure. Arch Intern Med. 2003;163(1):41-45.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tawk M, Goodrich S, Kinasewitz G, Orr W. The effect of 1 week of continuous positive airway pressure treatment in obstructive sleep apnea patients with concomitant gastroesophageal reflux. Chest. 2006;130(4):1003-1008.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shepherd K, Hillman D, Holloway R, Eastwood P. Mechanisms of nocturnal gastroesophageal reflux events in obstructive sleep apnea. Sleep Breath. 2011;15(3):561-570.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ing AJ, Ngu MC, Breslin AB. Obstructive sleep apnea and gastroesophageal reflux. Am J Med. 2000;108:120s-125s.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnson DA, Orr WC, Crawley JA, et al. Effect of esomeprazole on nighttime heartburn and sleep quality in patients with GERD: a randomized, placebo-controlled trial. Am J Gastroenterol. 2005;100(9):1914-1922.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnson D, Crawley JA, Hwang C, Brown K. Clinical trial: esomeprazole for moderate-to-severe nighttime heartburn and gastro-oesophageal reflux disease-related sleep disturbances. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2010;32(2):182-190.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fass R, Chey WD, Zakko SF, et al. Clinical trial: the effects of the proton pump inhibitor dexlansoprazole MR on daytime and nighttime heartburn in patients with non-erosive reflux disease. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2009;29(12):1261-1272.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fass R, Johnson DA, Orr WC, et al. The effect of dexlansoprazole MR on nocturnal heartburn and GERD-related sleep disturbances in patients with symptomatic GERD. Am J Gastroenterol. 2011;106(3):421-431.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peura DA, Riff DS, Snoddy AM, Fennerty MB. Clinical trial: lansoprazole 15 or 30 mg once daily vs. placebo for treatment of frequent nighttime heartburn in self-treating subjects. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2009;30(5):459-468.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Orr WC, Craddock A, Goodrich S. Acidic and non-acidic reflux during sleep under conditions of powerful acid suppression. Chest. 2007;131(2):460-465.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Orr WC, Goodrich S, Robert J. The effect of acid suppression on sleep patterns and sleep-related gastro-oesophageal reflux. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2005;21(2):103-108.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pehlivanov ND, Olyaee M, Sarosiek I, McCallum RW. Comparison of morning and evening administration of rabeprazole for gastro-oesophageal reflux and nocturnal gastric acid breakthrough in patients with reflux disease: a double-blind, cross-over study. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2003;18(9):883-890.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miner P, Delemos B, Xiang J, Lococo J, Ieni J. Effects of a single dose of rabeprazole 20 mg and pantoprazole 40 mg on 24-h intragastric acidity and oesophageal acid exposure: a randomized study in gastro-oesophageal reflux disease patients with a history of nocturnal heartburn. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2010;31(9):991-1000.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Janiak P, Thumshirn M, Menne D, et al. Clinical trial: the effects of adding ranitidine at night to twice daily omeprazole therapy on nocturnal acid breakthrough and acid reflux in patients with systemic sclerosis - a randomized controlled, cross-over trial. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2007;26(9):1259-1265.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Orr WC, Harnish MJ. The efficacy of omeprazole twice daily with supplemental H2 blockade at bedtime in the suppression of nocturnal oesophageal and gastric acidity. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2003;17(12):1553-1558.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang Q, Lehmann A, Rigda R, Dent J, Holloway RH. Control of transient lower oesophageal sphincter relaxations and reflux by the GABAB agonist baclofen in patients with gastro-oesophageal reflux disease. Gut. 2002;50(1):19-24.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Orr WC, Goodrich S, Wright S, Shepherd K, Mellow M. The effect of baclofen on nocturnal gastroesophageal reflux and measures of sleep quality: a randomized, cross-over trial. Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2012;24(6):pp. 553-9, e253.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jha LK, Fass R, Gadam R, et al. The effect of ramelteon on heartburn symptoms of patients with gastroesophageal reflux disease and chronic insomnia: a pilot study. J Clin Gastroenterol. 2016;50(2):e19-e24.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gagliardi GS, Shah AP, Goldstein M, et al. Effect of zolpidem on the sleep arousal response to nocturnal esophageal acid exposure. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2009;7(9):948-952.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cohen JA, Arain A, Harris PA, et al. Surgical trial investigating nocturnal gastroesophageal reflux and sleep (STINGERS). Surg Endosc. 2003;17(3):394-400.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yamasaki T, Quan SF, Fass R. The effect of sleep deficiency on esophageal acid exposure of healthy controls and patients with gastroesophageal reflux disease. Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2019;31(12):e13705.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hila A, Castell DO. Nighttime reflux is primarily an early event. J Clin Gastroenterol. 2005;39(7):579-583.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oude Nijhuis RAB, Sweis R, Abdul-Razakq H, et al. Characterisation of patients with supine nighttime reflux: observations made with prolonged wireless oesophageal pH monitoring. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2021;54(2):144-152.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fujiwara Y, Machida AI, Watanabe Y, et al. Association between dinner-to-bed time and gastro-esophageal reflux disease. Am J Gastroenterol. 2005;100(12):2633-2636.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Katz PO, Dunbar KB, Schnoll-Sussman FH, Greer KB, Yadlapati R, Spechler SJ. ACG clinical guideline for the diagnosis and management of gastroesophageal reflux disease. J Am Coll Gastroenterol. 2022;117(1):27-56. doi:10.14309/ajg.0000000000001538</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaltenbach T, Crockett S, Gerson LB. Are lifestyle measures effective in patients with gastroesophageal reflux disease?: An evidence-based approach. Arch Intern Med. 2006;166(9):965-971.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Allampati S, Lopez R, Thota PN, Ray M, Birgisson S, Gabbard SL. Use of a positional therapy device significantly improves nocturnal gastroesophageal reflux symptoms. Dis Esophagus. 2017;30(3):1-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Person E, Rife C, Freeman J, Clark A, Castell DO. A novel sleep positioning device reduces gastroesophageal reflux: a randomized controlled trial. J Clin Gastroenterol. 2015;49(8):655-659.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Katz PO, Dunbar KB, Schnoll-Sussman FH, Greer KB, Yadlapati R, Spechler SJ. ACG clinical guideline for the diagnosis and management of gastroesophageal reflux disease. Am J Gastroenterol. 2022;117(1):27-56.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peghini PL, Katz PO, Bracy NA, Castell DO. Nocturnal recovery of gastric acid secretion with twice-daily dosing of proton pump inhibitors. Am J Gastroenterol. 1998;93(5):763-767.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang Y, Pan T, Wang Q, Guo Z. Additional bedtime H2-receptor antagonist for the control of nocturnal gastric acid breakthrough. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2009;(4).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shin JM, Kim N. Pharmacokinetics and pharmacodynamics of the proton pump inhibitors. J Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2013;19(1):25-35.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ours TM, Fackler WK, Richter JE, Vaezi MF. Nocturnal acid breakthrough: clinical significance and correlation with esophageal acid exposure. Am J Gastroenterol. 2003;98(3):545-550.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghoshal UC, Chourasia D, Tripathi S, Misra A, Singh K. Relationship of severity of gastroesophageal reflux disease with gastric acid secretory profile and esophageal acid exposure during nocturnal acid breakthrough: a study using 24-h dual-channel pH-metry. Scand J Gastroenterol. 2008;43(6):654-661.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weigt J, Kandulski A, Büsch F, Malfertheiner P. Nocturnal gastric acid breakthrough is not associated with night-time gastroesophageal reflux in GERD patients. Dig Dis. 2009;27(1):68-73.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McRorie JW, Kirby JA, Miner PB. Histamine2-receptor antagonists: Rapid development of tachyphylaxis with repeat dosing. World J Gastrointest Pharmacol Ther. 2014;5(2):57-62.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mardani J, Lundell L, Engström C. Total or posterior partial fundoplication in the treatment of GERD: results of a randomized trial after 2 decades of follow-up. Ann Surg. 2011;253(5):875-878.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lafullarde T, Watson DI, Jamieson GG, Myers JC, Game PA, Devitt PG. Laparoscopic Nissen fundoplication: five-year results and beyond. Arch Surg. 2001;136(2):180-184.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Basoglu OK, Vardar R, Tasbakan MS, et al. Obstructive sleep apnea syndrome and gastroesophageal reflux disease: the importance of obesity and gender. Sleep Breath. 2015;19(2):585-592.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heinemann S, Graf KI, Karaus M, Dorow P. Occurrence of obstructive sleep related respiratory disorder in conjunction with gastroesophageal reflux. Pneumologie. 1995;49(Suppl 1):139-141.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kuribayashi S, Kusano M, Kawamura O, et al. Mechanism of gastroesophageal reflux in patients with obstructive sleep apnea syndrome. Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2010;22(6):611-e172.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kuribayashi S, Massey BT, Hafeezullah M, et al. Upper esophageal sphincter and gastroesophageal junction pressure changes act to prevent gastroesophageal and esophagopharyngeal reflux during apneic episodes in patients with obstructive sleep apnea. Chest. 2010;137(4):769-776.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Warren RL, Davis SM. The role of baclofen in the treatment of gastroesophageal reflux disease. J Pharm Technol. 2015;31(6):258-261.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
