<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35468258</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>06</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2982</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Apr</Month>
              <Day>25</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Neurogastroenterology and motility : the official journal of the European Gastrointestinal Motility Society</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Neurogastroenterol Motil</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Fasting pyloric diameter and distensibility by functional endoluminal imaging probe in unsedated healthy volunteers.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e14386</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e14386</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/nmo.14386</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Recent studies with functional endoluminal imaging probe (EndoFLIP<sup>®</sup> ) measure physiologic characteristics of the pylorus. EndoFLIP<sup>®</sup> has the potential to select optimal candidates for gastric peroral endoscopic myotomy (G-POEM). Normative values of the pylorus using EndoFLIP<sup>®</sup> have not been established.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Twenty-four healthy volunteers (20-56 years old; 15 females) underwent unsedated, transoral EndoFLIP<sup>®</sup> measurements of the pylorus after 8 h of fasting. Measurements of diameter (DM), balloon pressure, and distensibility index (DI) of the pylorus were obtained twice over 5 min at 40, 50, and 60 ml balloon distensions.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="KEY RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Pyloric DM at 40, 50, and 60 ml balloon distensions were 13.0 ± 2.5, 14.3 ± 1.8, and 17.2 ± 2.0 mm, respectively. DM with 60 ml distension was notably higher than with 40 and 50 ml distensions. Pyloric DI at 40, 50, and 60 ml distensions were 10.9 ± 4.8, 11.3 ± 5.8, and 11.1 ± 4.3 mm<sup>2</sup> /mm Hg, respectively (p = 0.86). Linear regression and Bland-Altman plots showed similar distribution of the DM and DI during the second minute compared with the full 5-min measurements at 50 ml distension, as well as between two sequential measurements using 50 ml distension. With 50 ml balloon distension, intraindividual coefficients of variation (COV<sub>intra</sub> ) for DM and DI were 13.8% and 29.6%, respectively, and interindividual COV (COV<sub>inter</sub> ) were 12.6% and 51.3%, respectively. Similar reproducibility was obtained with 40 ml balloon distension.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS AND INFERENCES" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Unsedated EndoFLIP<sup>®</sup> can be used to characterize human fasting pyloric diameter and distensibility, with best performance observed with 40 ml and 50 ml distensions and data collection during the second minute. Normative values reported serve as reference values for future studies.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zheng</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ting</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Clinical Enteric Neuroscience Translational and Epidemiological Research (CENTER), Division of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, Minnesota, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Vosoughi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kia</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6797-9386</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Clinical Enteric Neuroscience Translational and Epidemiological Research (CENTER), Division of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, Minnesota, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Busciglio</LastName>
            <ForeName>Irene</ForeName>
            <Initials>I</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Clinical Enteric Neuroscience Translational and Epidemiological Research (CENTER), Division of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, Minnesota, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tebay</LastName>
            <ForeName>Lisa</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Clinical Enteric Neuroscience Translational and Epidemiological Research (CENTER), Division of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, Minnesota, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Burton</LastName>
            <ForeName>Duane</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Clinical Enteric Neuroscience Translational and Epidemiological Research (CENTER), Division of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, Minnesota, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Camilleri</LastName>
            <ForeName>Michael</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6472-7514</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Clinical Enteric Neuroscience Translational and Epidemiological Research (CENTER), Division of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, Minnesota, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <GrantList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>R01 DK125680</GrantID>
            <Acronym>DK</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIDDK NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>R01-DK122280andR01-DK125680</GrantID>
            <Acronym>NH</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
        </GrantList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>04</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Neurogastroenterol Motil</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9432572</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1350-1925</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">G-POEM</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">area</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">compliance</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">gastroparesis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tone</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>31</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
          <Hour>17</Hour>
          <Minute>25</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35468258</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/nmo.14386</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mearin F, Camilleri M, Malagelada JR. Pyloric dysfunction in diabetics with recurrent nausea and vomiting. Gastroenterology. 1986;90(6):1919-1925.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aghaie Meybodi M, Qumseya BJ, Shakoor D, et al. Efficacy and feasibility of G-POEM in management of patients with refractory gastroparesis: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Endosc Int Open. 2019;7(3):E322-E329.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vosoughi K, Ichkhanian Y, Benias P, et al. Gastric per-oral endoscopic myotomy (G-POEM) for refractory gastroparesis: results from an international prospective trial. Gut. 2022;71(1):25-33.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hustak RMJ, Vackova Z, et al. Endoscopic pyloromyotomy (G-POEM) improves symptoms in patients with refractory gastroparesis - a randomized sham controlled trial. United Eur Gastroenterol J. 2021;9:10-11.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zheng T, Camilleri M. Selecting optimal patients with gastroparesis for G-POEM procedure. Gut. 2022;71(4):659-660.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Desprez C, Melchior C, Wuestenberghs F, et al. Pyloric distensibility measurement predicts symptomatic response to intrapyloric botulinum toxin injection. Gastrointest Endosc. 2019;90(5):754-760 e751.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jacques J, Pagnon L, Hure F, et al. Peroral endoscopic pyloromyotomy is efficacious and safe for refractory gastroparesis: prospective trial with assessment of pyloric function. Endoscopy. 2019;51(1):40-49.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gregor L, Wo J, DeWitt J, et al. Gastric peroral endoscopic myotomy for the treatment of refractory gastroparesis: a prospective single-center experience with mid-term follow-up (with video). Gastrointest Endosc. 2021;94(1):35-44.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Conchillo JM, Straathof JWA, Mujagic Z, et al. Gastric peroral endoscopic pyloromyotomy for decompensated gastroparesis: comprehensive motility analysis in relation to treatment outcomes. Endosc Int Open. 2021;9(2):E137-E144.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Attaar M, Su B, Wong HJ, et al. Significant changes in impedance planimetry (EndoFLIP) measurements after peroral pyloromyotomy for delayed gastric emptying. Surg Endosc. 2022;36(2):1536-1543.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Watts LS, Baker JR, Lee ALA, et al. Impact of gastric per-oral endoscopic myotomy on static and dynamic pyloric function in gastroparesis patients. Neurogastroent Motil. 2020;32(11):e13892.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vosoughi K, Ichkhanian Y, Jacques J, et al. Role of endoscopic functional luminal imaging probe in predicting the outcome of gastric peroral endoscopic pyloromyotomy (with video). Gastrointest Endosc. 2020;91(6):1289-1299.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Camilleri M, Lembo A, Katzka DA. Opioids in gastroenterology: treating adverse effects and creating therapeutic benefits. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2017;15(9):1338-1349.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Camilleri M, Sanders KM. Opiates, the pylorus, and gastroparesis. Gastroenterology. 2020;159(2):414-421.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>deLeon A, Ahlstrand R, Thorn SE, Wattwil M. Effects of propofol on oesophageal sphincters: a study on young and elderly volunteers using high-resolution solid-state manometry. Eur J Anaesthesiol. 2011;28(4):273-278.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schnoor J, Unger JK, Kuepper T, et al. Effects of propofol and fentanyl on duodenal motility activity in pigs. Can Vet J. 2005;46(11):995-1001.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Inada T, Asai T, Yamada M, Shingu K. Propofol and midazolam inhibit gastric emptying and gastrointestinal transit in mice. Anesth Analg. 2004;99(4):1102-1106.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Diss LB, Villeneuve S, Pearce KR, Yeoman MS, Patel BA. Region specific differences in the effect of propofol on the murine colon result in dysmotility. Auton Neurosci. 2019;219:19-24.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jagtap N, Kalapala R, Reddy DN. Assessment of pyloric sphincter physiology using functional luminal imaging probe in healthy volunteers. J Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2020;26(3):391-396.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gourcerol G, Tissier F, Melchior C, et al. Impaired fasting pyloric compliance in gastroparesis and the therapeutic response to pyloric dilatation. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2015;41(4):360-367.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Talley NJ, Phillips SF, Wiltgen CM, Zinsmeister AR, Melton LJ3rd. Assessment of functional gastrointestinal disease: the bowel disease questionnaire. Mayo Clin Proc. 1990;65(11):1456-1479.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Locke GR, Talley NJ, Weaver AL, Zinsmeister AR. A new questionnaire for gastroesophageal reflux disease. Mayo Clin Proc. 1994;69(6):539-547.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jehangir A, Malik Z, Petrov RV, Parkman HP. EndoFLIP and pyloric dilation for gastroparesis symptoms refractory to Pyloromyotomy/Pyloroplasty. Dig Dis Sci. 2021;66(8):2682-2690.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Malik Z, Sankineni A, Parkman HP. Assessing pyloric sphincter pathophysiology using EndoFLIP in patients with gastroparesis. Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2015;27(4):524-531.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Desprez C, Roman S, Leroi AM, Gourcerol G. The use of impedance planimetry (Endoscopic Functional Lumen Imaging Probe, EndoFLIP(R)) in the gastrointestinal tract: A systematic review. Neurogastroent Motil. 2020;32(9):e13980.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
