<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35467405</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>25</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2165-0497</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Apr</Month>
              <Day>25</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Microbiology spectrum</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Microbiol Spectr</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Construction and Analysis of the Complete Genome Sequence of Leprosy Agent Mycobacterium lepromatosis.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e0169221</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e0169221</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1128/spectrum.01692-21</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Leprosy is caused by Mycobacterium leprae and Mycobacterium <i>lepromatosis</i>. We report construction and analyses of the complete genome sequence of <i>M. lepromatosis</i> FJ924. The genome contained 3,271,694 nucleotides to encode 1,789 functional genes and 1,564 pseudogenes. It shared 1,420 genes and 885 pseudogenes (71.4%) with M. leprae but differed in 1,281 genes and pseudogenes (28.6%). In phylogeny, the leprosy bacilli started from a most recent common ancestor (MRCA) that diverged ~30 million years ago (Mya) from environmental organism Mycobacterium haemophilum. The MRCA then underwent reductive evolution with pseudogenization, gene loss, and chromosomal rearrangements. Analysis of the shared pseudogenes estimated the pseudogenization event ~14 Mya, shortly before species bifurcation. Afterwards, genomic changes occurred to lesser extent in each species. Like M. leprae, four major types of highly repetitive sequences were detected in <i>M. lepromatosis</i>, contributing to chromosomal rearrangements within and after MRCA. Variations in genes and copy numbers were noted, such as three copies of the gene encoding bifunctional diguanylate cyclase/phosphodiesterase in <i>M. lepromatosis</i>, but single copy in M. leprae; 6 genes encoding the TetR family transcriptional regulators in <i>M. lepromatosis</i>, but 11 such genes in M. leprae; presence of <i>hemW</i> gene in <i>M. lepromatosis</i>, but absence in M. leprae; and others. These variations likely aid unique pathogenesis, such as diffuse lepromatous leprosy associated with <i>M. lepromatosis</i>, while the shared genomic features should explain the common pathogenesis of dermatitis and neuritis in leprosy. Together, these findings and the genomic data of <i>M. lepromatosis</i> may facilitate future research and care for leprosy. <b>IMPORTANCE</b> Leprosy is a dreaded infection that still affects millions of people worldwide. Mycobacterium <i>lepromatosis</i> is a recently recognized cause in addition to the well-known Mycobacterium leprae. <i>M. lepromatosis</i> is likely specific for diffuse lepromatous leprosy, a severe form of the infection and endemic in Mexico. This study constructed and annotated the complete genome sequence of <i>M. lepromatosis</i> FJ924 and performed comparative genomic analyses with related mycobacteria. The results afford new and refined insights into the genome size, gene repertoire, pseudogenes, phylogenomic relationship, genome organization and plasticity, process and timing of reductive evolution, and genetic and proteomic basis for pathogenesis. The availability of the complete <i>M. lepromatosis</i> genome may prove to be useful for future research and care for the infection.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Silva</LastName>
            <ForeName>Francisco J</ForeName>
            <Initials>FJ</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6911-6541</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute for Integrative Systems Biology (I2SysBio), University of Valenciagrid.5338.d and CSIC, Paterna, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Genomics and Health Area, Foundation for the Promotion of Sanitary and Biomedical Research, Valencia, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Santos-Garcia</LastName>
            <ForeName>Diego</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3401-2662</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Laboratory of Biometry and Evolutionary Biology UMR CNRS, University of Lyon, Villeurbanne, France.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zheng</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xiaofeng</ForeName>
            <Initials>X</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Bioinformatics and Computational Biology, The University of Texas MD Anderson Cancer Center, Houston, Texas, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Li</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Bioinformatics and Computational Biology, The University of Texas MD Anderson Cancer Center, Houston, Texas, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Han</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xiang Y</ForeName>
            <Initials>XY</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8472-0870</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Laboratory Medicine, The University of Texas MD Anderson Cancer Center, Houston, Texas, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>04</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Microbiol Spectr</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101634614</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2165-0497</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mycobacterium leprae</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mycobacterium lepromatosis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">genomics</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">leprosy</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">reductive evolution</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>28</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35467405</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/spectrum.01692-21</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
