<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35466500</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>29</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-0193</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Apr</Month>
              <Day>25</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Human brain mapping</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Hum Brain Mapp</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Differences in working memory coding of biological motion attributed to oneself and others.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/hbm.25879</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The question how the brain distinguishes between information about self and others is of fundamental interest to both philosophy and neuroscience. In this functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI) study, we sought to distinguish the neural substrates of representing a full-body movement as one's movement and as someone else's movement. Participants performed a delayed match-to-sample working memory task where a retained full-body movement (displayed using point-light walkers) was arbitrarily labeled as one's own movement or as performed by someone else. By using arbitrary associations we aimed to address a limitation of previous studies, namely that our own movements are more familiar to us than movements of other people. A searchlight multivariate decoding analysis was used to test where information about types of movement and about self-association was coded. Movement specific activation patterns were found in a network of regions also involved in perceptual processing of movement stimuli, however not in early sensory regions. Information about whether a memorized movement was associated with the self or with another person was found to be coded by activity in the left middle frontal gyrus (MFG), left inferior frontal gyrus (IFG), bilateral supplementary motor area, and (at reduced threshold) in the left temporoparietal junction (TPJ). These areas are frequently reported as involved in action understanding (IFG, MFG) and domain-general self/other distinction (TPJ). Finally, in univariate analysis we found that selecting a self-associated movement for retention was related to increased activity in the ventral medial prefrontal cortex.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Authors. Human Brain Mapping published by Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Woźniak</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mateusz</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1693-7020</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Cognition and Philosophy Lab, Department of Philosophy, Monash University, Melbourne, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Social Mind and Body Research Group, Department of Cognitive Science, Central European University, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Neurocomputation and Neuroimaging Unit (NNU), Department of Education and Psychology, Freie Universität Berlin, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Schmidt</LastName>
            <ForeName>Timo Torsten</ForeName>
            <Initials>TT</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Neurocomputation and Neuroimaging Unit (NNU), Department of Education and Psychology, Freie Universität Berlin, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yuan-Hao</ForeName>
            <Initials>YH</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Neurocomputation and Neuroimaging Unit (NNU), Department of Education and Psychology, Freie Universität Berlin, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Blankenburg</LastName>
            <ForeName>Felix</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Neurocomputation and Neuroimaging Unit (NNU), Department of Education and Psychology, Freie Universität Berlin, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hohwy</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jakob</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Cognition and Philosophy Lab, Department of Philosophy, Monash University, Melbourne, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Monash Centre for Consciousness &amp; Contemplative Studies, Monash University, Melbourne, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>04</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Hum Brain Mapp</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9419065</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1065-9471</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MVPA</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">biological motion</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">body representation</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mirror neurons</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">self-other</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">self-representation</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">working memory</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>16</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35466500</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hbm.25879</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Albers, A. M., Kok, P., Toni, I., Dijkerman, H. C., &amp; De Lange, F. P. (2013). Shared representations for working memory and mental imagery in early visual cortex. Current Biology, 23(15), 1427-1431.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baumeister, R. F. (1999). The self in social psychology. Psychology Press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bischoff, M., Zentgraf, K., Lorey, B., Pilgramm, S., Balser, N., Baumgartner, E., … Munzert, J. (2012). Motor familiarity: Brain activation when watching kinematic displays of one's own movements. Neuropsychologia, 50(8), 2085-2092.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blanke, O. (2012). Multisensory brain mechanisms of bodily self-consciousness. Nature Reviews. Neuroscience, 13(8), 556-571. https://doi.org/10.1038/nrn3292</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blanke, O., Slater, M., &amp; Serino, A. (2015). Behavioral, neural, and computational principles of bodily self-consciousness. Neuron, 88(1), 145-166. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2015.09.029</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Calvo-Merino, B., Glaser, D. E., Grèzes, J., Passingham, R. E., &amp; Haggard, P. (2004). Action observation and acquired motor skills: An FMRI study with expert dancers. Cerebral Cortex, 15(8), 1243-1249.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Calvo-Merino, B., Grèzes, J., Glaser, D. E., Passingham, R. E., &amp; Haggard, P. (2006). Seeing or doing? Influence of visual and motor familiarity in action observation. Current Biology, 16(19), 1905-1910.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Caspers, S., Zilles, K., Laird, A. R., &amp; Eickhoff, S. B. (2010). ALE meta-analysis of action observation and imitation in the human brain. NeuroImage, 50(3), 1148-1167.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Caughey, S., Falbén, J. K., Tsamadi, D., Persson, L. M., Golubickis, M., &amp; Macrae, C. N. (2020). Self-prioritization during stimulus processing is not obligatory. Psychological Research, 85(2), 503-508.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chang, C.-C., &amp; Lin, C.-J. (2011). LIBSVM: A library for support vector machines. ACM Transactions on Intelligent Systems and Technology (TIST), 2(3), 27.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Christoff, K., Cosmelli, D., Legrand, D., &amp; Thompson, E. (2011). Specifying the self for cognitive neuroscience. Trends in Cognitive Sciences, 15(3), 104-112. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tics.2011.01.001</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Christophel, T. B., Cichy, R. M., Hebart, M. N., &amp; Haynes, J.-D. (2015). Parietal and early visual cortices encode working memory content across mental transformations. NeuroImage, 106, 198-206.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Christophel, T. B., Hebart, M. N., &amp; Haynes, J.-D. (2012). Decoding the contents of visual short-term memory from human visual and parietal cortex. Journal of Neuroscience, 32(38), 12983-12989.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Christophel, T. B., Klink, P. C., Spitzer, B., Roelfsema, P. R., &amp; Haynes, J.-D. (2017). The distributed nature of working memory. Trends in Cognitive Sciences, 21(2), 111-124.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cook, R., Bird, G., Catmur, C., Press, C., &amp; Heyes, C. (2014). Mirror neurons: From origin to function. Behavioral and Brain Sciences, 37(2), 177-192.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cross, E. S., Hamilton, A. F. d. C., &amp; Grafton, S. T. (2006). Building a motor simulation de novo: Observation of dance by dancers. NeuroImage, 31(3), 1257-1267.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cross, E. S., Hamilton, A. F. D. C., Kraemer, D. J., Kelley, W. M., &amp; Grafton, S. T. (2009). Dissociable substrates for body motion and physical experience in the human action observation network. European Journal of Neuroscience, 30(7), 1383-1392.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>D'Argembeau, A. (2013). On the role of the ventromedial prefrontal cortex in self-processing: The valuation hypothesis. Frontiers in Human Neuroscience, 7, 372.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Vignemont, F. (2010). Body schema and body image-Pros and cons. Neuropsychologia, 48(3), 669-680.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Vignemont, F. (2018). Mind the body: An exploration of bodily self-awareness. Oxford University Press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Devue, C., Collette, F., Balteau, E., Degueldre, C., Luxen, A., Maquet, P., &amp; Brédart, S. (2007). Here I am: The cortical correlates of visual self-recognition. Brain Research, 1143, 169-182.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dewey, J. A., &amp; Knoblich, G. (2016). Representation of self versus others' actions. In S. S. Obhi &amp; E. S. Cross (Eds.), Shared representations: Sensorimotor foundations of social life (p. 351). SAGE Publications.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gainotti, G. (2007). Face familiarity feelings, the right temporal lobe and the possible underlying neural mechanisms. Brain Research Reviews, 56(1), 214-235.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gallagher, S. (2000). Philosophical conceptions of the self: Implications for cognitive science. Trends in Cognitive Sciences, 4(1), 14-21.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gallagher, S. (2005). How the body shapes the mind. Clarendon Press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Galvez-Pol, A., Calvo-Merino, B., &amp; Forster, B. (2020). Revealing the body in the brain: An ERP method to examine sensorimotor activity during visual perception of body-related information. Cortex, 125, 332-344.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Galvez-Pol, A., Forster, B., &amp; Calvo-Merino, B. (2020). Beyond action observation: Neurobehavioral mechanisms of memory for visually perceived bodies and actions. Neuroscience &amp; Biobehavioral Reviews, 116, 508-518.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ganesh, S., van Schie, H. T., de Lange, F. P., Thompson, E., &amp; Wigboldus, D. H. (2011). How the human brain goes virtual: Distinct cortical regions of the person-processing network are involved in self-identification with virtual agents. Cerebral Cortex, 22(7), 1577-1585.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gillihan, S. J., &amp; Farah, M. J. (2005). Is self special? A critical review of evidence from experimental psychology and cognitive neuroscience. Psychological Bulletin, 131(1), 76-97.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gläscher, J., &amp; Gitelman, D. (2008). Contrast weights in flexible factorial design with multiple groups of subjects.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grossman, E., Donnelly, M., Price, R., Pickens, D., Morgan, V., Neighbor, G., &amp; Blake, R. (2000). Brain areas involved in perception of biological motion. Journal of Cognitive Neuroscience, 12(5), 711-720.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grossman, E. D., &amp; Blake, R. (2002). Brain areas active during visual perception of biological motion. Neuron, 35(6), 1167-1175.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hebart, M. N., Görgen, K., &amp; Haynes, J.-D. (2015). The decoding toolbox (TDT): A versatile software package for multivariate analyses of functional imaging data. Frontiers in Neuroinformatics, 8, 88.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heed, T., Buchholz, V. N., Engel, A. K., &amp; Röder, B. (2015). Tactile remapping: From coordinate transformation to integration in sensorimotor processing. Trends in Cognitive Sciences, 19(5), 251-258.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hu, C., Di, X., Eickhoff, S. B., Zhang, M., Peng, K., Guo, H., &amp; Sui, J. (2016). Distinct and common aspects of physical and psychological self-representation in the brain: A meta-analysis of self-bias in facial and self-referential judgements. Neuroscience &amp; Biobehavioral Reviews, 61, 197-207.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnson-Frey, S. H., Maloof, F. R., Newman-Norlund, R., Farrer, C., Inati, S., &amp; Grafton, S. T. (2003). Actions or hand-object interactions? Human inferior frontal cortex and action observation. Neuron, 39(6), 1053-1058.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jokisch, D., Daum, I., &amp; Troje, N. F. (2006). Self recognition versus recognition of others by biological motion: Viewpoint-dependent effects. Perception, 35(7), 911-920.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kalenzaga, S., Sperduti, M., Anssens, A., Martinelli, P., Devauchelle, A.-D., Gallarda, T., … Krebs, M.-O. (2015). Episodic memory and self-reference via semantic autobiographical memory: Insights from an fMRI study in younger and older adults. Frontiers in Behavioral Neuroscience, 8, 449.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kanayama, N., &amp; Hiromitsu, K. (2021). Triadic body representations in the human cerebral cortex and peripheral nerves. In Y. Ataria, S. Tanaka, &amp; S. Gallagher (Eds.), Body schema and body image: New directions (p. 133). Oxford University Press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kriegeskorte, N., Goebel, R., &amp; Bandettini, P. (2006). Information-based functional brain mapping. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, 103(10), 3863-3868.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee, S.-H., &amp; Baker, C. I. (2016). Multi-voxel decoding and the topography of maintained information during visual working memory. Frontiers in Systems Neuroscience, 10, 2.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Legrand, D., &amp; Ruby, P. (2009). What is self-specific? Theoretical investigation and critical review of neuroimaging results. Psychological Review, 116(1), 252-282.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leshikar, E. D., &amp; Duarte, A. (2012). Medial prefrontal cortex supports source memory accuracy for self-referenced items. Social Neuroscience, 7(2), 126-145.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Limanowski, J., &amp; Blankenburg, F. (2013). Minimal self-models and the free energy principle. Frontiers in Human Neuroscience, 7, 547. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnhum.2013.00547</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Limanowski, J., &amp; Blankenburg, F. (2016). Integration of visual and proprioceptive limb position information in human posterior parietal, premotor, and extrastriate cortex. Journal of Neuroscience, 36(9), 2582-2589.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lockwood, P. L., Wittmann, M. K., Apps, M. A., Klein-Flügge, M. C., Crockett, M. J., Humphreys, G. W., &amp; Rushworth, M. F. (2018). Neural mechanisms for learning self and other ownership. Nature Communications, 9(1), 1-11.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lu, X., Huang, J., Yi, Y., Shen, M., Weng, X., &amp; Gao, Z. (2016). Holding biological motion in working memory: An fMRI study. Frontiers in Human Neuroscience, 10, 251.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Macey, P. M., Macey, K. E., Kumar, R., &amp; Harper, R. M. (2004). A method for removal of global effects from fMRI time series. NeuroImage, 22(1), 360-366.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Macuga, K. L., &amp; Frey, S. H. (2011). Selective responses in right inferior frontal and supramarginal gyri differentiate between observed movements of oneself vs. another. Neuropsychologia, 49(5), 1202-1207.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martinelli, P., Sperduti, M., &amp; Piolino, P. (2013). Neural substrates of the self-memory system: New insights from a meta-analysis. Human Brain Mapping, 34(7), 1515-1529. https://doi.org/10.1002/hbm.22008</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mattan, B., Quinn, K. A., Apperly, I. A., Sui, J., &amp; Rotshtein, P. (2015). Is it always me first? Effects of self-tagging on third-person perspective-taking. Journal of Experimental Psychology. Learning, Memory, and Cognition, 41(4), 1100-1117. https://doi.org/10.1037/xlm0000078</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Molenberghs, P., Cunnington, R., &amp; Mattingley, J. B. (2012). Brain regions with mirror properties: A meta-analysis of 125 human fMRI studies. Neuroscience &amp; Biobehavioral Reviews, 36(1), 341-349.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Molnar-Szakacs, I., Iacoboni, M., Koski, L., &amp; Mazziotta, J. C. (2005). Functional segregation within pars opercularis of the inferior frontal gyrus: Evidence from fMRI studies of imitation and action observation. Cerebral Cortex, 15(7), 986-994.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morita, T., Asada, M., &amp; Naito, E. (2020). Right-hemispheric dominance in self-body recognition is altered in left-handed individuals. Neuroscience, 425, 68-89.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Myers, N. E., Stokes, M. G., &amp; Nobre, A. C. (2017). Prioritizing information during working memory: Beyond sustained internal attention. Trends in Cognitive Sciences, 21(6), 449-461.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Neisser, U. (1988). Five kinds of self-knowledge. Philosophical Psychology, 1(1), 35-59.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Northoff, G., Heinzel, A., De Greck, M., Bermpohl, F., Dobrowolny, H., &amp; Panksepp, J. (2006). Self-referential processing in our brain-A meta-analysis of imaging studies on the self. NeuroImage, 31(1), 440-457.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Payne, S., Tsakiris, M., &amp; Maister, L. (2017). Can the self become another? Investigating the effects of self-association with a new facial identity. Quarterly Journal of Experimental Psychology, 70(6), 1085-1097. https://doi.org/10.1080/17470218.2015.1137329</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pelphrey, K. A., Morris, J. P., Michelich, C. R., Allison, T., &amp; McCarthy, G. (2005). Functional anatomy of biological motion perception in posterior temporal cortex: An fMRI study of eye, mouth and hand movements. Cerebral Cortex, 15(12), 1866-1876.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Philippi, C. L., Duff, M. C., Denburg, N. L., Tranel, D., &amp; Rudrauf, D. (2012). Medial PFC damage abolishes the self-reference effect. Journal of Cognitive Neuroscience, 24(2), 475-481.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pitcher, D., &amp; Ungerleider, L. G. (2020). Evidence for a third visual pathway specialized for social perception. Trends in Cognitive Sciences, 25(2), 100-110.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Qin, P., &amp; Northoff, G. (2011). How is our self related to midline regions and the default-mode network? NeuroImage, 57(3), 1221-1233.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Qin, P., Wang, M., &amp; Northoff, G. (2020). Linking bodily, environmental and mental states in the self: A three-level model based on a meta-analysis. Neuroscience &amp; Biobehavioral Reviews, 115, 77-95. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neubiorev.2020.05.004</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Quesque, F., &amp; Brass, M. (2019). The role of the temporoparietal junction in self-other distinction. Brain Topography, 32(6), 943-955.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Riggall, A. C., &amp; Postle, B. R. (2012). The relationship between working memory storage and elevated activity as measured with functional magnetic resonance imaging. Journal of Neuroscience, 32(38), 12990-12998.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rizzolatti, G., &amp; Sinigaglia, C. (2010). The functional role of the parieto-frontal mirror circuit: Interpretations and misinterpretations. Nature Reviews Neuroscience, 11(4), 264-274.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saygin, A. P. (2007a). Brain areas involved in biological motion perception: What is involved and what is necessary. Journal of Vision, 7(9), 492.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saygin, A. P. (2007b). Superior temporal and premotor brain areas necessary for biological motion perception. Brain, 130(9), 2452-2461.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saygin, A. P., Wilson, S. M., Hagler, D. J., Bates, E., &amp; Sereno, M. I. (2004). Point-light biological motion perception activates human premotor cortex. Journal of Neuroscience, 24(27), 6181-6188.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schäfer, S., Wentura, D., &amp; Frings, C. (2017). Distinctiveness effects in self-prioritization. Visual Cognition, 25(1-3), 399-411.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmidt, T. T., &amp; Blankenburg, F. (2018). Brain regions that retain the spatial layout of tactile stimuli during working memory-A 'tactospatial sketchpad'? NeuroImage, 178, 531-539.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmidt, T. T., Schröder, P., Reinhardt, P., &amp; Blankenburg, F. (2020). Rehearsal of tactile working memory: Premotor cortex recruits two dissociable neuronal content representations. Human Brain Mapping, 42(1), 245-258. https://doi.org/10.1002/hbm.25220</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmidt, T. T., Wu, Y.-H., &amp; Blankenburg, F. (2017). Content-specific codes of parametric vibrotactile working memory in humans. Journal of Neuroscience, 37, 1167-1117.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schwoebel, J., &amp; Coslett, H. B. (2005). Evidence for multiple, distinct representations of the human body. Journal of Cognitive Neuroscience, 17(4), 543-553.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shi, Z., Zhou, A., Han, W., &amp; Liu, P. (2011). Effects of ownership expressed by the first-person possessive pronoun. Consciousness and Cognition, 20(3), 951-955. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.concog.2010.12.008</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shultz, S., Lee, S. M., Pelphrey, K., &amp; McCarthy, G. (2011). The posterior superior temporal sulcus is sensitive to the outcome of human and non-human goal-directed actions. Social Cognitive and Affective Neuroscience, 6(5), 602-611.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sokolov, A. A., Zeidman, P., Erb, M., Ryvlin, P., Friston, K. J., &amp; Pavlova, M. A. (2018). Structural and effective brain connectivity underlying biological motion detection. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, 115(51), E12034-E12042.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sugiura, M., Sassa, Y., Jeong, H., Miura, N., Akitsuki, Y., Horie, K., … Kawashima, R. (2006). Multiple brain networks for visual self-recognition with different sensitivity for motion and body part. NeuroImage, 32(4), 1905-1917.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sui, J., He, X., &amp; Humphreys, G. W. (2012). Perceptual effects of social salience: Evidence from self-prioritization effects on perceptual matching. Journal of Experimental Psychology. Human Perception and Performance, 38(5), 1105-1117. https://doi.org/10.1037/a0029792</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sui, J., &amp; Humphreys, G. W. (2015). The integrative self: How self-reference integrates perception and memory. Trends in Cognitive Sciences, 19(12), 719-728. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tics.2015.08.015</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sui, J., Liu, M., Mevorach, C., &amp; Humphreys, G. W. (2015). The salient self: The left intraparietal sulcus responds to social as well as perceptual-salience after self-association. Cerebral Cortex, 25(4), 1060-1068.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sui, J., Rotshtein, P., &amp; Humphreys, G. W. (2013). Coupling social attention to the self forms a network for personal significance. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 110(19), 7607-7612. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1221862110</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Symons, C. S., &amp; Johnson, B. T. (1997). The self-reference effect in memory: A meta-analysis. Psychological Bulletin, 121(3), 371-394.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tsakiris, M. (2010). My body in the brain: A neurocognitive model of body-ownership. Neuropsychologia, 48(3), 703-712.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tsakiris, M. (2017). The multisensory basis of the self: From body to identity to others. The Quarterly Journal of Experimental Psychology, 70(4), 597-609.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Uluç, I., Schmidt, T. T., Wu, Y.-H., &amp; Blankenburg, F. (2018). Content-specific codes of parametric auditory working memory in humans. NeuroImage, 183, 254-262.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Uluç, I., Velenosi, L. A., Schmidt, T. T., &amp; Blankenburg, F. (2020). Parametric representation of tactile numerosity in working memory. eNeuro, 7(1). ENEURO.0090-19.2019. https://doi.org/10.1523/ENEURO.0090-19.2019</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vaina, L. M., Solomon, J., Chowdhury, S., Sinha, P., &amp; Belliveau, J. W. (2001). Functional neuroanatomy of biological motion perception in humans. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, 98(20), 11656-11661.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van Kemenade, B. M., Muggleton, N., Walsh, V., &amp; Saygin, A. P. (2012). Effects of TMS over premotor and superior temporal cortices on biological motion perception. Journal of Cognitive Neuroscience, 24(4), 896-904.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vanrie, J., &amp; Verfaillie, K. (2004). Perception of biological motion: A stimulus set of human point-light actions. Behavior Research Methods, Instruments, &amp; Computers, 36(4), 625-629.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Woźniak, M. (2019). How to grow a self: development of the self in a Bayesian brain. PsyArXiv. 1-48. https://doi.org/10.31234/osf.io/6e3ad</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Woźniak, M., &amp; Hohwy, J. (2020). Stranger to my face: top-down and bottom-up effects underlying prioritization of images of one's face. PLoS One, 15(7), e0235627. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0235627</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Woźniak, M., &amp; Knoblich, G. (2019). Self-prioritization of fully unfamiliar stimuli. Quarterly Journal of Experimental Psychology, 72, 2110-2120. https://doi.org/10.1177/1747021819832981</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Woźniak, M., &amp; Knoblich, G. (2021). Self-prioritization depends on assumed task-relevance of self-association. Psychological Research Psychologische Forschung. Advance online publication. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00426-021-01584-5</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Woźniak, M., Kourtis, D., &amp; Knoblich, G. (2018). Prioritization of arbitrary faces associated to self: An EEG study. PLoS One, 13(1), e0190679.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu, Y.-H., Uluç, I., Schmidt, T. T., Tertel, K., Kirilina, E., &amp; Blankenburg, F. (2018). Overlapping frontoparietal networks for tactile and visual parametric working memory representations. NeuroImage, 166, 325-334.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yankouskaya, A., Humphreys, G., Stolte, M., Stokes, M., Moradi, Z., &amp; Sui, J. (2017). An anterior-posterior axis within the ventromedial prefrontal cortex separates self and reward. Social Cognitive and Affective Neuroscience, 12(12), 1859-1868.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yankouskaya, A., &amp; Sui, J. (2021). Self-positivity or self-negativity as a function of the medial prefrontal cortex. Brain Sciences, 11(2), 264.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yaoi, K., Osaka, M., &amp; Osaka, N. (2015). Neural correlates of the self-reference effect: Evidence from evaluation and recognition processes. Frontiers in Human Neuroscience, 9, 383.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yin, S., Bi, T., Chen, A., &amp; Egner, T. (2021). Ventromedial prefrontal cortex drives the prioritization of self-associated stimuli in working memory. Journal of Neuroscience, 41(9), 2012-2023.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhao, S., Uono, S., Li, C., Yoshimura, S., &amp; Toichi, M. (2018). The influence of self-referential processing on attentional orienting in frontoparietal networks. Frontiers in Human Neuroscience, 12, 199.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhou, A., Shi, Z., Zhang, P., Liu, P., Han, W., Wu, H., … Xia, R. (2010). An ERP study on the effect of self-relevant possessive pronoun. Neuroscience Letters, 480(2), 162-166. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neulet.2010.06.033</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
