<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35465876</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>26</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>29</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1557-9875</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>40</Volume>
            <Issue>2</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Neurologic clinics</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Neurol Clin</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Chiari Malformation (Update on Diagnosis and Treatment).</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>297</StartPage>
          <EndPage>307</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>297-307</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.ncl.2021.11.007</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0733-8619(21)00118-3</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Chiari Malformation Type I (CMI) is a congenital malformation diagnosed by MRI findings of at least 5 mm of cerebellar ectopy below the foramen magnum. CM1 is frequently associated with syringomyelia. Herein, we discuss the history of CMI and syringomyelia, including early pathological and surgical studies. We also describe recent investigations into the pathogenesis and pathophysiology of CMI and their practical implications on management and surgical intervention. We also highlight the recent development of the Common Data Elements for CMI, providing a framework for ongoing investigations. Finally, we discuss current controversies of surgical management in CMI.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022 Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Rosenblum</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jared S</ForeName>
            <Initials>JS</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>National Institutes of Health, National Cancer Institute, Neuro-Oncology Branch, 37 Convent Drive, MSC 4254, Bethesda, MD, 20892 USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Pomeraniec</LastName>
            <ForeName>I Jonathan</ForeName>
            <Initials>IJ</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>National Institutes of Health, National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Stroke, Surgical Neurology Branch, 10 Center Drive, Room 3D20, Bethesda, MD, 20892 USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Heiss</LastName>
            <ForeName>John D</ForeName>
            <Initials>JD</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>National Institutes of Health, National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Stroke, Surgical Neurology Branch, 10 Center Drive, Room 3D20, Bethesda, MD, 20892 USA. Electronic address: heissj@ninds.nih.gov.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <GrantList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>Z99 NS999999</GrantID>
            <Acronym>ImNIH</Acronym>
            <Agency>Intramural NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>ZIA NS003050</GrantID>
            <Acronym>ImNIH</Acronym>
            <Agency>Intramural NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
        </GrantList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>31</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Neurol Clin</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8219232</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0733-8619</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001139" MajorTopicYN="Y">Arnold-Chiari Malformation</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005539" MajorTopicYN="N">Foramen Magnum</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008279" MajorTopicYN="N">Magnetic Resonance Imaging</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013595" MajorTopicYN="Y">Syringomyelia</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000000981" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnostic imaging</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000601" MajorTopicYN="N">surgery</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chiari malformation</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Diagnosis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Syrinx</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release">
          <Year>2023</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>55</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35465876</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS1794767</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9043468</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ncl.2021.11.007</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">S0733-8619(21)00118-3</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oldfield EH. Pathogenesis of Chiari I-Pathophysiology of Syringomyelia: Implications for Therapy: A Summary of 3 Decades of Clinical Research. Neurosurgery
2017; 64(CN_suppl_1):66–77</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28899066</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hiremath SB, Fitsori A, Boto J, Torres C, Zakhari N, Dietemann J-L, Meling TR, Vargas MI. The Perplexity Surrounding Chiari Malformations—Are We Any Wiser Now?
AJNR Am. J. Neuroradiol
2020; 41(11):1975–1981</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7658834</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32943418</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koehler PJ. Chiari’s description of cerebellar ectopy (1891): With a summary of Cleland’s and Arnold’s contributions and some early observations on neural-tube defects. J Neurosurg. 1991;75:823–826.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1919713</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chiari H
Concerning alterations in the cerebellum resulting from cerebral hydrocephalus. Pediatric Neurosci. 1891;13:3–8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chiari H
Uber Ver~inderungendes Kleinhirns, des Pons und der Medulla Oblongata infolge von congenitaler Hy- drocephalie des Grosshirns. Denksehriften der Kais Akad Wiss math-naturw. 1896;63:71–116</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Myelocyste Arnold J., Transposition von Gewebskeimen und Sympodie. Zieglers Beitr Pathol Anal. 1894;16:1–28</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cleland J: Contribution to the study of spina bifida, encephalocele, and anencephalus. J Anat Physiol. 1883; 17: 257–292</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Padget DH. Development of so-called dysraphism; with embryologic evidence of clinical Arnold-Chiari and Dandy-Walker malformations. Johns Hopkins Med J
1972; 130(3):127–65</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4621888</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marín-Padilla M
Cephalic Axial Skeletal-Neural Dysraphic Disorders: embryology and Pathology. Can J Neurol Sci
1991; 18(2):153–169</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2070298</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Buell TJ, Heiss JD, Oldfield EH. Pathogenesis and Cerebrospinal Fluid Hydrodynamics of the Chiari I Malformation. Neurosurg Clin N Am
2015; 26(4):495–499</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5140100</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26408057</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heiss JD, Patronas N, DeVroom HL, Shawker T, Ernis R, Kammerer W, Eidsath A, Talbot T, Morris J, Eskioglu E, Oldfield EH. Elucidating the pathophysiology of syringomyelia. J Neurosurg. 1999;91(4):553–62</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10507374</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gardner WJ, Angel J. The mechanism of syringomyelia and its surgical correction. Clin Neurosurg. 1958;6:131–140</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13826542</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raybaud C and Jallo GI. Chapter 2: Chiari I deformity in children: etiopathogenesis and radiologic diagnosis. In: Ed(s) Manto M and Huisman TAGM. Handbook of Clinical Neurology Vol 155 (3rd series). Edinburgh, U.K.
Elsevier;2018. 25–48</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29891063</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nishikawa M; Sakamoto H; Hakuba A; Nakanishi N; Inoue Y
Pathogenesis of Chiari malformation: A morphometric study of the posterior cranial fossa. J Neurosurg
1997; 86: 40–47.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8988080</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Taylor DG, Mastorakos P, Jane JA, Oldfield EH. Two distinct populations of Chiari I malformation based on presence or absence of posterior fossa crowdedness on magnetic resonance imaging. J Neurosurg. 2016;126(6):1–7</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26894456</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raybaud C
Jallo GI. Chiari I deformity in children: etiopathogenesis and radiologic diagnosis. Handb Clin Neurol. 2018;155:25–48</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29891063</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pan KS, Heiss JD, Brown SM, Collins MT, Boyce AM. Chiari I Malformation and Basilar Invagination in Fibrous Dysplasia: Prevalence, Mechanisms, and Clinical Implications. J Bone Miner Res
2018; 33(11): 1990–1998</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6218312</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29924878</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Urbizu A; Khan TN; Ashley-Koch AE
Genetic dissection of Chiari malformation type I using endophenotypes and stratification. J. Rare Dis. Res. Treat </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rosenblum JS, Cappadona AJ, Argersinger DP, Pang Y, Wang H, Nazari MA, Munasinghe JP, Donahuge DR, Jha A, Smirniotopoulos JG, Miettinen MM, Knutsen RH, Kozel BA, Zhuang Z, Pacak K, Heiss JD.. Neuraxial Dysraphism in EPAS1-Associated Syndrome due to Improper Mesenchymal Transition. Neurol Genet
2020; 6(3): e414.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7164966</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32337341</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kniffin CL; McKusick VA
OMIM-Online Mendelian Inheritance in Man: Chiari Malformation Type, I. Published 5/12/1992. Updated 10/07/2016. Available online: https://www.omim.org/entry/118420#title (accessed on
27 July 2021).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mastorakos P and Heiss JD. Chapter 38: Treatment of the Adult Chiari I Malformation. In: Tubbs RS
et al., eds. The Chiari Malformations. Springer Nature Switzerland; 2020: 443–457</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McConnell AA, Parker HL. A deformity of the hindbrain associated with internal hydrocephalus. Its relation to the Arnold-Chiari malformation. Brain. 1938;61:415–29.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Adams RD, Schatzki R, Scovill WB. The Arnold- Chiari malformation. Diagnosis, demonstration by intraspinal Lipiodol and successful surgical treatment. N Engl J Med. 1941;225:125–31.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bucy PC, Lichtenstein BW. Arnold-Chiari defor- mity in an adult without obvious cause. J Neurosurg. 1945;2:245–50.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gardner WJ, Goodall RJ. The surgical treatment of Arnold-Chiari malformation in adults; an explanation of its mechanism and importance of encephalography in diagnosis. J Neurosurg. 1950;7(3):199–206.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15415776</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Levy WJ, Mason L, Hahn JF. Chiari malformation presenting in adults: a surgical experience in 127 cases. Neurosurgery. 1983;12(4):377–90.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6856062</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pillay PK. Thecoperitoneal shunting for syringomy- elia. J Neurosurg. 1991;75(5):835–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1919718</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chauvet D, Carpentier A, George B. Dura splitting decompression in Chiari type 1 malformation: clinical experience and radiological findings. Neurosurg Rev. 2009;32(4):465–70.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19644715</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>16.
Durham SR, Fjeld-Olenec K. Comparison of posterior fossa decompression with and without duraplasty for the surgical treatment of Chiari malformation Type I in pediatric patients: a meta-analysis. J Neurosurg Pediatr. 2008;2(1):42–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18590394</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Isu T, Sasaki H, Takamura H, Kobayashi N. Foramen magnum decompression with removal of the outer layer of the dura as treatment for syringomyelia occurring with Chiari I malformation. Neurosurgery. 1993;33(5):844–9; discussion 9–50.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kotil K, Ton T, Tari R, Savas Y. Delamination technique together with longitudinal incisions for treatment of Chiari I/syringomyelia complex: a prospective clinical study. Cerebrospinal Fluid Res. 2009;6:7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2706797</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19545443</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Romero FR, Pereira CAdB. Suboccipital craniectomy with or without duraplasty: what is the best choice in patients with Chiari type 1 malformation?
Arq Neuropsiquiatr. 2010;68(4):623–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20730321</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Luciano MG, Batzdorf U, Kula RW, Rocque BG, Maher CO, Heiss J, Martin BA, Bolognese PA, Ashley-Koch A, Limbrick D, Poppe DJ, Esposito KM, Odenkirchen J, Esterlitz JR, Ala’i S, Joseph K, Feldman RS, Riddle R; Chiari I Malformation Common Data Element Working Group. Development of Common Data Elements for Use in Chiari Malformation Type I Clinical Research: An NIH/NINDS Project. Neurosurgery. 2019. 
Dec
1;85(6):854–860. doi: 10.1093/neuros/nyy475.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/neuros/nyy475</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7054710</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30690581</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Batzdorf U, McArthur DL, Bentson JR. Surgical treatment of Chiari malformation with and without syringomyelia: experience with 177 adult patients. J Neurosurg. 2013. 
Feb;118(2):232–42. doi: 10.3171/2012.10.JNS12305. Epub 2012 Nov 23.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3171/2012.10.JNS12305</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23176335</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sadler B, Skidmore A, Gewirtz J, Anderson RCE, Haller G, Ackerman LL, Adelson PD, Ahmed R, Albert GW, Aldana PR, Alden TD, Averill C, Baird LC, Bauer DF, Bethel-Anderson T, Bierbrauer KS, Bonfield CM, Brockmeyer DL, Chern JJ, Couture DE, Daniels DJ, Dlouhy BJ, Durham SR, Ellenbogen RG, Eskandari R, Fuchs HE, George TM, Grant GA, Graupman PC, Greene S, Greenfield JP, Gross NL, Guillaume DJ, Hankinson TC, Heuer GG, Iantosca M, Iskandar BJ, Jackson EM, Jea AH, Johnston JM, Keating RF, Khan N, Krieger MD, Leonard JR, Maher CO, Mangano FT, Mapstone TB, McComb JG, McEvoy SD, Meehan T, Menezes AH, Muhlbauer M, Oakes WJ, Olavarria G, O’Neill BR, Ragheb J, Selden NR, Shah MN, Shannon CN, Smith J, Smyth MD, Stone SSD, Tuite GF, Wait SD, Wellons JC, Whitehead WE, Park TS, Limbrick DD, Strahle JM. Extradural decompression versus duraplasty in Chiari malformation type I with syrinx: outcomes on scoliosis from the Park-Reeves Syringomyelia Research Consortium. J Neurosurg Pediatr. 2021. 
Jun
18:1–9. doi: 10.3171/2020.12.PEDS20552. Epub ahead of print.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3171/2020.12.PEDS20552</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yahanda AT, Adelson PD, Akbari SHA, Albert GW, Aldana PR, Alden TD, Anderson RCE, Bauer DF, Bethel-Anderson T, Brockmeyer DL, Chern JJ, Couture DE, Daniels DJ, Dlouhy BJ, Durham SR, Ellenbogen RG, Eskandari R, George TM, Grant GA, Graupman PC, Greene S, Greenfield JP, Gross NL, Guillaume DJ, Hankinson TC, Heuer GG, Iantosca M, Iskandar BJ, Jackson EM, Johnston JM, Keating RF, Krieger MD, Leonard JR, Maher CO, Mangano FT, McComb JG, McEvoy SD, Meehan T, Menezes AH, O’Neill BR, Olavarria G, Ragheb J, Selden NR, Shah MN, Shannon CN, Shimony JS, Smyth MD, Stone SSD, Strahle JM, Torner JC, Tuite GF, Wait SD, Wellons JC, Whitehead WE, Park TS, Limbrick DD. Dural augmentation approaches and complication rates after posterior fossa decompression for Chiari I malformation and syringomyelia: a Park-Reeves Syringomyelia Research Consortium study. J Neurosurg Pediatr. 2021. 
Feb
12:1–10. doi: 10.3171/2020.8.PEDS2087. Epub ahead of print.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3171/2020.8.PEDS2087</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>CreveCoeur TS, Yahanda AT, Maher CO, Johnson GW, Ackerman LL, Adelson PD, Ahmed R, Albert GW, Aldana PR, Alden TD, Anderson RCE, Baird L, Bauer DF, Bierbrauer KS, Brockmeyer DL, Chern JJ, Couture DE, Daniels DJ, Dauser RC, Durham SR, Ellenbogen RG, Eskandari R, Fuchs HE, George TM, Grant GA, Graupman PC, Greene S, Greenfield JP, Gross NL, Guillaume DJ, Haller G, Hankinson TC, Heuer GG, Iantosca M, Iskandar BJ, Jackson EM, Jea AH, Johnston JM, Keating RF, Kelly MP, Khan N, Krieger MD, Leonard JR, Mangano FT, Mapstone TB, McComb JG, Menezes AH, Muhlbauer M, Oakes WJ, Olavarria G, O’Neill BR, Park TS, Ragheb J, Selden NR, Shah MN, Shannon C, Shimony JS, Smith J, Smyth MD, Stone SSD, Strahle JM, Tamber MS, Torner JC, Tuite GF, Wait SD, Wellons JC, Whitehead WE, Limbrick DD. Occipital-Cervical Fusion and Ventral Decompression in the Surgical Management of Chiari-1 Malformation and Syringomyelia: Analysis of Data From the Park-Reeves Syringomyelia Research Consortium. Neurosurgery. 2021. 
Jan 13;88(2):332–341. doi: 10.1093/neuros/nyaa460.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/neuros/nyaa460</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hale AT, Adelson PD, Albert GW, Aldana PR, Alden TD, Anderson RCE, Bauer DF, Bonfield CM, Brockmeyer DL, Chern JJ, Couture DE, Daniels DJ, Durham SR, Ellenbogen RG, Eskandari R, George TM, Grant GA, Graupman PC, Greene S, Greenfield JP, Gross NL, Guillaume DJ, Heuer GG, Iantosca M, Iskandar BJ, Jackson EM, Johnston JM, Keating RF, Leonard JR, Maher CO, Mangano FT, McComb JG, Meehan T, Menezes AH, O’Neill B, Olavarria G, Park TS, Ragheb J, Selden NR, Shah MN, Smyth MD, Stone SSD, Strahle JM, Wait SD, Wellons JC, Whitehead WE, Shannon CN, Limbrick DD; Park-Reeves Syringomyelia Research Consortium Investigators. Factors associated with syrinx size in pediatric patients treated for Chiari malformation type I and syringomyelia: a study from the Park-Reeves Syringomyelia Research Consortium. J Neurosurg Pediatr. 2020. 
Mar
6:1–11. doi: 10.3171/2020.1.PEDS19493. Epub ahead of print.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3171/2020.1.PEDS19493</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
