<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35464873</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>29</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1831-4732</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>20</Volume>
            <Issue>4</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Apr</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>EFSA journal. European Food Safety Authority</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>EFSA J</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Scientific advice related to nutrient profiling for the development of harmonised mandatory front-of-pack nutrition labelling and the setting of nutrient profiles for restricting nutrition and health claims on foods.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e07259</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e07259</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e07259</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2903/j.efsa.2022.7259</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Following a request from the European Commission, the EFSA Panel on Nutrition, Novel Foods and Food Allergens (NDA) was asked to deliver scientific advice related to nutrient profiling for the development of harmonised mandatory front-of-pack nutrition labelling and the setting of nutrient profiles for restricting nutrition and health claims on foods. This Opinion is based on systematic reviews and meta-analyses of human studies on nutritionally adequate diets, data from the Global Burden of Disease framework, clinical practice guidelines, previous EFSA opinions and the priorities set by EU Member States in the context of their Food-Based Dietary Guidelines and associated nutrient/food intake recommendations. Relevant publications were retrieved through comprehensive searches in PubMed. The nutrients included in the assessment are those likely to be consumed in excess or in inadequate amounts in a majority of European countries. Food groups with important roles in European diets have been considered. The Panel concludes that dietary intakes of saturated fatty acids (SFA), sodium and added/free sugars are above, and intakes of dietary fibre and potassium below, current dietary recommendations in a majority of European populations. As excess intakes of SFAs, sodium and added/free sugars and inadequate intakes of dietary fibre and potassium are associated with adverse health effects, they could be included in nutrient profiling models. Energy could be included because a reduction in energy intake is of public health importance for European populations. In food group/category-based nutrient profiling models, total fat could replace energy in most food groups owing to its high-energy density, while the energy density of food groups with low or no fat content may be well accounted for by the inclusion of (added/free) sugars. Some nutrients may be included in nutrient profiling models for reasons other than their public health importance, e.g. as a proxy for other nutrients of public health importance, or to allow for a better discrimination of foods within the same food category.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 Wiley‐VCH Verlag GmbH &amp; Co. KgaA on behalf of the European Food Safety Authority.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <CollectiveName>EFSA Panel on Nutrition, Novel Foods and Food Allergens (NDA)</CollectiveName>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Turck</LastName>
            <ForeName>Dominique</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bohn</LastName>
            <ForeName>Torsten</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Castenmiller</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jacqueline</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>de Henauw</LastName>
            <ForeName>Stefaan</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hirsch-Ernst</LastName>
            <ForeName>Karen Ildico</ForeName>
            <Initials>KI</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Knutsen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Helle Katrine</ForeName>
            <Initials>HK</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Maciuk</LastName>
            <ForeName>Alexandre</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mangelsdorf</LastName>
            <ForeName>Inge</ForeName>
            <Initials>I</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>McArdle</LastName>
            <ForeName>Harry J</ForeName>
            <Initials>HJ</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Naska</LastName>
            <ForeName>Androniki</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Peláez</LastName>
            <ForeName>Carmen</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Pentieva</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kristina</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Thies</LastName>
            <ForeName>Frank</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tsabouri</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sophia</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Vinceti</LastName>
            <ForeName>Marco</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bresson</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jean-Louis</ForeName>
            <Initials>JL</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Siani</LastName>
            <ForeName>Alfonso</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>04</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>EFSA J</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101642076</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1831-4732</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dietary reference values</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">diet‐related chronic diseases</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">food‐based dietary guidelines</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nutrient intakes</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nutrient profiling models</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">public health</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>40</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35464873</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9016720</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2903/j.efsa.2022.7259</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">EFS27259</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Abdelhamid AS, Brown TJ, Brainard JS, Biswas P, Thorpe GC, Moore HJ, Deane KH, Summerbell CD, Worthington HV, Song F and Hooper L, 2020. Omega‐3 fatty acids for the primary and secondary prevention of cardiovascular disease. Cochrane Database Systematic Review, 3. 10.1002/14651858.CD003177.pub5
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/14651858.CD003177.pub5</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Abete I, Romaguera D, Vieira AR, Lopez de Munain A and Norat T, 2014. Association between total, processed, red and white meat consumption and all‐cause, CVD and IHD mortality: a meta‐analysis of cohort studies. British Journal of Nutrition, 112, 762–775. 10.1017/S000711451400124X
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S000711451400124X</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Aburto NJ, Hanson S, Gutierrez H, Hooper L, Elliott P and Cappuccio FP, 2013. Effect of increased potassium intake on cardiovascular risk factors and disease: systematic review and meta‐analyses. BMJ, 346, f1378. 10.1136/bmj.f1378
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.f1378</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Afshin A, Micha R, Khatibzadeh S and Mozaffarian D, 2014. Consumption of nuts and legumes and risk of incident ischemic heart disease, stroke, and diabetes: a systematic review and meta‐analysis. American Journal of Clinical Nutrition, 100, 278–288. 10.3945/ajcn.113.076901
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/ajcn.113.076901</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Al‐Shaar L, Satija A, Wang DD, Rimm EB, Smith‐Warner SA, Stampfer MJ, Hu FB and Willett WC, 2020. Red meat intake and risk of coronary heart disease among US men: prospective cohort study. BMJ, 371, m4141. 10.1136/bmj.m4141
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.m4141</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
American Diabetes Association
, 2014. Diagnosis and classification of diabetes mellitus. Diabetes Care, 37, S81–S90. 10.2337/dc14-S081
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/dc14-S081</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24357215</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
ANSES (Agence nationale de sécurité sanitaire de l’alimentation, de l’environnement et du travail)
, 2016. Actualisation des repères du PNNS: élaboration des références nutritionnelles. 196 pp.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Arnett DK, Blumenthal RS, Albert MA, Buroker AB, Goldberger ZD, Hahn EJ, Himmelfarb CD, Khera A, Lloyd‐Jones D, McEvoy JW, Michos ED, Miedema MD, Munoz D, Smith SC Jr, Virani SS, Williams KA Sr, Yeboah J and Ziaeian B, 2019. 2019 ACC/AHA Guideline on the primary prevention of cardiovascular disease: a report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Task Force on Clinical Practice Guidelines. Circulation, 140, e596–e646. 10.1161/CIR.0000000000000678
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIR.0000000000000678</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7734661</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30879355</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Astrup A, Magkos F, Bier DM, Brenna JT, de Oliveira Otto MC, Hill JO, King JC, Mente A, Ordovas JM, Volek JS, Yusuf S and Krauss RM, 2020. Saturated fats and health: a reassessment and proposal for food‐based recommendations: JACC state‐of‐the‐art review. Journal of the American College of Cardiology, 76, 844–857. 10.1016/j.jacc.2020.05.077
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2020.05.077</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32562735</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Aune D, Giovannucci E, Boffetta P, Fadnes LT, Keum N, Norat T, Greenwood DC, Riboli E, Vatten LJ and Tonstad S, 2017. Fruit and vegetable intake and the risk of cardiovascular disease, total cancer and all‐cause mortality‐a systematic review and dose‐response meta‐analysis of prospective studies. International Journal of Epidemiology, 46, 1029–1056. 10.1093/ije/dyw319
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ije/dyw319</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5837313</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28338764</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Aune D, Keum N, Giovannucci E, Fadnes LT, Boffetta P, Greenwood DC, Tonstad S, Vatten LJ, Riboli E and Norat T, 2016a. Nut consumption and risk of cardiovascular disease, total cancer, all‐cause and cause‐specific mortality: a systematic review and dose‐response meta‐analysis of prospective studies. BMC Medical, 14, 207. 10.1186/s12916-016-073
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12916-016-073</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Aune D, Sen A, Prasad M, Norat T, Janszky I, Tonstad S, Romundstad P and Vatten LJ, 2016b. BMI and all cause mortality: systematic review and non‐linear dose‐response meta‐analysis of 230 cohort studies with 3.74 million deaths among 30.3 million participants. BMJ, 353. 10.1136/bmj.i2156
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.i2156</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Aune D, Ursin G and Veierød MB, 2009. Meat consumption and the risk of type 2 diabetes: a systematic review and meta‐analysis of cohort studies. Diabetologia, 52, 2277–2287. 10.1007/s00125-009-1481-x
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00125-009-1481-x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19662376</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Barciela‐Alonso MC and Bermejo‐Barrera P, 2015. Variation of food mineral content during industrial and culinary processing. Handbook of Mineral Elements in Food, 163–176. 10.1002/9781118654316.ch8
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/9781118654316.ch8</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Bazzano LA, 2008. Effects of soluble dietary fiber on low‐density lipoprotein cholesterol and coronary heart disease risk. Current Atherosclerosis Reports, 10, 473–477. 10.1007/s11883-008-0074-3
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11883-008-0074-3</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18937894</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Bechthold A, Boeing H, Schwedhelm C, Hoffmann G, Knüppel S, Iqbal K, De Henauw S, Michels N, Devleesschauwer B, Schlesinger S and Schwingshackl L, 2019. Food groups and risk of coronary heart disease, stroke and heart failure: a systematic review and dose‐response meta‐analysis of prospective studies. Critical Reviews in Food Science and Nutrition, 59, 1071–1090. 10.1080/10408398.2017.1392288
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10408398.2017.1392288</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29039970</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Bendsen NT, Christensen R, Bartels EM and Astrup A, 2011. Consumption of industrial and ruminant trans fatty acids and risk of coronary heart disease: a systematic review and meta‐analysis of cohort studies. European Journal of Clinical Nutrition, 65, 773–783. 10.1038/ejcn.2011.34
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ejcn.2011.34</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21427742</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Bischoff‐Ferrari HA, Dawson‐Hughes B, Baron JA, Burckhardt P, Li R, Spiegelman D, Specker B, Orav JE, Wong JB, Staehelin HB, O'Reilly E, Kiel DP and Willett WC, 2007. Calcium intake and hip fracture risk in men and women: a meta‐analysis of prospective cohort studies and randomized controlled trials. American Journal of Clinical Nutrition, 86, 1780–1790. 10.1093/ajcn/86.5.1780
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ajcn/86.5.1780</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Boffetta P, Couto E, Wichmann J, Ferrari P, Trichopoulos D, Bueno‐de‐Mesquita HB, van Duijnhoven FJ, Büchner FL, Key T, Boeing H, Nöthlings U, Linseisen J, Gonzalez CA, Overvad K, Nielsen MR, Tjønneland A, Olsen A, Clavel‐Chapelon F, Boutron‐Ruault MC, Morois S, Lagiou P, Naska A, Benetou V, Kaaks R, Rohrmann S, Panico S, Sieri S, Vineis P, Palli D, van Gils CH, Peeters PH, Lund E, Brustad M, Engeset D, Huerta JM, Rodríguez L, Sánchez MJ, Dorronsoro M, Barricarte A, Hallmans G, Johansson I, Manjer J, Sonestedt E, Allen NE, Bingham S, Khaw KT, Slimani N, Jenab M, Mouw T, Norat T, Riboli E and Trichopoulou A, 2010. Fruit and vegetable intake and overall cancer risk in the European Prospective Investigation into Cancer and Nutrition (EPIC). Journal of the National Cancer Institute, 102, 529–537. 10.1093/jnci/djq072
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jnci/djq072</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20371762</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Borch D, Juul‐Hindsgaul N, Veller M, Astrup A, Jaskolowski J and Raben A, 2016. Potatoes and risk of obesity, type 2 diabetes, and cardiovascular disease in apparently healthy adults: a systematic review of clinical intervention and observational studies. American Journal of Clinical Nutrition, 104, 489–498. 10.3945/ajcn.116.132332
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/ajcn.116.132332</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Brannon PM and Taylor CL, 2017. Iron supplementation during pregnancy and infancy: uncertainties and implications for research and policy. Nutrients, 9. 10.3390/nu9121327
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu9121327</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Briggs MA, Petersen KS and Kris‐Etherton PM, 2017. Saturated fatty acids and cardiovascular disease: replacements for saturated fat to reduce cardiovascular risk. Healthcare (Basel), 5. 10.3390/healthcare5020029
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/healthcare5020029</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Capuano E, van der Veer G, Verheijen PJJ, Heenan SP, van de Laak LFJ, Koopmans HBM and van Ruth SM, 2013. Comparison of a sodium‐based and a chloride‐based approach for the determination of sodium chloride content of processed foods in the Netherlands. Journal of Food Composition and Analysis, 31, 129–136. 10.1016/j.jfca.2013.04.004
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jfca.2013.04.004</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Chen Z, Ahmed M, Ha V, Jefferson K, Malik V, Ribeiro PAB, Zuchinali P and Drouin‐Chartier J‐P, 2021. Dairy product consumption and cardiovascular health: a systematic review and meta‐analysis of prospective cohort studies. Advances in Nutrition, 10.1093/advances/nmab118
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/advances/nmab118</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Cummings J, 2001. The effect of dietary fiber on fecal weight and composition. In: Spiller G (ed.). CRC Handbook of Dietary Fiber in Human Nutrition, CRC Press, Boca Raton, Florida, USA. pp. 183–252.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
D‐A‐CH (Deutsche Gesellschaft für Ernährung, Österreichische Gesellschaft für Ernährung, Schweizerische Gesellschaft für Ernährung)
, 2015. Referenzwerte für die Nährstoffzufuhr, DGE, Bonn, Germany.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Davis C, Bryan J, Hodgson J and Murphy K, 2015. Definition of the Mediterranean Diet; a literature review. Nutrients, 7, 9139–9153. 10.3390/nu7115459
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu7115459</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4663587</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26556369</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Devi A and Khatkar BS, 2018. Effects of fatty acids composition and microstructure properties of fats and oils on textural properties of dough and cookie quality. Journal of Food Science and Technology, 55, 321–330. 10.1007/s13197-017-2942-8
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13197-017-2942-8</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5756218</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29358825</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
DH (Department of Health)
, 1991. Dietary reference values for food energy and nutrients for the United Kingdom. Report of the Panel on Dietary Reference Values of the Committee on Medical Aspects of Food Policy, HMSO, London, UK. 212 pp.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Dold S, Zimmermann MB, Jukic T, Kusic Z, Jia Q, Sang Z, Quirino A, San Luis TOL, Fingerhut R, Kupka R, Timmer A, Garrett GS and Andersson M, 2018. Universal salt iodization provides sufficient dietary iodine to achieve adequate iodine nutrition during the first 1000 days: A cross‐sectional multicenter study. Journal of Nutrition, 148, 587–598. 10.1093/jn/nxy015
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jn/nxy015</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Drouin‐Chartier JP, Brassard D, Tessier‐Grenier M, Côté JA, Labonté M, Desroches S, Couture P and Lamarche B, 2016. Systematic review of the association between dairy product consumption and risk of cardiovascular‐related clinical outcomes. Advances in Nutrition, 7, 1026–1040. 10.3945/an.115.011403
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/an.115.011403</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5105032</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28140321</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Du H, van der
 AD, Boshuizen
 HC, Forouhi
 NG, Wareham
 NJ, Halkjaer
 J, Tjønneland
 A, Overvad
 K, Jakobsen
 MU, Boeing
 H, Buijsse
 B, Masala
 G, Palli
 D, Sørensen
 TI, Saris
 WH and Feskens
 EJ, 2010. Dietary fiber and subsequent changes in body weight and waist circumference in European men and women. American Journal of Clinical Nutrition, 91, 329–336. 10.3945/ajcn.2009.28191
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/ajcn.2009.28191</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
EFSA (European Food Safety Authority)
, 2009. Scientific substantiation of a health claim related to Calcium plus Vitamin D3 chewing tablets and reduction of the risk of osteoporotic fractures by reducing bone loss pursuant to Article 14 of Regulation (EC) No 1924/2006. EFSA Journal 2009;7(8):1180, 13 pp. 10.2903/j.efsa.2009.1180
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2903/j.efsa.2009.1180</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
EFSA (European Food Safety Authority)
, 2020. Draft framework for protocol development for EFSA’s scientific assessments. EFSA supporting publication 2020;EN‐1843, 46 pp. 10.2903/sp.efsa.2020.EN-1843
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2903/sp.efsa.2020.EN-1843</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
EFSA NDA Panel (EFSA Panel on Dietetic Products Nutrition and Allergies)
, 2009. Scientific Opinion on the substantiation of health claims related to vitamin C and protection of DNA, proteins and lipids from oxidative damage (ID 129, 138, 143, 148), antioxidant function of lutein (ID 146), maintenance of vision (ID 141, 142), collagen formation (ID 130, 131, 136, 137, 149), function of the nervous system (ID 133), function of the immune system (ID 134), function of the immune system during and after extreme physical exercise (ID 144), non‐haem iron absorption (ID 132, 147), energy‐yielding metabolism (ID 135), and relief in case of irritation in the upper respiratory tract (ID 1714, 1715) pursuant to Article 13(1) of Regulation (EC) No 1924/2006 on request from the European Commission. EFSA Journal 2009;7(9):1226, 28 pp. 10.2903/j.efsa.2009.1226
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2903/j.efsa.2009.1226</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
EFSA NDA Panel (EFSA Panel on Dietetic Products Nutrition and Allergies)
, 2017. Scientific Opinion on the safety and suitability for use by infants of follow‐on formulae with a protein content of at least 1.6 g/100 kcal. EFSA Journal 2017;15(5):4781, 29 pp. 10.2903/j.efsa.2017.4781
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2903/j.efsa.2017.4781</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
EFSA NDA Panel (EFSA Panel on Dietetic Products, Nutrition and Allergies)
, 2008. The setting of nutrient profiles for foods bearing nutrition and health claims pursuant to Article 4 of the Regulation (EC) No 1924/2006 ‐ Scientific Opinion of the Panel on Dietetic Products, Nutrition and Allergies. EFSA Journal 2008;6(2):644, 45 pp. 10.2903/j.efsa.2008.644
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2903/j.efsa.2008.644</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
EFSA NDA Panel (EFSA Panel on Dietetic Products, Nutrition and Allergies)
, 2010a. Scientific Opinion in relation to the authorisation procedure for health claims on calcium and vitamin D and the reduction of the risk of osteoporotic fractures by reducing bone loss pursuant to Article 14 of Regulation (EC) No 1924/2006. EFSA Journal 2010;8(5):1609, 10 pp. 10.2903/j.efsa.2010.1609
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2903/j.efsa.2010.1609</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
EFSA NDA Panel (EFSA Panel on Dietetic Products, Nutrition, and Allergies)
, 2010b. Scientific Opinion on Dietary Reference Values for carbohydrates and dietary fibre. EFSA Journal 2010;8(3):1462, 77 pp. 10.2903/j.efsa.2010.1462
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2903/j.efsa.2010.1462</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
EFSA NDA Panel (EFSA Panel on Dietetic Products, Nutrition, and Allergies)
, 2010c. Scientific Opinion on Dietary Reference Values for fats, including saturated fatty acids, polyunsaturated fatty acids, monounsaturated fatty acids, trans fatty acids, and cholesterol. EFSA Journal 2010;8(3):1461, 107 pp. 10.2903/j.efsa.2010.1461
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2903/j.efsa.2010.1461</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
EFSA NDA Panel (EFSA Panel on Dietetic Products, Nutrition, Allergies)
, 2010d. Scientific Opinion on establishing Food‐Based Dietary Guidelines. EFSA Journal 2010;8(3):1460, 42 pp. 10.2903/j.efsa.2010.1460
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2903/j.efsa.2010.1460</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
EFSA NDA Panel (EFSA Panel on Dietetic Products, Nutrition, and Allergies)
, 2010e. Scientific Opinion on principles for deriving and applying Dietary Reference Values. EFSA Journal 2010;8(3):1458, 45 pp. 10.2903/j.efsa.20101458
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2903/j.efsa.20101458</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
EFSA NDA Panel (EFSA Panel on Dietetic Products, Nutrition and Allergies)
, 2010f. Scientific Opinion on the substantiation of health claims related to eicosapentaenoic acid (EPA), docosahexaenoic acid (DHA), docosapentaenoic acid (DPA) and maintenance of normal cardiac function (ID 504, 506, 516, 527, 538, 703, 1128, 1317, 1324, 1325), maintenance of normal blood glucose concentrations (ID 566), maintenance of normal blood pressure (ID 506, 516, 703, 1317, 1324), maintenance of normal blood HDL‐cholesterol concentrations (ID 506), maintenance of normal (fasting) blood concentrations of triglycerides (ID 506, 527, 538, 1317, 1324, 1325), maintenance of normal blood LDL‐cholesterol concentrations (ID 527, 538, 1317, 1325, 4689), protection of the skin from photo‐oxidative (UV‐induced) damage (ID 530), improved absorption of EPA and DHA (ID 522, 523), contribution to the normal function of the immune system by decreasing the levels of eicosanoids, arachidonic acid‐derived mediators and pro‐inflammatory cytokines (ID 520, 2914), and “immunomodulating agent” (4690) pursuant to Article 13(1) of Regulation (EC) No 1924/2006. EFSA Journal 2010;8(10):1796, 32 pp. 10.2903/j.efsa.2010.1796
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2903/j.efsa.2010.1796</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
EFSA NDA Panel (EFSA Panel on Dietetic Products, Nutrition and Allergies)
, 2010g. Scientific Opinion on the substantiation of health claims related to stearic acid and maintenance of normal blood cholesterol concentrations (ID 716, 1657) pursuant to Article 13(1) of Regulation (EC) No 1924/2006. EFSA Journal 2010;8(2):1476, 14 pp. 10.2903/j.efsa.2010.1476
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2903/j.efsa.2010.1476</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
EFSA NDA Panel (EFSA Panel on Dietetic Products, Nutrition and Allergies)
, 2011a. Scientific Opinion on the substantiation of a health claim related to vitamin D and risk of falling pursuant to Article 14 of Regulation (EC) No 1924/2006. EFSA Journal 2011;9(9):2382, 18 pp. 10.2903/j.efsa.2011.2382
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2903/j.efsa.2011.2382</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
EFSA NDA Panel (EFSA Panel on Dietetic Products, Nutrition and Allergies)
, 2011b. Scientific Opinion on the substantiation of health claims related to foods with reduced amounts of saturated fatty acids (SFAs) and maintenance of normal blood LDL‐cholesterol concentrations. (ID 620, 671, 4332) pursuant to Article 13(1) of Regulation (EC) No 1924/2006. EFSA Journal 2011;9(4):2062, 14 pp. 10.2903/j.efsa.2011.2062
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2903/j.efsa.2011.2062</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
EFSA NDA Panel (EFSA Panel on Dietetic Products, Nutrition and Allergies)
, 2011c. Scientific Opinion on the substantiation of health claims related to polyphenols in olive and protection of LDL particles from oxidative damage (ID 1333, 1638, 1639, 1696, 2865), maintenance of normal blood HDL‐cholesterol concentrations (ID 1639), maintenance of normal blood pressure (ID 3781), “anti‐inflammatory properties” (ID 1882), “contributes to the upper respiratory tract health” (ID 3468), “can help to maintain a normal function of gastrointestinal tract” (3779), and “contributes to body defences against external agents” (ID 3467) pursuant to Article 13(1) of Regulation (EC) No 1924/2006. EFSA Journal 2011;9(4):2033, 25 pp. 10.2903/j.efsa.2011.2033
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2903/j.efsa.2011.2033</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
EFSA Nda Panel (EFSA Panel on Dietetic Products, Nutrition and Allergies)
, 2011d. Scientific Opinion on the substantiation of health claims related to the replacement of mixtures of saturated fatty acids (SFAs) as present in foods or diets with mixtures of monounsaturated fatty acids (MUFAs) and/or mixtures of polyunsaturated fatty acids (PUFAs), and maintenance of normal blood LDL‐cholesterol concentrations (ID 621, 1190, 1203, 2906, 2910, 3065) pursuant to Article 13(1) of Regulation (EC) No 1924/2006. EFSA Journal 2011;9(4):2069, 18 pp. 10.2903/j.efsa.2011.2069
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2903/j.efsa.2011.2069</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
EFSA NDA Panel (EFSA Panel on Dietetic Products, Nutrition and Allergies)
, 2012a. Scientific Opinion on Dietary Reference Values for protein. EFSA Journal 2012;10(2):2557, 66 pp. 10.2903/j.efsa.2012.2557
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2903/j.efsa.2012.2557</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
EFSA NDA Panel (EFSA Panel on Dietetic Products, Nutrition and Allergies)
, 2012b. Scientific Opinion related to the Tolerable Upper Intake Level of eicosapentaenoic acid (EPA), docosahexaenoic acid (DHA) and docosapentaenoic acid (DPA). EFSA Journal 2012;10(7):2815, 48 pp. 10.2903/j.efsa.2012.2815
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2903/j.efsa.2012.2815</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
EFSA NDA Panel (EFSA Panel on Dietetic Products, Nutrition and Allergies)
, 2013. Scientific Opinion on Dietary Reference Values for energy. EFSA Journal 2013;11(1):3005, 112 pp. 10.2903/j.efsa.2013.3005
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2903/j.efsa.2013.3005</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
EFSA NDA Panel (EFSA Panel on Dietetic Products, Nutrition and Allergies)
, 2014a. Scientific Opinion on Dietary Reference Values for folate. EFSA Journal 2014;12(11):3893, 59 pp. 10.2903/j.efsa.2014.3893
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2903/j.efsa.2014.3893</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
EFSA NDA Panel (EFSA Panel on Panel on Dietetic Products, Nutrition and Allergies)
, 2014b. Scientific Opinion on Dietary Reference Values for iodine. EFSA Journal 2014;12(5):3660, 57 pp. 10.2903/j.efsa.2014.3660
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2903/j.efsa.2014.3660</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
EFSA NDA Panel (EFSA Panel on Dietetic Products, Nutrition and Allergies)
, 2014c. Scientific Opinion on health benefits of seafood (fish and shellfish) consumption in relation to health risks associated with exposure to methylmercury. EFSA Journal 2014;12(7):3761, 80 pp. 10.2903/j.efsa.2014.3761
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2903/j.efsa.2014.3761</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
EFSA NDA Panel (EFSA Panel on Dietetic Products, Nutrition and Allergies)
, 2015a. Scientific Opinion on Dietary Reference Values for calcium. EFSA Journal 2015;13(5):4101, 82 pp. 10.2903/j.efsa.2015.4101
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2903/j.efsa.2015.4101</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
EFSA NDA Panel (EFSA Panel on Dietetic Products, Nutrition and Allergies)
, 2015b. Scientific Opinion on Dietary Reference Values for iron. EFSA Journal 2015;13(10):4254, 115 pp. 10.2903/j.efsa.2015.4254
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2903/j.efsa.2015.4254</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
EFSA NDA Panel (EFSA Panel on Dietetic Products, Nutrition and Allergies)
, 2016a. Scientific opinion on Dietary Reference Values for potassium. EFSA Journal 2016;14(10):4592, 56 pp. 10.2903/j.efsa.2016.4592
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2903/j.efsa.2016.4592</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
EFSA NDA Panel (EFSA Panel on Dietetic Products, Nutrition and Allergies)
, 2016b. Scientific opinion on Dietary Reference Values for vitamin D. EFSA Journal 2016;14(10):4547, 145 pp. 10.2903/j.efsa.2016.4547
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2903/j.efsa.2016.4547</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
EFSA NDA Panel (EFSA Panel on Dietetic Products, Nutrition and Allergies)
, 2018. Guidance for the scientific requirements for health claims related to antioxidants, oxidative damage and cardiovascular health (Revision 1). EFSA Journal 2018;16(1):5136, 21 pp. 10.2903/j.efsa.2018.5136
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2903/j.efsa.2018.5136</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
EFSA NDA Panel (EFSA Panel on Nutrition, Novel Foods and Food Allergens)
, 2019a. Scientific Opinion on the appropriate age range for introduction of complementary feeding into an infant’s diet. EFSA Journal 2019;17(9):5780, 241 pp. 10.2903/j.efsa.2019.5780
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2903/j.efsa.2019.5780</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
EFSA NDA Panel (EFSA Panel on Nutrition, Novel Foods and Food Allergens)
, 2019b. Scientific Opinion on the Dietary Reference Values for sodium. EFSA Journal 2019;17(9):5778, 191 pp. 10.2903/j.efsa.2019.5778
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2903/j.efsa.2019.5778</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
EFSA NDA Panel (EFSA Panel on Nutrition, Novel Foods and Food Allergens)
, 2022. Scientific Opinion on the Tolerable upper intake level for dietary sugars. EFSA Journal 2022;20(2):7074, 337 pp. 10.2903/j.efsa.2021.7074
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2903/j.efsa.2021.7074</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Eilander A, Harika RK and Zock PL, 2015. Intake and sources of dietary fatty acids in Europe: are current population intakes of fats aligned with dietary recommendations?
European Journal of Lipid Science and Technology, 117, 1370–1377. 10.1002/ejlt.201400513
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ejlt.201400513</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4736684</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26877707</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Elia M and Cummings JH, 2007. Physiological aspects of energy metabolism and gastrointestinal effects of carbohydrates. European Journal of Clinical Nutrition, 61, S40–S74. 10.1038/sj.ejcn.1602938
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sj.ejcn.1602938</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17992186</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Ellegård L and Andersson H, 2007. Oat bran rapidly increases bile acid excretion and bile acid synthesis: an ileostomy study. European Journal of Clinical Nutrition, 61, 938–945. 10.1038/sj.ejcn.1602607
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sj.ejcn.1602607</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17251929</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
European Commission
, 2012. Survey on Members States’ implementation of the EU salt reduction framework. 26 pp. Available online: https://ec.europa.eu/health//sites/health/files/nutrition_physical_activity/docs/salt_report1_en.pdf
</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
European Commission
, 2020a. COMMISSION STAFF WORKING DOCUMENT EVALUATION of the Regulation (EC) No 1924/2006 on nutrition and health claims made on foods with regard to nutrient profiles and health claims made on plants and their preparations and of the general regulatory framework for their use in foods. SWD(2020) 95 final Available online: https://ec.europa.eu/food/system/files/2020‐05/labelling_nutrition‐claims_swd_2020‐95_part‐1.pdf
</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
European Commission
, 2020b. Report from the Commission to the European Parliament and the Council regarding the use of additional forms of expression and presentation of the nutrition declaration. COM(2020) 207 final, 25 pp.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Eyles H, Webster J, Jebb S, Capelin C, Neal B and Ni Mhurchu C, 2013. Impact of the UK voluntary sodium reduction targets on the sodium content of processed foods from 2006 to 2011: analysis of household consumer panel data. Preventive Medicine, 57, 555–560. 10.1016/j.ypmed.2013.07.024
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ypmed.2013.07.024</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23954183</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Fan M, Li Y, Wang C, Mao Z, Zhou W, Zhang L, Yang X, Cui S and Li L, 2019. Dietary protein consumption and the risk of type 2 diabetes: a dose‐response meta‐analysis of prospective studies. Nutrients, 11. 10.3390/nu11112783
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu11112783</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Farvid MS, Sidahmed E, Spence ND, Mante Angua K, Rosner BA and Barnett JB, 2021. Consumption of red meat and processed meat and cancer incidence: a systematic review and meta‐analysis of prospective studies. European Journal of Epidemiology, 36, 937–951. 10.1007/s10654-021-00741-9
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10654-021-00741-9</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34455534</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Fewtrell M, Bronsky J, Campoy C, Domellof M, Embleton N, Fidler Mis N, Hojsak I, Hulst JM, Indrio F, Lapillonne A and Molgaard C, 2017. Complementary feeding: A position paper by the European Society for Paediatric Gastroenterology, Hepatology, and Nutrition (ESPGHAN) Committee on Nutrition. Journal of Pediatric Gastroenterology and Nutrition, 64, 119–132. 10.1097/MPG.0000000000001454
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MPG.0000000000001454</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28027215</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Global BMI Mortality Collaboration
, Di Angelantonio E, Bhupathiraju Sh N, Wormser D, Gao P, Kaptoge S, Berrington de Gonzalez A, Cairns BJ, Huxley R, Jackson Ch L, Joshy G, Lewington S, Manson JE, Murphy N, Patel AV, Samet JM, Woodward M, Zheng W, Zhou M, Bansal N, Barricarte A, Carter B, Cerhan JR, Smith GD, Fang X, Franco OH, Green J, Halsey J, Hildebrand JS, Jung KJ, Korda RJ, McLerran DF, Moore SC, O'Keeffe LM, Paige E, Ramond A, Reeves GK, Rolland B, Sacerdote C, Sattar N, Sofianopoulou E, Stevens J, Thun M, Ueshima H, Yang L, Yun YD, Willeit P, Banks E, Beral V, Chen Z, Gapstur SM, Gunter MJ, Hartge P, Jee SH, Lam TH, Peto R, Potter JD, Willett WC, Thompson SG, Danesh J and 
Hu
FB,
2016. Body‐mass index and all‐cause mortality: individual‐participant‐data meta‐analysis of 239 prospective studies in four continents. Lancet, 388, 776–786. 10.1016/S0140-6736(16)30175-1
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(16)30175-1</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4995441</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27423262</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Guasch‐Ferré M, Liu G, Li Y, Sampson L, Manson JE, Salas‐Salvadó J, Martínez‐González MA, Stampfer MJ, Willett WC, Sun Q and Hu FB, 2020. Olive Oil Consumption and Cardiovascular Risk in U.S. Adults. Journal of the American College of Cardiology, 75, 1729–1739. 10.1016/j.jacc.2020.02.036
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2020.02.036</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7233327</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32147453</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Guo J, Astrup A, Lovegrove JA, Gijsbers L, Givens DI and Soedamah‐Muthu SS, 2017. Milk and dairy consumption and risk of cardiovascular diseases and all‐cause mortality: dose‐response meta‐analysis of prospective cohort studies. European Journal of Epidemiology, 32, 269–287. 10.1007/s10654-017-0243-1
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10654-017-0243-1</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5437143</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28374228</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Guo F, Zhang Q, Jiang H, He Y, Li M, Ran J, Lin J, Tian L and Ma L, 2021. Dietary potato intake and risks of type 2 diabetes and gestational diabetes mellitus. Clinical Nutrition, 40, 3754–3764. 10.1016/j.clnu.2021.04.039
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clnu.2021.04.039</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34130021</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Hall KD, Sacks G, Chandramohan D, Chow CC, Wang YC, Gortmaker SL and Swinburn BA, 2011. Quantification of the effect of energy imbalance on bodyweight. Lancet, 378, 826–837. 10.1016/S0140-6736(11)60812-X
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(11)60812-X</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3880593</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21872751</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Han MA, Zeraatkar D, Guyatt GH, Vernooij RWM, El Dib R, Zhang Y, Algarni A, Leung G, Storman D, Valli C, Rabassa M, Rehman N, Parvizian MK, Zworth M, Bartoszko JJ, Lopes LC, Sit D, Bala MM, Alonso‐Coello P and Johnston BC, 2019. Reduction of red and processed meat intake and cancer mortality and incidence: a systematic review and meta‐analysis of cohort studies. Annals of Internal Medicine, 171, 711–720. 10.7326/m19-0699
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/m19-0699</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31569214</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Händel MN, Rohde JF, Jacobsen R, Nielsen SM, Christensen R, Alexander DD, Frederiksen P and Heitmann BL, 2020. Processed meat intake and incidence of colorectal cancer: a systematic review and meta‐analysis of prospective observational studies. European Journal of Clinical Nutrition, 74, 1132–1148. 10.1038/s41430-020-0576-9
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41430-020-0576-9</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32029911</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
HCN (Health Council of the Netherlands)
, 2018. Dietary Reference Values for vitamins and minerals for adults. No. 2018/19e, 34 pp.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
IARC (International Agency for Research on Cancer)
, 2018. IARC Monographs on the evaluation of carcinogenic risks to humans: red meat and processed meat. Available online: https://monographs.iarc.who.int/wp‐content/uploads/2018/06/mono114.pdf
</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
IoM (Institute of Medicine)
, 1998. Dietary Reference Intakes for thiamin, riboflavin, niacin, vitamin B6, folate, vitamin B12, pantothenic acid, biotin, and choline, National Academy Press, Washington, DC, USA, Food and Nutrition Board. 591 pp.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
IoM (Institute of Medicine)
, 2011. Dietary Reference Intakes for calcium and vitamin D, National Academies Press, Washington, DC, USA. 1133 pp.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Ittermann T, Albrecht D, Arohonka P, Bilek R, de Castro JJ, Dahl L, Filipsson Nystrom H, Gaberscek S, Garcia‐Fuentes E, Gheorghiu ML, Hubalewska‐Dydejczyk A, Hunziker S, Jukic T, Karanfilski B, Koskinen S, Kusic Z, Majstorov V, Makris KC, Markou KB, Meisinger C, Milevska Kostova N, Mullen KR, Nagy EV, Pirags V, Rojo‐Martinez G, Samardzic M, Saranac L, Strele I, Thamm M, Top I, Trofimiuk‐Müldner M, Ünal B, Koskinen S, Vila L, Vitti P, Winter B, Woodside JV, Zaletel K, Zamrazil V, Zimmermann M, Erlund I and Völzke H, 2020. Standardized map of iodine status in Europe. Thyroid, 30, 1346–1354. 10.1089/thy.2019.0353
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/thy.2019.0353</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32460688</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Jensen MD, Ryan DH, Apovian CM, Ard JD, Comuzzie AG, Donato KA, Hu FB, Hubbard VS, Jakicic JM, Kushner RF, Loria CM, Millen BE, Nonas CA, Pi‐Sunyer FX, Stevens J, Stevens VJ, Wadden TA, Wolfe BM and Yanovski SZ, 2014. 2013 AHA/ACC/TOS Guideline for the management of overweight and obesity in adults. Circulation, 129, S102–S138. 10.1161/01.cir.0000437739.71477.ee
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.cir.0000437739.71477.ee</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5819889</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24222017</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Jepsen S, Blanco J, Buchalla W, Carvalho JC, Dietrich T, Dörfer C, Eaton KA, Figuero E, Frencken JE, Graziani F, Higham SM, Kocher T, Maltz M, Ortiz‐Vigon A, Schmoeckel J, Sculean A, Tenuta LM, van der Veen MH and Machiulskiene V, 2017. Prevention and control of dental caries and periodontal diseases at individual and population level: consensus report of group 3 of joint EFP/ORCA workshop on the boundaries between caries and periodontal diseases. Journal of Clinical Periodontology, 44, S85–s93. 10.1111/jcpe.12687
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jcpe.12687</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28266120</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Kang ZQ, Yang Y and Xiao B, 2020. Dietary saturated fat intake and risk of stroke: systematic review and dose‐response meta‐analysis of prospective cohort studies. Nutrition, Metabolism, and Cardiovascular Diseases, 30, 179–189. 10.1016/j.numecd.2019.09.028
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.numecd.2019.09.028</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Kanis JA, Norton N, Harvey NC, Jacobson T, Johansson H, Lorentzon M, McCloskey EV, Willers C and Borgstrom F, 2021. SCOPE 2021: a new scorecard for osteoporosis in Europe. Archives of Osteoporosis, 16, 82. 10.1007/s11657-020-00871-9
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11657-020-00871-9</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8172408</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34080059</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Kloss L, Meyer JD, Graeve L and Vetter W, 2015. Sodium intake and its reduction by food reformulation in the European Union — A review. NFS Journal, 1, 9–19. 10.1016/j.nfs.2015.03.001
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nfs.2015.03.001</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Knuuti J, Wijns W, Saraste A, Capodanno D, Barbato E, Funck‐Brentano C, Prescott E, Storey RF, Deaton C, Cuisset T, Agewall S, Dickstein K, Edvardsen T, Escaned J, Gersh BJ, Svitil P, Gilard M, Hasdai D, Hatala R, Mahfoud F, Masip J, Muneretto C, Valgimigli M, Achenbach S, Bax JJ and the ESC Scientific Document Group, 2019. 2019 ESC Guidelines for the diagnosis and management of chronic coronary syndromes: the Task Force for the diagnosis and management of chronic coronary syndromes of the European Society of Cardiology (ESC). European Heart Journal, 41, 407–477. 10.1093/eurheartj/ehz425
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurheartj/ehz425</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Koh‐Banerjee P, Chu NF, Spiegelman D, Rosner B, Colditz G, Willett W and Rimm E, 2003. Prospective study of the association of changes in dietary intake, physical activity, alcohol consumption, and smoking with 9‐y gain in waist circumference among 16 587 US men. American Journal of Clinical Nutrition, 78, 719–727. 10.1093/ajcn/78.4.719
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ajcn/78.4.719</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Labonté M, Poon T, Gladanac B, Ahmed M, Franco‐Arellano B, Rayner M and L'Abbé MR, 2018. Nutrient profile models with applications in government‐led nutrition policies aimed at health promotion and noncommunicable disease prevention: a systematic review. Advances in Nutrition, 9, 741–788. 10.1093/advances/nmy045
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/advances/nmy045</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6247226</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30462178</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Iqbal R, Dehghan M, Mente A, Rangarajan S, Wielgosz A, Avezum A, Seron P, AlHabib KF, Lopez-Jaramillo P, Swaminathan S, Mohammadifard N, Zatońska K, Bo H, Varma RP, Rahman O, Yusufali A, Lu Y, Ismail N, Rosengren A, Imeryuz N, Yeates K, Chifamba J, Dans A, Kumar R, Xiaoyun L, Tsolekile L, Khatib R, Diaz R, Teo K and Yusuf S, 2021. Associations of unprocessed and processed meat intake with mortality and cardiovascular disease in 21 countries [Prospective Urban Rural Epidemiology (PURE) Study]: a prospective cohort study.
American Journal of Clinical Nutrition, 114, 1049–1058. 10.1093/ajcn/nqaa448
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ajcn/nqaa448</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Ma C, Avenell A, Bolland M, Hudson J, Stewart F, Robertson C, Sharma P, Fraser C and MacLennan G, 2017. Effects of weight loss interventions for adults who are obese on mortality, cardiovascular disease, and cancer: systematic review and meta‐analysis. BMJ, 359. 10.1136/bmj.j4849
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.j4849</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Mach F, Baigent C, Catapano AL, Koskinas KC, Casula M, Badimon L, Chapman MJ, De Backer GG, Delgado V, Ference BA, Graham IM, Halliday A, Landmesser U, Mihaylova B, Pedersen TR, Riccardi G, Richter DJ, Sabatine MS, Taskinen MR, Tokgozoglu L, Wiklund O and Group ESCSD, 2020. 2019 ESC/EAS Guidelines for the management of dyslipidaemias: lipid modification to reduce cardiovascular risk. European Heart Journal, 41, 111–188. 10.1093/eurheartj/ehz455
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurheartj/ehz455</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31504418</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Mayhew AJ, de Souza RJ, Meyre D, Anand SS and Mente A, 2016. A systematic review and meta‐analysis of nut consumption and incident risk of CVD and all‐cause mortality. British Journal of Nutrition, 115, 212–225. 10.1017/S0007114515004316
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0007114515004316</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
McRae MP, 2017. Dietary fiber is beneficial for the prevention of cardiovascular disease: an umbrella review of meta‐analyses. Journal of Chiropractic Medicine, 16, 289–299. 10.1016/j.jcm.2017.05.005
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcm.2017.05.005</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5731843</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29276461</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Micha R, Khatibzadeh S, Shi P, Fahimi S, Lim S, Andrews KG, Engell RE, Powles J, Ezzati M, Mozaffarian D and the Global Burden of Diseases Nutrition and Chronic Diseases Expert Group, 2014. Global, regional, and national consumption levels of dietary fats and oils in 1990 and 2010: a systematic analysis including 266 country‐specific nutrition surveys. BMJ, 348. 10.1136/bmj.g2272
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.g2272</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Micha R, Wallace SK and Mozaffarian D, 2010. Red and processed meat consumption and risk of incident coronary heart disease, stroke, and diabetes mellitus: a systematic review and meta‐analysis. Circulation, 121, 2271–2283. 10.1161/circulationaha.109.924977
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/circulationaha.109.924977</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2885952</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20479151</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Milman NT, 2019. Dietary iron intake in women of reproductive age in Europe: a review of 49 studies from 29 countries in the period 1993–2015. Journal of Nutrition and Metabolism, 2019, 7631306. 10.1155/2019/7631306
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2019/7631306</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6595378</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31312532</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Milman NT, 2020a. Dietary iron intake in pregnant women in Europe: a review of 24 studies from 14 countries in the period 1991–2014. Journal of Nutrition and Metabolism, 2020, 7102190. 10.1155/2020/7102190
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2020/7102190</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7060865</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32185079</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Milman NT, 2020b. Dietary iron intakes in men in Europe are distinctly above the recommendations: a review of 39 national studies from 20 countries in the period 1995–2016. Gastroenterology Research, 13, 233–245. 10.14740/gr1344
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.14740/gr1344</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7781270</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33447302</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Mithril C, Dragsted LO, Meyer C, Blauert E, Holt MK and Astrup A, 2012. Guidelines for the new nordic diet. Public Health Nutrition, 15, 1941–1947. 10.1017/S136898001100351X
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S136898001100351X</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22251407</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Mithril C, Dragsted LO, Meyer C, Tetens I, Biltoft‐Jensen A and Astrup A, 2013. Dietary composition and nutrient content of the New Nordic Diet. Public Health Nutrition, 16, 777–785. 10.1017/s1368980012004521
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/s1368980012004521</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23089239</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Mongraw‐Chaffin ML, Peters SAE, Huxley RR and Woodward M, 2015. The sex‐specific association between BMI and coronary heart disease: a systematic review and meta‐analysis of 95 cohorts with 1.2 million participants. The Lancet Diabetes &amp; Endocrinology, 3, 437–449. 10.1016/S2213-8587(15)00086-8
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2213-8587(15)00086-8</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4470268</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25960160</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Mouratidou T, Livaniou A, Martín Saborido C, Wollgast J and Caldeira S, 2014. Trans fatty acids in Europe: where do we stand?
JRC Science and Policy Reports, 68 pp.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Mozaffarian D, 2016. Dietary and policy priorities for cardiovascular disease, diabetes, and obesity: a comprehensive review. Circulation, 133, 187–225. 10.1161/circulationaha.115.018585
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/circulationaha.115.018585</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4814348</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26746178</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Mozaffarian D, Dashti HS, Wojczynski MK, Chu AY, Nettleton JA, Männistö S, Kristiansson K, Reedik M, Lahti J, Houston DK, Cornelis MC, van Rooij FJA, Dimitriou M, Kanoni S, Mikkilä V, Steffen LM, de Oliveira Otto MC, Qi L, Psaty B, Djousse L, Rotter JI, Harald K, Perola M, Rissanen H, Jula A, Krista F, Mihailov E, Feitosa MF, Ngwa JS, Xue L, Jacques PF, Perälä MM, Palotie A, Liu Y, Nalls NA, Ferrucci L, Hernandez D, Manichaikul A, Tsai MY, Kiefte‐de Jong JC, Hofman A, Uitterlinden AG, Rallidis L, Ridker PM, Rose LM, Buring JE, Lehtimäki T, Kähönen M, Viikari J, Lemaitre R, Salomaa V, Knekt P, Metspalu A, Borecki IB, Cupples LA, Eriksson JG, Kritchevsky SB, Bandinelli S, Siscovick D, Franco OH, Deloukas P, Dedoussis G, Chasman DI, Raitakari O and Tanaka T, 2017. Genome‐wide association meta‐analysis of fish and EPA+DHA consumption in 17 US and European cohorts. PLoS One, 12, e0186456. 10.1371/journal.pone.0186456
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0186456</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Mozaffarian D, Micha R and Wallace S, 2010. Effects on coronary heart disease of increasing polyunsaturated fat in place of saturated fat: a systematic review and meta‐analysis of randomized controlled trials. PLoS Med, 7, e1000252. 10.1371/journal.pmed.1000252
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pmed.1000252</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Mozaffarian D and Rimm EB, 2006. Fish intake, contaminants, and human health: evaluating the risks and the benefits. JAMA, 296, 1885–1899. 10.1001/jama.296.15.1885
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.296.15.1885</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17047219</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Mozaffarian D and Wu JH, 2011. Omega‐3 fatty acids and cardiovascular disease: effects on risk factors, molecular pathways, and clinical events. Journal of the American College of Cardiology, 58, 2047–2067. 10.1016/j.jacc.2011.06.063
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2011.06.063</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22051327</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
NASEM (National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine)
, 2019. Dietary Reference Intakes for sodium and potassium, The National Academies Press, Washington, DC, USA. 498 pp. Available online: https://www.nap.edu/read/25353/chapter/1
</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
NCM (Nordic Council of Ministers)
, 2014. Nordic Nutrition Recommendations 2012. Integrating nutrition and physical activity, 5th Edition. 627 pp.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Neuenschwander M, Ballon A, Weber KS, Norat T, Aune D, Schwingshackl L and Schlesinger S, 2019. Role of diet in type 2 diabetes incidence: umbrella review of meta‐analyses of prospective observational studies. BMJ, 366. 10.1136/bmj.l2368
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.l2368</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
NHMRC (National Health and Medical Research Council)
, 2017. Nutrient Reference Values for Australia and New Zealand including Recommended Dietary Intake, 320 pp.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Ni Mhurchu C, Capelin C, Dunford EK, Webster JL, Neal BC and Jebb SA&lt; 2011. Sodium content of processed foods in the United Kingdom: analysis of 44,000 foods purchased by 21,000 households. American Journal of Clinical Nutrition, 93, 594–600. 10.3945/ajcn.110.004481
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/ajcn.110.004481</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
NICE (National Institute for Health and Care Excellence)
, 2014. Vitamin D: supplement use in specific population groups. Public health guideline PH56, 55 pp.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
NICE (National Institute for Health and Care Excellence)
, 2015. Preventing excess weight gain. NICE. Guideline NG7, 55 pp.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Nouri‐Majd S, Salari‐Moghaddam A, Aminianfar A, Larijani B and Esmaillzadeh A, 2022. Association between red and processed meat consumption and risk of prostate cancer: a systematic review and meta‐analysis. Frontiers in Nutrition, 9. 10.3389/fnut.2022.801722
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnut.2022.801722</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Papier K, Knuppel A, Syam N, Jebb SA and Key TJ, 2021. Meat consumption and risk of ischemic heart disease: A systematic review and meta‐analysis. Critical Reviews in Food Science and Nutrition, 1–12. 10.1080/10408398.2021.1949575
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10408398.2021.1949575</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Poorolajal J, Heidarimoghis F, Karami M, Cheraghi Z, Gohari‐Ensaf F, Shahbazi F, Zareie B, Ameri P and Sahraee F, 2021. Factors for the primary prevention of breast cancer: a meta‐analysis of prospective cohort studies. Journal of Research Health Science, 21, e00520. 10.34172/jrhs.2021.57
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.34172/jrhs.2021.57</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Portalatin M and Winstead N, 2012. Medical management of constipation. Clinics in Colon and Rectal Surgery, 25, 12–19. 10.1055/s-0032-1301754
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0032-1301754</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3348737</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23449608</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Puska P and Ståhl T, 2010. Health in all policies‐the Finnish initiative: background, principles, and current issues. Annual Review of Public Health, 31, 315–328. 10.1146/annurev.publhealth.012809.103658
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev.publhealth.012809.103658</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Quan W, Jiao Y, Xue C, Li Y, Wang Z, Zeng M, Qin F, He Z and Chen J, 2020. Processed potatoes intake and risk of type 2 diabetes: a systematic review and meta‐analysis of nine prospective cohort studies. Critical Reviews in Food Science and Nutrition, 1–9. 10.1080/10408398.2020.1843395
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10408398.2020.1843395</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Rand WM, Pellett PL and Young VR, 2003. Meta‐analysis of nitrogen balance studies for estimating protein requirements in healthy adults. American Journal of Clinical Nutrition, 77, 109–127. 10.1093/ajcn/77.1.109
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ajcn/77.1.109</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
van der Reijden OL, Zimmermann MB and Galetti V, 2017. Iodine in dairy milk: sources, concentrations and importance to human health. Best Practice &amp; Research Clinical Endocrinology &amp; Metabolism, 31, 385–395. 10.1016/j.beem.2017.10.004
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.beem.2017.10.004</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29221567</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Rimm EB, Appel LJ, Chiuve SE, Djoussé L, Engler MB, Kris‐Etherton PM, Mozaffarian D, Siscovick DS, Lichtenstein AH, the American Heart Association Nutrition Committee of the Council on Lifestyle and Cardiometabolic Health, the Council on Epidemiology and Prevention, the Council on Cardiovascular Disease in the Young, the Council on Cardiovascular and Stroke Nursing and the Council on Clinical Cardiology, 2018. Seafood long‐chain n‐3 polyunsaturated fatty acids and cardiovascular disease: a science advisory from the American Heart Association. Circulation, 138, e35–e47. 10.1161/CIR.0000000000000574
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIR.0000000000000574</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6903778</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29773586</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Roe MA, Bell S, Oseredczuk M, Christensen T, Westenbrink S, Pakkala H, Presser K and Finglas PM, 2013. Updated food composition database for nutrient intake. EFSA supporting publication 2013;EN‐355, 21 pp.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Rong Y, Chen L, Zhu T, Song Y, Yu M, Shan Z, Sands A, Hu FB and Liu L, 2013. Egg consumption and risk of coronary heart disease and stroke: dose‐response meta‐analysis of prospective cohort studies. BMJ, 346, e8539. 10.1136/bmj.e8539
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.e8539</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Rosato V, Temple NJ, La Vecchia C, Castellan G, Tavani A and Guercio V, 2019. Mediterranean diet and cardiovascular disease: a systematic review and meta‐analysis of observational studies. European Journal of Nutrition, 58, 173–191. 10.1007/s00394-017-1582-0
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00394-017-1582-0</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29177567</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Rusińska A, Płudowski P, Walczak M, Borszewska‐Kornacka MK, Bossowski A, Chlebna‐Sokół D, Czech‐Kowalska J, Dobrzańska A, Franek E, Helwich E, Jackowska T, Kalina MA, Konstantynowicz J, Książyk J, Lewiński A, Łukaszkiewicz J, Marcinowska‐Suchowierska E, Mazur A, Michałus I, Peregud‐Pogorzelski J, Romanowska H, Ruchała M, Socha P, Szalecki M, Wielgoś M, Zwolińska D and Zygmunt A, 2018. Vitamin D supplementation guidelines for general population and groups at risk of vitamin D deficiency in Poland‐Recommendations of the Polish Society of Pediatric Endocrinology and Diabetes and the Expert Panel with participation of national specialist consultants and representatives of scientific societies‐2018 update. Frontiers in Endocrinology, 9, 246. 10.3389/fendo.2018.00246
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fendo.2018.00246</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5990871</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29904370</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
SACN (Scientific Advisory Committee on Nutrition)
, 2017. Update on Folic Acid. 82 pp.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Santos M, Rito AI, Matias FN, Assunção R, Castanheira I and Loureiro I, 2021. Nutrient profile models a useful tool to facilitate healthier food choices: a comprehensive review. Trends in Food Science &amp; Technology, 110, 120–131. 10.1016/j.tifs.2021.01.082
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tifs.2021.01.082</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Schwingshackl L, Hoffmann G, Lampousi AM, Knüppel S, Iqbal K, Schwedhelm C, Bechthold A, Schlesinger S and Boeing H, 2017. Food groups and risk of type 2 diabetes mellitus: a systematic review and meta‐analysis of prospective studies. European Journal of Epidemiology, 32, 363–375. 10.1007/s10654-017-0246-y
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10654-017-0246-y</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5506108</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28397016</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Schwingshackl L, Zähringer J, Beyerbach J, Werner SW, Heseker H, Koletzko B and Meerpohl JJ, 2021. Total dietary fat intake, fat quality, and health outcomes: a scoping review of systematic reviews of prospective studies. Annals of Nutrition and Metabolism, 77, 4–15. 10.1159/000515058
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000515058</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Siri‐Tarino PW, Sun Q, Hu FB and Krauss RM, 2010. Meta‐analysis of prospective cohort studies evaluating the association of saturated fat with cardiovascular disease. American Journal of Clinical Nutrition, 91, 535–546. 10.3945/ajcn.2009.27725
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/ajcn.2009.27725</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
de Souza RJ, Mente A, Maroleanu A, Cozma AI, Ha V, Kishibe T, Uleryk E, Budylowski P, Schünemann H, Beyene J and Anand SS, 2015. Intake of saturated and trans unsaturated fatty acids and risk of all cause mortality, cardiovascular disease, and type 2 diabetes: systematic review and meta‐analysis of observational studies. BMJ, 351. 10.1136/bmj.h3978
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.h3978</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Spiro A and Buttriss JL, 2014. Vitamin D: an overview of vitamin D status and intake in Europe. Nutrition Bulletin, 39, 322–350. 10.1111/nbu.12108
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/nbu.12108</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4288313</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25635171</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Stephen AM, Champ MM, Cloran SJ, Fleith M, van Lieshout L, Mejborn H and Burley VJ, 2017. Dietary fibre in Europe: current state of knowledge on definitions, sources, recommendations, intakes and relationships to health. Nutrition Research Reviews, 30, 149–190. 10.1017/S095442241700004X
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S095442241700004X</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28676135</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Storcksdieck genannt Bonsmann S, Marandola G, Ciriolo E, Bavel R and Wollgast J, 2020a. Front‐of‐pack nutrition labelling schemes: a comprehensive review. EUR 29811 EN, Luxembourg, Publications Office of the European Union 2020, ISBN 978‐92‐76‐08970‐4. 10.2760/180167
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2760/180167</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Storcksdieck genannt Bonsmann S, Meusel V, Grammatikaki E, Bakogianni I, Tan M, Wollgast J and Louro Caldeira S, 2020b. Food‐Based Dietary Guidelines database. European Commission, 2020, JRC118752.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Thanapluetiwong S, Chewcharat A, Takkavatakarn K, Praditpornsilpa K, Eiam‐Ong S and Susantitaphong P, 2020. Vitamin D supplement on prevention of fall and fracture: a meta‐analysis of randomized controlled trials. Medicine, 99, e21506. 10.1097/md.0000000000021506
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/md.0000000000021506</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Threapleton DE, Greenwood DC, Evans CE, Cleghorn CL, Nykjaer C, Woodhead C, Cade JE, Gale CP and Burley VJ, 2013. Dietary fibre intake and risk of cardiovascular disease: systematic review and meta‐analysis. BMJ, 347. 10.1136/bmj.f6879
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.f6879</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Tian S, Xu Q, Jiang R, Han T, Sun C and Na L, 2017. Dietary protein consumption and the risk of type 2 diabetes: a systematic review and meta‐analysis of cohort studies. Nutrients, 9. 10.3390/nu9090982
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu9090982</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Ubago‐Guisado E, Rodríguez‐Barranco M, Ching‐López A, Petrova D, Molina‐Montes E, Amiano P, Barricarte‐Gurrea A, Chirlaque M‐D, Agudo A and Sánchez M‐J, 2021. Evidence Update on the Relationship between Diet and the Most Common Cancers from the European Prospective Investigation into Cancer and Nutrition (EPIC) Study: a Systematic Review. Nutrients, 13, 3582.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8540388</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34684583</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
USDA (United States Department of Agriculture)
, 2020. Dietary Guidelines for Americans 2020–2025. 164 pp.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Vernooij RWM, Zeraatkar D, Han MA, El Dib R, Zworth M, Milio K, Sit D, Lee Y, Gomaa H, Valli C, Swierz MJ, Chang Y, Hanna SE, Brauer PM, Sievenpiper J, de Souza R, Alonso‐Coello P, Bala MM, Guyatt GH and Johnston BC, 2019. Patterns of red and processed meat consumption and risk for cardiometabolic and cancer outcomes: a systematic review and meta‐analysis of cohort studies. Annals of Internal Medicine, 171, 732–741. 10.7326/m19-1583
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/m19-1583</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31569217</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Vinceti M, Filippini T, Crippa A, de Sesmaisons A, Wise LA and Orsini N, 2016. Meta‐analysis of potassium intake and the risk of stroke. Journal of the American Heart Association, 5. 10.1161/JAHA.116.004210
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/JAHA.116.004210</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Visseren FLJ, Mach F, Smulders YM, Carballo D, Koskinas KC, Bäck M, Benetos A, Biffi A, Boavida J‐M, Capodanno D, Cosyns B, Crawford C, Davos CH, Desormais I, Di Angelantonio E, Franco OH, Halvorsen S, Hobbs FDR, Hollander M, Jankowska EA, Michal M, Sacco S, Sattar N, Tokgozoglu L, Tonstad S, Tsioufis KP, van Dis I, van Gelder IC, Wanner C, Williams B and the E. S. C. Scientific Document Group, 2021. 2021 ESC Guidelines on cardiovascular disease prevention in clinical practice: developed by the Task Force for cardiovascular disease prevention in clinical practice with representatives of the European Society of Cardiology and 12 medical societies; with the special contribution of the European Association of Preventive Cardiology (EAPC). European Heart Journal, 10.1093/eurheartj/ehab484
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurheartj/ehab484</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Wang X, Ouyang Y, Liu J, Zhu M, Zhao G, Bao W and Hu FB, 2014. Fruit and vegetable consumption and mortality from all causes, cardiovascular disease, and cancer: systematic review and dose‐response meta‐analysis of prospective cohort studies. BMJ, 349. 10.1136/bmj.g4490
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.g4490</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Wang X, Lin X, Ouyang YY, Liu J, Zhao G, Pan A and Hu FB, 2016. Red and processed meat consumption and mortality: dose‐response meta‐analysis of prospective cohort studies. Public Health Nutrition, 19, 893–905. 10.1017/s1368980015002062
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/s1368980015002062</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26143683</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Wang Y, Harding SV, Thandapilly SJ, Tosh SM, Jones PJH and Ames NP, 2017. Barley β‐glucan reduces blood cholesterol levels via interrupting bile acid metabolism. British Journal of Nutrition, 118, 822–829. 10.1017/s0007114517002835
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/s0007114517002835</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Wang DD, Li Y, Bhupathiraju SN, Rosner BA, Sun Q, Giovannucci EL, Rimm EB, Manson JE, Willett WC, Stampfer MJ and Hu FB, 2021. Fruit and vegetable intake and mortality: results from 2 prospective cohort studies of US men and women and a meta‐analysis of 26 cohort studies. Circulation, 143, 1642–1654. 10.1161/circulationaha.120.048996
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/circulationaha.120.048996</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8084888</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33641343</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
WCRF/AICR (World Cancer Research Fund/American Institute for Cancer Research)
, 2018. Diet, nutrition and physical activity and cancer: a global perspective. 116 pp. Available online: https://www.wcrf.org/diet‐and‐cancer/
</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Webster JL, Dunford EK and Neal BC, 2010. A systematic survey of the sodium contents of processed foods. American Journal of Clinical Nutrition, 91, 413–420. 10.3945/ajcn.2009.28688
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/ajcn.2009.28688</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
WHO (World Health Organization)
, 2003. Diet, nutrition and the prevention of chronic diseases: report of a joint WHO/FAO expert consultation. WHO Technical Report Series, 916, 160.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
WHO (World Health Organization)
, 2004. Iodine Status Worldwide ‐ WHO Global Database on Iodine Deficiency. 58 pp.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
WHO (World Health Organization)
, 2012. Guideline: Potassium Intake for Adults and Children. 52 pp.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
WHO (World Health Organization)
, 2015a. Guideline: Sugars Intake for Adults and Children. 59 pp.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
WHO (World Health Organization)
, 2015b. WHO Regional Office for Europe nutrient profile model. 11 pp.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
WHO (World Health Organization)
, 2019. Guiding Principles and Framework Manual for front‐of‐pack Labelling for Promoting Healthy Diet. 46 pp.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
WHO/FAO (World Health Organization/Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations)
, 2004. Vitamin and mineral requirements in human nutrition: report of a Joint FAO/WHO Expert Consultation, Bangkok, Thailand, 21–30 September 1998. 341 pp.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Willett WC, Howe GR and Kushi LH, 1997. Adjustment for total energy intake in epidemiologic studies. American Journal of Clinical Nutrition, 65, 1220S–1228S. 10.1093/ajcn/65.4.1220S
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ajcn/65.4.1220S</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Willett W, Rockstrom J, Loken B, Springmann M, Lang T, Vermeulen S, Garnett T, Tilman D, DeClerck F, Wood A, Jonell M, Clark M, Gordon LJ, Fanzo J, Hawkes C, Zurayk R, Rivera JA, De Vries W, Majele Sibanda L, Afshin A, Chaudhary A, Herrero M, Agustina R, Branca F, Lartey A, Fan S, Crona B, Fox E, Bignet V, Troell M, Lindahl T, Singh S, Cornell SE, Srinath Reddy K, Narain S, Nishtar S and Murray CJL, 2019. Food in the Anthropocene: the EAT‐Lancet Commission on healthy diets from sustainable food systems. Lancet, 393, 447–492. 10.1016/S0140-6736(18)31788-4
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(18)31788-4</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30660336</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Williams B, Mancia G, Spiering W, Agabiti Rosei E, Azizi M, Burnier M, Clement DL, Coca A, de Simone G, Dominiczak A, Kahan T, Mahfoud F, Redon J, Ruilope L, Zanchetti A, Kerins M, Kjeldsen SE, Kreutz R, Laurent S, Lip GYH, McManus R, Narkiewicz K, Ruschitzka F, Schmieder RE, Shlyakhto E, Tsioufis C, Aboyans V, Desormais I and the E. S. C. Scientific Document Group, 2018. 2018 ESC/ESH Guidelines for the management of arterial hypertension. European Heart Journal, 39, 3021–3104. 10.1093/eurheartj/ehy339
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurheartj/ehy339</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30165516</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Wolever TM, Tosh SM, Gibbs AL, Brand‐Miller J, Duncan AM, Hart V, Lamarche B, Thomson BA, Duss R and Wood PJ, 2010. Physicochemical properties of oat β‐glucan influence its ability to reduce serum LDL cholesterol in humans: a randomized clinical trial. American Journal of Clinical Nutrition, 92, 723–732. 10.3945/ajcn.2010.29174
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/ajcn.2010.29174</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Wood JD, Enser M, Richardson RI and Whittington FM, 2007. Fatty acids in meat and meat products. In: Chow CK (ed.). Fatty acids in foods and their health implications, FL, USA, CRC Press, Boca Raton. pp. 87–107.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
World Cancer Research Fund and American Institute for Cancer Research
, 2018. Body fatness and weight gain adn the risk of cancer. Continuous Project Update Report 2018. 142 pp, available online: https://www.wcrf.org/diet‐and‐cancer/
</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Yao B, Fang H, Xu W, Yan Y, Xu H, Liu Y, Mo M, Zhang H and Zhao Y, 2014. Dietary fiber intake and risk of type 2 diabetes: a dose‐response analysis of prospective studies. European Journal of Epidemiology, 29, 79–88. 10.1007/s10654-013-9876-x
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10654-013-9876-x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24389767</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Yao P, Bennett D, Mafham M, Lin X, Chen Z, Armitage J and Clarke R, 2019. Vitamin D and calcium for the prevention of fracture: a systematic review and meta‐analysis. JAMA Network Open, 2, e1917789. 10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2019.17789
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2019.17789</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Yumuk V, Tsigos C, Fried M, Schindler K, Busetto L, Micic D, Toplak H and the Obesity Management Task Force of the European Association for the Study of Obesity, 2015. European Guidelines for obesity management in adults. Obesity Facts, 8, 402–424. 10.1159/000442721
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000442721</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5644856</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26641646</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Zeraatkar D, Han MA, Guyatt GH, Vernooij RWM, El Dib R, Cheung K, Milio K, Zworth M, Bartoszko JJ, Valli C, Rabassa M, Lee Y, Zajac J, Prokop‐Dorner A, Lo C, Bala MM, Alonso‐Coello P, Hanna SE and Johnston BC, 2019. Red and processed meat consumption and risk for all‐cause mortality and cardiometabolic outcomes: a systematic review and meta‐analysis of cohort studies. Annals of Internal Medicine, 171, 703–710. 10.7326/m19-0655
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/m19-0655</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31569213</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Zheng J, Huang T, Yu Y, Hu X, Yang B and Li D, 2012. Fish consumption and CHD mortality: an updated meta‐analysis of seventeen cohort studies. Public Health Nutrition, 15, 725–737. 10.1017/S1368980011002254
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S1368980011002254</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21914258</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Zhang Z, Xu G, Liu D, Zhu W, Fan X and Liu X, 2013. Dietary fiber consumption and risk of stroke. European Journal of Epidemiology, 28, 119–130. 10.1007/s10654-013-9783-1
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10654-013-9783-1</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23430035</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Zhang Y, You
 D, Lu
 N, Duan
 D, Feng
 X, Astell‐Burt
 T, Zhu
 P, Han
 L, Duan
 S and Zou
 Z, 2018. Potatoes consumption and risk of type 2 diabetes: a meta‐analysis. Iranian Journal of Public Health, 47, 1627–1635.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6294859</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30581777</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Zhang B, Xiong K, Cai J and Ma A, 2020. Fish consumption and coronary heart disease: a meta‐analysis. Nutrients, 12. 10.3390/nu12082278
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu12082278</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Zhu Y, Bo Y and Liu Y, 2019. Dietary total fat, fatty acids intake, and risk of cardiovascular disease: a dose‐response meta‐analysis of cohort studies. Lipids in Health and Disease, 18. 10.1186/s12944-019-1035-2
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12944-019-1035-2</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Zong G, Gao A, Hu FB and Sun Q, 2016. Whole grain intake and mortality from all causes, cardiovascular disease, and cancer: a meta‐analysis of prospective cohort studies. Circulation, 133, 2370–2380. 10.1161/circulationaha.115.021101
</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/circulationaha.115.021101</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4910651</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27297341</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
