<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35467049</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>01</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1439-0531</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Apr</Month>
              <Day>25</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Reproduction in domestic animals = Zuchthygiene</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Reprod Domest Anim</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Suppression of reproductive behaviour and gonadal function in female horses-An update.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/rda.14129</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The behaviour of mares is often detrimental to their performance resulting in frequent demand for methods to suppress gonadal function. In addition, prevention of unintended reproduction especially in feral horse populations may require methods for suppression of gonadal function. Surgical ovariectomy is a safe method but not an acceptable approach in feral mares and undesired in mares where future breeding is considered. There are different approaches for artificial prolongation of the luteal phase resulting in transient inhibition of oestrus and ovulation. Among those, treatment with natural or synthetic progestogens is considered the most common and successful method. Whereas application of intrauterine devices may result in prolongation of luteal function in non-pregnant mares, intrauterine insertion of glass balls is no longer recommended because of complications in individual mares. There are several safer alternatives that may be of interest, especially for population control in free-roaming horses. Treatment with long-acting deslorelin implants inhibited ovulation and oestrus behaviour in mares for limited and variable time intervals in a dose-dependent manner. The effect of GnRH vaccines varies considerably among individual mares, is age dependent, and oestrus-like behaviour may still occur. Contraception via immunization against native porcine or recombinant zona pellucida antigen is successful, but immunocontraception is as much a result of ovarian inactivity as an antibody-based block to sperm-oocyte binding. In conclusion, several treatments for suppression of gonadal function in mares are available, but there are advantages and disadvantages associated that have to be considered. The treatment of choice will thus differ with regard to the demands.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Authors. Reproduction in Domestic Animals published by Wiley-VCH GmbH.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Aurich</LastName>
            <ForeName>Christine</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6077-7362</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Artificial Insemination and Embryo Transfer, Department for Small Animals and Horses, Vetmeduni Vienna, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kaps</LastName>
            <ForeName>Martim</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Artificial Insemination and Embryo Transfer, Department for Small Animals and Horses, Vetmeduni Vienna, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>04</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>Germany</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Reprod Domest Anim</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9015668</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0936-6768</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">behaviour</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">female horse</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">oestrus suppression</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ovulation</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
          <Hour>8</Hour>
          <Minute>58</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35467049</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/rda.14129</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Allen, W. R., &amp; Rossdale, P. D. (1973). A preliminary study upon the use of prostaglandins for inducing oestrus in non-cycling Thoroughbred mares. Equine Veterinary Journal, 5, 137-140. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.2042-3306.1973.tb03213.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Argo, C. M., &amp; Turnbull, E. B. (2010). The effect of intra-uterine devices on the reproductive physiology and behaviour of pony mares. The Veterinary Journal, 186, 39-46. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tvjl.2009.07.013</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Asa, C. S. (1980). Sexual behavior in ovariectomized and seasonally anovulatory pony mares (Equus caballus). Hormones and Behavior, 14, 46-54. https://doi.org/10.1016/0018-506X(80)90014-8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Asa, C. S. (1986). Sexual behavior of mares. Veterinary Clinics of North America: Equine Practice, 2, 519-534.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aurich, C., Daels, P. F., Ball, B. A., &amp; Aurich, J. E. (1995). Effects of gonadal steroids on the opioid regulation of LH and prolactin release in pony mares. Journal of Endocrinology, 147, 195-202.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barber, M. R., &amp; Fayrer-Hosken, R. A. (2000). Possible mechanisms of mammalian immunocontraception. Journal of Reproductive Immunology, 46, 103-124. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0165-0378(99)00063-7</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bradley, M. P., Eade, J., Penhale, J., &amp; Bird, P. (1999). Vaccines for fertility regulation of wild and domestic species. Journal of Biotechnology, 73, 91-101. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0168-1656(99)00112-1</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>British Horserace Authority (2018). BHA NOTICE - REGUMATE EQUINE. Retrieved from https://www.britishhorseracing.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/BHA-Notice-Regumate-200918.pdf</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Burger, D., Wohlfender, F., &amp; Imboden, I. (2008). Managing a mare for breeding and sport. Pferdeheilkunde, 24, 102-107. https://doi.org/10.21836/PEM20080122</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cox, J. H., &amp; DeBowes, R. M. (1987). Colic-like discomfort associated with ovulation in two mares. Journal of the American Veterinary Medical Association, 191, 1451-1452.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Crowell-Davis, S. L. (2007). Sexual behaviour of mares. Hormones and Behavior, 52, 12-17.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cuervo-Arango, J., Claes, A. N., &amp; Stout, T. A. E. (2019). Mare and stallion effects on blastocyst production in a commercial equine ovum pick-up - intracytoplasmic sperm injection program. Reproduction, Fertility, and Development, 31, 1894-1903. https://doi.org/10.1071/RD19201</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Daels, P. F., &amp; Hughes, J. P. (1995). Fertility control using intrauterine devices: An alternative for population control in wild horses. Theriogenology, 44, 629-639. https://doi.org/10.1016/0093-691X(95)00243-2</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Daels, P. F., McCue, P. M., DeMoraes, M. J., &amp; Hughes, J. P. (1996). Persistence of the luteal phase following ovulation during altrenogest treatment in mares. Theriogenology, 46, 799-811. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0093-691X(96)00238-5</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dalin, A. M., Andresen, O., &amp; Malmgren, L. (2002). Immunization against GnRH in mature mares: Antibody titres, ovarian function, hormonal levels and oestrous behaviour. Journal of Veterinary Medicine. A, Physiology, Pathology, Clinical Medicine, 49, 125-131. https://doi.org/10.1046/j.1439-0442.2002.00427.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Amorim, M. D., Chenier, T., Nairn, D., Green, J., Manning, S., &amp; Card, C. (2016). Complications associated with intrauterine glass marbles in five mares. Journal of the American Veterinary Medical Association, 249, 1196-1201. https://doi.org/10.2460/javma.249.10.1196</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elhay, M., Newbold, A., Britton, A., Turley, P., Dowsett, K., &amp; Walker, J. (2007). Suppression of behavioural and physiological oestrus in the mare by vaccination against GnRH. Australian Veterinary Journal, 85, 39-45. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1751-0813.2006.00092.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Farquhar, V. J., McCue, P. M., Carnevale, E. M., Nett, T. M., &amp; Squires, E. L. (2002). Deslorelin acetate (Ovuplant) therapy in cycling mares: Effect of implant removal on FSH secretion and ovarian function. Equine Veterinary Journal, 34, 417-420. https://doi.org/10.2746/042516402776249227</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Farquhar, V. J., McCue, P. M., Nett, T. M., &amp; Squires, E. L. (2001). Effect of deslorelin acetate on gonadotropin secretion and ovarian follicle development in cycling mares. Journal of the American Veterinary Medical Association, 218, 749-752. https://doi.org/10.2460/javma.2001.218.749</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fayrer-Hosken, R. (2008). Controlling animal populations using anti-fertility vaccines. Reproduction in Domestic Animals, 43, 179-185. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1439-0531.2008.01159.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fedorka, C. E., Ball, B. A., Walker, O. F., Conley, A. J., Corbin, C. J., Lu, K. G., Hanneman, J. M., Troedsson, M. H. T., &amp; Adams, A. A. (2019). Alteration of the mare's immune system by the synthetic progestin, altrenogest. American Journal of Reproductive Immunology, 82, e13145. https://doi.org/10.1111/aji.13145</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Freeman, C. E., &amp; Lyle, S. K. (2015). Chronic intermittent colic in a mare attributed to uterine marbles. Equine Veterinary Education, 27, 469-473. https://doi.org/10.1111/eve.12408</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garcia, M. C., Freedman, L. J., &amp; Ginther, O. J. (1979). Interaction of seasonal ovarian factors in the regulation of LH and FSH secretion in the mare. Journal of Reproduction and Fertility Supplement, 27, 103-111.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garcia, M. C., &amp; Ginther, O. J. (1978). Regulation of plasma LH by estradiol and progesterone in ovariectomized mares. Biology of Reproduction, 19, 447-453.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garza, F., Thompson, D. L., French, D. D., Wiest, J. J., St George, R. L., Ashley, K. B., Jones, L. S., Mitchell, P. S., &amp; McNeil, D. R. (1986). Active Immunization of intact mares against gonadotropin-releasing hormone: Differential effects on secretion of luteinizing hormone and follicle-stimulating hormone. Biology of Reproduction, 35, 347-352. https://doi.org/10.1095/biolreprod35.2.347</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gautier, C., Schmidt, K., Aurich, J., &amp; Aurich, C. (2018). Effects of implants containing the GnRH agonist deslorelin on testosterone release and semen characteristics in Shetland stallions. Animal Reproduction Science, 195, 230-241. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.anireprosci.2018.05.027</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ginther, O. J. (1990). Prolonged luteal activity in mares-A semantic quagmire. Equine Veterinary Journal, 22, 152-156. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.2042-3306.1990.tb04235.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Glazar, B. S., McCue, P. M., Bruemmer, J. E., &amp; Squires, E. L. (2004). Deslorelin on Day 8 or 12 postovulation does not luteinize follicles during an artificially maintained diestrous phase in the mare. Theriogenology, 62, 57-64. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.theriogenology.2003.07.024</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gradil, C. M., Uricchio, C. K., &amp; Schwarz, A. (2019). Self-assembling intrauterine device (Upod) modulation of the reproductive cycle in mares. Journal of Equine Veterinary Science, 83, 102690. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jevs.2019.02.009</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hedberg, Y., Dalin, A.-M., Forsberg, M., Lundeheim, N., Hoffmann, B., Ludwig, C., &amp; Kindahl, H. (2007). Effect of ACTH (tetracosactide) on steroid hormone levels in the mare. Part A: Effect in intact normal mares and mares with possible estrous related behavioral abnormalities. Animal Reproduction Science, 100, 73-91. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.anireprosci.2006.06.008</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hedberg, Y., Dalin, A.-M., Forsberg, M., Lundeheim, N., Sandh, G., Hoffmann, B., Ludwig, C., &amp; Kindahl, H. (2007). Effect of ACTH (tetracosactide) on steroid hormone levels in the mare. Part B: Effect in ovariectomized mares (including estrous behavior). Animal Reproduction Science, 100, 92-106. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.anireprosci.2006.06.007</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hedberg, Y., Dalin, A.-M., Santesson, M., &amp; Kindahl, H. (2006). A preliminary study on the induction of dioestrous ovulation in the mare - a possible method for inducing prolonged luteal phase. Acta Veterinaria Scandinavica, 48, 12. https://doi.org/10.1186/1751-0147-48-12</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hershman, L., &amp; Douglas, R. H. (1979). The critical period for the maternal recognition of pregnancy in pony mares. Journal of Reproduction and Fertility Supplement, 27, 457-463.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hobbs, R. J., &amp; Hinds, L. A. (2018). Could current fertility control methods be effective for landscape-scale management of populations of wild horses (Equus caballus) in Australia. Wildlife Research, 45, 195-207. https://doi.org/10.1071/WR17136</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Holyoak, G. R., Lyman, C. C., Wang, S., Germaine, S. S., Anderson, C. O., Baldrighi, J. M., Vemula, N., Rezabek, G. B., &amp; Kane, A. J. (2021). Efficacy of a Y-design silastic elastomer intrauterine device as a horse contraceptive. The Journal of Wildlife Management, 85, 1169-1174. https://doi.org/10.1002/jwmg.22027</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hooper, R. N., Taylor, T. S., Varner, D. D., &amp; Blanchard, T. L. (1993). Effects of bilateral ovariectomy via colpotomy in mares: 23 cases (1984-1990). Journal of the American Veterinary Medical Association, 203, 1043-1046.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hoopes, K. H., Gradil, C. M., Vanderwall, D. K., Mason, H. M., Sarnecky, B. A., &amp; Davies, C. J. (2021). Preliminary study of the contraceptive effect of a self-assembling intrauterine device (iUPODs) in mares maintained in a paddock with a fertile stallion. Animal Reproduction Science, 236, 106881. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.anireprosci.2021.106881</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Imboden, I., Janett, F., Burger, D., Crowe, M. A., Hässig, M., &amp; Thun, R. (2006). Influence of immunization against GnRH on reproductive cyclicity and estrous behavior in the mare. Theriogenology, 66, 1866-1875. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.theriogenology.2006.04.038</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>International Equestrian Federation (FEI) (2022). Equine prohibited substance list 2022. Retrieved from https://inside.fei.org/sites/default/files/2022%20Prohibited%20Substances%20List.pdf</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>International Federation of Horserace Authorities (IFHA) (2021). International Agreement on Breeding, Racing and Wagering and Appendixes, Article 6. Retrieved from https://www.ifhaonline.org/resources/ifAgreement.pdf</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnson, C. A., Thompson, D. L., Kulinski, K. M., &amp; Guitreau, A. M. (2000). Prolonged interovulatory interval and hormonal changes in mares following the use of Ovuplant™ to hasten ovulation. Journal of Equine Veterinary Science, 20, 331-336. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0737-0806(00)70421-7</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Joonè, C. J., Bertschinger, H. J., Gupta, S. K., Fosgate, G. T., Arukha, A. P., Minhas, V., Dieterman, E., &amp; Schulman, M. L. (2017). Ovarian function and pregnancy outcome in pony mares following immunocontraception with native and recombinant porcine zona pellucida vaccines. Equine Veterinary Journal, 49, 189-195. https://doi.org/10.1111/evj.12557</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Joonè, C. J., Gradil, C. M., Picard, J. A., Taylor, J. D., de Tonnerre, D., &amp; Cavalieri, J. (2021). The contraceptive efficacy of a self-assembling intra-uterine device in domestic mares. Australian Veterinary Journal, 99, 130-136. https://doi.org/10.1111/avj.13055</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Joonè, C. J., Nolan, M. B., Bertschinger, H. J., &amp; Schulman, M. L. (2019). Researching immunocontraceptive vaccines with mares (Equus caballus) as both a target and model for African elephant (Loxodonta africana) cows: A review. Animal Reproduction Science, 207, 146-152. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.anireprosci.2019.06.002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Joonè, C. J., Schulman, M. L., &amp; Bertschinger, H. J. (2017). Ovarian dysfunction associated with zona pellucida-based immunocontraceptive vaccines. Theriogenology, 89, 329-337. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.theriogenology.2016.09.018</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaps, M., Lutzer, A., Gautier, C., Nagel, C., Aurich, J., &amp; Aurich, C. (2022). Altrenogest reduces the stress response of three-year-old warmblood mares during their initial equestrian training. Domestic Animal Endocrinology, 80, 106728.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaps, M., Okada, C. T. C., Gautier, C. M., Aurich, J., &amp; Aurich, C. (2021). Deslorelin slow-release implants delay ovulation and increase plasma AMH concentration and small antral follicles in Haflinger mares. Animals, 11, 1600. https://doi.org/10.3390/ani11061600</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaps, M., Okada, C. T. C., Gautier, C. M., Aurich, J., Scarlet, D., Kuhl, J., &amp; Aurich, C. (2021). Transient suppression of ovulatory ovarian function in pony mares after treatment with slow-release deslorelin implants. Domestic Animal Endocrinology, 74, 106505. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.domaniend.2020.106505</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Katila, T. (2015). Clinical commentary: Techniques to suppress oestrus in mares. Equine Veterinary Education, 27, 344-345. https://doi.org/10.1111/eve.12324</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Keith, L., Ball, B. A., Scoggin, K., Esteller-Vico, A., Woodward, E. M., Troedsson, M. H. T., &amp; Squires, E. L. (2013). Diestrus administration of oxytocin prolongs luteal maintenance and reduces plasma PGFM concentrations and endometrial COX-2 expression in mares. Theriogenology, 79, 616-624. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.theriogenology.2012.11.015</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kirkpatrick, J. F., Rowan, A., Lamberski, N., Wallace, R., Frank, K., &amp; Lyda, R. (2009). The practical side of immunocontraception: Zona proteins and wildlife. Journal of Reproductive Immunolology, 83, 151-157. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jri.2009.06.257</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Laconi, M. R., Casteller, G., Gargiulo, P. A., Bregonzio, C., &amp; Cabrera, R. J. (2001). The anxiolytic effect of allopregnanolone is associated with gonadal hormonal status in female rats. European Journal of Pharmacology, 417, 111-116. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0014-2999(01)00865-2</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lefranc, A. C., &amp; Allen, W. R. (2004). Nonpharmacological suppression of oestrus in the mare. Equine Veterinary Journal, 36, 183-185. https://doi.org/10.2746/0425164044868675</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu, I. K. M., Bernoco, M., &amp; Feldman, M. (1989). Contraception in mares heteroimmunized with pig zonae pellucidae. Journal of Reproduction and Fertilility, 85, 19-29. https://doi.org/10.1530/jrf.0.0850019</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lofstedt, R. M., &amp; Patel, J. H. (1989). Evaluation of the ability of altrenogest to control the equine estrous cycle. Journal of the American Veterinary Medical Association, 194, 361-364.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Loy, R. G., &amp; Swan, S. M. (1966). Effects of exogenous progestogens on reproductive phenomena in mares. Journal of Animal Science, 25, 821-826. https://doi.org/10.2527/jas1966.253821x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lyman, C. C., Baldrighi, J. M., Anderson, C. O., Germaine, S. S., Kane, A. J., &amp; Holyoak, G. R. (2021). Modification of O-ring intrauterine devices (IUDs) in mares: Contraception without estrus suppression. Animal Reproduction Science, 234, 106864. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.anireprosci.2021.106864</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Majewska, M. D., Harrison, N. L., Schwartz, R. D., Barker, J. L., &amp; Paul, S. M. (1986). Steroid hormone metabolites are barbiturate-like modulators of the GABA receptor. Science, 232, 1004-1007. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.2422758</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martı́nez-Mota, Lucı́a, Contreras, C. M., &amp; Saavedra, M. (1999). Progesterone reduces immobility in rats forced to swim. Archives of Medical Research, 30, 286-289. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0188-0128(99)00024-X</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McConaghy, F. F., Green, L. A., Colgan, S., &amp; Morris, L. H. (2016). Studies of the pharmacokinetic profile, in vivo efficacy and safety of injectable altrenogest for the suppression of oestrus in mares. Australian Veterinary Journal, 94, 248-255. https://doi.org/10.1111/avj.12459</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McCue, P. M. (2003). Estrus suppression in performance horses. Journal of Equine Veterinary Science, 23, 342-344. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0737-0806(03)01021-9</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McCue, P. M. (2016). Hormone therapy in clinical equine practice. Veterinary Clinic of North America: Equine Practice, 32, 425-434. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cveq.2016.07.001</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McCue, P. M., Farquhar, V. J., Carnevale, E. M., &amp; Squires, E. L. (2002). Removal of deslorelin (Ovuplant™) implant 48 h after administration results in normal interovulatory intervals in mares. Theriogenology, 58, 865-870. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0093-691X(02)00923-8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McKinnon, A. O., Lescun, T. B., Walker, J. H., Vasey, J. R., &amp; Allen, W. R. (2000). The inability of some synthetic progestagens to maintain pregnancy in the mare. Equine Veterinary Journal, 32, 83-85. https://doi.org/10.2746/042516400777612035</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morris, L. H., Fraser, B. S., Cantley, C., &amp; Wilsher, S. (2017). The hazards associated with the use of intrauterine glass balls to suppress oestrus in mares. Equine Veterinary Education, 29, 125e30. https://doi.org/10.1111/eve.12600</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Newcombe, J. R. (1997). The incidence of ovulation during the luteal phase from day 4 to day 20 in pregnant and non pregnant mares. Journal of Equine Veterinary Science, 17, 120-122. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0737-0806(97)80275-4</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nie, G. J., Johnson, K. E., Braden, T. D., &amp; Wenzel, J. G. W. (2003). Use of an intra-uterine glass ball protocol to extend luteal function in mares. Journal of Equine Veterinary Science, 23, 266-273. https://doi.org/10.1053/jevs.2003.75</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nolan, M. B., Bertschinger, H. J., Roth, R., Crampton, M., Martins, I. S., Fosgate, G. T., Stout, T. A., &amp; Schulman, M. L. (2018). Ovarian function following immunocontraceptive vaccination of mares using native porcine and recombinant zona pellucida vaccines formulated with a non-Freund's adjuvant and anti-GnRH vaccines. Theriogenology, 120, 111-116. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.theriogenology.2018.07.044</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nolan, M. B., Schulman, M. L., Botha, A. E., Human, A.-M., Roth, R., Crampton, M. C., &amp; Bertschinger, H. J. (2019). Serum antibody immunoreactivity and safety of native porcine and recombinant zona pellucida vaccines formulated with a non-Freund's adjuvant in horses. Vaccine, 37, 1299-1306. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vaccine.2019.01.053</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Palmer, S. E. (1993). Standing laparoscopic laser technique for ovariectomy in five mares. Journal of the American Veterinary Medical Association, 203, 279-283.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parkinson, K. C., Vanderwall, D. K., Rigas, J., &amp; Sweat, A. (2020). Effect of chronic administration of oxytocin on corpus luteum function in cycling mares. Journal of Equine Veterinary Science, 90, 102991. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jevs.2020.102991</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Picazo, O., &amp; Fernández-Guasti, A. (1995). Anti-anxiety effects of progesterone and some of its reduced metabolites: An evaluation using the burying behavior test. Brain Research, 680, 135-141. https://doi.org/10.1016/0006-8993(95)00254-N</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pryor, P., &amp; Tibary, A. (2005). Management of estrus in the performance mare. Clinical Techniques in Equine Practice, 4, 197-209. https://doi.org/10.1053/j.ctep.2005.07.001</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rivera del Alamo, M. M., Katila, T., Palviainen, M., &amp; Reilas, T. (2021). Effects of intrauterine devices on proteins in the uterine lavage fluid of mares. Theriogenology, 165, 1-9. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.theriogenology.2021.02.001</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rivera Del Alamo, M. M., Reilas, T., Kindahl, H., &amp; Katila, T. (2008). Mechanisms behind intrauterine device-induced luteal persistence in mares. Animal Reproduction Science, 107, 94-106. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.anireprosci.2007.06.010</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Röcken, M., Mosel, G., Seyrek-Intas, K., Seyrek-Intas, D., Litzke, F., Verver, J., &amp; Rijkenhuizen, A. B. M. (2011). Unilateral and bilateral laparoscopic ovariectomy in 157 mares: A retrospective multicenter study. Veterinary Surgery, 40, 1009-1014. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1532-950X.2011.00884.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roessner, H. A., Kurtz, K. A., &amp; Caron, J. P. (2015). Laparoscopic ovariectomy diminishes estrus-associated behavioral problems in mares. Journal of Equine Veterinary Science, 35, 250-253. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jevs.2015.01.007</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schulman, M. L., Botha, A. E., Muenscher, S. B., Annandale, C. H., Guthrie, A. J., &amp; Bertschinger, H. J. (2013). Reversibility of the effects of GnRH-vaccination used to suppress reproductive function in mares. Equine Veterinary Journal, 45, 111-113. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.2042-3306.2012.00577.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Squires, E. L., Heesemann, C. P., Webel, S. K., Shideler, R. K., &amp; Voss, J. L. (1983). Relationship of altrenogest to ovarian activity, hormone concentrations and fertility of mares. Journal of Animal Science, 56, 901-910.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Squires, E. L., Stevens, W. B., McGlothlin, D. E., &amp; Pickett, B. W. (1979). Effect of an oral progestin on the estrous cycle and fertility of mares. Journal of Animal Science, 49, 729-735.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stabenfeldt, G. H., Hughes, J. P., Evans, J. W., &amp; Neely, D. P. (1974). Spontaneous prolongation of luteal activity in the mare. Equine Veterinary Journal, 6, 158-163. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.2042-3306.1974.tb03952.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Storer, W. A., Thompson, D. L., Gilley, R. M., &amp; Burns, P. J. (2009). Evaluation of injectable sustained release progestin formulations for suppression of estrus and ovulation in mares. Journal of Equine Veterinary Science, 29, 33-36. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jevs.2008.11.007</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stout, T. A. E., &amp; Colenbrander, B. (2004). Suppressing reproductive activity in horses using GnRH vaccines, antagonists or agonists. Animal Reproduction Science, 82-83, 633-643. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.anireprosci.2004.04.009</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swegen, A., &amp; Aitken, R. J. (2016). Prospects for immunocontraception in feral horse population control: Exploring novel targets for an equine fertility vaccine. Reproduction, Fertility, and Development, 28, 853-863. https://doi.org/10.1071/RD14280</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tshewang, U., Dowsett, K. F., Knott, L. M., &amp; Trigg, T. E. (1997). Preliminary study of ovarian activity in fillies treated with a GnRH vaccine. Australian Veterinary Journal, 75, 663-667. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1751-0813.1997.tb15366.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Turner, R. M., Vanderwall, D. K., &amp; Stawicki, R. (2015). Complications associated with the presence of two intrauterine glass balls used for oestrus suppression in a mare. Equine Veterinary Education, 27, 340-343. https://doi.org/10.1111/eve.12311</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>U.S. Food and Drug Administration. FDA Animal Drug Safety Communication (2019). FDA highlights potential health risks to people exposed to altrenogest products for horses or pigs. [November 05, 2019]; Retrieved from https://www.fda.gov/animal-veterinary/cvm-updates/fda-animal-drug-safety-communication-fda-highlights-potential-health-risks-people-exposed</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vanderwall, D. K. (2015). Is it time to retire the use of intrauterine glass balls for estrus suppression in mares? Journal of the American Veterinary Medical Association, 247, 346-347. https://doi.org/10.2460/javma.247.4.346</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vanderwall, D. K., Parkinson, K. C., &amp; Rigas, J. (2016). How to use oxytocin treatment to prolong corpus luteum function for suppressing estrus in mares. Journal of Equine Veterinary Science, 36, 1-4. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jevs.2015.09.007</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vanderwall, D. K., Rasmussen, D. M., Carnahan, K. G., &amp; Davis, T. L. (2012). Effect of administration of oxytocin during diestrus on corpus luteum function and endometrial oxytocin receptor concentration in cycling mares. Journal of Equine Veterinary Science, 32, 536-541.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
