<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35460460</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>23</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1720-8386</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Apr</Month>
              <Day>23</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of endocrinological investigation</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Endocrinol Invest</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>The dopaminergic control of Cushing's syndrome.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40618-021-01661-x</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Cushing's Syndrome (CS), or chronic endogenous hypercortisolism, is a rare and serious disease due to corticotroph pituitary (Cushing's disease, CD) and extra-pituitary (ectopic CS) tumours overproducing ACTH, or cortisol-secreting adrenal tumours or lesions (adrenal CS). The first-line treatment for CS is represented by the surgical removal of the responsible tumour, but surgery might be unfeasible or ineffective and medical treatment can be required in a relevant percentage of patients with CS, especially CD and ectopic CS. Corticotroph pituitary and extra-pituitary tumours, as well as adrenal tumours and lesions responsible for CS express dopamine receptors (DRs), which have been found to mediate inhibition of hormone secretion and/or cell proliferation in experimental setting, suggesting that dopaminergic system, particularly DRs, might represent a target for the treatment of CS. Dopamine agonists (DAs), particularly cabergoline (CAB), are currently used as off-label treatment for CD, the most common form of CS, demonstrating efficacy in controlling hormone secretion and tumour growth in a relevant number of cases, with the improvement of clinical picture, and displaying good safety profile. Therefore, CAB may be considered a reasonable alternative treatment for persistent or recurrent CD after pituitary surgery failure, but occasionally also before pituitary surgery, as adjuvant treatment, or even instead of pituitary surgery as first-line treatment in case of surgery contraindications or refusal. A certain beneficial effect of CAB has been also reported in ectopic CS. However, the role of DAs in the clinical management of the different types of CS requires further evaluations.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Pivonello</LastName>
            <ForeName>R</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9632-1348</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Dipartimento Di Medicina Clinica E Chirurgia, Sezione Di Endocrinologia, Università Federico II Di Napoli, Naples, Italy. rosario.pivonello@unina.it.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>UNESCO Chair for Health Education and Sustainable Development, Federico II University, Naples, Italy. rosario.pivonello@unina.it.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Pivonello</LastName>
            <ForeName>C</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Dipartimento Di Medicina Clinica E Chirurgia, Sezione Di Endocrinologia, Università Federico II Di Napoli, Naples, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Simeoli</LastName>
            <ForeName>C</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Dipartimento Di Medicina Clinica E Chirurgia, Sezione Di Endocrinologia, Università Federico II Di Napoli, Naples, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>De Martino</LastName>
            <ForeName>M C</ForeName>
            <Initials>MC</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Dipartimento Di Medicina Clinica E Chirurgia, Sezione Di Endocrinologia, Università Federico II Di Napoli, Naples, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Colao</LastName>
            <ForeName>A</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Dipartimento Di Medicina Clinica E Chirurgia, Sezione Di Endocrinologia, Università Federico II Di Napoli, Naples, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>UNESCO Chair for Health Education and Sustainable Development, Federico II University, Naples, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>04</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>Italy</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Endocrinol Invest</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>7806594</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0391-4097</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cabergoline</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cushing’s disease</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cushing’s syndrome</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dopamine</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dopaminergic system</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2020</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>4</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35460460</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40618-021-01661-x</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40618-021-01661-x</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pivonello R, De Martino MC, De Leo M et al (2008) Cushing’s syndrome. Endocrinol Metab Clin North Am 37(1):135–149</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18226734</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pivonello R, Isidori AM, De Martino MC et al (2016) Complications of Cushing’s syndrome: state of the art. Lancet Diabetes Endocrinol 4(7):611–629</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27177728</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pivonello R, De Leo M, Cozzolino A, Colao A (2015) The treatment of Cushing’s disease. Endocr Rev 36(4):385–486</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26067718</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4523083</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pivonello R, Ferrigno R, De Martino MC et al (2020) Medical treatment of Cushing’s disease: an overview of the current and recent clinical trials. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) 11:648</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pivonello R, Ferone D, Lombardi G et al (2007) Novel insights in dopamine receptor physiology. Eur J Endocrinol 156(Suppl 1):S13-21</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17413183</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Missale C, Nash SR, Robinson SW et al (1998) Dopamine receptors: from structure to function. Physiol Rev 78(1):189–225</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9457173</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beaulieu JM, Gainetdinov RR (2011) The physiology, signaling, and pharmacology of dopamine receptors. Pharmacol Rev 63(1):182–217</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21303898</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Klein MO, Battagello DS, Cardoso AR et al (2019) Dopamine: functions, signaling, and association with neurological diseases. Cell Mol Neurobiol 39(1):31–59</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30446950</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rubi B, Maechler P (2010) Minireview: new roles for peripheral dopamine on metabolic control and tumor growth: let’s seek the balance. Endocrinology 151(12):5570–5581</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21047943</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hellysaz A (2018) Anatomical studies of the dopamine system in the hypothalamus and the pituitary gland, Dipartimento: Inst för neurovetenskap / Dept of Neuroscience, Samuelssonsalen, Tomtebodavägen 6, Karolinska Institutet, Solna</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>KA Gregerson (2001) Mechanisms of dopamine action on the lactotroph, in prolactin, ND Horseman, (Eds), Springer, Boston, MA</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pivonello R, Waaijers M, Kros JM et al (2017) Dopamine D2 receptor expression in the corticotroph cells of the human normal pituitary gland. Endocrine 57(2):314–325</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27738887</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Souza EB, Kuhar MJ (1984) Dopamine receptors in the anterior lobe of the human pituitary gland: autoradiographic localization. Brain Res 306(1–2):391–395</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6466987</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cooper O, Greenman Y (2018) Dopamine agonists for pituitary adenomas. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) 9:469</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Molitch ME (2017) Diagnosis and treatment of pituitary adenomas: a review. JAMA 317(5):516–524</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28170483</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Melmed S, Casanueva FF, Hoffman AR et al (2011) Diagnosis and treatment of hyperprolactinemia: an endocrine society clinical practice guideline. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 96(2):273–288</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21296991</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Katznelson L, Atkinson JL, Cook DM et al (2011) American association of clinical endocrinologists medical guidelines for clinical practice for the diagnosis and treatment of acromegaly–2011 update: executive summary. Endocr Pract 17(4):636–646</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21846619</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pivonello R, Ferone D, de Herder WW et al (2004) Dopamine receptor expression and function in human normal adrenal gland and adrenal tumors. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 89(9):4493–4502</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15356054</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van der Pas R, Feelders RA, Gatto F et al (2013) Preoperative normalization of cortisol levels in Cushing’s disease after medical treatment: consequences for somatostatin and dopamine receptor subtype expression and in vitro response to somatostatin analogs and dopamine agonists. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 98(12):E1880–E1890</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24081741</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tateno T, Kato M, Tani Y et al (2009) Differential expression of somatostatin and dopamine receptor subtype genes in adrenocorticotropin (ACTH)-secreting pituitary tumors and silent corticotroph adenomas. Endocr J 56(4):579–584</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19318729</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Bruin C, Pereira AM, Feelders RA et al (2009) Coexpression of dopamine and somatostatin receptor subtypes in corticotroph adenomas. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 94(4):1118–1124</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19141584</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sickler T, Trarbach EB, Frassetto FP et al (2019) Filamin A and DRD2 expression in corticotrophinomas. Pituitary 22(2):163–169</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30799513</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pivonello R, Ferone D, de Herder WW et al (2004) Dopamine receptor expression and function in corticotroph pituitary tumors. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 89(5):2452–2462</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15126577</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pivonello R, Ferone D, de Herder WW et al (2007) Dopamine receptor expression and function in corticotroph ectopic tumors. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 92(1):65–69</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17032724</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Palui R, Sahoo J, Kamalanathan S et al (2022) Effect of cabergoline monotherapy in Cushing’s disease: an individual participant data meta-analysis. Palui R, Sahoo J, Kamalanathan S, Kar SS, Selvarajan S, Durgia H (eds.) . J Endocrinol Invest 41(12):1445–1455</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Palui R, Sahoo J, Kamalanathan S, Kar SS, Selvarajan S, Durgia H (2022) Correction to: Palui R, Sahoo J, Kamalanathan S, Kar SS, Selvarajan S, Durgia H. Effect of cabergoline monotherapy in Cushing' disease: an individual participant data meta-analysis. J Endocrinol Invest 45(4):899–900</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pivonello R, De Martino MC, Cappabianca P et al (2009) The medical treatment of Cushing’s disease: effectiveness of chronic treatment with the dopamine agonist cabergoline in patients unsuccessfully treated by surgery. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 94(1):223–230</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18957500</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Godbout A, Manavela M, Danilowicz K et al (2010) Cabergoline monotherapy in the long-term treatment of Cushing’s disease. Eur J Endocrinol 163(5):709–716</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20702648</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vilar L, Naves LA, Azevedo MF et al (2010) Effectiveness of cabergoline in monotherapy and combined with ketoconazole in the management of Cushing’s disease. Pituitary 13(2):123–129</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19943118</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barbot M, Albiger N, Ceccato F et al (2014) Combination therapy for Cushing’s disease: effectiveness of two schedules of treatment: should we start with cabergoline or ketoconazole? Pituitary 17(2):109–117</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23468128</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lila AR, Gopal RA, Acharya SV et al (2010) Efficacy of cabergoline in uncured (persistent or recurrent) Cushing disease after pituitary surgical treatment with or without radiotherapy. Endocr Pract 16(6):968–976</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20497937</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ferriere A, Cortet C, Chanson P et al (2017) Cabergoline for Cushing’s disease: a large retrospective multicenter study. Eur J Endocrinol 176(3):305–314</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28007845</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Feelders RA, de Bruin C, Pereira AM et al (2010) Pasireotide alone or with cabergoline and ketoconazole in Cushing’s disease. N Engl J Med 362(19):1846–1848</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20463350</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>K.P. Feelders R, Bex M, González Devia D, Boguszewski C, Gogas Yavus D et al (2017) Prospective phase II study (CAPACITY) of pasireotide monotherapy or in combination with cabergoline in patients with Cushing’s disease, In Poster: Presented at ENDO, Orlando, FL</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Willhauck MJ, Popperl G, Rachinger W et al (2012) An unusual case of ectopic ACTH syndrome. Exp Clin Endocrinol Diabetes 120(2):63–67</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22187295</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ilie MD, Raverot V, Tronc F et al (2019) Cabergoline in severe ectopic or occult Cushing’s syndrome. Eur J Endocrinol 181(1):K1–K9</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31048558</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pivonello R, Ferone D, Lamberts SW, Colao A (2005) Cabergoline plus lanreotide for ectopic Cushing’s syndrome. N Engl J Med 352(23):2457–2458</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15944436</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Modica R, Colao A, Faggiano A (2015) Complete clinical and biochemical control with cabergoline and octreotide in a patient with ectopic ACTH syndrome before surgery. J Endocrinol Invest 38(3):373–374</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25480427</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bruno OD, Danilowicz K, Manavela M et al (2010) Long-term management with octreotide or cabergoline in ectopic corticotropin hypersecretion: case report and literature review. Endocr Pract 16(5):829–834</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20497940</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pivonello R, Faggiano A, Di Salle F et al (1999) Complete remission of Nelson’s syndrome after 1-year treatment with cabergoline. J Endocrinol Invest 22(11):860–865</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10710275</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Casulari LA, Naves LA, Mello PA et al (2004) Nelson’s syndrome: complete remission with cabergoline but not with bromocriptine or cyproheptadine treatment. Horm Res 62(6):300–305</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15557761</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Korshunov KS, Blakemore LJ, Trombley PQ (2017) Dopamine: a modulator of circadian rhythms in the central nervous system. Front Cell Neurosci 11:91</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28420965</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5376559</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>MYH Omote (2009) Vesicular Neurotransmitter Transporte, in Encyclopedia of Neuroscience, In: Binder MD, Windhorst U (Eds), Springer, Berlin</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cho DI, Min C, Jung KS et al (2012) The N-terminal region of the dopamine D2 receptor, a rhodopsin-like GPCR, regulates correct integration into the plasma membrane and endocytic routes. Br J Pharmacol 166(2):659–675</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22117524</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3417496</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giros B, Sokoloff P, Martres MP et al (1989) Alternative splicing directs the expression of two D2 dopamine receptor isoforms. Nature 342(6252):923–926</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2531847</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Monsma FJ Jr, McVittie LD, Gerfen CR et al (1989) Multiple D2 dopamine receptors produced by alternative RNA splicing. Nature 342(6252):926–929</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2480527</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giros B, Martres MP, Pilon C et al (1991) Shorter variants of the D3 dopamine receptor produced through various patterns of alternative splicing. Biochem Biophys Res Commun 176(3):1584–1592</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2039532</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Van Tol HH, Wu CM, Guan HC et al (1992) Multiple dopamine D4 receptor variants in the human population. Nature 358(6382):149–152</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1319557</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vallone D, Picetti R, Borrelli E (2000) Structure and function of dopamine receptors. Neurosci Biobehav Rev 24(1):125–132</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10654668</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Booth AK, Gutierrez-Hartmann A (2015) Signaling pathways regulating pituitary lactotrope homeostasis and tumorigenesis. Adv Exp Med Biol 846:37–59</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25472533</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iaccarino C, Samad TA, Mathis C et al (2002) Control of lactotrop proliferation by dopamine: essential role of signaling through D2 receptors and ERKs. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 99(22):14530–14535</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12391292</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">137917</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Radl D, De Mei C, Chen E et al (2013) Each individual isoform of the dopamine D2 receptor protects from lactotroph hyperplasia. Mol Endocrinol 27(6):953–965</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23608643</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3656237</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Radl DB, Ferraris J, Boti V et al (2011) Dopamine-induced apoptosis of lactotropes is mediated by the short isoform of D2 receptor. PLoS ONE 6(3):e18097</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21464994</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3064585</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roof AK, Jirawatnotai S, Trudeau T et al (2018) The balance of PI3K and ERK signaling is dysregulated in prolactinoma and modulated by dopamine. Endocrinology 159(6):2421–2434</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29726995</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6172703</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Welsh GI, Hall DA, Warnes A et al (1998) Activation of microtubule-associated protein kinase (Erk) and p70 S6 kinase by D2 dopamine receptors. J Neurochem 70(5):2139–2146</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9572301</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>An JJ, Cho SR, Jeong DW et al (2003) Anti-proliferative effects and cell death mediated by two isoforms of dopamine D2 receptors in pituitary tumor cells. Mol Cell Endocrinol 206(1–2):49–62</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12943989</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peverelli E, Olgiati L, Locatelli M et al (2010) The dopamine-somatostatin chimeric compound BIM-23A760 exerts antiproliferative and cytotoxic effects in human non-functioning pituitary tumors by activating ERK1/2 and p38 pathways. Cancer Lett 288(2):170–176</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19619936</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leng ZG, Lin SJ, Wu ZR et al (2017) Activation of DRD5 (dopamine receptor D5) inhibits tumor growth by autophagic cell death. Autophagy 13(8):1404–1419</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28613975</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5584849</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lin SJ, Leng ZG, Guo YH et al (2015) Suppression of mTOR pathway and induction of autophagy-dependent cell death by cabergoline. Oncotarget 6(36):39329–39341</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26513171</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4770775</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Winters SJ, Ghooray DT, Yang RQ et al (2014) Dopamine-2 receptor activation suppresses PACAP expression in gonadotrophs. Endocrinology 155(7):2647–2657</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24823390</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4060190</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cronin MJ, Thorner MO, Hellmann P, Rogol AD (1984) Bromocriptine inhibits growth hormone release from rat pituitary cells in primary culture. Proc Soc Exp Biol Med 175(2):191–195</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6694976</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stefaneanu L, Kovacs K, Horvath E et al (2001) Dopamine D2 receptor gene expression in human adenohypophysial adenomas. Endocrine 14(3):329–336</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11444429</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brown CH, Bains JS, Ludwig M, Stern JE (2013) Physiological regulation of magnocellular neurosecretory cell activity: integration of intrinsic, local and afferent mechanisms. J Neuroendocrinol 25(8):678–710</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23701531</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>(1983) The neurohypophysis: structure, function and control. Prog Brain Res. 60: 3–532</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moos F, Richard P (1982) Excitatory effect of dopamine on oxytocin and vasopressin reflex releases in the rat. Brain Res 241(2):249–260</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7104713</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Takeuchi M (2001) The mammalian pars intermedia—structure and function—. Zoolog Sci 18:133–144</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Amar AP, Weiss MH (2003) Pituitary anatomy and physiology. Neurosurg Clin N Am 14(1):11–23</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12690976</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mannelli M, Pupilli C, Fabbri G et al (1988) Endogenous dopamine (DA) and DA2 receptors: a mechanism limiting excessive sympathetic-adrenal discharge in humans. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 66(3):626–631</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3280589</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pupilli C, Lanzillotti R, Fiorelli G et al (1994) Dopamine D2 receptor gene expression and binding sites in adrenal medulla and pheochromocytoma. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 79(1):56–61</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8027253</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu KD, Chen YM, Chu TS et al (2001) Expression and localization of human dopamine D2 and D4 receptor mRNA in the adrenal gland, aldosterone-producing adenoma, and pheochromocytoma. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 86(9):4460–4467</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11549694</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chang HW, Huang CY, Yang SY et al (2014) Role of D2 dopamine receptor in adrenal cortical cell proliferation and aldosterone-producing adenoma tumorigenesis. J Mol Endocrinol 52(2):87–96</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24293642</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Missale C, Lombardi C, De Cotiis R et al (1989) Dopaminergic receptor mechanisms modulating the renin-angiotensin system and aldosterone secretion: an overview. J Cardiovasc Pharmacol 14(Suppl 8):S29-39</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2483440</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Osinga TE, Links TP, Dullaart RPF et al (2017) Emerging role of dopamine in neovascularization of pheochromocytoma and paraganglioma. FASEB J 31(6):2226–2240</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28264974</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5434646</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bonuccelli U, Pavese N (2006) Dopamine agonists in the treatment of Parkinson’s disease. Expert Rev Neurother 6(1):81–89</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16466315</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Auriemma RS, Pirchio R, De Alcubierre D et al (2019) Dopamine agonists: from the 1970s to today. Neuroendocrinology 109(1):34–41</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30852578</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mashiter K, Adams E, Beard M, Holley A (1977) Bromocriptine inhibits prolactin and growth-hormone release by human pituitary tumours in culture. Lancet 2(8030):197–198</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">69814</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Farrell WE, Clark AJ, Stewart MF et al (1992) Bromocriptine inhibits pro-opiomelanocortin mRNA and ACTH precursor secretion in small cell lung cancer cell lines. J Clin Invest 90(3):705–710</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1325994</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">329920</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ferone D, de Herder WW, Pivonello R et al (2008) Correlation of in vitro and in vivo somatotropic adenoma responsiveness to somatostatin analogs and dopamine agonists with immunohistochemical evaluation of somatostatin and dopamine receptors and electron microscopy. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 93(4):1412–1417</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18211974</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miyoshi T, Otsuka F, Otani H et al (2008) Involvement of bone morphogenetic protein-4 in GH regulation by octreotide and bromocriptine in rat pituitary GH3 cells. J Endocrinol 197(1):159–169</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18372242</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beck-Peccoz P, Persani L (2002) Medical management of thyrotropin-secreting pituitary adenomas. Pituitary 5(2):83–88</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12675505</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yin D, Kondo S, Takeuchi J, Morimura T (1994) Induction of apoptosis in murine ACTH-secreting pituitary adenoma cells by bromocriptine. FEBS Lett 339(1–2):73–75</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7508871</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tang C, Sun R, Wen G et al (2019) Bromocriptine and cabergoline induce cell death in prolactinoma cells via the ERK/EGR1 and AKT/mTOR pathway respectively. Cell Death Dis 10(5):335</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31000722</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6472389</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li Q, Su Z, Liu J et al (2014) Dopamine receptor D2S gene transfer improves the sensitivity of GH3 rat pituitary adenoma cells to bromocriptine. Mol Cell Endocrinol 382(1):377–384</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24184771</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gagliano T, Filieri C, Minoia M et al (2013) Cabergoline reduces cell viability in non functioning pituitary adenomas by inhibiting vascular endothelial growth factor secretion. Pituitary 16(1):91–100</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22350942</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu X, Tang C, Wen G et al (2018) The mechanism and pathways of dopamine and dopamine agonists in prolactinomas. Front Endocrinol (Lausanne) 9:768</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rowther FB, Richardson A, Clayton RN, Farrell WE (2010) Bromocriptine and dopamine mediate independent and synergistic apoptotic pathways in pituitary cells. Neuroendocrinology 91(3):256–267</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20110659</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nieman LK, Biller BM, Findling JW et al (2015) Treatment of Cushing’s syndrome: an endocrine society clinical practice guideline. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 100(8):2807–2831</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26222757</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4525003</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Bruin C, Hanson JM, Meij BP et al (2008) Expression and functional analysis of dopamine receptor subtype 2 and somatostatin receptor subtypes in canine cushing’s disease. Endocrinology 149(9):4357–4366</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18483151</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2553383</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sato A, Hara Y (2018) Protein expression of somatostatin receptor 2, somatostatin receptor 5 and dopamine D2 receptor in normal pituitary gland and ACTH-secreting pituitary adenoma in dogs. Res Vet Sci 119:61–66</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29864631</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pawlikowski M (2010) Immunohistochemical detection of dopamine D2 receptors in human pituitary adenomas. Folia Histochem Cytobiol 48(3):394–397</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21071344</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grossrubatscher E, Veronese S, Ciaramella PD et al (2008) High expression of dopamine receptor subtype 2 in a large series of neuroendocrine tumors. Cancer Biol Ther 7(12):1970–1978</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18981718</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Diakatou E, Kaltsas G, Tzivras M et al (2011) Somatostatin and dopamine receptor profile of gastroenteropancreatic neuroendocrine tumors: an immunohistochemical study. Endocr Pathol 22(1):24–30</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21287294</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Occhi G, Regazzo D, Albiger NM et al (2014) Activation of the dopamine receptor type-2 (DRD2) promoter by 9-cis retinoic acid in a cellular model of Cushing’s disease mediates the inhibition of cell proliferation and ACTH secretion without a complete corticotroph-to-melanotroph transdifferentiation. Endocrinology 155(9):3538–3549</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24926820</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lamberts SW, Birkenhager JC (1976) Bromocriptine in Nelson’s syndrome and Cushing’s disease. Lancet 2(7989):811</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">61490</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lamberts SW, Timmermans HA, De Jong FH, Birkenhager JC (1977) The role of dopaminergic depletion in the pathogenesis of Cushing’s disease and the possible consequences for medical therapy. Clin Endocrinol (Oxf) 7(3):185–193</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Invitti C, De Martin M, Danesi L, Cavagnini F (1995) Effect of injectable bromocriptine in patients with Cushing’s disease. Exp Clin Endocrinol Diabetes 103(4):266–271</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7584534</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miller JW, Crapo L (1993) The medical treatment of Cushing’s syndrome. Endocr Rev 14(4):443–458</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7693447</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mercado-Asis LB, Yasuda K, Murayama M et al (1992) Beneficial effects of high daily dose bromocriptine treatment in Cushing’s disease. Endocrinol Jpn 39(4):385–395</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1332855</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lamberts SW, Klijn JG, de Quijada M et al (1980) The mechanism of the suppressive action of bromocriptine on adrenocorticotropin secretion in patients with Cushing’s disease and Nelson’s syndrome. J Clin Endocrinol Metab 51(2):307–311</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6249835</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Burman P, Eden-Engstrom B, Ekman B et al (2016) Limited value of cabergoline in Cushing’s disease: a prospective study of a 6-week treatment in 20 patients. Eur J Endocrinol 174(1):17–24</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26582653</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shraga-Slutzky I, Shimon I, Weinshtein R (2006) Clinical and biochemical stabilization of Nelson’s syndrome with long-term low-dose cabergoline treatment. Pituitary 9(2):151–154</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16845600</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Petrossians P, Ronci N, Valdes Socin H et al (2001) ACTH silent adenoma shrinking under cabergoline. Eur J Endocrinol 144(1):51–57</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11174837</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Manavela MP, Danilowicz K, Bruno OD (2012) Macrocorticotropinoma shrinkage and control of hypercortisolism under long-term cabergoline therapy: case report. Pituitary 15(Suppl 1):33–36</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22038028</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elshafie O, Osman A, Aamer F et al (2012) Cushing’s Disease: sustained remission in five cases induced by medical therapy with the dopamine agonist cabergoline. Sultan Qaboos Univ Med J 12(4):493–497</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23275847</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3524000</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miyoshi T, Otsuka F, Takeda M et al (2004) Effect of cabergoline treatment on Cushing’s disease caused by aberrant adrenocorticotropin-secreting macroadenoma. J Endocrinol Invest 27(11):1055–1059</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15754738</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ahmed A, Furqan S, Islam N (2012) Disappearance of pituitary macro adenoma with combination of ketoconazole and cabergoline treatment: an unusual case of Cushing’s syndrome with interesting findings. BMJ Case Rep 2012:bcr0320126025</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22761217</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3391398</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Woo I, Ehsanipoor RM (2013) Cabergoline therapy for Cushing disease throughout pregnancy. Obstet Gynecol 122(2 Pt 2):485–487</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23884269</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nakhleh A, Saiegh L, Reut M et al (2016) Cabergoline treatment for recurrent cushing’s disease during pregnancy. Hormones (Athens) 15(3):453–458</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gopal R, Bandgar T, Menon P, Shah N (2008) Remission in Cushing disease with cabergoline. Ann Saudi Med 28(3):224–225</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18500188</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6074420</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bertrand A, Marec-Berard P, Raverot G et al (2010) Cabergoline therapy of paraneoplastic cushing syndrome in children. Pediatr Blood Cancer 55(3):589–590</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20658641</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
