<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35466415</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>02</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2125</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Apr</Month>
              <Day>25</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>British journal of clinical pharmacology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Br J Clin Pharmacol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Thromboembolic events in Janus kinase inhibitors: A pharmacovigilance study from 2012 to 2021 based on the Food and Drug Administration's Adverse Event Reporting System.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/bcp.15361</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="AIMS" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">As a new type of drug developed rapidly in recent years, Janus kinase inhibitors (JAKinibs) have caused controversy due to possible adverse reactions of thromboembolism. The aim of this study was to analyse and evaluate the association between thromboembolic events and the use of JAKinibs, on the base of the latest data in the Food and Drug Administration's Adverse Event Reporting System.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A disproportionality analysis was conducted, utilizing data from 1 January 2012 to 30 September 2021 in the FAERS. For each drug-adverse event pair, reporting odds ratio (ROR) and information components (IC) were calculated.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 15 positive safety signals were detected within the FAERS: ruxolitinib was significantly associated with portal vein thrombosis (ROR<sub>025</sub>  = 3.49, IC<sub>025</sub>  = 1.50); tofacitinib immediate release with pulmonary embolism (ROR<sub>025</sub>  = 2.09, IC<sub>025</sub>  = 1.02) and thrombosis (ROR<sub>025</sub>  = 1.15, IC<sub>025</sub>  = 0.18); tofacitinib extended release with pulmonary embolism (ROR<sub>025</sub>  = 1.27, IC<sub>025</sub>  = 0.26) and thrombosis (ROR<sub>025</sub>  = 1.29, IC<sub>025</sub>  = 0.33); baricitinib with deep vein thrombosis (ROR<sub>025</sub>  = 8.27, IC<sub>025</sub>  = 3.00), portal vein thrombosis (ROR<sub>025</sub>  = 1.97, IC<sub>025</sub>  = 0.63), pulmonary embolism (ROR<sub>025</sub>  = 7.90, IC<sub>025</sub>  = 2.94), thrombosis (ROR<sub>025</sub>  = 2.04, IC<sub>025</sub>  = 0.93) and venous thrombosis (ROR<sub>025</sub>  = 2.15, IC<sub>025</sub>  = 0.81); upadacitinib with pulmonary embolism (ROR<sub>025</sub>  = 1.25, IC<sub>025</sub>  = 0.25), pulmonary thrombosis (ROR<sub>025</sub>  = 5.32, IC<sub>025</sub>  = 2.33) and thrombosis (ROR<sub>025</sub>  = 2.72, IC<sub>025</sub>  = 1.39); and filgotinib with pulmonary embolism (ROR<sub>025</sub>  = 4.83, IC<sub>025</sub>  = 2.10). In the analysis of the time to onset of thromboembolic events, no obviously recognizable pattern was found. Several safety signals with embolic and thrombotic events (Standardised MedDRA Query) were found in the study.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This pharmacovigilance study covered 8 types of JAKinib that are already on the market, and provided new safety signals based on past safety information. Some of these signals still need more medical evidence.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 British Pharmacological Society.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Dong</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ziwei</ForeName>
            <Initials>Z</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3915-0597</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Medicine, Tongji University Shanghai, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ye</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xiaofei</ForeName>
            <Initials>X</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Health Statistics, Naval Medical University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Chenxin</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Health Statistics, Naval Medical University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Rui</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Health Statistics, Naval Medical University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Liu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Dongxu</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Medicine, Tongji University Shanghai, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Xu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xiao</ForeName>
            <Initials>X</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Medicine, Tongji University Shanghai, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhou</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xiang</ForeName>
            <Initials>X</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Medicine, Tongji University Shanghai, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>He</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jia</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2338-9501</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Medicine, Tongji University Shanghai, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Health Statistics, Naval Medical University, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>04</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Br J Clin Pharmacol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>7503323</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0306-5251</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">FAERS</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">JAK inhibitors</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">disproportionality analysis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacovigilance study</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">spontaneous reporting system</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">thromboembolic events</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>15</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35466415</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bcp.15361</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>O'Shea JJ, Holland SM, Staudt LM. JAKs and STATs in immunity, immunodeficiency, and cancer. N Engl J Med. 2013;368(2):161-170. doi:10.1056/NEJMra1202117</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iorizzo M, Tosti A. Emerging drugs for alopecia areata: JAK inhibitors. Expert Opin Emerg Drugs. 2018;23(1):77-81. doi:10.1080/14728214.2018.1444750</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Phan K, Sebaratnam DF. JAK inhibitors for alopecia areata: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 2019;33(5):850-856. doi:10.1111/jdv.15489</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang EHC, Sallee BN, Tejeda CI, Christiano AM. JAK Inhibitors for Treatment of Alopecia Areata. J Invest Dermatol. 2018;138(9):1911-1916. doi:10.1016/j.jid.2018.05.027</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Winthrop KL. The emerging safety profile of JAK inhibitors in rheumatic disease. Nat Rev Rheumatol. 2017;13(4):234-243. doi:10.1038/nrrheum.2017.23</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Banerjee S, Biehl A, Gadina M, Hasni S, Schwartz DM. JAK-STAT Signaling as a Target for Inflammatory and Autoimmune Diseases: Current and Future Prospects. Drugs. 2017;77(5):521-546. doi:10.1007/s40265-017-0701-9</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verden A, Dimbil M, Kyle R, Overstreet B, Hoffman KB. Analysis of Spontaneous Postmarket Case Reports Submitted to the FDA Regarding Thromboembolic Adverse Events and JAK Inhibitors. Drug Saf. 2018;41(4):357-361. doi:10.1007/s40264-017-0622-2</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Setyawan J, Azimi N, Strand V, Yarur A, Fridman M. Reporting of Thromboembolic Events with JAK Inhibitors: Analysis of the FAERS Database 2010-2019. Drug Saf. 2021;44(8):889-897. doi:10.1007/s40264-021-01082-y</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Angelini J, Talotta R, Roncato R, et al. JAK-Inhibitors for the Treatment of Rheumatoid Arthritis: A Focus on the Present and an Outlook on the Future. Biomolecules. 2020;10(7):1002. doi:10.3390/biom10071002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huang J, Meng L, Yang B, Sun S, Luo Z, Chen H. Safety Profile of Epidermal Growth Factor Receptor Tyrosine Kinase Inhibitors: A Disproportionality Analysis of FDA Adverse Event Reporting System. Sci Rep. 2020;10(1):4803. doi:10.1038/s41598-020-61571-5</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tregunno PM, Fink DB, Fernandez-Fernandez C, Lázaro-Bengoa E, Norén GN. Performance of probabilistic method to detect duplicate individual case safety reports. Drug Saf. 2014;37(4):249-258. doi:10.1007/s40264-014-0146-y</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Strandell J, Caster O, Bate A, Norén N, Edwards IR. Reporting patterns indicative of adverse drug interactions: a systematic evaluation in VigiBase. Drug Saf. 2011;34(3):253-266. doi:10.2165/11586990-000000000-00000</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lehman HP, Chen J, Gould AL, et al. An evaluation of computer-aided disproportionality analysis for post-marketing signal detection. Clin Pharmacol Ther. 2007;82(2):173-180. doi:10.1038/sj.clpt.6100233</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Montastruc JL, Sommet A, Bagheri H, Lapeyre-Mestre M. Benefits and strengths of the disproportionality analysis for identification of adverse drug reactions in a pharmacovigilance database. Br J Clin Pharmacol. 2011;72(6):905-908. doi:10.1111/j.1365-2125.2011.04037.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van Puijenbroek EP, Bate A, Leufkens HGM, Lindquist M, Orre R, Egberts ACG. A comparison of measures of disproportionality for signal detection in spontaneous reporting systems for adverse drug reactions. Pharmacoepidemiol Drug Saf. 2002;11(1):3-10. doi:10.1002/pds.668</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Almenoff JS, Pattishall EN, Gibbs TG, DuMouchel W, Evans SJW, Yuen N. Novel statistical tools for monitoring the safety of marketed drugs. Clin Pharmacol Ther. 2007;82(2):157-166. doi:10.1038/sj.clpt.6100258</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ang PS, Chen Z, Chan CL, Tai BC. Data mining spontaneous adverse drug event reports for safety signals in Singapore - a comparison of three different disproportionality measures. Expert Opin Drug Saf. 2016;15(5):583-590. doi:10.1517/14740338.2016.1167184</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Norén GN, Hopstadius J, Bate A. Shrinkage observed-to-expected ratios for robust and transparent large-scale pattern discovery. Stat Methods Med Res. 2013;22(1):57-69. doi:10.1177/0962280211403604</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen C, Chen T, Liang J, et al. Cardiotoxicity Induced by Immune Checkpoint Inhibitors: A Pharmacovigilance Study From 2014 to 2019 Based on FAERS. Front Pharmacol. 2021;12:616505. doi:10.3389/fphar.2021.616505</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alexander SP, Fabbro D, Kelly E, et al. THE CONCISE GUIDE TO PHARMACOLOGY 2021/22: Enzymes. Br J Pharmacol. 2021;178(Suppl 1):S313-s411.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gregson J, Kaptoge S, Bolton T, et al. Cardiovascular Risk Factors Associated With Venous Thromboembolism. JAMA Cardiol. 2019;4(2):163-173. doi:10.1001/jamacardio.2018.4537</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vallejo-Yagüe E, Weiler S, Micheroli R, Burden AM. Thromboembolic Safety Reporting of Tofacitinib and Baricitinib: An Analysis of the WHO VigiBase. Drug Saf. 2020;43(9):881-891. doi:10.1007/s40264-020-00958-9</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mease P, Charles-Schoeman C, Cohen S, et al. Incidence of venous and arterial thromboembolic events reported in the tofacitinib rheumatoid arthritis, psoriasis and psoriatic arthritis development programmes and from real-world data. Ann Rheum Dis. 2020;79(11):1400-1413. doi:10.1136/annrheumdis-2019-216761</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smolen JS, Landewé RBM, Bijlsma JWJ, et al. EULAR recommendations for the management of rheumatoid arthritis with synthetic and biological disease-modifying antirheumatic drugs: 2019 update. Ann Rheum Dis. 2020;79(6):685-699. doi:10.1136/annrheumdis-2019-216655</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schiffer M, Kowalski A, Zhao J, Bewersdorf JP, Lewis Jr RS, Zeidan AM. Fedratinib hydrochloride to treat intermediate-2 or high-risk primary or secondary myelofibrosis. Drugs Today (Barc). 2020;56(12):755-768. doi:10.1358/dot.2020.56.12.3230206</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dhillon S, Keam SJ. Filgotinib: First Approval. Drugs. 2020;80(18):1987-1997. doi:10.1007/s40265-020-01439-0</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Feagan BG, Danese S, Loftus EV Jr, et al. Filgotinib as induction and maintenance therapy for ulcerative colitis (SELECTION): a phase 2b/3 double-blind, randomised, placebo-controlled trial. Lancet. 2021;397(10292):2372-2384. doi:10.1016/S0140-6736(21)00666-8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saliba W, Mishchenko E, Cohen S, Rennert G, Preis M. Association between myelofibrosis and thromboembolism: A population-based retrospective cohort study. J Thromb Haemost. 2020;18(4):916-925. doi:10.1111/jth.14754</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aylı M, Özcan M, Cengiz Seval G. Ruxolitinib Treatment in a Patient with Primary Myelofibrosis Resistant to Conventional Therapies and Splenectomy: A Case Report. Turk J Haematol. 2015;32(2):180-183. doi:10.4274/tjh.2013.0338</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Atzeni F, Popa CD, Nucera V, Nurmohamed MT. Safety of JAK inhibitors: focus on cardiovascular and thromboembolic events. Expert Rev Clin Immunol. 2022;1-12.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
