<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35474908</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>29</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2667-0313</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>2</Volume>
            <Issue>3</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Aug</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Phytomedicine Plus : International journal of phytotherapy and phytopharmacology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Phytomed Plus</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Ayurvedic formulations: Potential COVID-19 therapeutics?</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>100286</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>100286</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.phyplu.2022.100286</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">While Molnupiravir and Paxlovid have recently been approved for use in some countries, there are no widely available treatments for COVID-19, the disease caused by SARS-CoV-2 infection. Herbal extracts have been used to treat respiratory clinical indications by Ayurvedic medicine practitioners with minimal adverse reactions and intense research efforts are currently under way to develop some of these formulations for COVID-19 treatment.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Literature search for <i>in silico, in vitro, in vivo,</i> and clinical studies on the topic of Ayurvedic formulations for potential COVID-19 treatment, in order to present the current state of current knowledge by integrating information across all systems.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The search yielded 20 peer reviewed articles on <i>in silico</i> studies examining the interaction of phytoconstituents of popular Ayurvedic formulations with SARS-CoV-2 components and its receptors; five articles on preclinical investigations of the ability of selected Ayurvedic formulations to inhibit functions of SARS-CoV-2 proteins; and 51 completed clinical trials on the efficacy of using Ayurvedic formulations for treatment of mild to moderate COVID-19. Clinical data was available from 17 of the 51 trials. There was a considerable overlap between formulations used in the <i>in silico</i> studies and the clinical trials. This finding was unexpected as there is no clearly stated alignment between studies and the traditional pathway to drug discovery- basic discovery leading to <i>in vitro</i> and <i>in vivo</i> proof of concept, followed by validation in clinical trials. This was further demonstrated in the majority of the <i>in silico</i> studies where focus was on potential antiviral mechanisms, while the clinical trials were focused on patient recovery using oral treatments. In all 17 clinical trials where data was available, Ayurvedic treatments lead to a shorter period to recovery in participants with COVID-19.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The most commonly used Ayurvedic treatments for management of respiratory symptoms associated with SARS-CoV-2 infection appear to have prophylactic and/or therapeutic properties. It would be of particular interest to assess synergistic and concomitant systemic effects and antiviral activities of individual phytoconstituents and their combinations in the Ayurvedic treatments.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mahaboob Ali</LastName>
            <ForeName>Anees Ahmed</ForeName>
            <Initials>AA</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Centre for Research in Therapeutic Solutions, Faculty of Science and Technology, University of Canberra, Canberra, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bugarcic</LastName>
            <ForeName>Andrea</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>National Centre for Naturopathic Medicine, Southern Cross University, Lismore, New South Wales, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Naumovski</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nenad</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Functional Foods and Nutrition Research Laboratory, Faculty of Health, University of Canberra, Canberra, Ngunnawal Country, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Nutrition-Dietetics, School of Health Science and Education, Harokopio University, Athens, Greece.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ghildyal</LastName>
            <ForeName>Reena</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Centre for Research in Therapeutic Solutions, Faculty of Science and Technology, University of Canberra, Canberra, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>04</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Phytomed Plus</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9918382982506676</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2667-0313</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Antivirals</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ayurvedic formulations</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Clinical trials</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">In silico molecular docking</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>17</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35474908</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9020642</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.phyplu.2022.100286</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">S2667-0313(22)00069-0</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Antonio A.d.S., Wiedemann L.S.M., Veiga-Junior V.F. Natural products’ role against COVID-19. RSC Adv. 2020;10:23379–23393.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arun A., Gupta A., Subramanian S., Kanchibhotla D. Evaluation of an Ayurvedic formulation in clinical recovery of COVID-19 patients: a placebo controlled pilot study among moderate-severe patients. Res. Square. 2021</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ayatollahi S.A., Sharifi-Rad J., Tsouh Fokou P.V., Mahady G.B., Ansar Rasul Suleria H., Krishna Kapuganti S., Gadhave K., Giri R., Garg N., Sharma R., Ribeiro D., Rodrigues C.F., Reiner Z., Taheri Y., Cruz-Martins N. Naturally occurring bioactives as antivirals: emphasis on coronavirus infection. Front. Pharmacol. 2021;12</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Balkrishna A., Bhatt A.B., Singh P., Haldar S., Varshney A. Comparative retrospective open-label study of ayurvedic medicines and their combination with allopathic drugs on asymptomatic and mildly-symptomatic COVID-19 patients. J. Herb. Med. 2021;29</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Balkrishna A., Khandrika L., Varshney A. Giloy ghanvati (Tinospora cordifolia (willd.) Hook. F. and Thomson) reversed SARS-CoV-2 viral spike-protein induced disease phenotype in the xenotransplant model of humanized zebrafish. Front. Pharmacol. 2021;12</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Balkrishna A., Pokhrel S., Singh H., Joshi M., Mulay V.P., Haldar S., Varshney A. Withanone from Withania somnifera attenuates SARS-CoV-2 RBD and host ACE2 interactions to rescue spike protein induced pathologies in humanized zebrafish model. Drug Des. Devel. Ther. 2021;15:1111–1133.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Balkrishna A., Verma S., Solleti S.K., Khandrika L., Varshney A. Calcio-herbal medicine Divya-Swasari-Vati ameliorates SARS-CoV-2 spike protein-induced pathological features and inflammation in humanized zebrafish model by moderating IL-6 and TNF-alpha cytokines. J. Inflamm. Res. 2020;13:1219–1243.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7783203</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33414643</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Banerjee S., Kar A., Mukherjee P.K., Haldar P.K., Sharma N., Katiyar C.K. Immunoprotective potential of Ayurvedic herb Kalmegh (Andrographis paniculata) against respiratory viral infections - LC-MS/MS and network pharmacology analysis. Phytochem. Anal. 2021;32:629–639.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33167083</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bartoszko J.J., Siemieniuk R.A.C., Kum E., Qasim A., Zeraatkar D., Ge L., Han M.A., Sadeghirad B., Agarwal A., Agoritsas T., Chu D.K., Couban R., Darzi A.J., Devji T., Ghadimi M., Honarmand K., Izcovich A., Khamis A., Lamontagne F., Loeb M., Marcucci M., McLeod S.L., Motaghi S., Murthy S., Mustafa R.A., Neary J.D., Pardo-Hernandez H., Rada G., Rochwerg B., Switzer C., Tendal B., Thabane L., Vandvik P.O., Vernooij R.W.M., Viteri-Garcia A., Wang Y., Yao L., Ye Z., Guyatt G.H., Brignardello-Petersen R. Prophylaxis against covid-19: living systematic review and network meta-analysis. BMJ. 2021;373:n949.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8073806</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33903131</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beigel J.H., Tomashek K.M., Dodd L.E. Remdesivir for the treatment of Covid-19 - final report. N. Engl. J. Med. 2020;383:1813–1826.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7262788</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32445440</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Borse S., Joshi M., Saggam A., Bhat V., Walia S., Marathe A., Sagar S., Chavan-Gautam P., Girme A., Hingorani L., Tillu G. Ayurveda botanicals in COVID-19 management: an in silico multi-target approach. PLoS ONE. 2021;16</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chan Y., Raju Allam V.S.R., Paudel K.R., Singh S.K., Gulati M., Dhanasekaran M., Gupta P.K., Jha N.K., Devkota H.P., Gupta G., Hansbro P.M., Oliver B.G.G., Chellappan D.K., Dua K. Nutraceuticals: unlocking newer paradigms in the mitigation of inflammatory lung diseases. Crit. Rev. Food Sci. Nutr. 2021:1–31.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen H.Y., Ma C.H., Cao K.J., Chung-Man Ho J., Ziea E., Wong V.T., Zhang Z.J. A systematic review and meta-analysis of herbal medicine on chronic obstructive pulmonary diseases. Evid. Based Complement. Alternat. Med. 2014 2014.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chikhale R.V., Gurav S.S., Patil R.B., Sinha S.K., Prasad S.K., Shakya A., Shrivastava S.K., Gurav N.S., Prasad R.S. Sars-cov-2 host entry and replication inhibitors from Indian ginseng: an in-silico approach. J. Biomol. Struct. Dyn. 2021;39:4510–4521.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7332873</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32568012</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chitra S.M., Mallika P., Anbu N., NarayanaBabu R., SugunaBai A., David Paul Raj R.S., Premnath D. An open clinical evaluation of selected Siddha regimen in expediting the management of COVID-19 -a randomized controlled study. J. Ayurveda Integr. Med. 2021</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chopra A., Srikanth N., Patwardhan B., Group A.C.R. Withania somnifera as a safer option to hydroxychloroquine in the chemoprophylaxis of COVID-19: results of interim analysis. Complement. Ther. Med. 2021;62</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Devpura G., Tomar B.S., Nathiya D., Sharma A., Bhandari D., Haldar S., Balkrishna A., Varshney A. Randomized placebo-controlled pilot clinical trial on the efficacy of ayurvedic treatment regime on COVID-19 positive patients. Phytomedicine. 2021;84</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dhawan M., Parmar M., Sharun K., Tiwari R., Bilal M., Dhama K. Medicinal and therapeutic potential of withanolides from Withania somnifera against COVID-19. J. Appl. Pharm. Sci. 2021</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Drozdzal S., Rosik J., Lechowicz K., Machaj F., Szostak B., Przybycinski J., Lorzadeh S., Kotfis K., Ghavami S., Los M.J. An update on drugs with therapeutic potential for SARS-CoV-2 (COVID-19) treatment. Drug Resist. Updat. 2021</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Enmozhi S.K., Raja K., Sebastine I., Joseph J. Andrographolide as a potential inhibitor of SARS-CoV-2 main protease: an in silico approach. J. Biomol. Struct. Dyn. 2021;39:3092–3098.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7212536</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32329419</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fung T.S., Liu D.X. Human coronavirus: host-pathogen interaction. Annu. Rev. Microbiol. 2019;73:529–557.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31226023</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gheware A., Dholakia D., Kannan S., Panda L., Rani R., Pattnaik B.R., Jain V., Parekh Y., Enayathullah M.G., Bokara K.K., Subramanian V., Mukerji M., Agrawal A., Prasher B. Adhatoda Vasica attenuates inflammatory and hypoxic responses in preclinical mouse models: potential for repurposing in COVID-19-like conditions. Respir. Res. 2021;22:99.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8022127</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33823870</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gheware A., Panda L., Khanna K., Bhatraju N.K., Jain V., Sagar S., Kumar M., Singh V.P., Kannan S., Subramanian V., Mukerji M., Agrawal A., Prasher B. Adhatoda vasica rescues the hypoxia-dependent severe asthma symptoms and mitochondrial dysfunction. Am. J. Physiol. Lung Cell. Mol. Physiol. 2021;320:L757–L769.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33565386</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gundeti M.S., Bhurke L.W., Mundada P.S., Murudkar S., Surve A., Sharma R., Mata S., Rana R., Singhal R., Vyas N., Khanduri S., Sharma B.S., Srikanth N., Dhiman K.S. AYUSH 64, a polyherbal Ayurvedic formulation in Influenza-like illness - Results of a pilot study. J. Ayurveda Integr. Med. 2020</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta A., Vedula S., Srivastava R., Tamoli S., Mundhe N., Wagh D.N., Batra S., Patil M., Pawar H.B., Rai R.K. Prospective, randomized, open-label, blinded end point, two-arm, comparative clinical study to evaluate the efficacy and safety of a fixed Ayurvedic regimen (FAR) as add-on to conventional treatment in the management of mild and moderate COVID-19 patients. J. Pharm. Bioallied. Sci. 2021;13:256–267.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8291116</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34349488</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gurung A.B., Ali M.A., Lee J., Abul Farah M., Al-Anazi K.M. In silico screening of FDA approved drugs reveals ergotamine and dihydroergotamine as potential coronavirus main protease enzyme inhibitors. Saudi J. Biol. Sci. 2020;27:2674–2682.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7286259</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32837219</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Havranek B., Islam S.M. An in silico approach for identification of novel inhibitors as potential therapeutics targeting COVID-19 main protease. J. Biomol. Struct. Dyn. 2021;39:4304–4315.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7309303</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32544024</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Government of India  . Ministry of AYUSH. Government of India; 2020. National clinical management protocol based on Ayurveda and Yoga for management of Covid-19.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jayk Bernal A., Gomes da Silva M.M., Musungaie D.B. Molnupiravir for oral treatment of COVID-19 in nonhospitalized patients. N. Engl. J. Med. 2021</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jeyanthi V., Kumar G.V. COVID-19 outbreak: an overview and India’s perspectives on the managementof infection. Indian J. Sci. Technol. 2020;13:3716–3724.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kesharwani A., Polachira S.K., Nair R., Agarwal A., Mishra N.N., Gupta S.K. Anti-HSV-2 activity of Terminalia chebula Retz extract and its constituents, chebulagic and chebulinic acids. BMC Complement. Altern. Med. 2017;17:110.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5310005</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28196487</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kindrachuk J., Ork B., Hart B.J., Mazur S., Holbrook M.R., Frieman M.B., Traynor D., Johnson R.F., Dyall J., Kuhn J.H., Olinger G.G., Hensley L.E., Jahrling P.B. Antiviral potential of ERK/MAPK and PI3K/AKT/mTOR signaling modulation for Middle East respiratory syndrome coronavirus infection as identified by temporal kinome analysis. Antimicrob. Agents Chemother. 2015;59:1088–1099.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4335870</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25487801</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kiran G., Karthik L., Shree Devi M.S., Sathiyarajeswaran P., Kanakavalli K., Kumar K.M., Ramesh Kumar D. In silico computational screening of Kabasura Kudineer - Official Siddha formulation and JACOM against SARS-CoV-2 spike protein. J. Ayurveda Integr. Med. 2020</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kulkarni, V., Sharma, N., Modi, D., Kumar, A., Joshi, J., Krishnamurthy, N., 2021. A Community-based participatory research to assess the feasibility of Ayurveda intervention in patients with mild-to-moderate COVID-19. medRxiv, 2021.2001.2020.21250198.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kumar, A., Prasad, G., Srivastav, S., Gautam, V.K., Sharma, N., 2020a. Efficacy and safety of guduchi ghan vati in the management of asymptomatic COVID-19 infection: an open label feasibility study. medRxiv, 2020.2009.2020.20198515.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kumar, A., Prasad, G., Srivastav, S., Gautam, V.K., Sharma, N., 2020b. A retrospective study on efficacy and safety of guduchi ghan vati for COVID-19 asymptomatic patients. medRxiv, 2020.2007.2023.20160424.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kumar V., Dhanjal J.K., Bhargava P., Kaul A., Wang J., Zhang H., Kaul S.C., Wadhwa R., Sundar D. Withanone and Withaferin-A are predicted to interact with transmembrane protease serine 2 (TMPRSS2) and block entry of SARS-CoV-2 into cells. J. Biomol. Struct. Dyn. 2020:1–13.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li P., Du R., Wang Y., Hou X., Wang L., Zhao X., Zhan P., Liu X., Rong L., Cui Q. Identification of chebulinic acid and chebulagic acid as novel influenza viral neuraminidase inhibitors. Front. Microbiol. 2020;11:182.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7093024</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32256457</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maurya D.K., Sharma D. Evaluation of traditional ayurvedic Kadha for prevention and management of the novel Coronavirus (SARS-CoV-2) using in silico approach. J. Biomol. Struct. Dyn. 2020:1–16.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maurya V.K., Kumar S., Bhatt M.L.B., Saxena S.K. Antiviral activity of traditional medicinal plants from Ayurveda against SARS-CoV-2 infection. J. Biomol. Struct. Dyn. 2020:1–17.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maurya V.K., Kumar S., Prasad A.K., Bhatt M.L.B., Saxena S.K. Structure-based drug designing for potential antiviral activity of selected natural products from Ayurveda against SARS-CoV-2 spike glycoprotein and its cellular receptor. Virusdisease. 2020;31:179–193.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7245990</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32656311</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mishra K.P., Singh A.K., Singh S.B. Hyperinflammation and immune response generation in COVID-19. NeuroImmunoModulation. 2020;27:80–86.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7801965</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33341814</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mulpuru, V., Mishra, N., 2021. Computational identification of SARS-CoV-2 inhibitor in Tinospora cordifolia, Cinnamomum zeylanicum and Myristica fragrans. Virusdisease, 1–7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Murugesan S., Kottekad S., Crasta I., Sreevathsan S., Usharani D., Perumal M.K., Mudliar S.N. Targeting COVID-19 (SARS-CoV-2) main protease through active phytocompounds of ayurvedic medicinal plants - Emblica officinalis (Amla), Phyllanthus niruri Linn. (Bhumi Amla) and Tinospora cordifolia (Giloy) - a molecular docking and simulation study. Comput. Biol. Med. 2021;136</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muthumanickam S., Kamaladevi A., Boomi P., Gowrishankar S., Pandian S.K. Indian ethnomedicinal phytochemicals as promising inhibitors of RNA-binding domain of SARS-CoV-2 nucleocapsid phosphoprotein: an in silico study. Front. Mol. Biosci. 2021;8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Natarajan S., Anbarasi C., Sathiyarajeswaran P., Manickam P., Geetha S., Kathiravan R., Prathiba P., Pitchiahkumar M., Parthiban P., Kanakavalli K., Balaji P. The efficacy of Siddha Medicine, Kabasura Kudineer (KSK) compared to vitamin C &amp; Zinc (CZ) supplementation in the management of asymptomatic COVID-19 cases: a structured summary of a study protocol for a randomised controlled trial. Trials. 2020;21:892.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7590253</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33109252</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Natarajan S., Anbarasi C., Sathiyarajeswaran P., Manickam P., Geetha S., Kathiravan R., Prathiba P., Pitchiahkumar M., Parthiban P., Kanakavalli K., Balaji P. Kabasura Kudineer (KSK), a poly-herbal Siddha medicine, reduced SARS-CoV-2 viral load in asymptomatic COVID-19 individuals as compared to vitamin C and zinc supplementation: findings from a prospective, exploratory, open-labeled, comparative, randomized controlled trial, Tamil Nadu, India. Trials. 2021;22:623.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8441246</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34526104</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>National Center for Complementary and Integrative Health, N., 2022. Ayurvedic medicine: in depth, in: Health, N.I.o. (Ed.).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parekar R.R., Bolegave S.S., Marathe P.A., Rege N.N. Experimental evaluation of analgesic, anti-inflammatory and anti-platelet potential of Dashamoola. J. Ayurveda Integr. Med. 2015;6:11–18.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4395922</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25878458</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parida P.K., Paul D., Chakravorty D. The natural way forward: molecular dynamics simulation analysis of phytochemicals from Indian medicinal plants as potential inhibitors of SARS-CoV-2 targets. Phytother. Res. 2020;34:3420–3433.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7537166</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32969524</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parisi G.F., Carota G., Castruccio Castracani C., Spampinato M., Manti S., Papale M., Di Rosa M., Barbagallo I., Leonardi S. Nutraceuticals in the prevention of viral infections, including COVID-19, among the pediatric population: a review of the literature. Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2021;22</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pawar K.S., Mastud R.N., Pawar S.K., Pawar S.S., Bhoite R.R., Bhoite R.R., Kulkarni M.V., Deshpande A.R. Oral curcumin with piperine as adjuvant therapy for the treatment of COVID-19: a randomized clinical trial. Front. Pharmacol. 2021;12</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rais A., Negi D.S., Yadav A., Arya H., Verma R., Galib R., Ahmad A., Kumar Yadav M., Ahirwar P.N. A Randomized open label parallel group pilot study to evaluate efficacy of Ayurveda interventions in the management of asymptomatic and mild COVID-19 patients-experiences of a Lucknow based level 2 hospital of Uttar Pradesh, India. J. Ayurveda Integr. Med. 2021</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rao, A., Ranganatha, R., Vikneswaran, G., Sagar, C., Mathu, R., Sherin, M., Sigamani, A., Reddy, M.R.K., 2020. AYUSH medicine as add-on therapy for mild category COVID-19; an open label randomised, controlled clinical trial. medRxiv 12, 20245019.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reis G., Dos Santos Moreira-Silva E.A., Silva D.C.M., Thabane L. Effect of early treatment with fluvoxamine on risk of emergency care and hospitalisation among patients with COVID-19: the TOGETHER randomised, platform clinical trial. Lancet Glob. Health. 2022;10:e42–e51.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8550952</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34717820</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sagar V., Kumar A.H.S. Efficacy of natural compounds from Tinospora cordifolia against SARS-CoV-2 protease, surface glycoprotein and RNA polymerase. Res. Square. 2021</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shree P., Mishra P., Selvaraj C., Singh S.K., Chaube R., Garg N., Tripathi Y.B. Targeting COVID-19 (SARS-CoV-2) main protease through active phytochemicals of ayurvedic medicinal plants - Withania somnifera (Ashwagandha), Tinospora cordifolia (Giloy) and Ocimum sanctum (Tulsi) - a molecular docking study. J. Biomol. Struct. Dyn. 2020:1–14.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shukla R., Singh S., Singh A., Misra K. Two pronged approach for prevention and therapy of COVID-19 (Sars-CoV-2) by a multi-targeted herbal drug, a component of ayurvedic decoction. Eur. J. Integr. Med. 2021;43</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Siemieniuk R.A., Bartoszko J.J., Diaz Martinez J.P., Kum E., Qasim A., Zeraatkar D., Izcovich A., Mangala S., Ge L., Han M.A., Agoritsas T., Arnold D., Avila C., Chu D.K., Couban R., Cusano E., Darzi A.J., Devji T., Foroutan F., Ghadimi M., Khamis A., Lamontagne F., Loeb M., Miroshnychenko A., Motaghi S., Murthy S., Mustafa R.A., Rada G., Rochwerg B., Switzer C., Vandvik P.O., Vernooij R.W., Wang Y., Yao L., Guyatt G.H., Brignardello-Petersen R. Antibody and cellular therapies for treatment of covid-19: a living systematic review and network meta-analysis. BMJ. 2021;374:n2231.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8459162</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34556486</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Siemieniuk R.A., Bartoszko J.J., Ge L., Zeraatkar D., Izcovich A., Kum E., Pardo-Hernandez H., Qasim A., Martinez J.P.D., Rochwerg B., Lamontagne F., Han M.A., Liu Q., Agarwal A., Agoritsas T., Chu D.K., Couban R., Cusano E., Darzi A., Devji T., Fang B., Fang C., Flottorp S.A., Foroutan F., Ghadimi M., Heels-Ansdell D., Honarmand K., Hou L., Hou X., Ibrahim Q., Khamis A., Lam B., Loeb M., Marcucci M., McLeod S.L., Motaghi S., Murthy S., Mustafa R.A., Neary J.D., Rada G., Riaz I.B., Sadeghirad B., Sekercioglu N., Sheng L., Sreekanta A., Switzer C., Tendal B., Thabane L., Tomlinson G., Turner T., Vandvik P.O., Vernooij R.W., Viteri-Garcia A., Wang Y., Yao L., Ye Z., Guyatt G.H., Brignardello-Petersen R. Drug treatments for covid-19: living systematic review and network meta-analysis. BMJ. 2020;370:m2980.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7390912</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32732190</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singh H., Bhargava S., Ganeshan S., Kaur R., Sethi T., Sharma M., Chauhan M., Chauhan N., Chauhan R., Chauhan P., Brahmachari S.K. Big data analysis of traditional knowledge-based Ayurveda medicine. Prog. Prevent. Med. 2018;3:e0020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singh S., Kola P., Kaur D., Singla G., Mishra V., Panesar P.S., Mallikarjunan K., Krishania M. Therapeutic potential of nutraceuticals and dietary supplements in the prevention of viral diseases: a review. Front. Nutr. 2021;8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Srivastava A., Rengaraju M., Srivastava S., Narayan V., Gupta V., Upadhayay R. A double blinded placebo controlled comparative clinical trial to evaluate the effectiveness of Siddha medicines, Kaba Sura Kudineer (KSK) &amp; Nilavembu Kudineer (NVK) along with standard Allopathy treatment in the management of symptomatic COVID 19 patients - a structured summary of a study protocol for a randomized controlled trial. Trials. 2021;22:130.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7876527</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33573696</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Srivastava A., Rengaraju M., Srivastava S., Narayanan V., Gupta V., Upadhayay R., Kumar J., Parameswaran S., KanakavalliKadarkarai AarthiVelmurugan. Efficacy of two siddha polyherbal decoctions, Nilavembu Kudineer and Kaba Sura Kudineer, along with standard allopathy treatment in the management of mild to moderate symptomatic COVID-19 patients-a double-blind, placebo-controlled, clinical trial. Trials. 2021;22:570.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8397852</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34454572</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Srivastava A., Siddiqui S., Ahmad R., Mehrotra S., Ahmad B., Srivastava A.N. Exploring nature's bounty: identification of Withania somnifera as a promising source of therapeutic agents against COVID-19 by virtual screening and in silico evaluation. J. Biomol. Struct. Dyn. 2020:1–51.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Steel A., Wardle J., Lloyd I. The potential contribution of traditional, complementary and integrative treatments in acute viral respiratory tract infections: rapid Reviews in response to the COVID-19 pandemic. Adv. Integr. Med. 2020;7:181–182.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7833414</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33520646</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thakar A., Panara K., Patel F., Bhagiya S., Goyal M., Bhinde S., Chaudhari S., Chaturvedi S. Add-on Ayurveda treatment for early stage COVID-19: a single center retrospective cohort study from Gujarat, India. J. Evid. Based Integr. Med. 2021;26 2515690X211020685.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tripathi M.K., Singh P., Sharma S., Singh T.P., Ethayathulla A.S., Kaur P. Identification of bioactive molecule from Withania somnifera (Ashwagandha) as SARS-CoV-2 main protease inhibitor. J. Biomol. Struct. Dyn. 2021;39:5668–5681.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7441797</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32643552</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Upadhyay A.K., Kumar K., Kumar A., Mishra H.S. Tinospora cordifolia (Willd.) Hook. f. and Thoms. (Guduchi) - validation of the Ayurvedic pharmacology through experimental and clinical studies. Int. J. Ayurveda Res. 2010;1:112–121.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2924974</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20814526</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Upadhyay S., Tripathi P.K., Singh M., Raghavendhar S., Bhardwaj M., Patel A.K. Evaluation of medicinal herbs as a potential therapeutic option against SARS-CoV-2 targeting its main protease. Phytother. Res. 2020;34:3411–3419.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7436756</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32748969</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>V'Kovski P., Kratzel A., Steiner S., Stalder H., Thiel V. Coronavirus biology and replication: implications for SARS-CoV-2. Nat. Rev. Microbiol. 2021;19:155–170.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7592455</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33116300</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang L., Yang R., Yuan B., Liu Y., Liu C. The antiviral and antimicrobial activities of licorice, a widely-used Chinese herb. Acta Pharm. Sin. B. 2015;5:310–315.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4629407</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26579460</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>WHO, 2021a. Coronavirus disease (COVID-19).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>WHO, 2021b . Weekly operational update on COVID-19 - 3 November 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Willcox M. Improved traditional phytomedicines in current use for the clinical treatment of malaria. Planta Med. 2011;77:662–671.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21204042</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang H., Rao Z. Structural biology of SARS-CoV-2 and implications for therapeutic development. Nat. Rev. Microbiol. 2021;19:685–700.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8447893</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34535791</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang W., Zheng Q., Song M., Xiao J., Cao Y., Huang Q., Ho C.T., Lu M. A review on the bioavailability, bio-efficacies and novel delivery systems for piperine. Food Funct. 2021;12:8867–8881.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34528635</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
