<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35475029</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>29</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2452-199X</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>19</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2023</Year>
              <Month>Jan</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Bioactive materials</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Bioact Mater</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Decoupling the role of chemistry and microstructure in hMSCs response to an osteoinductive calcium phosphate ceramic.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>127</StartPage>
          <EndPage>138</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>127-138</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.bioactmat.2022.03.030</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Calcium phosphates (CaP) are widely used synthetic bone graft substitutes, having bioactivity that is regulated by a set of intertwined physico-chemical and structural properties. While some CaPs have shown to be as effective in regenerating large bone defects as autologous bone, there is still the need to understand the role of individual material properties in CaP performance. Here, we aimed to decouple the effects of chemical composition and surface-microstructure of a beta-tricalcium phosphate (TCP) ceramic, with proven osteoinductive potential, on human mesenchymal stromal cells (hMSCs) differentiation. To this end, we replicated the surface structure of the TCP ceramic into polylactic acid without inorganic additives, or containing the chemical constituents of the ceramic, i.e., a calcium salt, a phosphate salt, or TCP powder. The microstructure of the different materials was characterized by confocal laser profilometry. hMSCs were cultured on the materials, and the expression of a set of osteogenic genes was determined. The cell culture medium was collected and the levels of calcium and phosphate ions were quantified by inductively-coupled plasma mass spectrometry. The results revealed that none of the tested combinations of properties in polymer/composite replicas was as potent in supporting the osteogenic differentiation of hMSCs as the original ceramic. Nevertheless, we observed some effects of the surface structure in the absence of inorganics, as well as combined effects of surface structure and the added salts, in particular calcium, on osteogenic differentiation. The approach presented here can be used to study the role of independent properties in other CaP-based biomaterials.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Authors.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Galván-Chacón</LastName>
            <ForeName>V P</ForeName>
            <Initials>VP</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>MERLN Institute for Technology Inspired Regenerative Medicine, Maastricht University, the Netherlands.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>de Melo Pereira</LastName>
            <ForeName>D</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>MERLN Institute for Technology Inspired Regenerative Medicine, Maastricht University, the Netherlands.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Vermeulen</LastName>
            <ForeName>S</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>MERLN Institute for Technology Inspired Regenerative Medicine, Maastricht University, the Netherlands.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yuan</LastName>
            <ForeName>H</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Kuros Biosciences BV, 3723 MB, Bilthoven, the Netherlands.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Li</LastName>
            <ForeName>J</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>MERLN Institute for Technology Inspired Regenerative Medicine, Maastricht University, the Netherlands.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Habibović</LastName>
            <ForeName>P</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>MERLN Institute for Technology Inspired Regenerative Medicine, Maastricht University, the Netherlands.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>04</Month>
          <Day>08</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Bioact Mater</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101685294</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2452-199X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Calcium phosphate</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chemical composition</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mesenchymal stromal cells</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Microstructure</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Osteogenic differentiation</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>19</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35475029</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9014318</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bioactmat.2022.03.030</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">S2452-199X(22)00146-3</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bohner M., Galea L., Doebelin N. Calcium phosphate bone graft substitutes: failures and hopes. J. Eur. Ceram. Soc. 2012;32(11):2663–2671.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Habraken W., et al.  Calcium phosphates in biomedical applications: materials for the future? Mater. Today. 2016;19(2):69–87.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Uskokovic V., Wu V.M. Calcium phosphate as a key material for socially responsible tissue engineering. Materials. 2016;9(6)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Russell T.A., Leighton R.K., Alpha B.S. Comparison of autogenous bone graft and endothermic calcium phosphate cement for defect augmentation in tibial plateau fractures. A multicenter, prospective, randomized study. J. Bone. Joint. Surg. Am. 2008;90(10):2057–2061.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18829901</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yuan H., et al.  Osteoinductive ceramics as a synthetic alternative to autologous bone grafting. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2010;107(31):13614–13619.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2922269</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20643969</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barrère-de Groot F., Yuan H., de Bruijn J.D. Clinical relevance of sub-micron textured calcium phosphates for bone tissue regeneration. Mater. Today Proc. 2018;5(7):15501–15505.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Costa-Rodrigues J., et al.  Hydroxyapatite surface roughness: complex modulation of the osteoclastogenesis of human precursor cells. Acta Biomater. 2012;8(3):1137–1145.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22178652</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deligianni D.D., et al.  Effect of surface roughness of hydroxyapatite on human bone marrow cell adhesion, proliferation, differentiation and detachment strength. Biomaterials. 2001;22:87–96.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11085388</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coathup M.J., et al.  The effect of particle size on the osteointegration of injectable silicate-substituted calcium phosphate bone substitute materials. J. Biomed. Mater. Res. B Appl. Biomater. 2013;101(6):902–910.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4166705</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23362131</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Uskokovic V., et al.  Effect of calcium phosphate particle shape and size on their antibacterial and osteogenic activity in the delivery of antibiotics in vitro. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces. 2013;5(7):2422–2431.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3647690</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23484624</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang L., et al.  Effect of particle size on osteoinductive potential of microstructured biphasic calcium phosphate ceramic. J. Biomed. Mater. Res. 2015;103(6):1919–1929.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lapczyna H., et al.  Effect of grain size and microporosity on the in vivo behaviour of beta-tricalcium phosphate scaffolds. Eur. Cell. Mater. 2014;28:299–319.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25340808</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kasten P., et al.  Porosity and pore size of beta-tricalcium phosphate scaffold can influence protein production and osteogenic differentiation of human mesenchymal stem cells: an in vitro and in vivo study. Acta Biomater. 2008;4(6):1904–1915.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18571999</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mattei G., et al.  Decoupling the role of stiffness from other hydroxyapatite signalling cues in periosteal derived stem cell differentiation. Sci. Rep. 2015;5:10778.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4451686</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26035412</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Burke D.P., Kelly D.J. Substrate stiffness and oxygen as regulators of stem cell differentiation during skeletal tissue regeneration: a mechanobiological model. PLoS One. 2012;7(7):e40737.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3404068</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22911707</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Witkowska-Zimny M., et al.  Effect of substrate stiffness on the osteogenic differentiation of bone marrow stem cells and bone-derived cells. Cell Biol. Int. 2013;37(6):608–616.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23447501</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Danoux C., et al.  The effects of crystal phase and particle morphology of calcium phosphates on proliferation and differentiation of human mesenchymal stromal cells. Adv. Healthc. Mater. 2016;5(14):1775–1785.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27232450</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ullah I., et al.  Synthesis, characterization and in vitro evaluation of zinc and strontium binary doped hydroxyapatite for biomedical application. Ceram. Int. 2020;46(10):14448–14459.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Birgani Z.T., et al.  Combinatorial incorporation of fluoride and cobalt ions into calcium phosphates to stimulate osteogenesis and angiogenesis. Biomed. Mater. 2016;11(1):15020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tahmasebi Birgani Z., et al.  Stimulatory effect of cobalt ions incorporated into calcium phosphate coatings on neovascularization in an in vivo intramuscular model in goats. Acta Biomater. 2016;36:267–276.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27000550</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Habibovic P., Barralet J.E. Bioinorganics and biomaterials: bone repair. Acta Biomater. 2011;7(8):3013–3026.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21453799</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xue W., et al.  Effect of hydroxyapatite coating crystallinity on dissolution and osseointegration in vivo. J. Biomed. Mater. Res. 2005;74(4):553–561.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee W.H., et al.  Synthesis and characterization of hydroxyapatite with different crystallinity: effects on protein adsorption and release. J. Biomed. Mater. Res. 2012;100(6):1539–1549.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Danoux C., et al.  Development of highly functional biomaterials by decoupling and recombining material properties. Adv. Mater. 2016;28(9):1803–1808.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26689847</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Anselme K., Bigerelle M. Statistical demonstration of the relative effect of surface chemistry and roughness on human osteoblast short-term adhesion. J. Mater. Sci. Mater. Med. 2006;17:471–479.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16688588</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>dos Santos E.A., et al.  Chemical and topographical influence of hydroxyapatite and beta-tricalcium phosphate surfaces on human osteoblastic cell behavior. J. Biomed. Mater. Res. 2009;89(2):510–520.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Davison N.L., et al.  Submicron-scale surface architecture of tricalcium phosphate directs osteogenesis in vitro and in vivo. Eur. Cell. Mater. 2014;27:281–297. ; discussion 296-7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24733686</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hacking S.A., et al.  Relative contributions of chemistry and topography to the osseointegration of hydroxyapatite coatings. Clin. Orthop. Relat. Res. 2002;(405):24–38.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Danoux C.B., et al.  Elucidating the individual effects of calcium and phosphate ions on hMSCs by using composite materials. Acta Biomater. 2015;17:1–15.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25676583</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Groen N., et al.  Linking the transcriptional landscape of bone induction to biomaterial design parameters. Adv. Mater. 2017;29(10)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Othman Z., et al.  The role of ENPP1/PC-1 in osteoinduction by calcium phosphate ceramics. Biomaterials. 2019;210:12–24.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31048198</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sun L., et al.  Independent effects of the chemical and microstructural surface properties of polymer/ceramic composites on proliferation and osteogenic differentiation of human MSCs. Acta Biomater. 2016;42:364–377.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27318269</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pegg E.C., et al.  Topographical and chemical effects of electrochemically assisted deposited hydroxyapatite coatings on osteoblast-like cells. J. Biomater. Appl. 2014;28(6):946–953.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23680819</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Davison N., et al.  In vivo performance of microstructured calcium phosphate formulated in novel water-free carriers. Acta Biomater. 2012;8(7):2759–2769.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22487931</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Duan R., et al.  Modulating bone regeneration in rabbit condyle defects with three surface-structured tricalcium phosphate ceramics. ACS Biomater. Sci. Eng. 2018;4(9):3347–3355.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6134343</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30221192</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang J., et al.  Topography of calcium phosphate ceramics regulates primary cilia length and TGF receptor recruitment associated with osteogenesis. Acta Biomater. 2017;57:487–497.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5489417</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28456657</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Doebelin N., Kleeberg R. Profex: a graphical user interface for the Rietveld refinement program BGMN. J. Appl. Crystallogr. 2015;48(Pt 5):1573–1580.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4603273</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26500466</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Daculsi G., LeGeros Z. Transformation of biphasic calcium phosphate ceramics in vivo: ultrastructural and physicochemical characterization. J. Biomed. Mater. Res. 1989;23:883–894.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2777831</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berzina-Cimdina L., Borodajenko N.  In: Infrared Spectroscopy. Materials Science, Engineering and Technology. Teophile T., editor. IntechOpen; 2012. Research of calcium phosphates using fourier transform infrared spectroscopy; pp. 123–148.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mobasherpour I., et al.  Synthesis of nanocrystalline hydroxyapatite by using precipitation method. J. Alloys Compd. 2007;430(1–2):330–333.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dasgupta S., et al.  Effect of grain size on mechanical, surface and biological properties of microwave sintered hydroxyapatite. Mater. Sci. Eng. C. Mater. Biol. Appl. 2013;33(5):2846–2854.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23623105</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deville J.-P., Cojocaru C.  In: Materials Surface Processing by Directed Energy Techniques. Pauleau Y., editor. Elsevier; 2006. Some examples on surfaces grown or modified by plasma interaction - applications to the biomedical field; p. 434.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shen M., et al.  Multivariate surface analysis of plasma-deposited tetraglyme for reduction of protein adsorption and monocyte adhesion. Langmuir. 2003;19:1692–1699.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Birgani Z.T., et al.  Human mesenchymal stromal cells response to biomimetic octacalcium phosphate containing strontium. J. Biomed. Mater. Res. 2016;104(8):1946–1960.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barbieri D., et al.  Influence of polymer molecular weight in osteoinductive composites for bone tissue regeneration. Acta Biomater. 2013;9(12):9401–9413.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23917043</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Habibovic P., et al.  Collagen biomineralization in vivo by sustained release of inorganic phosphate ions. Adv. Mater. 2010;22(16):1858–1862.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20512962</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li L., Crosby K., Sawicki M. Effects of surface roughness of hydroxyapatite on cell attachment and proliferation. J. Biotechnol. Biomater. 2012;2(6)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boyan B., et al.  Mechanisms involved in osteoblast response to implant surface morphology. Annu. Rev. Mater. Res. 2001;31:357–371.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rausch-fan X., et al.  Differentiation and cytokine synthesis of human alveolar osteoblasts compared to osteoblast-like cells (MG63) in response to titanium surfaces. Dent. Mater. 2008;24(1):102–110.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17467048</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Golub E., Boesze-Battaglia K. The role of alkaline phosphatase in mineralization. Curr. Opin. Orthop. 2007;18(5):444–448.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Orimo H. The mechanism of mineralization and the role of alkaline phosphatase in health and disease. J. Nippon Med. Sch. 2010;77(1):4–12.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20154452</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vimalraj S. Alkaline phosphatase: structure, expression and its function in bone mineralization. Gene. 2020;754:1448555.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sun J., et al.  Role of bone morphogenetic protein-2 in osteogenic differentiation of mesenchymal stem cells. Mol. Med. Rep. 2015;12(3):4230–4237.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4526091</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26096280</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bruderer M., et al.  Role and regulation of RUNX2 in osteogenesis. Eur. Cell. Mater. 2014;28:269–286.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25340806</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu J., et al.  Potential mechanisms underlying the Runx2 induced osteogenesis of bone marrow mesenchymal stem cells. Am. J. Tourism Res. 2015;7(12):2527–2535.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Qin C., Baba O., Butler W. Post-translational modifications of sibling proteins and their roles in osteogenesis and dentinogenesis. Crit. Rev. Oral Biol. Med. 2004;15(3):126–136.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15187031</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roach H. Why does bone matrix contain non-collagenous proteins? The possible roles of osteocalcin, osteonectin, osteopontin and bone sialoprotein in bone mineralization and resorption. Cell Biol. Int. 1994;18(6):617–628.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8075622</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang J., et al.  The size of surface microstructures as an osteogenic factor in calcium phosphate ceramics. Acta Biomater. 2014;10(7):3254–3263.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24681376</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang J., et al.  Nano-hydroxyapatite coating promotes porous calcium phosphate ceramic-induced osteogenesis via BMP/smad signaling pathway. Int. J. Nanomed. 2019;14:7987–8000.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bigi A., et al.  Human osteoblast response to pulsed laser deposited calcium phosphate coatings. Biomaterials. 2005;26(15):2381–2389.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15585241</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mitran V., et al.  Osteoblast cell response to naturally derived calcium phosphate-based materials. Materials. 2018;11(7)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muller P., et al.  Calcium phosphate surfaces promote osteogenic differentiation of mesenchymal stem cells. J. Cell Mol. Med. 2008;12(1):281–291.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3823489</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18366455</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yuasa T., et al.   vol. 24. 2005. pp. 207–212. (Proliferation and Differentiation of Cultured MC3T3-E1 Osteoblasts on Surface-Layer Modified Hydroxyapatite Ceramic with Acid and Heat Treatments). 2.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Acevedo-Acevedo S., Crone W.C. Substrate stiffness effect and chromosome missegregation in hIPS cells. J. Negat. Results Biomed. 2015;14:22.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4683860</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26683848</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van de Velde K., Kiekens P. Biopolymers: overview of several properties andconsequences on their applications. Polym. Test. 2002;21:433–442.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Esmaeilzadeh J., et al.  Microstructure and mechanical properties of biodegradable poly (D/L) lactic acid/polycaprolactone blends processed from the solvent-evaporation technique. Mater. Sci. Eng. C. Mater. Biol. Appl. 2017;71:807–819.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27987776</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Murphy W.L., McDevitt T.C., Engler A.J. Materials as stem cell regulators. Nat. Mater. 2014;13(6):547–557.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4163547</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24845994</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sun M., et al.  Effects of matrix stiffness on the morphology, adhesion, proliferation and osteogenic differentiation of mesenchymal stem cells. Int. J. Med. Sci. 2018;15(3):257–268.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5820855</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29483817</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Janmey P.A., Fletcher D.A., Reinhart-King C.A. Stiffness sensing by cells. Physiol. Rev. 2020;100(2):695–724.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7276923</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31751165</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tahmasebi Birgani Z., et al.  Poly(lactic acid) microspheres for local delivery of bioinorganics for applications in bone regeneration. Adv. Biomater. Device. Med. 2014;1(1):1–10.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen J., et al.  Conductive nanofibrous composite scaffolds based on in-situ formed polyaniline nanoparticle and polylactide for bone regeneration. J. Colloid Interface Sci. 2018;514:517–527.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29289734</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barradas A.M., et al.  A calcium-induced signaling cascade leading to osteogenic differentiation of human bone marrow-derived mesenchymal stromal cells. Biomaterials. 2012;33(11):3205–3215.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22285104</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cheng S., et al.  Effects of extracellular calcium on viability and osteogenic differentiation of bone marrow stromal cells in vitro. Hum. Cell. 2013;26(3):114–120.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23749732</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jung G.Y., Park Y.J., Han J.S. Effects of HA released calcium ion on osteoblast differentiation. J. Mater. Sci. Mater. Med. 2010;21(5):1649–1654.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20162336</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maeno S., et al.  The effect of calcium ion concentration on osteoblast viability, proliferation and differentiation in monolayer and 3D culture. Biomaterials. 2005;26(23):4847–4855.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15763264</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Karageorgiou V., Kaplan D. Porosity of 3D biomaterial scaffolds and osteogenesis. Biomaterials. 2005;26(27):5474–5491.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15860204</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Klenke F.M., et al.  Impact of pore size on the vascularization and osseointegration of ceramic bone substitutes in vivo. J. Biomed. Mater. Res. 2009;85(3):777–786.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marino A., et al.  The Osteoprint: a bioinspired two-photon polymerized 3-D structure for the enhancement of bone-like cell differentiation. Acta Biomater. 2014;10(10):4304–4313.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24907661</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maazouz Y., et al.  Cell-free, quantitative mineralization measurements as a proxy to identify osteoinductive bone graft substitutes. Biomaterials. 2021;275:120912.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34098150</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
