<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35474043</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>27</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1708-0428</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Apr</Month>
              <Day>26</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Obesity surgery</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Obes Surg</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Prediction Factors of Early Postoperative Bleeding after Bariatric Surgery.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s11695-022-06059-z</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Identifying the possible predictors of postoperative bleeding is advantageous to reduce healthcare costs and promote patients' recovery. The aim of this study was to determine early postoperative bleeding predictors after bariatric surgery.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This retrospective study was conducted using data from 2260 patients who underwent bariatric surgery. We diagnosed early postoperative bleeding by the following symptoms: abdominal pain, hypotension, tachycardia, hematemesis, melena, decreased hemoglobin level, the need for at least two units of packed red blood cells (PRBCs) transfusion, and reoperation within the first 48 h after surgery.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Our results showed the odds of early postoperative bleeding in laparoscopic Roux-en-Y gastric bypass (LRYGB) were higher than in laparoscopic sleeve gastrectomy (LSG) (OR 3.49, 95% CI 1.79 to 6.80). In addition, prior intragastric balloon (IGB) (OR 3.14, 95% CI 1.18 to 8.34) and oral non-aspirin non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs (NSAIDs) (OR 5.91, 95% CI 1.79 to 20.63) were positively associated with the occurrence of postoperative bleeding. In contrast, there was an inverse relationship between staple line oversewing and the odds of postoperative bleeding (OR 0.18, 95% CI 0.04 to 0.81). After stratification data based on the type of the surgery, the positive association between IGB and the odds of bleeding was constant in the LRYGB group. In the LSG group, use of non-aspirin NSAIDs was linked to a higher incidence of postoperative bleeding, while oversewing of the staple line lowered the incidence of this event.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Our results demonstrated a positive association between type of procedure, history of IGB, and oral non-aspirin NSIADs use, as well as an inverse relationship between staple line oversewing and the odds of bleeding after bariatric surgery.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Science+Business Media, LLC, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Golzarand</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mahdieh</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2651-9276</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Nutrition and Endocrine Research Center, Research Institute for Endocrine Sciences, Shahid Beheshti University of Medical Sciences, 1985717413, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Toolabi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Karamollah</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Surgery, Imam Khomeini Hospital, Tehran University of Medical Sciences, 1419733141, Tehran, Iran. tolabika@tums.ac.ir.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Parsaei</LastName>
            <ForeName>Reza</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>West Nikan Hospital, 1985717413, Theran, Iran.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>04</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Obes Surg</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9106714</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0960-8923</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gastric bypass</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hemorrhage</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Retrospective cohort</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sleeve gastrectomy</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>34</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35474043</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11695-022-06059-z</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s11695-022-06059-z</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kumbhari V, Cummings DE, Kalloo AN, Schauer PR. AGA clinical practice update on evaluation and management of early complications after bariatric/metabolic surgery: expert review. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2021;19(8):1531–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cgh.2021.03.020</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sheka AC, Kizy S, Wirth K, Grams J, Leslie D, Ikramuddin S. Racial disparities in perioperative outcomes after bariatric surgery. Surg Obesity Relat Dis. 2019;15(5):786–93.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.soard.2018.12.021</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nijland LMG, de Castro SMM, van Veen RN. Risk factors associated with prolonged hospital stay and readmission in patients after primary bariatric surgery. Obes Surg. 2020;30(6):2395–402.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11695-020-04507-2</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khalaj A, Tasdighi E, Hosseinpanah F, Mahdavi M, Valizadeh M, Farahmand E, et al. Two-year outcomes of sleeve gastrectomy versus gastric bypass: first report based on Tehran obesity treatment study (TOTS). BMC Surg. 2020;20(1):160.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12893-020-00819-3</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nielsen HJ, Nedrebø BG, Fosså A, Andersen JR, Assmus J, Dagsland VH, et al. Seven-year trajectories of body weight, quality of life and comorbidities following Roux-en-Y gastric bypass and sleeve gastrectomy. Int J Obesity (2005). 2022;46(4):739–49.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vilallonga R, Hidalgo M, Garcia Ruiz de Gordejuela A, Caubet E, Gonzalez O, Ciudin A, et al. Operative and postoperative complications of laparoscopic sleeve gastrectomy in super and nonsuper obese patients: a center of excellence experience comparative study. J Laparoendosc Adv Surg Tech - A. 2020;30(5):501–7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peterli R, Wölnerhanssen BK, Peters T, Vetter D, Kröll D, Borbély Y, et al. Effect of Laparoscopic sleeve gastrectomy vs laparoscopic Roux-en-Y gastric bypass on weight loss in patients with morbid obesity: the SM-BOSS randomized clinical trial. JAMA. 2018;319(3):255–65.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2017.20897</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salminen P, Helmiö M, Ovaska J, Juuti A, Leivonen M, Peromaa-Haavisto P, et al. Effect of laparoscopic sleeve gastrectomy vs laparoscopic Roux-en-Y gastric bypass on weight loss at 5 years among patients with morbid obesity: the SLEEVEPASS randomized clinical trial. JAMA. 2018;319(3):241–54.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2017.20313</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Angelis F, Abdelgawad M, Rizzello M, Mattia C, Silecchia G. Perioperative hemorrhagic complications after laparoscopic sleeve gastrectomy: four-year experience of a bariatric center of excellence. Surg Endosc. 2017;31(9):3547–51.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00464-016-5383-y</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fecso AB, Samuel T, Elnahas A, Sockalingam S, Jackson T, Quereshy F, et al. Clinical indicators of postoperative bleeding in bariatric surgery. Surg Laparoscop Endoscop Percutaneous Techniques. 2018;28(1):52–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/SLE.0000000000000480</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goel R, Nasta AM, Goel M, Prasad A, Jammu G, Fobi M, et al. Complications after bariatric surgery: a multicentric study of 11,568 patients from Indian bariatric surgery outcomes reporting group. J Minim Access Surg. 2021;17(2):213–20.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/jmas.JMAS_12_20</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Amirian H, Torquati A, Omotosho P. Racial disparity in 30-day outcomes of metabolic and bariatric surgery. Obes Surg. 2020;30(3):1011–20.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11695-019-04282-9</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Melissas J, Stavroulakis K, Tzikoulis V, Peristeri A, Papadakis JA, Pazouki A, et al. Sleeve gastrectomy vs Roux-en-Y gastric bypass. Data from IFSO-European Chapter Center of Excellence Program. Obesity Surg. 2017;27(4):847–55.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mocanu V, Dang J, Ladak F, Switzer N, Birch DW, Karmali S. Predictors and outcomes of bleed after sleeve gastrectomy: an analysis of the MBSAQIP data registry. Surg Obesity Relat Dis. 2019;15(10):1675–81.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.soard.2019.07.017</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zafar SN, Miller K, Felton J, Wise ES, Kligman M. Postoperative bleeding after laparoscopic Roux en Y gastric bypass: predictors and consequences. Surg Endosc. 2019;33(1):272–80.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00464-018-6365-z</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leeman M, Huisbrink J, Wijnand JMA, Biter LU, Verbrugge SJC, Dunkelgrun M, et al. Trial protocol: preoperative administration of tranexamic acid in sleeve gastrectomy (PATAS) to reduce haemorrhage rates. A randomised controlled trial. BMJ Open 2020;10(2):e034572.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Toolabi K, Golzarand M, Farid R. Laparoscopic Roux-en-Y gastric bypass and laparoscopic sleeve gastrectomy in terms of efficacy and safety: a comparative study during 11-year experience. Obes Surg. 2021;31(6):2489–96.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11695-021-05313-0</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>James PA, Oparil S, Carter BL, Cushman WC, Dennison-Himmelfarb C, Handler J, et al. 2014 evidence-based guideline for the management of high blood pressure in adults: report from the panel members appointed to the Eighth Joint National Committee (JNC 8). JAMA. 2014;311(5):507–20.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jama.2013.284427</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Patrzyk M, Sonke J, Glitsch A, Kessler R, Steveling A, Lünse S, et al. Gastric balloon implantation as part of morbid adiposity therapy changes the structure of the stomach wall. Visceral Med. 2021;37(5):418–25.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000514264</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dang JT, Switzer NJ, Sun WYL, Raghavji F, Birch DW, Karmali S. Evaluating the safety of intragastric balloon: an analysis of the Metabolic and Bariatric Surgery Accreditation and Quality Improvement Program. Surg Obesity Relat Dis. 2018;14(9):1340–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.soard.2018.05.003</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Susmallian S, Danoch R, Raskin B, Raziel A, Barnea R, Dvora P. Assessing bleeding risk in bariatric surgeries: a retrospective analysis study. Digest Dis (Basel, Switzerland). 2020;38(6):449–57.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000506456</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Castro A, Cassinello N, Alfonso R, Ortega J. Preoperative risk factors for early hemorrhagic complications in bariatric surgery: a case-control study. Surg Endosc. 2021;36(1):430–4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00464-021-08302-7</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Janik MR, Walędziak M, Brągoszewski J, Kwiatkowski A, Paśnik K. Prediction model for hemorrhagic complications after laparoscopic sleeve gastrectomy: development of SLEEVE BLEED calculator. Obes Surg. 2017;27(4):968–72.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11695-016-2417-4</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Javanainen MH, Scheinin T, Mustonen H, Leivonen M. Retrospective analysis of 3 different antithrombotic prophylaxis regimens in bariatric surgery. Surg Obesity Relat Dis. 2016;12(3):675–80.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.soard.2015.12.017</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gagner M, Buchwald JN. Comparison of laparoscopic sleeve gastrectomy leak rates in four staple-line reinforcement options: a systematic review. Surg Obesity Relat Dis. 2014;10(4):713–23.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.soard.2014.01.016</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gagner M, Kemmeter P. Comparison of laparoscopic sleeve gastrectomy leak rates in five staple-line reinforcement options: a systematic review. Surg Endosc. 2020;34(1):396–407.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00464-019-06782-2</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Demeusy A, Sill A, Averbach A. Current role of staple line reinforcement in 30-day outcomes of primary laparoscopic sleeve gastrectomy: an analysis of MBSAQIP data, 2015–2016 PUF. Surg Obesity Relat Dis. 2018;14(10):1454–61.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.soard.2018.06.024</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Özgen G, Çalıkoğlu İ, Acunaş B, Yerdel MA. Staple-line reinforcement using barbed sutures in 1008 sleeve gastrectomies. Langenbeck’s Arch Surg. 2021;406(5):1683–90.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00423-021-02161-5</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Banescu B, Balescu I, Copaescu C. Postoperative bleeding risk after sleeve gastrectomy. a two techniques of stapled line reinforcement comparative study in 4996 patients. Chirurgia (Bucharest, Romania: 1990). 2019;114(6):693–703.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Taha O, Abdelaal M, Talaat M, Abozeid M. A randomized comparison between staple-line oversewing versus no reinforcement during laparoscopic vertical sleeve gastrectomy. Obes Surg. 2018;28(1):218–25.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11695-017-2835-y</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu C, Wang FG, Yan WM, Yan M, Song MM. Is there necessity for oversewing the staple line during laparoscopic sleeve gastrectomy? An updated systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. J Investig Surg. 2020;33(9):839–50.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/08941939.2019.1665380</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Borjas G, Gonzalez M, Maldonado A, Urdaneta A, Ramos E. Oversewing staple line of the gastric remnant in gastric bypass reduces postoperative bleeding. Annals Med Surg. 2021;67:102534.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mojkowska A, Gazdzinski S, Fraczek M, Wyleżoł M. Gastric ulcer hemorrhage - a potential life-threatening complication of intragastric balloon treatment of obesity. Obes Facts. 2017;10(2):153–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000456666</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reed L, Edriss H, Nugent K. Gastric ulceration and bleeding with hemodynamic instability caused by an intragastric balloon for weight loss. Clin Endoscop. 2018;51(6):584–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5946/ce.2018.038</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tate CM, Geliebter A. Intragastric balloon treatment for obesity: FDA safety updates. Adv Ther. 2018;35(1):1–4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12325-017-0647-z</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
