<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35470926</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>26</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1099-1573</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Apr</Month>
              <Day>26</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Phytotherapy research : PTR</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Phytother Res</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Synergistic effects of Nepeta menthoides and Melissa officinalis aqueous extracts on reserpine-induced depressive-like behaviors in mice.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ptr.7457</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Nepeta menthoides Boiss. &amp; Buhse and Melissa officinalis are extensively used in Persian medicine for the treatment of depression. Considering the active ingredients and main phenolic compounds of these plants and possible synergistic effects, this study examined the antidepressant and antioxidant activities of aqueous extract of N. menthoides (NM) and M. officinalis (MO) in reserpinized mice alone and combination. Mice were pretreated orally for 1-week with normal saline (10 ml/kg), fluoxetine (20 mg/kg), imipramine (10 mg/kg), NM (50-100-200-400 mg/kg), MO (150-350-550-750 mg/kg), and combination (NM 50 with MO 150 mg/kg). The behavioral changes were evaluated using forced swim, tail suspension, and open field tests, 24 hr after reserpine injection (4 mg/kg) on eighth day. The amounts of active components in the extracts and catalase (CAT) as a brain oxidative stress were measured with enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay. Data showed that this combination produced a synergistic action on behaviors and a significant increase in CAT activity. High-performance liquid chromatography results showed that rosmarinic acid contents in MO and NM were 6.42 ± 1.1 and 11.03 ± 2.16 mg/g of dried extract, respectively. Total flavonoid and phenolic contents of MO were higher than NM. The findings suggest that the present combination produces an antidepressant-like effect, which is possibly triggered by its antioxidant properties.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Talebi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sedighe</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5321-1042</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Traditional Persian Medicine, School of Medicine, Shahed University, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Rahmati</LastName>
            <ForeName>Batool</ForeName>
            <Initials>B</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Physiology, Faculty of Medicine, Shahed University, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Jorjani</LastName>
            <ForeName>Masoumeh</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4790-4747</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Neurobiology Research Center and Department of Pharmacology , Faculty of Medicine, Shahid Beheshti University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Emadi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Fatemeh</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Traditional Persian Medicine, School of Medicine, Shahed University, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Traditional Medicine Clinical Trial Research Center, Shahed University, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ghaffari</LastName>
            <ForeName>Farzaneh</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Traditional Medicine, Shahid Beheshti University of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Naseri</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mohsen</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9239-768X</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Traditional Persian Medicine, School of Medicine, Shahed University, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Traditional Medicine Clinical Trial Research Center, Shahed University, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Hikmat, Islamic and Traditional Medicine Department, The Academy of Medical Sciences, Tehran, Iran.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>04</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Phytother Res</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8904486</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0951-418X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Melissa officinalis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nepeta menthoides</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Persian medicine</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">antidepressant effects</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">catalase activity</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacological synergy</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
          <Hour>8</Hour>
          <Minute>53</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35470926</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ptr.7457</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aghili Khorasani, M. (2011). Makhzan al-Advieh. Tehran, Iran: Sabzara Press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Araj-Khodaei, M., Noorbala, A. A., Yarani, R., Emadi, F., Emaratkar, E., Faghihzadeh, S., &amp; Naseri, M. (2020). A double-blind, randomized pilot study for comparison of Melissa officinalis L. and Lavandula angustifolia Mill. with fluoxetine for the treatment of depression. BMC Complementary Medicine and Therapies, 20(1), 1-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Avicenna, A. A. H. (2005). Al-Qanon fi al-Tibb (the canon on medicine.) (Vol. 2). Beirut, Lebanon: Dare Ehyae al-Torathe al-Arabi.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beardslee, W. R., Solantaus, T. S., Morgan, B. S., Gladstone, T. R., &amp; Kowalenko, N. M. (2012). Preventive interventions for children of parents with depression: International perspectives. Medical Journal of Australia, 196(7), 23-25. https://doi.org/10.5694/mjao11.11289</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bhatt, S., Nagappa, A. N., &amp; Patil, C. R. (2020). Role of oxidative stress in depression. Drug Discovery Today, 25(7), 1270-1276.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bolandghamat, S., Moghimi, A., &amp; Iranshahi, M. (2011). Effects of ethanolic extract of pine needles (Pinus eldarica Medw.) on reserpine-induced depression-like behavior in male Wistar rats. Pharmacognosy Magazine, 7(27), 248-253.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bradford, N. (1976). A rapid and sensitive method for the quantitation microgram quantities of a protein isolated from red cell membranes. Analytical Biochemistry, 72(248), e254.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brera, C., Grossi, S., De Santis, B., &amp; Miraglia, M. (2003). Automated HPLC method for the determination of ochratoxin a in wine samples. Journal of Liquid Chromatography &amp; Related Technologies, 26(1), 119-133.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Can, Ö. D., Özkay, Ü. D., &amp; Üçel, U. İ. (2013). Anti-depressant-like effect of vitexin in BALB/c mice and evidence for the involvement of monoaminergic mechanisms. European Journal of Pharmacology, 699(1-3), 250-257.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Council, N. R. (2010). Guide for the care and use of laboratory animals.Washington DC: National academies press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Daly, M., Sutin, A. R., &amp; Robinson, E. (2021). Depression reported by US adults in 2017-2018 and march and April 2020. Journal of Affective Disorders, 278, 131-135.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dastmalchi, K., Dorman, H. D., Oinonen, P. P., Darwis, Y., Laakso, I., &amp; Hiltunen, R. (2008). Chemical composition and in vitro antioxidative activity of a lemon balm (Melissa officinalis L.) extract. LWT-Food Science and Technology, 41(3), 391-400. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.lwt.2007.03.007</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deng, P., Pang, Z.-P., Lei, Z., Shikano, S., Xiong, Q., Harvey, B. K., … Xu, Z. C. (2011). Up-regulation of A-type potassium currents protects neurons against cerebral ischemia. Journal of Cerebral Blood Flow &amp; Metabolism, 31(9), 1823-1835.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dimmitt, S., Stampfer, H., &amp; Martin, J. H. (2017). When less is more-efficacy with less toxicity at the ED50. British Journal of Clinical Pharmacology, 83(7), 1365-1368. https://doi.org/10.1111/bcp.13281</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dzhavadian, O. M. (2020). The impact of social advertising on mental health of population. Mental Health: Global Challenges Journal, 3(2), 4-5. https://doi.org/10.32437/mhgcj.v4i2.95</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>El-Marasy, S. A., El Awdan, S. A., Hassan, A., Ahmed-Farid, O. A., &amp; Ogaly, H. A. (2021). Anti-depressant effect of cerebrolysin in reserpine-induced depression in rats: Behavioral, biochemical, molecular and immunohistochemical evidence. Chemico-Biological Interactions, 334, 109329.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Emamghoreishi, M., &amp; Talebianpour, M. (2015). Antidepressant effect of Melissa officinalis in the forced swimming test. DARU Journal of Pharmaceutical Sciences, 17(1), 42-47. http://194.225.220.118/index.php/daru/article/view/520</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fellah, F., Djenidi, R., &amp; Chebout, I. (2020). Protective effect of Sphaerococcus coronopifolius crude extract in combination with bacillus Calmette-Guerin on ligature-induced depression in female Wistar rats. Psychiatry Investigation, 17(2), 130-139.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Feng, R., He, M. C., Li, Q., Liang, X. Q., Tang, D. Z., Zhang, J. L., … Zhang, Y. (2020). Phenol glycosides extract of Fructus Ligustri Lucidi attenuated depressive-like behaviors by suppressing neuroinflammation in hypothalamus of mice. Phytotherapy Research, 34(12), 3273-3286.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghazizadeh, J., Hamedeyazdan, S., Torbati, M., Farajdokht, F., Fakhari, A., Mahmoudi, J., … Sadigh-Eteghad, S. (2020). Melissa officinalis L. hydro-alcoholic extract inhibits anxiety and depression through prevention of central oxidative stress and apoptosis. Experimental Physiology, 105(4), 707-720.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hritcu, L., Ionita, R., Postu, P. A., Gupta, G. K., Turkez, H., Lima, T. C., &amp; de Sousa, D. P. (2017). Antidepressant flavonoids and their relationship with oxidative stress, Oxidative Medicine and Cellular Longevity, 2017, 1-18.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jalali, A., Firouzabadi, N., &amp; Zarshenas, M. M. (2021). Pharmacogenetic-based management of depression: Role of traditional Persian medicine. Phytotherapy Research, 35(9), 5031-5052.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Keck, M. E., Nicolussi, S., Spura, K., Blohm, C., Zahner, C., &amp; Drewe, J. (2020). Effect of the fixed combination of valerian, lemon balm, passionflower, and butterbur extracts (Ze 185) on the prescription pattern of benzodiazepines in hospitalized psychiatric patients-A retrospective case-control investigation. Phytotherapy Research, 34(6), 1436-1445.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khan, H., Perviz, S., Sureda, A., Nabavi, S. M., &amp; Tejada, S. (2018). Current standing of plant derived flavonoids as an antidepressant. Food and Chemical Toxicology, 119, 176-188.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khurana, K., &amp; Bansal, N. (2019). Lacidipine attenuates reserpine-induced depression-like behavior and oxido-nitrosative stress in mice. Naunyn-Schmiedeberg's Archives of Pharmacology, 392(10), 1265-1275.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kpemissi, M., Metowogo, K., Melila, M., Veerapur, V. P., Negru, M., Taulescu, M., &amp; Aklikokou, K. (2020). Acute and subchronic oral toxicity assessments of Combretum micranthum (Combretaceae) in Wistar rats. Toxicology Reports, 7, 162-168.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lin, S.-H., Chou, M.-L., Chen, W.-C., Lai, Y.-S., Lu, K.-H., Hao, C.-W., &amp; Sheen, L.-Y. (2015). A medicinal herb, Melissa officinalis L. ameliorates depressive-like behavior of rats in the forced swimming test via regulating the serotonergic neurotransmitter. Journal of Ethnopharmacology, 175, 266-272.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Memariani, Z., Rahimi, A., Farzaei, M. H., &amp; Nejad, N. Z. (2019). Nepeta menthoides Boiss. &amp; Buhse, an endemic species in Iran: A review of traditional uses, phytochemistry and pharmacology. Journal of Herbmed Pharmacology, 8(3), 194-204.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mirghafourvand, M., Malakouti, J., Mohammad, A. C. S., Farshbaf, K. A., &amp; Ghanbari, H. S. (2016). The effects of lemon balm (Melissa officinalis L.) alone and in combination with nepeta menthoides on the menstrual bleeding in students with premenstrual syndrome: A randomized controlled trial. Iranian Red Crescent Medical Journal, 18(12), 142-148.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mirza, F. J., Amber, S., Hassan, D., Ahmed, T., &amp; Zahid, S. (2021). Rosmarinic acid and ursolic acid alleviate deficits in cognition, synaptic regulation and adult hippocampal neurogenesis in an Aβ1-42-induced mouse model of Alzheimer's disease. Phytomedicine, 83, 153490.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mozaffarpur, S. A., Naseri, M., Kamalinejad, M., Shams, M. A., Memariani, Z., Moeini, R., &amp; Shirafkan, H. (2020). Nine steps to discover new medicines from traditional sources: The example of Persian medicine. The Journal of Alternative and Complementary Medicine, 26(5), 365-368.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nair, A. B., &amp; Jacob, S. (2016). A simple practice guide for dose conversion between animals and human. Journal of Basic and Clinical Pharmacy, 7(2), 27-31.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Naseri, V., Chavoshzadeh, Z., Mizani, A., Daneshfard, B., Ghaffari, F., Abbas-Mohammadi, M., &amp; Naseri, M. (2021). Effect of topical marshmallow (Althaea officinalis) on atopic dermatitis in children: A pilot double-blind active-controlled clinical trial of an in-silico-analyzed phytomedicine. Phytotherapy Research, 35(3), 1389-1398.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ozerov, A., Bagmetova, V., Chernysheva, Y. V., &amp; Tyurenkov, I. (2016). Comparison of the efficiency of adeprophen and antidepressants of various groups on the model of reserpine-induced depression in rats. Bulletin of Experimental Biology and Medicine, 160(5), 649-652.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pagano, E., Iannotti, F. A., Piscitelli, F., Romano, B., Lucariello, G., Venneri, T., &amp; Borrelli, F. (2021). Efficacy of combined therapy with fish oil and phytocannabinoids in murine intestinal inflammation. Phytotherapy Research, 35(1), 517-529.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Park, H. J., Baik, H. J., Kim, D. Y., Lee, G. Y., Woo, J. H., Zuo, Z., &amp; Chung, R. K. (2015). Doxepin and imipramine but not fluoxetine reduce the activity of the rat glutamate transporter EAAT3 expressed in Xenopus oocytes. BMC Anesthesiology, 15(1), 1-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Porsolt, R. D., Le Pichon, M., &amp; Jalfre, M. (1977). Depression: A new animal model sensitive to antidepressant treatments. Nature, 266(5604), 730-732.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rahbardar, M. G., &amp; Hosseinzadeh, H. (2020). Effects of rosmarinic acid on nervous system disorders: An updated review. Naunyn-Schmiedeberg's Archives of Pharmacology, 393(10), 1779-1795.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ranjbar, M., Firoozabadi, A., Salehi, A., Ghorbanifar, Z., Zarshenas, M. M., Sadeghniiat-Haghighi, K., &amp; Rezaeizadeh, H. (2018). Effects of herbal combination (Melissa officinalis L. and Nepeta menthoides Boiss. &amp; Buhse) on insomnia severity, anxiety and depression in insomniacs: Randomized placebo controlled trial. Integrative Medicine Research, 7(4), 328-332.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raval, K., &amp; Patel, H. (2020). Review on common observed HPLC troubleshooting problems. International Journal of Pharma Research and Health Sciences, 8(4), 3195-3202.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Réus, G. Z., Stringari, R. B., de Souza, B., Petronilho, F., Dal-Pizzol, F., Hallak, J. E., &amp; Quevedo, J. (2010). Harmine and imipramine promote antioxidant activities in prefrontal cortex and hippocampus. Oxidative Medicine and Cellular Longevity, 3(5), 325-331.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rezaei, F., Rahmati, B., Malakian, M., Khalili, M., &amp; Alizadeh, M. (2020). The effects of swimming exercise and Nepeta menthoides on depression and anxiety induced by reserpine. Journal of Basic and Clinical Pathophysiology, 8(1), 42-46. https://doi.org/10.22070/jbcp.2020.4949.1123</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salehi-Sadaghiani, M., Javadi-Paydar, M., Gharedaghi, M. H., Zandieh, A., Heydarpour, P., Yousefzadeh-Fard, Y., &amp; Dehpour, A. R. (2012). NMDA receptor involvement in antidepressant-like effect of pioglitazone in the forced swimming test in mice. Psychopharmacology, 223(3), 345-355.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shakeri, A., Sahebkar, A., &amp; Javadi, B. (2016). Melissa officinalis L. A review of its traditional uses, phytochemistry and pharmacology. Journal of Ethnopharmacology, 188, 204-228. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jep.2016.05.010</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sullivan, G. M., &amp; Feinn, R. (2012). Using effect size or why the P value is not enough. Journal of Graduate Medical Education, 4(3), 279-282.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Takeda, H., Tsuji, M., Inazu, M., Egashira, T., &amp; Matsumiya, T. (2002). Rosmarinic acid and caffeic acid produce antidepressive-like effect in the forced swimming test in mice. European Journal of Pharmacology, 449(3), 261-267.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tian, J.-S., Cui, Y.-L., Hu, L.-M., Gao, S., Chi, W., Dong, T.-J., &amp; Liu, L.-P. (2010). Antidepressant-like effect of genipin in mice. Neuroscience Letters, 479(3), 236-239.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tonekaboni, S. M. M. (2007). Tohfat-ol-momenin. Tehran: Nashr-e Shahr.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yan, T., Wang, N., Liu, B., Wu, B., Xiao, F., He, B., &amp; Jia, Y. (2021). Schisandra chinensis ameliorates depressive-like behaviors by regulating microbiota-gut-brain axis via its anti-inflammation activity. Phytotherapy Research, 35(1), 289-296.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zheng, M., Fan, Y., Shi, D., &amp; Liu, C. (2013). Antidepressant-like effect of flavonoids extracted from Apocynum venetum leaves on brain monoamine levels and dopaminergic system. Journal of Ethnopharmacology, 147(1), 108-113.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhou, X., Seto, S. W., Chang, D., Kiat, H., Razmovski-Naumovski, V., Chan, K., &amp; Bensoussan, A. (2016). Synergistic effects of Chinese herbal medicine: A comprehensive review of methodology and current research. Frontiers in Pharmacology, 7, 201.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
