<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35470331</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>27</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>01</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1538-8662</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>47</Volume>
            <Issue>5</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>01</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>The Nurse practitioner</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Nurse Pract</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>How NPs can eliminate practice barriers to intrauterine device use.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>22</StartPage>
          <EndPage>30</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>22-30</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/01.NPR.0000827120.41973.df</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Barriers to intrauterine device use include cost, absence of qualified providers, the lack of simplified insertion protocols, cultural hesitation, and misconceptions of appropriateness of use. This article outlines how NPs can eliminate practice barriers to intrauterine device use and prevent unintended pregnancy.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bach</LastName>
            <ForeName>Susan</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Heavey</LastName>
            <ForeName>Elizabeth</ForeName>
            <Initials>E</Initials>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Nurse Pract</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>7603663</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0361-1817</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007434" MajorTopicYN="Y">Intrauterine Devices</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011247" MajorTopicYN="N">Pregnancy</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>59</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35470331</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/01.NPR.0000827120.41973.df</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">00006205-202205000-00006</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pregnancy Risk Assessment Monitoring System. 2019. www.cdc.gov/prams/index.htm.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Runyan A, Welch RA, Kramer KJ, et al. Long-acting reversible contraception: placement, continuation, and removal rates at an inner-city Academic Medical Center Clinic. J Clin Med. 2021;10(9). doi:10.3390/jcm10091918.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Foster DG. Dramatic decreases in US abortion rates: public health achievement or failure. Am J Public Health. 2017;107(12):1860–1862. doi:10.2105/AJPH.2017.304152.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Finer LB, Zolna MR. Declines in unintended pregnancy in the United States, 2008-2011. N Engl J Med. 2016;374(9):843–852. doi:10.1056/NEJMsa1506575.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Healthy People 2030. Reduce the proportion of unintended pregnancies — FP-01. https://health.gov/healthypeople/objectives-and-data/browse-objectives/family-planning/reduce-proportion-unintended-pregnancies-fp-01.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Diamond-Smith N, Logan R, Marshall C, et al. COVID-19's impact on contraception experiences: Exacerbation of structural inequities in women's health. Contraception. 2021;104(6):600–605. doi:10.1016/j.contraception.2021.08.011</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. Contraception. 2020. www.cdc.gov/reproductivehealth/contraception/index.htm.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hubacher D, Kavanaugh M. Historical record-setting trends in IUD use in the United States. Contraception. 2018;98(6):467–470. doi:10.1016/j.contraception.2018.05.016.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hopkins K, Hubert C, Coleman-Minahan K, et al. Unmet demand for short-acting hormonal and long-acting reversible contraception among community college students in Texas. J Am Coll Health. 2018;66(5):360–368. www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/07448481.2018.1431901?journalCode=vach20.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/07448481.2018.1431901?journalCode=vach20</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Winner B, Peipert JF, Zhao Q, et al. Effectiveness of long-acting reversible contraception. N Engl J Med. 2012;366(21):1998–2007.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Newland JA. Addressing the social determinants of health. Nurse Pract. 2021;46(12):6. doi:10.1097/01.NPR.0000798252.52511.96.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nurse Practitioners in Women's Health. Structural racism and implicit bias in women's healthcare. 2020. www.npwh.org/lms/filebrowser/file?fileName=Structural%20Racism%20Implicit%20Bias%20in%20Women%27s%20Healthcare%20Nov2020.pdf.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>National Academies of Sciences, Engineering and Medicine. The Future of Nursing 2020-2030: Charting a Path to Achieve Health Equity. Washington, DC: The National Academic Press; 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Julian Z, Robles D, Whetstone S, et al. Community-informed models of perinatal and reproductive health services provision: a justice-centered paradigm toward equity among Black birthing communities. Semin Perinatol. 2020;44(5):151267. doi:10.1016/j.semperi.2020.151267.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hardeman RR, Karbeah J, Kozhimannil KB. Applying a critical race lens to relationship-centered care in pregnancy and childbirth: an antidote to structural racism. Birth. 2020;47(1):3–7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Turok DK, Gero A, Simmons RG, et al. Levonorgestrel vs. copper intrauterine devices for emergency contraception. N Engl J Med. 2021;384:335–344. doi:10.1056/NEJMoa2022141.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mirena [package insert]. Whippany, NJ: Bayer HealthCare Pharmaceuticals Inc.; 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>What are the types of IUDs? Planned parenthood. 2021. www.plannedparenthood.org/learn/birth-control/IUD.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ritchie J, Phelan N, Briggs P. Intrauterine contraception. Ostet Gynecol. 2021;23(3):187–195. doi:10.1111/tog.12743.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hatcher RA, Haddad L, Zieman M. Managing Contraception. 15th ed. Bridging the Gap Foundation; 2019.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paragard Adverse Reactions. https://hcp.paragard.com/safety.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Committee opinion: immediate postpartum long-acting reversible contraception. 2021. www.acog.org/clinical/clinical-guidance/committee-opinion/articles/2016/08/immediate-postpartum-long-acting-reversible-contraception.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Psyche V. Outcomes of immediate postpartum intrauterine contraceptive device. Int J Gynaecol Obstet. 2021;128(S2):245–255. doi:10.1111/1471-0528.20_16715.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Averbach SH, Ermias Y, Jeng G, et al. Expulsion of intrauterine devices after postpartum placement by timing of placement, delivery type, and intrauterine device type: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2020;223(2):177–188. doi:10.1016/j.ajog.2020.02.045.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dewan R, Bharti N, Mittal A, Dewan A. Early IUD insertion after medically induced abortion. Eur J Contracept Reprod Health Care. 2018;23(3):231–236. doi:10.1080/13625187.2018.1473569</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haeger KO, Lamme J, Cleland K. State of emergency contraception in the U.S., 2018. Contracept Reprod Med. 2018;3:20. doi:10.1186/s40834-018-0067-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abma JC, Martinez GM. Sexual activity and contraceptive use among teenagers in the United States, 2011-2015. Natl Health Stat Rep. 2017;(104):1–23.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>US Selected Practice Recommendations (US SPR) for contraceptive use, 2016. www.cdc.gov/reproductivehealth/contraception/mmwr/spr/summary.html.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lambright T, Shapiro NA. The art of managing long-acting reversible contraception for teens: hormonal and nonhormonal intrauterine devices and hormonal implants have been proven safe and effective for adolescent patients. Clin Advis. 2020;23(8).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Adolescents and long-acting reversible contraception: implants and intrauterine devices. Committee Opinion. ACOG. 2018;735. www.acog.org/clinical/clinical-guidance/committee-opinion/articles/2018/05/adolescents-and-long-acting-reversible-contraception-implants-and-intrauterine-devices.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Esposito CP. Intrauterine device initiation after gonococcal and chlamydial infections: a practice workflow initiative. J Nurse Pract. 2021;17(7):803–807. doi:10.1016/j.nurpra.2021.03.012.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang Y, Sheth S, Weidner AKH, Egwuatu P, Webb L, Shih G. Immediate postpartum IUD training within a regional network of family medicine residencies. PRiMER. 2021;5:24. doi:10.22454/PRiMER.2021.421778.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Girum T, Wasie A. Return of fertility after discontinuation of contraception: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Contracept Reprod Med. 2018;3:9. doi:10.1186/s40834-018-0064-y.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kebodeaux CA, Schwartz BI. Experience with intrauterine device insertion in never sexually active adolescents: a retrospective cohort study. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2018;219(6):600.e1–600.e7. doi:10.1016/j.ajog.2018.09.033.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dawn S. Does the IUD cause PID and infertility. Verywell health. 2020. www.verywellhealth.com/does-the-IUD-cause-pid-and-infertility-906762.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rowlands S, Oloto E, Horwell DH. Intrauterine devices and risk of uterine perforation: current perspectives. Open Access J Contracept. 2016;7:19–32. doi:10.2147/OAJC.S85546.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jatlaoui TC, Whiteman MK, Jeng G, et al. Intrauterine device expulsion after postpartum placement: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Obstet Gynecol. 2018;132(4):895–905. doi:10.1097/AOG.0000000000002822.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ramos-Rivera M, Averbach S, Selvaduray P, Gibson A, Ngo LL. Complications after interval postpartum intrauterine device insertion. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2022;226(1):95.e1–95.e8. doi:10.1016/j.ajog.2021.08.028.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gilliam ML, Jensen JT, Eisenberg DL, Thomas MA, Olariu A, Creinin MD. Relationship of parity and prior cesarean delivery to levonorgestrel 52 mg intrauterine system expulsion over 6 years. Contraception. 2021;103(6):444–449. doi:10.1016/j.contraception.2021.02.013.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang J, Sasamoto N, Babic A, et al. Intrauterine device use and risk of ovarian cancer: results from the New England Case-Control study and Nurses' Health Studies. Int J Cancer. 2021;149(1):75–83. doi:10.1002/ijc.33531.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaiser Family Foundation. Medicaid Coverage of family planning benefits: findings from a 2021 state survey. www.kff.org/womens-health-policy/report/medicaid-coverage-of-family-planning-benefits-findings-from-a-2021-state-survey/.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heisel E, Kolenic GE, Moniz MM, et al. Intrauterine device insertion before and after mandated health care coverage: the importance of baseline costs. Obstet Gynecol. 2018;131(5):843–849. doi:10.1097/AOG.0000000000002567.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Curtis KM, Tepper NK, Jatlaoui TC, Whiteman MK. Removing medical barriers to contraception – evidence-based recommendations from the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, 2016. Contraception. 2016;94(6):579–581. doi:10.1016/j.contraception.2016.08.007.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hatcher RA. Contraceptive Technology, 21st Edition. New York, NY: Ayer Company publishers, Inc.; 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>IUD Placement. 2021. www.acog.org/education-and-events/creog/curriculum-resources/cases-in-high-value-care/IUD-placement.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
