<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35485414</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>16</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2042-6984</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Apr</Month>
              <Day>29</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>International forum of allergy &amp; rhinology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Int Forum Allergy Rhinol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Outcomes of endoscopic endonasal resection of pediatric craniopharyngiomas.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/alr.23009</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Craniopharyngiomas have traditionally been treated via open transcranial approaches. More recent, endoscopic endonasal approaches have been increasingly used; however, there has been limited evaluation of long-term outcomes for this approach.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A retrospective review was performed to analyze patients with pediatric craniopharyngioma undergoing endonasal endoscopic resection from 2012 to 2020. Demographic information, clinicopathologic factors, and outcomes including follow-up and recurrences were analyzed.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">All 42 patients, with a mean age of 8.0 years, were included. The median follow-up time was 49 months. Mean tumor diameter was 3.6 cm. All of the tumors had sellar and suprasellar components. The most common presenting symptoms were headaches (64.3%), visual changes (59.5%), and nausea/vomiting (38.1%). Most patients (73.3%) had resolution of their presenting symptoms by their first postoperative visit. Vision improved or remained normal in 69.0% of patients. Postoperatively, incidence of panhypopituitarism or diabetes insipidus developed in 89.7% and 77.8% of patients, respectively. The postoperative cerebrospinal fluid leak rate was 7.1%. The recurrence rate was 9.5%.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Endoscopic endonasal resection for pediatric craniopharyngiomas can achieve high rates of resection with low rates of disease recurrence when compared with the outcomes of open transcranial resection reported in the literature. However, hypothalamic-pituitary dysfunction remains a significant postoperative morbidity in both approaches.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 ARS-AAOA, LLC.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Patel</LastName>
            <ForeName>Tapan D</ForeName>
            <Initials>TD</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5347-0167</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Otorhinolaryngology-Head &amp; Neck Surgery, University of Pennsylvania, Health System, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Rullan-Oliver</LastName>
            <ForeName>Bianca</ForeName>
            <Initials>B</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9341-0126</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Otorhinolaryngology-Head &amp; Neck Surgery, University of Pennsylvania, Health System, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ungerer</LastName>
            <ForeName>Heather</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Otorhinolaryngology-Head &amp; Neck Surgery, University of Pennsylvania, Health System, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Storm</LastName>
            <ForeName>Phillip B</ForeName>
            <Initials>PB</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Neurosurgery, Children's Hospital of Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kohanski</LastName>
            <ForeName>Michael A</ForeName>
            <Initials>MA</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Otorhinolaryngology-Head &amp; Neck Surgery, University of Pennsylvania, Health System, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Adappa</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nithin D</ForeName>
            <Initials>ND</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Otorhinolaryngology-Head &amp; Neck Surgery, University of Pennsylvania, Health System, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Palmer</LastName>
            <ForeName>James N</ForeName>
            <Initials>JN</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Otorhinolaryngology-Head &amp; Neck Surgery, University of Pennsylvania, Health System, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>04</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Int Forum Allergy Rhinol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101550261</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2042-6976</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">endonasal</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">endoscopic</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">outcomes</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pediatric craniopharyngioma</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>43</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35485414</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/alr.23009</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Frank G, et al. The endoscopic extended transsphenoidal approach for craniopharyngiomas. Neurosurgery. 2006;59(1):75-83.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jagannathan J, et al. Pediatric sellar tumors: diagnostic procedures and management. Neurosurg Focus. 2005;18(6A):E6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rigante M, et al. Endoscopic transsphenoidal approach versus microscopic approach in children. Int J Pediatr Otorhinolaryngol. 2011;75(9):1132-1136.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stamm AC, Vellutini E, Balsalobre L. Craniopharyngioma. Otolaryngol Clin North Am. 2011;44(4):937-952. viii.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bunin GR, et al. The descriptive epidemiology of craniopharyngioma. J Neurosurg. 1998;89(4):547-551.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Campbell PG, et al. Endocrinological and ophthalmological consequences of an initial endonasal endoscopic approach for resection of craniopharyngiomas. Neurosurg Focus. 2010;28(4):E8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cappabianca P, et al. Extended endoscopic endonasal approach to the midline skull base: the evolving role of transsphenoidal surgery. Adv Tech Stand Neurosurg. 2008;33:151-199.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Divitiis E, et al. The role of the endoscopic transsphenoidal approach in pediatric neurosurgery. Childs Nerv Syst. 2000;16(10-11):692-696.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dehdashti AR, et al. Expanded endoscopic endonasal approach for anterior cranial base and suprasellar lesions: indications and limitations. Neurosurgery. 2009;64(4):677-687. Discussion 687-689.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Frazier JL, et al. Combined endoscopic and microscopic management of pediatric pituitary region tumors through one nostril: technical note with case illustrations. Childs Nerv Syst. 2008;24(12):1469-1478.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gardner PA, et al. Outcomes following endoscopic, expanded endonasal resection of suprasellar craniopharyngiomas: a case series. J Neurosurg. 2008;109(1):6-16.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jane JA Jr, et al. Early outcomes of endoscopic transsphenoidal surgery for adult craniopharyngiomas. Neurosurg Focus. 2010;28(4):E9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Patel VS, et al. Outcomes after endoscopic endonasal resection of craniopharyngiomas in the pediatric population. World Neurosurg. 2017;108:6-14.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Locatelli D, et al. Endoscopic endonasal transsphenoidal surgery for sellar tumors in children. Int J Pediatr Otorhinolaryngol. 2010;74(11):1298-1302.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alalade AF, et al. Suprasellar and recurrent pediatric craniopharyngiomas: expanding indications for the extended endoscopic transsphenoidal approach. J Neurosurg Pediatr. 2018;21(1):72-80.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ali ZS, et al. Suprasellar pediatric craniopharyngioma resection via endonasal endoscopic approach. Childs Nerv Syst. 2013;29(11):2065-2070.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen W, et al. Long-term impact of pediatric endoscopic endonasal skull base surgery on midface growth. J Neurosurg Pediatr. 2019;23(4):523-530.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giovannetti F, et al. Endoscopic endonasal skull base surgery in pediatric patients. a single center experience. J Craniomaxillofac Surg. 2018;46(12):2017-2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jane JA Jr, et al. The transsphenoidal resection of pediatric craniopharyngiomas: a case series. J Neurosurg Pediatr. 2010;5(1):49-60.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koutourousiou M, et al. Endoscopic endonasal surgery for craniopharyngiomas: surgical outcome in 64 patients. J Neurosurg. 2013;119(5):1194-1207.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kuan EC, et al. Lack of sphenoid pneumatization does not affect endoscopic endonasal pediatric skull base surgery outcomes. Laryngoscope. 2019;129(4):832-836.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Madsen PJ, et al. Endoscopic endonasal resection versus open surgery for pediatric craniopharyngioma: comparison of outcomes and complications. J Neurosurg Pediatr. 2019;1:1-10.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parasher AK, et al. The impact of expanded endonasal skull base surgery on midfacial growth in pediatric patients. Laryngoscope. 2020;130(2):338-342.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Soldozy S, et al. Endoscopic endonasal surgery outcomes for pediatric craniopharyngioma: a systematic review. Neurosurg Focus. 2020;48(1):E6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stapleton AL, et al. Risk factors for cerebrospinal fluid leak in pediatric patients undergoing endoscopic endonasal skull base surgery. Int J Pediatr Otorhinolaryngol. 2017;93:163-166.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yamada S, et al. Therapeutic outcomes of transsphenoidal surgery in pediatric patients with craniopharyngiomas: a single-center study. J Neurosurg Pediatr. 2018;21(6):549-562.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muller HL. Craniopharyngioma and hypothalamic injury: latest insights into consequent eating disorders and obesity. Curr Opin Endocrinol Diabetes Obes. 2016;23(1):81-89.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jeswani S, et al. Comparative analysis of outcomes following craniotomy and expanded endoscopic endonasal transsphenoidal resection of craniopharyngioma and related tumors: a single-institution study. J Neurosurg. 2016;124(3):627-638.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Albright AL, et al. Individualized treatment of pediatric craniopharyngiomas. Childs Nerv Syst. 2005;21(8-9):649-654.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elliott RE, Jane JA Jr, Wisoff JH. Surgical management of craniopharyngiomas in children: meta-analysis and comparison of transcranial and transsphenoidal approaches. Neurosurgery. 2011;69(3):630-643. Discussion 643.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim SK, et al. Radical excision of pediatric craniopharyngioma: recurrence pattern and prognostic factors. Childs Nerv Syst. 2001;17(9):531-536. Discussion 537.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Veeravagu A, et al. The role of radiosurgery in the treatment of craniopharyngiomas. Neurosurg Focus. 2010;28(4):E11.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zuccaro G, et al. Complications in paediatric craniopharyngioma treatment. Childs Nerv Syst. 1996;12(7):385-390. Discussion 390-391.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
