<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35481869</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>07</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1460-9568</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Apr</Month>
              <Day>28</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>The European journal of neuroscience</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Eur J Neurosci</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Circadian activities of the brain MNK-eIF4E signalling axis contribute to diurnal rhythms of some cognitive functions.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ejn.15678</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Although it is well recognized that the circadian timing system profoundly influences cognitive performance, the underlying molecular mechanisms remain poorly defined. Our previous work has found that the mitogen-activated protein kinase-interacting kinase (MNK)-eukaryotic translation initiation factor 4E (eIF4E) axis, a conserved cellular signalling pathway regulating mRNA translation, modulates the function of the suprachiasmatic nucleus (SCN), the master circadian clock. Here, with the use of a combination of genetic, biochemical and behavioural approaches, we investigated the distribution and temporal regulation of eIF4E phosphorylation in the brain and its role in regulating the diurnal oscillations of some aspects of cognition in mice. We found that activities of the MNK-eIF4E axis, as indicated by the level of eIF4E phosphorylation at Ser209, exhibited significant circadian oscillations in a variety of brain regions, including but not limited to the prefrontal cortex, the hippocampus, the amygdala and the cerebellum. Phosphorylated eIF4E was enriched in neurons but not in astrocytes or microglia. Mice lacking eIF4E phosphorylation (eIF4E<sup>S209A/S209A</sup> ) or the MNKs (Mnk<sup>1-/-,2-/-</sup> ), the kinases that phosphorylate eIF4E, exhibited impaired diurnal variations of novel object recognition, object location memory, Barnes maze learning and ambulatory activities. Together, these results suggest that circadian activities of the MNK-eIF4E axis contribute to the diurnal rhythms of some cognitive functions, highlighting a role for rhythmic translational control in circadian regulation of cognitive performance.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Authors. European Journal of Neuroscience published by Federation of European Neuroscience Societies and John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Liu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Dong</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences, University of Minnesota Medical School, Duluth, MN, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Li</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jin</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences, University of Minnesota Medical School, Duluth, MN, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Neuroscience and Translational Medicine, College of Life Science and Agronomy, Zhoukou Normal University, Zhoukou, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lin</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hao</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences, University of Minnesota Medical School, Duluth, MN, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lorsung</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ethan</ForeName>
            <Initials>E</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences, University of Minnesota Medical School, Duluth, MN, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Le</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nam</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences, University of Minnesota Medical School, Duluth, MN, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Singla</LastName>
            <ForeName>Rubal</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences, University of Minnesota Medical School, Duluth, MN, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mishra</LastName>
            <ForeName>Abhishek</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences, University of Minnesota Medical School, Duluth, MN, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Fukunaga</LastName>
            <ForeName>Rikiro</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biochemistry, Faculty of Pharmacy, Osaka Medical and Pharmaceutical University, Takatsuki, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Cao</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ruifeng</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5105-7726</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences, University of Minnesota Medical School, Duluth, MN, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neuroscience, University of Minnesota Medical School, Minneapolis, MN, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <GrantList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>R01 NS118026</GrantID>
            <Acronym>NS</Acronym>
            <Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>NS118026</GrantID>
            <Acronym>NH</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
        </GrantList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>04</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>France</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Eur J Neurosci</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8918110</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0953-816X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MNK</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">behaviour</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">circadian rhythm</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cognition</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">eIF4E</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mouse</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">phosphorylation</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
          <Hour>10</Hour>
          <Minute>39</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35481869</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ejn.15678</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aguilar-Valles, A., Haji, N., De Gregorio, D., Matta-Camacho, E., Eslamizade, M. J., Popic, J., Sharma, V., Cao, R., Rummel, C., Tanti, A., Wiebe, S., Nuñez, N., Comai, S., Nadon, R., Luheshi, G., Mechawar, N., Turecki, G., Lacaille, J. C., Gobbi, G., &amp; Sonenberg, N. (2018). Translational control of depression-like behavior via phosphorylation of eukaryotic translation initiation factor 4E. Nature Communications, 9(1), 2459. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-018-04883-5</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Amir, S., &amp; Stewart, J. (2009). Motivational modulation of rhythms of the expression of the clock protein PER2 in the limbic forebrain. Biological Psychiatry, 65(10), 829-834. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biopsych.2008.12.019</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Amorim, I. S., Kedia, S., Kouloulia, S., Simbriger, K., Gantois, I., Jafarnejad, S. M., Li, Y., Kampaite, A., Pooters, T., Romanò, N., &amp; Gkogkas, C. G. (2018). Loss of eIF4E phosphorylation engenders depression-like behaviors via selective mRNA translation. The Journal of Neuroscience, 38(8), 2118-2133. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.2673-17.2018</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bach, M. E., Hawkins, R. D., Osman, M., Kandel, E. R., &amp; Mayford, M. (1995). Impairment of spatial but not contextual memory in CaMKII mutant mice with a selective loss of hippocampal LTP in the range of the theta frequency. Cell, 81(6), 905-915. https://doi.org/10.1016/0092-8674(95)90010-1</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cain, S. W., Chalmers, J. A., &amp; Ralph, M. R. (2012). Circadian modulation of passive avoidance is not eliminated in arrhythmic hamsters with suprachiasmatic nucleus lesions. Behavioural Brain Research, 230(1), 288-290. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bbr.2012.02.022</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cain, S. W., &amp; Ralph, M. R. (2009). Circadian modulation of conditioned place avoidance in hamsters does not require the suprachiasmatic nucleus. Neurobiology of Learning and Memory, 91(1), 81-84. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nlm.2008.10.005</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cao, R., Butcher, G. Q., Karelina, K., Arthur, J. S., &amp; Obrietan, K. (2013). Mitogen- and stress-activated protein kinase 1 modulates photic entrainment of the suprachiasmatic circadian clock. The European Journal of Neuroscience, 37, 130-140. https://doi.org/10.1111/ejn.12028</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cao, R., Gkogkas, C. G., de Zavalia, N., Blum, I. D., Yanagiya, A., Tsukumo, Y., Xu, H., Lee, C., Storch, K. F., Liu, A. C., Amir, S., &amp; Sonenberg, N. (2015). Light-regulated translational control of circadian behavior by eIF4E phosphorylation. Nature Neuroscience, 18(6), 855-862. https://doi.org/10.1038/nn.4010</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chaudhury, D., &amp; Colwell, C. S. (2002). Circadian modulation of learning and memory in fear-conditioned mice. Behavioural Brain Research, 133, 95-108. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0166-4328(01)00471-5</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chaudhury, D., Wang, L. M., &amp; Colwell, C. S. (2005). Circadian regulation of hippocampal long-term potentiation. Journal of Biological Rhythms, 20(3), 225-236. https://doi.org/10.1177/0748730405276352</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Costa-Mattioli, M., Sossin, W. S., Klann, E., &amp; Sonenberg, N. (2009). Translational control of long-lasting synaptic plasticity and memory. Neuron, 61, 10-26. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2008.10.055</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dolci, C., Montaruli, A., Roveda, E., Barajon, I., Vizzotto, L., Grassi Zucconi, G., &amp; Carandente, F. (2003). Circadian variations in expression of the trkB receptor in adult rat hippocampus. Brain Research, 994(1), 67-72. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.brainres.2003.09.018</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dubruille, R., &amp; Emery, P. (2008). A plastic clock: How circadian rhythms respond to environmental cues in Drosophila. Molecular Neurobiology, 38, 129-145. https://doi.org/10.1007/s12035-008-8035-y</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eckel-Mahan, K. L. (2012). Circadian Oscillations within the Hippocampus Support Memory Formation and Persistence. Frontiers in Molecular Neuroscience, 5, 46. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnmol.2012.00046</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eckel-Mahan, K. L., Phan, T., Han, S., Wang, H., Chan, G. C., Scheiner, Z. S., &amp; Storm, D. R. (2008). Circadian oscillation of hippocampal MAPK activity and cAmp: Implications for memory persistence. Nature Neuroscience, 11(9), 1074-1082. https://doi.org/10.1038/nn.2174</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fernandez, F., Lu, D., Ha, P., Costacurta, P., Chavez, R., Heller, H. C., &amp; Ruby, N. F. (2014). Circadian rhythm. Dysrhythmia in the suprachiasmatic nucleus inhibits memory processing. Science, 346(6211), 854-857. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.1259652</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Furic, L., Rong, L., Larsson, O., Koumakpayi, I. H., Yoshida, K., Brueschke, A., Petroulakis, E., Robichaud, N., Pollak, M., Gaboury, L. A., Pandolfi, P. P., Saad, F., &amp; Sonenberg, N. (2010). eIF4E phosphorylation promotes tumorigenesis and is associated with prostate cancer progression. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 107(32), 14134-14139. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1005320107</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Genheden, M., Kenney, J. W., Johnston, H. E., Manousopoulou, A., Garbis, S. D., &amp; Proud, C. G. (2015). BDNF stimulation of protein synthesis in cortical neurons requires the MAP kinase-interacting kinase MNK1. The Journal of Neuroscience, 35, 972-984. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.2641-14.2015</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gerstner, J. R., &amp; Yin, J. C. (2010). Circadian rhythms and memory formation. Nature Reviews. Neuroscience, 11(8), 577-588. https://doi.org/10.1038/nrn2881</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gkogkas, C. G., Khoutorsky, A., Cao, R., Jafarnejad, S. M., Prager-Khoutorsky, M., Giannakas, N., Kaminari, A., Fragkouli, A., Nader, K., Price, T. J., Konicek, B. W., Graff, J. R., Tzinia, A. K., Lacaille, J. C., &amp; Sonenberg, N. (2014). Pharmacogenetic inhibition of eIF4E-dependent Mmp9 mRNA translation reverses fragile X syndrome-like phenotypes. Cell Reports, 9(5), 1742-1755. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.celrep.2014.10.064</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kandel, E. R., Dudai, Y., &amp; Mayford, M. R. (2014). The molecular and systems biology of memory. Cell, 157, 163-186. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cell.2014.03.001</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Karatsoreos, I. N., &amp; Silver, R. (2007). Minireview: The neuroendocrinology of the suprachiasmatic nucleus as a conductor of body time in mammals. Endocrinology, 148(12), 5640-5647. https://doi.org/10.1210/en.2007-1083</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krishnan, H. C., &amp; Lyons, L. C. (2015). Synchrony and desynchrony in circadian clocks: Impacts on learning and memory. Learning &amp; Memory, 22(9), 426-437. https://doi.org/10.1101/lm.038877.115</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martino, T. A., &amp; Harrington, M. E. (2020). The time for circadian medicine. Journal of Biological Rhythms, 35(5), 419-420. https://doi.org/10.1177/0748730420946501</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McMartin, L., Kiraly, M., Heller, H. C., Madison, D. V., &amp; Ruby, N. F. (2021). Disruption of circadian timing increases synaptic inhibition and reduces cholinergic responsiveness in the dentate gyrus. Hippocampus, 31, 422-434. https://doi.org/10.1002/hipo.23301</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mintz, E. M., Marvel, C. L., Gillespie, C. F., Price, K. M., &amp; Albers, H. E. (1999). Activation of NMDA receptors in the suprachiasmatic nucleus produces light-like phase shifts of the circadian clock in vivo. The Journal of Neuroscience, 19(12), 5124-5130. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.19-12-05124.1999</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moy, J. K., Khoutorsky, A., Asiedu, M. N., Black, B. J., Kuhn, J. L., Barragán-Iglesias, P., Megat, S., Burton, M. D., Burgos-Vega, C. C., Melemedjian, O. K., Boitano, S., Vagner, J., Gkogkas, C. G., Pancrazio, J. J., Mogil, J. S., Dussor, G., Sonenberg, N., &amp; Price, T. J. (2017). The MNK-eIF4E signaling Axis contributes to injury-induced nociceptive plasticity and the development of chronic pain. The Journal of Neuroscience, 37(31), 7481-7499. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.0220-17.2017</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nitabach, M. N., &amp; Taghert, P. H. (2008). Organization of the Drosophila circadian control circuit. Current Biology, 18, R84-R93. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cub.2007.11.061</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Panda, S. (2016). Circadian physiology of metabolism. Science, 354(6315), 1008-1015. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.aah4967</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paul, M. J., &amp; Schwartz, W. J. (2007). On the chronobiology of cohabitation. Cold Spring Harbor Symposia on Quantitative Biology, 72(1), 615-621. https://doi.org/10.1101/sqb.2007.72.042</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Phan, T. X., Chan, G. C., Sindreu, C. B., Eckel-Mahan, K. L., &amp; Storm, D. R. (2011). The diurnal oscillation of MAP (mitogen-activated protein) kinase and adenylyl cyclase activities in the hippocampus depends on the suprachiasmatic nucleus. The Journal of Neuroscience, 31(29), 10640-10647. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.6535-10.2011</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Prosser, R. A., McArthur, A. J., &amp; Gillette, M. U. (1989). cGMP induces phase shifts of a mammalian circadian pacemaker at night, in antiphase to cAMP effects. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 86(17), 6812-6815. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.86.17.6812</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Proud, C. G. (2007). Signalling to translation: How signal transduction pathways control the protein synthetic machinery. The Biochemical Journal, 403, 217-234. https://doi.org/10.1042/BJ20070024</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reppert, S. M., &amp; Weaver, D. R. (2002). Coordination of circadian timing in mammals. Nature, 418(6901), 935-941. https://doi.org/10.1038/nature00965</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Richter, J. D., &amp; Sonenberg, N. (2005). Regulation of cap-dependent translation by eIF4E inhibitory proteins. Nature, 433(7025), 477-480. https://doi.org/10.1038/nature03205</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ruby, N. F. (2021). Suppression of circadian timing and its impact on the Hippocampus. Frontiers in Neuroscience, 15, 642376. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnins.2021.642376</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Silver, R., &amp; Kriegsfeld, L. J. (2014). Circadian rhythms have broad implications for understanding brain and behavior. The European Journal of Neuroscience, 39(11), 1866-1880. https://doi.org/10.1111/ejn.12593</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smarr, B. L., Jennings, K. J., Driscoll, J. R., &amp; Kriegsfeld, L. J. (2014). A time to remember: The role of circadian clocks in learning and memory. Behavioral Neuroscience, 128, 283-303. https://doi.org/10.1037/a0035963</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Snider, K. H., Dziema, H., Aten, S., Loeser, J., Norona, F. E., Hoyt, K., &amp; Obrietan, K. (2016). Modulation of learning and memory by the targeted deletion of the circadian clock gene Bmal1 in forebrain circuits. Behavioural Brain Research, 308, 222-235. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bbr.2016.04.027</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tosini, G., Baba, K., Hwang, C. K., &amp; Iuvone, P. M. (2012). Melatonin: An underappreciated player in retinal physiology and pathophysiology. Experimental Eye Research, 103, 82-89. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.exer.2012.08.009</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ueda, T., Watanabe-Fukunaga, R., Fukuyama, H., Nagata, S., &amp; Fukunaga, R. (2004). Mnk2 and Mnk1 are essential for constitutive and inducible phosphorylation of eukaryotic initiation factor 4E but not for cell growth or development. Molecular and Cellular Biology, 24(15), 6539-6549. https://doi.org/10.1128/MCB.24.15.6539-6549.2004</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vogel-Ciernia, A., &amp; Wood, M. A. (2014). Examining object location and object recognition memory in mice. Current Protocols in Neuroscience, 69, 31-17. https://doi.org/10.1002/0471142301.ns0831s69</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang, L. M.-C., Dragich, J. M., Kudo, T., Odom, I. H., Welsh, D. K., O'Dell, T. J., &amp; Colwell, C. S. (2009). Expression of the Circadian Clock Gene Period2 in the Hippocampus: Possible Implications for Synaptic Plasticity and Learned Behaviour. ASN Neuro, 1(3), e00012. https://doi.org/10.1042/an20090020</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wardlaw, S. M., Phan, T. X., Saraf, A., Chen, X., &amp; Storm, D. R. (2014). Genetic disruption of the core circadian clock impairs hippocampus-dependent memory. Learning &amp; Memory, 21(8), 417-423. https://doi.org/10.1101/lm.035451.114</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Waskiewicz, A. J., Flynn, A., Proud, C. G., &amp; Cooper, J. A. (1997). Mitogen-activated protein kinases activate the serine/threonine kinases Mnk1 and Mnk2. The EMBO Journal, 16(8), 1909-1920. https://doi.org/10.1093/emboj/16.8.1909</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weil, Z. M., &amp; Nelson, R. J. (2014). Introduction to the special issue on circadian rhythms in behavioral neuroscience. Behavioral Neuroscience, 128(3), 237-239. https://doi.org/10.1037/a0036740</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
