<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35481315</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>30</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>14</Volume>
            <Issue>3</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Mar</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Cureus</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Antipsychotic Drug Utilization and Adverse Drug Reaction Profiling in Patients With Schizophrenia at a Tertiary Care Hospital in Western India.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e23378</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e23378</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e23378</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.23378</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Introduction Prescription pattern studies conducted in patients with schizophrenia have shown variability in the utilization of antipsychotics based on the geographical location of the study setting. Moreover, there is only a sparse number of studies specifically related to adverse drug reactions (ADRs) in schizophrenia. Hence, a need was felt to study the antipsychotic utilization pattern and adverse drug reactions in patients with schizophrenia in our setting. Methods This was a cross-sectional, observational study conducted at the psychiatry outpatient department (OPD) of a tertiary care hospital in India. Patients diagnosed to have schizophrenia as per the Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders, Fifth Edition (DSM-5) were included in the study provided they had been prescribed antipsychotic medications at the study center for at least three months. The sociodemographic profile of the patients and caregivers was recorded, and prescription pattern assessment was done using WHO core drug use indicators. Information related to ADRs was recorded, and further assessment was done based on the causality, severity, and preventability of ADRs. Results A total of 250 patients were enrolled in the study. Risperidone (40.25%) and olanzapine (26.32%) were the most commonly prescribed antipsychotic drugs, while trihexyphenidyl was the most frequently prescribed concomitant medication. Among the 37 cases of adverse drug reactions that were recorded, amenorrhea, sedation, and weight gain were found to be the most common. The majority of ADRs were of mild severity in addition to being non-preventable. Conclusion It was observed that atypical antipsychotics were commonly prescribed in the study center, and the majority of the ADRs were mild and not preventable, which shows the adequacy of prescribing practices in the current setting.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022, Tripathi et al.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tripathi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Raakhi K</ForeName>
            <Initials>RK</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Pharmacology and Therapeutics, Seth Gordhandas Sunderdas Medical College and King Edward Memorial Hospital, Mumbai, IND.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gajbhiye</LastName>
            <ForeName>Snehalata</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Pharmacology and Therapeutics, Seth Gordhandas Sunderdas Medical College and King Edward Memorial Hospital, Mumbai, IND.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Jalgaonkar</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sharmila</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Pharmacology and Therapeutics, Seth Gordhandas Sunderdas Medical College and King Edward Memorial Hospital, Mumbai, IND.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Khatri</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nishtha</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Pharmacology and Therapeutics, Seth Gordhandas Sunderdas Medical College and King Edward Memorial Hospital, Mumbai, IND.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sayyed</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mohsin</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Pharmacology and Therapeutics, Seth Gordhandas Sunderdas Medical College and King Edward Memorial Hospital, Mumbai, IND.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Parkar</LastName>
            <ForeName>Shubhangi</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Psychiatry, Seth Gordhandas Sunderdas Medical College and King Edward Memorial Hospital, Mumbai, IND.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">adverse drug reaction</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">antipsychotics</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cross-sectional</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">drug utilization</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">who indicators</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>38</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35481315</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9033527</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.23378</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lavretsky H. Clinical handbook of schizophrenia. New York, NY: Guilford Press; 2008. History of schizophrenia as a psychiatric disorder; pp. 3–13.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>American Psychiatric Association. Arlington, VA: American Psychiatric Publishing, Inc.; 2013. Diagnostic and statistical manual of mental disorders (5th edition)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Global epidemiology and burden of schizophrenia: findings from the Global Burden of Disease Study 2016. Charlson FJ, Ferrari AJ, Santomauro DF, et al.  Schizophr Bull. 2018;44:1195–1203.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6192504</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29762765</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Psychotropic prescriptions for the treatment of schizophrenia in an outpatient clinic. Okpataku CI, Tawani D. Trends Psychiatry Psychother. 2017;39:165–172.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28876362</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schizophrenia: psycho-social demographic profile and drug utilization study of anti-psychotics at a government medical teaching. Jyothi NU, Pradeep P, Kumar MV, Sandeep K, Ramadasu P, Rao N. https://www.wjpps.com/Wjpps_controller/abstract_id/3763 World J Pharm Pharm Sci. 2015;4:1036–1045.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Analysis of prescribing pattern and techniques of switching over of antipsychotics in outpatients of a tertiary care hospital in Delhi: a prospective, observational study. Kumar S, Chawla S, Bimba HV, Rana P, Dutta S, Kumar S. https://www.jbclinpharm.org/articles/analysis-of-prescribing-pattern-and-techniques-of-switching-over-of-antipsychotics-in-outpatients-of-a-tertiary-care-hospital-in-d.html J Basic Clin Pharma. 2017;8:178–184.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Atypical antipsychotics usage in long-term follow-up of first episode schizophrenia. Shrivastava A, Johnston M, Terpstra K, Stitt L, Shah N. Indian J Psychiatry. 2012;54:248–252.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3512362</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23226849</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Prescribing pattern of antipsychotic medications in patients with schizophrenia in a tertiary care hospital. Sushma HK, Jyothi CH, Somashekar HS, Avanthi E, Imran M, Raja B. https://www.ijbcp.com/index.php/ijbcp/article/view/878 Int J Basic Clin Pharmacol. 2015;4:134.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Adverse effects of atypical antipsychotics : differential risk and clinical implications. Haddad PM, Sharma SG. CNS Drugs. 2007;21:911–936.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17927296</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Adverse drug reactions associated with antipsychotics, antidepressants, mood stabilizers, and stimulants. Givens CJ. Nurs Clin North Am. 2016;51:309–321.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27229284</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Management of common adverse effects of antipsychotic medications. Stroup TS, Gray N. World Psychiatry. 2018;17:341–356.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6127750</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30192094</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Updating income ranges for Kuppuswamy's socio-economic status scale for the year 2014. Oberoi SS. Indian J Public Health. 2015;59:156–157.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26021657</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>World Health Organization: Guide to good prescribing.  [
Dec;
2020 
];https://apps.who.int/iris/bitstream/handle/10665/59001/WHO_DAP_94.11.pdf 2020 </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>A study of agreement between the Naranjo algorithm and WHO-UMC criteria for causality assessment of adverse drug reactions. Belhekar MN, Taur SR, Munshi RP. Indian J Pharmacol. 2014;46:117–120.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3912795</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24550597</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>An analysis of seriousness, predictability and preventability of adverse drug reactions reported at a tertiary care teaching hospital in Kerala, India: a retrospective observational record based study. Shajahan J, Parathoduvil AA, Purushothaman S. Int J Basic Clin Pharmacol. 2018;7</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Causality, severity and preventability assessment of adverse cutaneous drug reaction: a prospective observational study in a tertiary care hospital. Padmavathi S, Manimekalai K, Ambujam S. http://www.jcdr.net/article_fulltext.asp. J Clin Diagn Res. 2013;7:2765–2767.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3919327</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24551632</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Adverse drug reaction monitoring in psychiatry out-patient department of an Indian teaching hospital. Sengupta G, Bhowmick S, Hazra A, Datta A, Rahaman M. Indian J Pharmacol. 2011;43:36–39.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3062118</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21455419</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>A study on prescribing pattern of antipsychotics in schizophrenia at a tertiary care hospital. Nukala S, Komaram RB, Singisetti S. Int J Pharm Sci Res. 2019;10:2628–2632.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Antipsychotic polypharmacy in schizophrenia: benefits and risks. Barnes TR, Paton C. CNS Drugs. 2011;25:383–399.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21476610</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Drug utilization pattern in schizophrenia. Munjely EJ, R. BLN, Punnoose VP. Int J Basic Clin Pharmacol. 2019;8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oral versus long-acting injectable antipsychotics in the treatment of schizophrenia and special populations at risk for treatment nonadherence: a systematic review. Zhornitsky S, Stip E. Schizophr Res Treatment. 2012;2012:407171.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3420751</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22966436</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Investigating the relationship between consultation length and patient experience: a cross-sectional study in primary care. Elmore N, Burt J, Abel G, Maratos FA, Montague J, Campbell J, Roland M. Br J Gen Pract. 2016;66:0–903.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Efficacy of atypical v. typical antipsychotics in the treatment of early psychosis: meta-analysis. Crossley NA, Constante M, McGuire P, Power P. Br J Psychiatry. 2010;196:434–439.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2878818</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20513851</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Anti-psychotic prescription pattern: a preliminary survey of Psychiatrists in India. Grover S, Avasthi A. Indian J Psychiatry. 2010;52:257–259.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2990827</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21180412</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clinical practice guidelines for management of schizophrenia. Grover S, Chakrabarti S, Kulhara P, Avasthi A. Indian J Psychiatry. 2017;59:0–33.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Conformance to schizophrenia treatment guidelines in North West-Bank, Palestine: focus on antipsychotic dosing and polytherapy. Sweileh WM, Odeh JB, Zyoud SH, Sawalha AF, Ihbeasheh MS. BMC Psychiatry. 2013;13:179.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3700822</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23816223</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Irrational fixed dose combinations of psychotropic drugs in India: cause of concern. Solanki MS, Banwari G. Indian J Pharmacol. 2016;48:468–469.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4980945</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27756968</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Benefits and limits of anticholinergic use in schizophrenia: focusing on its effect on cognitive function. Ogino S, Miyamoto S, Miyake N, Yamaguchi N. Psychiatry Clin Neurosci. 2014;68:37–49.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24102938</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Adverse drug reactions and their impact on quality of life in patients on antipsychotic therapy at a tertiary care center in Delhi. Chawla S, Kumar S. Indian J Psychol Med. 2017;39:293–298.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5461839</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28615763</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
