<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35486167</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>29</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1432-1084</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Apr</Month>
              <Day>29</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>European radiology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Eur Radiol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Systematic review and meta-analysis of MRI features for differentiating autoimmune pancreatitis from pancreatic adenocarcinoma.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00330-022-08816-1</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To identify reliable MRI features for differentiating autoimmune pancreatitis (AIP) from pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma (PDAC) and to summarize their diagnostic accuracy.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We conducted a systematic literature review and meta-analysis using PubMed, EMBASE, and the Cochrane Library to identify original articles published between January 2006 and July 2021. The pooled diagnostic accuracy, including the diagnostic odds ratios (DORs) with 95% confidence intervals (CIs) of the identified features, was calculated using a bivariate random effects model.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Twelve studies were included, and 92 overlapping descriptors were subsumed under 16 MRI features. Ten features favoring AIP were diffuse enlargement (DOR, 75; 95% CI, 9-594), capsule-like rim (DOR, 52; 95% CI, 20-131), multiple main pancreatic duct (MPD) strictures (DOR, 47; 95% CI, 17-129), homogeneous delayed enhancement (DOR, 46; 95% CI, 21-104), low apparent diffusion coefficient value (DOR, 30), speckled enhancement (DOR, 30), multiple pancreatic masses (DOR, 29), tapered narrowing of MPD (DOR, 15), penetrating duct sign (DOR, 14), and delayed enhancement (DOR, 13). Six features favoring PDAC were target type enhancement (DOR, 41; 95% CI, 11-158), discrete pancreatic mass (DOR, 35; 95% CI, 15-80), upstream MPD dilatation (DOR, 13), peripancreatic fat infiltration (DOR, 10), upstream parenchymal atrophy (DOR, 5), and vascular involvement (DOR, 3).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study identified 16 informative MRI features to differentiate AIP from PDAC. Among them, diffuse enlargement, capsule-like rim, multiple MPD strictures, and homogeneous delayed enhancement favored AIP with the highest DORs, whereas discrete mass and target type enhancement favored PDAC.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="KEY POINTS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">• The MRI features with the highest pooled diagnostic odds ratios (DORs) for autoimmune pancreatitis were diffuse enlargement of the pancreas (75), capsule-like rim (52), multiple strictures of the main pancreatic duct (47), and homogeneous delayed enhancement (46). • The MRI features with the highest pooled DORs for pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma were target type enhancement (41) and discrete pancreatic mass (35).</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to European Society of Radiology.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yoon</LastName>
            <ForeName>Seung Bae</ForeName>
            <Initials>SB</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, College of Medicine, The Catholic University of Korea, Seoul, South Korea.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Jeon</LastName>
            <ForeName>Tae Yeon</ForeName>
            <Initials>TY</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Radiology and Center for Imaging Science, Samsung Medical Center, Sungkyunkwan University School of Medicine, Seoul, South Korea.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Moon</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sung-Hoon</ForeName>
            <Initials>SH</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7879-3114</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Hallym University Sacred Heart Hospital, Hallym University College of Medicine, 22, Gwanpyeong-ro 170 beon-gil, Dongan-gu, Anyang, Gyeonggi-do, 14068, South Korea. endomoon@hallym.or.kr.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lee</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sang Min</ForeName>
            <Initials>SM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Hallym University Sacred Heart Hospital, Hallym University College of Medicine, Anyang, South Korea.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kim</LastName>
            <ForeName>Myung-Hwan</ForeName>
            <Initials>MH</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, University of Ulsan, College of Medicine, Asan Medical Center, Seoul, South Korea.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>04</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>Germany</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Eur Radiol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9114774</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0938-7994</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Autoimmune pancreatitis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Diagnosis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Magnetic resonance imaging</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Odds ratio</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pancreatic neoplasms</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
          <Hour>11</Hour>
          <Minute>14</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35486167</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00330-022-08816-1</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00330-022-08816-1</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kamisawa T, Zen Y, Nakazawa T, Okazaki K (2018) Advances in IgG4-related pancreatobiliary diseases. Lancet Gastroenterol Hepatol 3:575–585</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2468-1253(18)30121-3</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nagpal SJS, Sharma A, Chari ST (2018) Autoimmune pancreatitis. Am J Gastroenterol 113:1301</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41395-018-0146-0</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shimosegawa T, Chari ST, Frulloni L et al (2011) International consensus diagnostic criteria for autoimmune pancreatitis: guidelines of the International Association of Pancreatology. Pancreas 40:352–358</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MPA.0b013e3182142fd2</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wallace ZS, Naden RP, Chari S et al (2020) The 2019 American College of Rheumatology/European League Against Rheumatism classification criteria for IgG4-related disease. Ann Rheum Dis 79:77–87</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/annrheumdis-2019-216561</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chari ST, Takahashi N, Levy MJ et al (2009) A diagnostic strategy to distinguish autoimmune pancreatitis from pancreatic cancer. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol 7:1097–1103</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cgh.2009.04.020</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moon SH, Kim MH, Park DH et al (2008) Is a 2-week steroid trial after initial negative investigation for malignancy useful in differentiating autoimmune pancreatitis from pancreatic cancer? A prospective outcome study. Gut 57:1704–1712</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/gut.2008.150979</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sahani DV, Sainani NI, Deshpande V, Shaikh MS, Frinkelberg DL, Fernandez-del Castillo C (2009) Autoimmune pancreatitis: disease evolution, staging, response assessment, and CT features that predict response to corticosteroid therapy. Radiology 250:118–129</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1148/radiol.2493080279</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Javed AA, Wright MJ, Ding D et al (2021) Autoimmune pancreatitis: a critical analysis of the surgical experience in an era of modern diagnostics. Pancreas 50:556–563</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MPA.0000000000001812</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yoon SB, Moon SH, Song TJ, Kim JH, Kim MH (2021) Endoscopic ultrasound-guided fine needle aspiration versus biopsy for diagnosis of autoimmune pancreatitis: systematic review and comparative meta-analysis. Dig Endosc 33:1024–1033</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Takahashi N, Fletcher JG, Hough DM et al (2009) Autoimmune pancreatitis: differentiation from pancreatic carcinoma and normal pancreas on the basis of enhancement characteristics at dual-phase CT. AJR Am J Roentgenol 193:479–484</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2214/AJR.08.1883</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee S, Kim JH, Kim SY et al (2018) Comparison of diagnostic performance between CT and MRI in differentiating non-diffuse-type autoimmune pancreatitis from pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma. Eur Radiol 28:5267–5274</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00330-018-5565-1</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ha J, Choi SH, Byun JH et al (2021) Meta-analysis of CT and MRI for differentiation of autoimmune pancreatitis from pancreatic adenocarcinoma. Eur Radiol 31:3427–3438</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00330-020-07416-1</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kamisawa T, Takuma K, Anjiki H et al (2010) Differentiation of autoimmune pancreatitis from pancreatic cancer by diffusion-weighted MRI. Am J Gastroenterol 105:1870–1875</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ajg.2010.87</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim HJ, Kim YK, Jeong WK, Lee WJ, Choi D (2015) Pancreatic duct "Icicle sign" on MRI for distinguishing autoimmune pancreatitis from pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma in the proximal pancreas. Eur Radiol 25:1551–1560</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00330-014-3548-4</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kwon JH, Kim JH, Kim SY et al (2019) Differentiating focal autoimmune pancreatitis and pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma: contrast-enhanced MRI with special emphasis on the arterial phase. Eur Radiol 29:5763–5771</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00330-019-06200-0</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Furuhashi N, Suzuki K, Sakurai Y, Ikeda M, Kawai Y, Naganawa S (2015) Differentiation of focal-type autoimmune pancreatitis from pancreatic carcinoma: assessment by multiphase contrast-enhanced CT. Eur Radiol 25:1366–1374</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00330-014-3512-3</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Takahashi M, Fujinaga Y, Notohara K et al (2020) Diagnostic imaging guide for autoimmune pancreatitis. Jpn J Radiol 38:591–612</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11604-020-00971-z</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM et al (2021) The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ 372:n71</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.n71</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schardt C, Adams MB, Owens T, Keitz S, Fontelo P (2007) Utilization of the PICO framework to improve searching PubMed for clinical questions. BMC Med Inform Decis Mak 7:16</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1472-6947-7-16</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Whiting PF, Rutjes AW, Westwood ME et al (2011) QUADAS-2: a revised tool for the quality assessment of diagnostic accuracy studies. Ann Intern Med 155:529–536</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/0003-4819-155-8-201110180-00009</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>You MW, Yun SJ (2019) Differentiating between hepatocellular carcinoma and intrahepatic cholangiocarcinoma using contrast-enhanced MRI features: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin Radiol 74:406 e409–406 e418</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim HY, Park JH, Lee YJ, Lee SS, Jeon JJ, Lee KH (2018) Systematic review and meta-analysis of CT features for differentiating complicated and uncomplicated appendicitis. Radiology 287:104–115</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1148/radiol.2017171260</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Park SH, Kim MH, Kim SY et al (2010) Magnetic resonance cholangiopancreatography for the diagnostic evaluation of autoimmune pancreatitis. Pancreas 39:1191–1198</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MPA.0b013e3181dbf469</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hur BY, Lee JM, Lee JE et al (2012) Magnetic resonance imaging findings of the mass-forming type of autoimmune pancreatitis: comparison with pancreatic adenocarcinoma. J Magn Reson Imaging 36:188–197</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmri.23609</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Naitoh I, Nakazawa T, Hayashi K et al (2012) Clinical differences between mass-forming autoimmune pancreatitis and pancreatic cancer. Scand J Gastroenterol 47:607–613</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/00365521.2012.667147</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muhi A, Ichikawa T, Motosugi U et al (2012) Mass-forming autoimmune pancreatitis and pancreatic carcinoma: differential diagnosis on the basis of computed tomography and magnetic resonance cholangiopancreatography, and diffusion-weighted imaging findings. J Magn Reson Imaging 35:827–836</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jmri.22881</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sugiyama Y, Fujinaga Y, Kadoya M et al (2012) Characteristic magnetic resonance features of focal autoimmune pancreatitis useful for differentiation from pancreatic cancer. Jpn J Radiol 30:296–309</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11604-011-0047-2</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sun GF, Zuo CJ, Shao CW, Wang JH, Zhang J (2013) Focal autoimmune pancreatitis: radiological characteristics help to distinguish from pancreatic cancer. World J Gastroenterol 19:3634–3641</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3748/wjg.v19.i23.3634</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Choi SY, Kim SH, Kang TW, Song KD, Park HJ, Choi YH (2016) Differentiating mass-forming autoimmune pancreatitis from pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma on the basis of contrast-enhanced MRI and DWI findings. AJR Am J Roentgenol 206:291–300</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2214/AJR.15.14974</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sekito T, Ishii Y, Serikawa M et al (2021) The role of apparent diffusion coefficient value in the diagnosis of localized type 1 autoimmune pancreatitis: differentiation from pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma and evaluation of response to steroids. Abdom Radiol (NY) 46:2014–2024</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00261-020-02907-7</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Choi YJ, Byun JH, Kim JY et al (2008) Diffuse pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma: characteristic imaging features. Eur J Radiol 67:321–328</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejrad.2007.07.010</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ishigami K, Tajima T, Nishie A et al (2010) MRI findings of pancreatic lymphoma and autoimmune pancreatitis: a comparative study. Eur J Radiol 74:e22–e28</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejrad.2009.03.022</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Triantopoulou C, Kolliakou E, Karoumpalis I, Yarmenitis S, Dervenis C (2012) Metastatic disease to the pancreas: an imaging challenge. Insights Imaging 3:165–172</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13244-011-0144-x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Manfredi R, Frulloni L, Mantovani W, Bonatti M, Graziani R, Pozzi Mucelli R (2011) Autoimmune pancreatitis: pancreatic and extrapancreatic MR imaging-MR cholangiopancreatography findings at diagnosis, after steroid therapy, and at recurrence. Radiology 260:428–436</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1148/radiol.11101729</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kawa S, Kamisawa T, Notohara K et al (2020) Japanese Clinical Diagnostic Criteria for Autoimmune Pancreatitis, 2018: Revision of Japanese Clinical Diagnostic Criteria for Autoimmune Pancreatitis, 2011. Pancreas 49:e13–e14</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MPA.0000000000001443</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim JH, Byun JH, Kim MH et al (2017) Pancreatic duct in autoimmune pancreatitis: intraindividual comparison of magnetic resonance pancreatography at 1.5 T and 3.0 T. Pancreas 46:921–926</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MPA.0000000000000853</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee SC, Yang CH, Chang CT, Yu KH (2021) Diagnostic utility of serum IgG4 in autoimmune pancreatitis: an updated comprehensive systematic review and meta-analysis. J Clin Gastroenterol. https://doi.org/10.1097/MCG.0000000000001612</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gardner TB, Levy MJ, Takahashi N, Smyrk TC, Chari ST (2009) Misdiagnosis of autoimmune pancreatitis: a caution to clinicians. Am J Gastroenterol 104:1620–1623</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ajg.2008.89</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kanno A, Nishimori I, Masamune A et al (2012) Nationwide epidemiological survey of autoimmune pancreatitis in Japan. Pancreas 41:835–839</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MPA.0b013e3182480c99</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Takahashi N, Fletcher JG, Fidler JL, Hough DM, Kawashima A, Chari ST (2008) Dual-phase CT of autoimmune pancreatitis: a multireader study. AJR Am J Roentgenol 190:280–286</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2214/AJR.07.2309</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
