<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35495592</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>03</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1792-1015</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>23</Volume>
            <Issue>6</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Experimental and therapeutic medicine</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Exp Ther Med</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Spironolactone alleviates myocardial fibrosis via inhibition of Ets-1 in mice with experimental autoimmune myocarditis.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>369</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>369</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">369</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3892/etm.2022.11296</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Spironolactone improves cardiac structure, function and prognosis in patients with heart failure and delays the progression of cardiac fibrosis. However, the exact underlying mechanism of this process remains to be elucidated. The present study therefore aimed to explore the protective effect and underlying mechanism of the aldosterone receptor antagonist, spironolactone, on myocardial fibrosis in mice with experimental autoimmune myocarditis (EAM). The EAM model was induced in BALB/c mice via immunization with murine cardiac α-myosin heavy chain sequence polypeptides. The cardiac function of the mice was assessed using echocardiography and the levels of inflammatory cytokines were quantified using ELISA. E26 transformation-specific sequence-1 (Ets-1) expression was knocked down using lentivirus-mediated small interference RNA. Total collagen deposition was assessed using Masson's trichrome and Ets-1, TGF-β1, Smad2/3, collagen I and III protein expression levels were detected using immunohistochemistry and western blotting. MMP-2 and MMP-9 mRNA expression levels and activity was determined using reverse transcription-quantitative PCR and gelatin zymography, respectively. The results of the present study demonstrated that spironolactone significantly improved myocardium hypertrophy, diastolic cardiac function and decreased myocardial inflammation and collagen deposition induced by EAM. Spironolactone treatment significantly inhibited Ets-1 and smad2/3 phosphorylation. In addition, inhibition of Ets-1 reduced the expression and activity of MMP-2 and MMP-9 and decreased cardiac fibrosis in EAM mice. The results indicated that the improvement of myocardial fibrosis by spironolactone may be associated with the TGF-β1/Smad-2/3/Ets-1 signaling pathway in EAM mice.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright: © Wang et al.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Wen-Ke</ForeName>
            <Initials>WK</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, The Second Hospital, Cheeloo College of Medicine, Shandong University, Jinan, Shandong 250033, P.R. China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ben</ForeName>
            <Initials>B</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of General Surgery, Qilu Hospital of Shandong University, Jinan, Shandong 250012, P.R. China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Cao</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xue-Hu</ForeName>
            <Initials>XH</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, The Second Hospital, Cheeloo College of Medicine, Shandong University, Jinan, Shandong 250033, P.R. China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Liu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yu-Sheng</ForeName>
            <Initials>YS</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cardiology, The Second Hospital, Cheeloo College of Medicine, Shandong University, Jinan, Shandong 250033, P.R. China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>04</Month>
          <Day>05</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Exp Ther Med</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101531947</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1792-0981</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">E26 transformation-specific sequence-1</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">experimental autoimmune myocarditis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">myocardial fibrosis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">spironolactone</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>42</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35495592</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9019666</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3892/etm.2022.11296</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">ETM-23-6-11296</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Watanabe K, Sukumaran V, Veeraveedu PT, Thandavarayan RA, Gurusamy N, Ma M, Arozal W, Sari FR, Lakshmanan AP, Arumugam S, et al.  Regulation of inflammation and myocardial fibrosis in experimental autoimmune myocarditis. Inflamm Allergy Drug Targets. 2011;10:218–225. doi: 10.2174/187152811795564091.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/187152811795564091</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21495969</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blyszczuk P, Muller-Edenborn B, Valenta T, Osto E, Stellato M, Behnke S, Glatz K, Basler K, Luscher TF, Distler O, et al.  Transforming growth factor-β-dependent Wnt secretion controls myofibroblast formation and myocardial fibrosis progression in experimental autoimmune myocarditis. Eur Heart J. 2017;38:1413–1425. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehw116.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurheartj/ehw116</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27099262</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Siwik DA, Chang DL, Colucci WS. Interleukin-1beta and tumor necrosis factor-alpha decrease collagen synthesis and increase matrix metalloproteinase activity in cardiac fibroblasts in vitro. Circ Res. 2000;86:1259–1265. doi: 10.1161/01.res.86.12.1259.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.res.86.12.1259</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10864917</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ono K, Matsumori A, Shioi T, Furukawa Y, Sasayama S. Cytokine gene expression after myocardial infarction in rat hearts: Possible implication in left ventricular remodeling. Circulation. 1998;98:149–156. doi: 10.1161/01.cir.98.2.149.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.cir.98.2.149</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9679721</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cardona A, Baker P, Kahwash R, Smart S, Phay JE, Basso C, Raman SV. Evidence of aldosterone synthesis in human myocardium in acute myocarditis. Int J Cardiol. 2019;275:114–119. doi: 10.1016/j.ijcard.2018.10.010.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijcard.2018.10.010</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30384979</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xiao J, Shimada M, Liu W, Hu D, Matsumori A. Anti-inflammatory effects of eplerenone on viral myocarditis. Eur J Heart Fail. 2009;11:349–353. doi: 10.1093/eurjhf/hfp023.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurjhf/hfp023</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19213804</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leader CJ, Moharram M, Coffey S, Sammut IA, Wilkins GW, Walker RJ. Myocardial global longitudinal strain: An early indicator of cardiac interstitial fibrosis modified by spironolactone, in a unique hypertensive rat model. PLoS One. 2019;14(e0220837) doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0220837.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0220837</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6690508</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31404095</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cohen JB, Schrauben SJ, Zhao L, Basso MD, Cvijic ME, Li Z, Yarde M, Wang Z, Bhattacharya PT, Chirinos DA, et al.  Clinical phenogroups in heart failure with preserved ejection fraction: Detailed phenotypes, prognosis, and response to spironolactone. JACC Heart Fail. 2020;8:172–184. doi: 10.1016/j.jchf.2019.09.009.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jchf.2019.09.009</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7058514</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31926856</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tanaka H, Sagisaka A, Suzuki N, Yamakawa M. Bombyx mori E26 transformation-specific 2 (BmEts2), an Ets family protein, represses Bombyx mori Rels (BmRels)-mediated promoter activation of antimicrobial peptide genes in the silkworm Bombyx mori. Insect Mol Biol. 2016;25:566–579. doi: 10.1111/imb.12244.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/imb.12244</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27227900</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gum R, Lengyel E, Juarez J, Chen JH, Sato H, Seiki M, Boyd D. Stimulation of 92-kDa gelatinase B promoter activity by ras is mitogen-activated protein kinase kinase 1-independent and requires multiple transcription factor binding sites including closely spaced PEA3/ets and AP-1 sequences. J Biol Chem. 1996;271:10672–10680. doi: 10.1074/jbc.271.18.10672.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.271.18.10672</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8631874</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nakamura Y, Esnault S, Maeda T, Kelly EA, Malter JS, Jarjour NN. Ets-1 regulates TNF-alpha-induced matrix metalloproteinase-9 and tenascin expression in primary bronchial fibroblasts. J Immunol. 2004;172:1945–1952. doi: 10.4049/jimmunol.172.3.1945.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4049/jimmunol.172.3.1945</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14734780</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cihakova D, Sharma RB, Fairweather D, Afanasyeva M, Rose NR. Animal models for autoimmune myocarditis and autoimmune thyroiditis. Methods Mol Med. 2004;102:175–193. doi: 10.1385/1-59259-805-6:175.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1385/1-59259-805-6:175</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15286386</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang WK, Wang B, Lu QH, Zhang W, Qin WD, Liu XJ, Liu XQ, An FS, Zhang Y, Zhang MX. Inhibition of high-mobility group box 1 improves myocardial fibrosis and dysfunction in diabetic cardiomyopathy. Int J Cardiol. 2014;172:202–212. doi: 10.1016/j.ijcard.2014.01.011.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijcard.2014.01.011</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24485636</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wehr MC, Hinrichs W, Brzozka MM, Unterbarnscheidt T, Herholt A, Wintgens JP, Papiol S, Soto-Bernardini MC, Kravchenko M, Zhang M, et al.  Spironolactone is an antagonist of NRG1-ERBB4 signaling and schizophrenia-relevant endophenotypes in mice. EMBO Mol Med. 2017;9:1448–1462. doi: 10.15252/emmm.201707691.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15252/emmm.201707691</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5653977</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28743784</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Perera P, Lobo V, Williams SR, Gharahbaghian L. Cardiac echocardiography. Crit Care Clin. 2014;30:47–92. doi: 10.1016/j.ccc.2013.08.003. v.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ccc.2013.08.003</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24295841</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pan XC, Li ZX, Wu DZ, Li SY, Xiang HB, Song YT. Mapping changes of whole brain blood flow in rats with myocardial ischemia/reperfusion injury assessed by positron emission tomography. Curr Med Sci. 2019;39:653–657. doi: 10.1007/s11596-019-2087-2.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11596-019-2087-2</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31347004</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rudski LG, Lai WW, Afilalo J, Hua L, Handschumacher MD, Chandrasekaran K, Solomon SD, Louie EK, Schiller NB. Guidelines for the echocardiographic assessment of the right heart in adults: A report from the American Society of Echocardiography endorsed by the European Association of Echocardiography, a registered branch of the European Society of Cardiology, and the Canadian Society of Echocardiography. J Am Soc Echocardiogr. 2010;23:685–713. doi: 10.1016/j.echo.2010.05.010. quiz 786-8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.echo.2010.05.010</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20620859</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Livak KJ, Schmittgen TD. Analysis of relative gene expression data using real-time quantitative PCR and the 2(-Delta Delta C(T)) Method. Methods. 2001;25:402–408. doi: 10.1006/meth.2001.1262.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1006/meth.2001.1262</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11846609</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weber KT. Aldosterone in congestive heart failure. N Engl J Med. 2001;345:1689–1697. doi: 10.1056/NEJMra000050.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMra000050</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11759649</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tschope C, Ammirati E, Bozkurt B, Caforio ALP, Cooper LT, Felix SB, Hare JM, Heidecker B, Heymans S, Hubner N, et al.  Myocarditis and inflammatory cardiomyopathy: Current evidence and future directions. Nat Rev Cardiol. 2021;18:169–193. doi: 10.1038/s41569-020-00435-x.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41569-020-00435-x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7548534</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33046850</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Trojanowska M. Ets factors and regulation of the extracellular matrix. Oncogene. 2000;19:6464–6471. doi: 10.1038/sj.onc.1204043.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/sj.onc.1204043</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11175362</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hanna A, Humeres C, Frangogiannis NG. The role of Smad signaling cascades in cardiac fibrosis. Cell Signal. 2021;77(109826) doi: 10.1016/j.cellsig.2020.109826.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cellsig.2020.109826</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7727442</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33160018</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yancy CW, Jessup M, Bozkurt B, Butler J, Casey DE Jr, Colvin MM, Drazner MH, Filippatos GS, Fonarow GC, Givertz MM, et al.  2017 ACC/AHA/HFSA Focused Update of the 2013 ACCF/AHA Guideline for the management of heart failure: A report of the American college of cardiology/American heart association task force on clinical practice guidelines and the heart failure society of America. Circulation. 2017;136:e137–e161. doi: 10.1161/CIR.0000000000000509.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/CIR.0000000000000509</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28455343</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iwasaka C, Tanaka K, Abe M, Sato Y. Ets-1 regulates angiogenesis by inducing the expression of urokinase-type plasminogen activator and matrix metalloproteinase-1 and the migration of vascular endothelial cells. J Cell Physiol. 1996;169:522–531. doi: 10.1002/(SICI)1097-4652(199612)169:3&lt;522::AID-JCP12&gt;3.0.CO;2-7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/(SICI)1097-4652(199612)169:3&lt;522::AID-JCP12&gt;3.0.CO;2-7</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8952701</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kukacka J, Prusa R, Kotaska K, Pelouch V. Matrix metalloproteinases and their function in myocardium. Biomed Pap Med Fac Univ Palacky Olomouc Czech Repub. 2005;149:225–236. doi: 10.5507/bp.2005.031.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5507/bp.2005.031</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16601761</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Staudt A, Staudt Y, Dorr M, Bohm M, Knebel F, Hummel A, Wunderle L, Tiburcy M, Wernecke KD, Baumann G, Felix SB. Potential role of humoral immunity in cardiac dysfunction of patients suffering from dilated cardiomyopathy. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2004;44:829–836. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2004.04.055.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2004.04.055</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15312867</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Keidar S, Kaplan M, Pavlotzky E, Coleman R, Hayek T, Hamoud S, Aviram M. Aldosterone administration to mice stimulates macrophage NADPH oxidase and increases atherosclerosis development: A possible role for angiotensin-converting enzyme and the receptors for angiotensin II and aldosterone. Circulation. 2004;109:2213–2220. doi: 10.1161/01.CIR.0000127949.05756.9D.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.CIR.0000127949.05756.9D</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15123520</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hu LJ, Chen YQ, Deng SB, Du JL, She Q. Additional use of an aldosterone antagonist in patients with mild to moderate chronic heart failure: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Br J Clin Pharmacol. 2013;75:1202–1212. doi: 10.1111/bcp.12012.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bcp.12012</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3635590</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23088367</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tsutamoto T. Mineralocorticoid receptor antagonist spironolactone improves left ventricular remodeling in patients with congestive heart failure and acute myocardial infarction. Nihon Yakurigaku Zasshi. 2004;124:90–100. doi: 10.1254/fpj.124.90. (In Japanese)</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1254/fpj.124.90</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15277727</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu X, Zhang X, Ye L, Yuan H. Protective mechanisms of berberine against experimental autoimmune myocarditis in a rat model. Biomed Pharmacother. 2016;79:222–230. doi: 10.1016/j.biopha.2016.02.015.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopha.2016.02.015</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27044832</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li J, Schwimmbeck PL, Tschope C, Leschka S, Husmann L, Rutschow S, Reichenbach F, Noutsias M, Kobalz U, Poller W, et al.  Collagen degradation in a murine myocarditis model: Relevance of matrix metalloproteinase in association with inflammatory induction. Cardiovasc Res. 2002;56:235–247. doi: 10.1016/s0008-6363(02)00546-1.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/s0008-6363(02)00546-1</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12393094</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li YY, Kadokami T, Wang P, McTiernan CF, Feldman AM. MMP inhibition modulates TNF-alpha transgenic mouse phenotype early in the development of heart failure. Am J Physiol Heart Circ Physiol. 2002;282:H983–H989. doi: 10.1152/ajpheart.00233.2001.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpheart.00233.2001</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11834496</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huber SA, Polgar J, Schultheiss P, Schwimmbeck P. Augmentation of pathogenesis of coxsackievirus B3 infections in mice by exogenous administration of interleukin-1 and interleukin-2. J Virol. 1994;68:195–206. doi: 10.1128/JVI.68.1.195-206.1994.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JVI.68.1.195-206.1994</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC236278</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8254729</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cleland JGF, Ferreira JP, Mariottoni B, Pellicori P, Cuthbert J, Verdonschot JAJ, Petutschnigg J, Ahmed FZ, Cosmi F, Brunner La Rocca HP, et al.  The effect of spironolactone on cardiovascular function and markers of fibrosis in people at increased risk of developing heart failure: The heart ‘OMics’ in AGEing (HOMAGE) randomized clinical trial. Eur Heart J. 2021;42:684–696. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehaa758.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurheartj/ehaa758</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7878013</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33215209</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brilla CG, Weber KT. Reactive and reparative myocardial fibrosis in arterial hypertension in the rat. Cardiovasc Res. 1992;26:671–677. doi: 10.1093/cvr/26.7.671.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cvr/26.7.671</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1423431</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu W, Gong W, He M, Liu Y, Yang Y, Wang M, Wu M, Guo S, Yu Y, Wang X, et al.  Spironolactone protects against diabetic cardiomyopathy in streptozotocin-induced diabetic rats. J Diabetes Res. 2018;2018(9232065) doi: 10.1155/2018/9232065.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2018/9232065</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6204188</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30406151</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Okuducu AF, Zils U, Michaelis SA, Michaelides S, von Deimling A. Ets-1 is up-regulated together with its target gene products matrix metalloproteinase-2 and matrix metalloproteinase-9 in atypical and anaplastic meningiomas. Histopathology. 2006;48:836–845. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2559.2006.02432.x.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2559.2006.02432.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16722933</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hahne JC, Okuducu AF, Fuchs T, Florin A, Wernert N. Identification of ETS-1 target genes in human fibroblasts. Int J Oncol. 2011;38:1645–1652. doi: 10.3892/ijo.2011.981.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3892/ijo.2011.981</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21424123</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hori Y, Kashimoto T, Yonezawa T, Sano N, Saitoh R, Igarashi S, Chikazawa S, Kanai K, Hoshi F, Itoh N, Higuchi S. Matrix metalloproteinase-2 stimulates collagen-I expression through phosphorylation of focal adhesion kinase in rat cardiac fibroblasts. Am J Physiol Cell Physiol. 2012;303:C947–C953. doi: 10.1152/ajpcell.00401.2011.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpcell.00401.2011</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22914642</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li Y, Ma J, Zhu H, Singh M, Hill D, Greer PA, Arnold JM, Abel ED, Peng T. Targeted inhibition of calpain reduces myocardial hypertrophy and fibrosis in mouse models of type 1 diabetes. Diabetes. 2011;60:2985–2994. doi: 10.2337/db10-1333.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/db10-1333</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3198063</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21911754</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhao N, Zou H, Qin J, Fan C, Liu Y, Wang S, Shan Z, Teng W, Li Y. MicroRNA-326 contributes to autoimmune thyroiditis by targeting the Ets-1 protein. Endocrine. 2018;59:120–129. doi: 10.1007/s12020-017-1465-4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12020-017-1465-4</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29181619</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu L, Fu M, Chen D, Han W, Ostrowski MC, Grossfeld P, Gao P, Ye M. Endothelial-specific deletion of Ets-1 attenuates Angiotensin II-induced cardiac fibrosis via suppression of endothelial-to-mesenchymal transition. BMB Rep. 2019;52:595–600. doi: 10.5483/BMBRep.2019.52.10.206.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5483/BMBRep.2019.52.10.206</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6827575</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30670148</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Steinl DC, Xu L, Ochoa-Espinosa A, Punjabi M, Kaufmann BA. Non-invasive contrast enhanced ultrasound molecular imaging of inflammation in autoimmune myocarditis for prediction of left ventricular fibrosis and remodeling. PLoS One. 2019;14(e0224377) doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0224377.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0224377</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6816567</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31658281</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hu HH, Chen DQ, Wang YN, Feng YL, Cao G, Vaziri ND, Zhao YY. New insights into TGF-beta/Smad signaling in tissue fibrosis. Chem Biol Interact. 2018;292:76–83. doi: 10.1016/j.cbi.2018.07.008.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cbi.2018.07.008</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30017632</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yue Y, Meng K, Pu Y, Zhang X. Transforming growth factor beta (TGF-β) mediates cardiac fibrosis and induces diabetic cardiomyopathy. Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2017;133:124–130. doi: 10.1016/j.diabres.2017.08.018.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.diabres.2017.08.018</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28934669</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Duivenvoorden WC, Hirte HW, Singh G. Transforming growth factor beta1 acts as an inducer of matrix metalloproteinase expression and activity in human bone-metastasizing cancer cells. Clin Exp Metastasis. 1999;17:27–34. doi: 10.1023/a:1026404227624.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1023/a:1026404227624</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10390144</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Okano K, Hibi A, Miyaoka T, Inoue T, Sugimoto H, Tsuchiya K, Akiba T, Nitta K. Inhibitory effects of the transcription factor Ets-1 on the expression of type I collagen in TGF-beta1-stimulated renal epithelial cells. Mol Cell Biochem. 2012;369:247–254. doi: 10.1007/s11010-012-1388-6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11010-012-1388-6</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22829018</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
