<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35498550</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>03</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2405-6766</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>27</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Food and waterborne parasitology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Food Waterborne Parasitol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Is <i>Cryptosporidium</i> a hijacker able to drive cancer cell proliferation?</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e00153</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e00153</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e00153</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.fawpar.2022.e00153</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The pathophysiological mechanisms of <i>Cryptosporidium</i> infection are multifactorial and not completely understood. Some advances achieved recently revealed that the infection by <i>Cryptosporidium parvum</i> induces cytoskeleton remodeling and actin reorganization through the implication of several intracellular signals involving, for example, PI3K, Src, Cdc42 and GTPases. It has also been reported that the infection by <i>C. parvum</i> leads to the activation of NF-κβ, known to induce anti-apoptotic mechanisms and to transmit oncogenic signals to epithelial cells. Despite the growing evidence about the hijacking of cellular pathways, potentially being involved in cancer onset, this information has rarely been linked to the tumorigenic potential of the parasite. However, several evidences support an association between <i>Cryptosporidium</i> infection and the development of digestive neoplasia. To explore the dynamics of <i>Cryptosporidium</i> infection, an animal model of cryptosporidiosis using corticoid dexamethasone-treated adult SCID (severe combined immunodeficiency) mice, orally infected with <i>C. parvum</i> or <i>Cryptosporidium muris</i> oocysts was implemented. <i>C. parvum</i>-infected animals developed digestive adenocarcinoma. When mechanisms involved in this neoplastic process were explored, the pivotal role of the Wnt pathway together with the alteration of the cytoskeleton was confirmed. Recently, a microarray assay allowed the detection of cancer-promoting genes and pathways highly up regulated in the group of <i>C. parvum</i> infected animals when compared to non-infected controls. Moreover, different human cases/control studies reported significant higher prevalence of <i>Cryptosporidium</i> infection among patients with recently diagnosed colon cancer before any treatment when compared to the control group (patients without colon neoplasia but with persistent digestive symptoms). These results suggest that <i>Cryptosporidium</i> is a potential oncogenic agent involved in cancer development beyond the usual suspects. If <i>Cryptosporidium</i> is able to hijack signal transduction, then is very likely that this contributes to transformation of its host cell. More research in the field is required in order to identify mechanisms and molecular factors involved in this process and to develop effective treatment interventions.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Author. Published by Elsevier Inc. on behalf of International Association of Food and Waterborne Parasitology.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Certad</LastName>
            <ForeName>Gabriela</ForeName>
            <Initials>G</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>U1019-UMR 9017-CIIL-Centre d'Infection et d'Immunité de Lille, Institut Pasteur de Lille, Université de Lille, CNRS, Inserm, CHU Lille, F-59000 Lille, France.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Délégation à la Recherche Clinique et à l'Innovation, Groupement des Hôpitaux de l'Institut Catholique de Lille, F-59462 Lomme, France.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>04</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Food Waterborne Parasitol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101762332</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2405-6766</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cryptosporidium</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Digestive cancer</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pathogenicity</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>There are no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
          <Hour>7</Hour>
          <Minute>12</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35498550</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9044164</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fawpar.2022.e00153</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">S2405-6766(22)00010-5</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ahsan M.I., Chowdhury M.S.R., Das M., Akter S., Roy S., Sharma B., Akhand R.N., Hasan M., Uddin M.B., Ahmed S.S.U. In silico identification and functional characterization of conserved miRNAs in the genome of Cryptosporidium parvum. Bioinform. Biol. Insights. 2021;15 doi: 10.1177/11779322211027665. 11779322211027665.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/11779322211027665</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Amadi B., Mwiya M., Sianongo S., Payne L., Watuka A., Katubulushi M., Kelly P. High dose prolonged treatment with nitazoxanide is not effective for cryptosporidiosis in HIV positive Zambian children: a randomised controlled trial. BMC Infect. Dis. 2009;9:195. doi: 10.1186/1471-2334-9-195.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2334-9-195</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2794874</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19954529</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Audebert C., Bonardi F., Caboche S., Guyot K., Touzet H., Merlin S., Gantois N., Creusy C., Meloni D., Mouray A., Viscogliosi E., Certad G., Benamrouz-Vanneste S., Chabé M. Genetic basis for virulence differences of various Cryptosporidium parvum carcinogenic isolates. Sci. Rep. 2020;10:7316. doi: 10.1038/s41598-020-64370-0.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-020-64370-0</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7193590</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32355272</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bañuls A.L., Thomas F., Renaud F. Of parasites and men. Infect. Genet. Evol. 2013;20:61–70.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23954419</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baydoun M., Vanneste S.B., Creusy C., Guyot K., Gantois N., Chabe M., Delaire B., Mouray A., Baydoun A., Forzy G., Chieux V., Gosset P., Senez V., Viscogliosi E., Follet J., Certad G. Three-dimensional (3D) culture of adult murine colon as an in vitro model of cryptosporidiosis: proof of concept. Sci. Rep. 2017;7:17288. doi: 10.1038/s41598-017-17304-2.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-017-17304-2</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5725449</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29230047</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Benamrouz S., Guyot K., Gazzola S., Mouray A., Chassat T., Delaire B., Chabé M., Gosset P., Viscogliosi E., Dei-Cas E., Creusy C., Conseil V., Certad G. Cryptosporidium parvum infection in SCID mice infected with only one oocyst: qPCR assessment of parasite replication in tissues and development of digestive cancer. PLoS One. 2012;7 doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0051232.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0051232</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Benamrouz S., Conseil V., Chabe M., Praet M., Audebert C., Blervaque R., Guyot K., Gazzola S., Mouray A., Chassat T., Delaire B., Goetinck N., Gantois N., Osman M., Slomianny C., Dehennaut V., Lefebvre T., Viscogliosi E., Cuvelier C., Dei-Cas E., Creusy C., Certad G. Cryptosporidium parvum-induced ileo-caecal adenocarcinoma and Wnt signaling in a mouse model. Dis. Model. Mech. 2014;7:693–700. doi: 10.1242/dmm.013292.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1242/dmm.013292</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4036476</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24652769</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bouzid M., Hunter P.R., Chalmers R.M., Tyler K.M. Cryptosporidium pathogenicity and virulence. Clin. Microbiol. Rev. 2013;26:115–134. doi: 10.1128/CMR.00076-12.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/CMR.00076-12</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3553671</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23297262</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bulavin D.V., Fornace A.J. p38 MAP kinase’s emerging role as a tumor suppressor. Adv. Cancer Res. 2004;92 doi: 10.1016/S0065-230X(04)92005-2.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0065-230X(04)92005-2</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Castellanos-Gonzalez A., Yancey L.S., Wang H.-C., Pantenburg B., Liscum K.R., Lewis D.E., White A.C. Cryptosporidium infection of human intestinal epithelial cells increases eression of osteoprotegerin: a novel mechanism for evasion of host defenses. J. Infect. Dis. 2008 doi: 10.1086/528374.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1086/528374</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Certad G., Creusy C., Ngouanesavanh T., Guyot K., Gantois N., Mouray A., Chassat T., Flament N., Fleurisse L., Pinon A., Delhaes L., Dei-Cas E. Development of Cryptosporidium parvum-induced gastrointestinal neoplasia in severe combined immunodeficiency (SCID) mice: severity of lesions is correlated with infection intensity. Am. J. Trop. Med. Hyg. 2010;82 doi: 10.4269/ajtmh.2010.09-0309.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4269/ajtmh.2010.09-0309</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Certad G., Creusy C., Guyot K., Mouray A., Chassat T., Delaire B., Pinon A., Sitja-Bobadilla A., Alvarez-Pellitero P., Praet M., Cuvelier C., Dei-Cas E. Fulminant cryptosporidiosis associated with digestive adenocarcinoma in SCID mice infected with Cryptosporidium parvum TUM1 strain. Int. J. Parasitol. 2010;40(13):1469–1475. doi: 10.1016/j.ijpara.2010.07.007. Epub 2010 Aug 12. PMID: 20708621.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijpara.2010.07.007</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20708621</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Certad G., Ngouanesavanh T., Guyot K., Gantois N., Chassat T., Mouray A., Fleurisse L., Pinon A., Cailliez J.-C., Dei-Cas E., Creusy C. Cryptosporidium parvum, a potential cause of colic adenocarcinoma. Infect. Agents Cancer. 2007;2:22. doi: 10.1186/1750-9378-2-22.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1750-9378-2-22</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Certad G., Benamrouz S., Guyot K., Mouray A., Chassat T., Flament N., Delhaes L., Coiteux V., Delaire B., Praet M., Cuvelier C., Gosset P., Dei-Cas E., Creusy C. Fulminant cryptosporidiosis after near-drowning: a human Cryptosporidium parvum strain implicated in invasive gastrointestinal adenocarcinoma and cholangiocarcinoma in an experimental model. Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 2012;78:1746–1751. doi: 10.1128/AEM.06457-11.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/AEM.06457-11</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3298136</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22247151</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Certad G., Viscogliosi E., Chabé M., Cacciò S.M. Pathogenic mechanisms of Cryptosporidium and Giardia. Trends Parasitol. 2017;33:561–576. doi: 10.1016/j.pt.2017.02.006.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pt.2017.02.006</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28336217</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cha M.-Y., Kim C.-M., Park Y.-M., Ryu W.-S. Hepatitis B Virus X protein is essential for the activation of Wnt/-Catenin signaling in hepatoma cells. Hepatology. 2004;39:1683–1693. doi: 10.1002/hep.20245.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hep.20245</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15185310</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cheeseman K., Certad G., Weitzman J.B. Parasites and cancer: is there a causal link? Med. Sci. 2016;32 doi: 10.1051/medsci/20163210020.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1051/medsci/20163210020</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen X.M., Levine S. a, Splinter P.L., Tietz P.S., Ganong A.L., Jobin C., Gores G.J., Paya C.V., LaRusso N.F. Cryptosporidium parvum activates nuclear factor kappaB in biliary epithelia preventing epithelial cell apoptosis. Gastroenterology. 2001;120:1774–1783. doi: 10.1053/gast.2001.24850.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/gast.2001.24850</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11375958</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen X.M., Huang B.Q., Splinter P.L., Orth J.D., Billadeau D.D., McNiven M.A., LaRusso N.F. Cdc42 and the actin-related protein/neural Wiskott-Aldrich syndrome protein network mediate cellular invasion by Cryptosporidium parvum. Infect. Immun. 2004;72:3011–3021. doi: 10.1128/IAI.72.5.3011-3021.2004.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/IAI.72.5.3011-3021.2004</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC387898</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15102814</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen X.-M., Splinter P.L., Tietz P.S., Huang B.Q., Billadeau D.D., LaRusso N.F. Phosphatidylinositol 3-kinase and frabin mediate Cryptosporidium parvum cellular invasion via activation of Cdc42. J. Biol. Chem. 2004;279:31671–31678. doi: 10.1074/jbc.M401592200.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.M401592200</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15133042</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen X.-M., Splinter P.L., O’Hara S.P., LaRusso N.F. A cellular micro-RNA, let-7i, regulates Toll-like receptor 4 expression and contributes to cholangiocyte immune responses against Cryptosporidium parvum infection. Int. J. Biol. Chem. 2007;282:28929–28938. doi: 10.1074/jbc.M702633200.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.M702633200</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Choudhry N., Korbel D.S., Edwards L.A., Bajaj-Elliott M., Mcdonald V. Dysregulation of interferon-g-mediated signalling pathway in intestinal epithelial cells by Cryptosporidium parvum. Cell. Microbiol. 2009;11:1354–1364. doi: 10.1111/j.1462-5822.2009.01336.x.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1462-5822.2009.01336.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19473199</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Crawford C.K., Kol A. The mucosal innate immune response to Cryptosporidium parvum, a Global One Health Issue. Front. Cell. Infect. Microbiol. 2021;2021(25) doi: 10.3389/fcimb.2021.689401.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fcimb.2021.689401</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Crosas-Molist E., Samain R., Kohlhammer L., Orgaz J.L., George S.L., Maiques O., Barcelo J., Sanz-Moreno V. Rho GTPase signaling in cancer progression and dissemination. Physiol. Rev. 2022;102:455–510. doi: 10.1152/physrev.00045.2020.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/physrev.00045.2020</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34541899</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deng M., Lancto C.A., Abrahamsen M.S. Cryptosporidium parvum regulation of human epithelial cell gene expression. Int. J. Parasitol. 2004;34:73–82.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14711592</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elliott D.A., Clark D.P. Cryptosporidium parvum induces host cell actin accumulation at the host- parasite interface. Infect. Immun. 2000;68:2315–2322. doi: 10.1128/IAI.68.4.2315-2322.2000.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/IAI.68.4.2315-2322.2000</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC97419</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10722635</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ewald P.W. An evolutionary perspective on parasitism as a cause of cancer. Adv. Parasitol. 2009;68:21–43. doi: 10.1016/S0065-308X(08)00602-7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0065-308X(08)00602-7</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19289189</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gong A.-Y., Zhou R., Hu G., Liu J., Sosnowska D., Drescher K.M., Dong H., Chen X.-M. Cryptosporidium parvum induces B7-H1 expression in cholangiocytes by down-rgulating microRNA-513. J. Infect. Dis. 2010;201:160–169. doi: 10.1086/648589.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1086/648589</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2791176</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19916867</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guérin A., Roy N.H., Kugler E.M., Berry L., Burkhardt J.K., Shin J.B., Striepen B. Cryptosporidium rhoptry effector protein ROP1 injected during invasion targets the host cytoskeletal modulator LMO7. Cell Host Microbe. 2021;29:1407–1420. doi: 10.1016/j.chom.2021.07.002.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chom.2021.07.002</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8475647</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34348092</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guesdon W., Auray G., Pezier T., Bussière F.I., Drouet F., Le Vern Y., Marquis M., Potiron L., Rabot S., Bruneau A., Werts C., Laurent F., Lacroix-Lamandé S. CCL20 displays antimicrobial activity against Cryptosporidium parvum, but its expression is reduced during infection in the intestine of neonatal mice. J. Infect. Dis. 2015;212:1332–1340. doi: 10.1093/infdis/jiv206.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/infdis/jiv206</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25838265</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hanahan D., Weinberg R.A. The hallmarks of cancer. Cell. 2000;100:57–70. doi: 10.1016/S0092-8674(00)81683-9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0092-8674(00)81683-9</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10647931</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haqshenas G., Doerig C. Targeting of host cell receptor tyrosine kinases by intracellular pathogens. Sci. Signal. 2019;12:eaau9894. doi: 10.1126/scisignal.aau9894.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/scisignal.aau9894</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31530732</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>He W., Li J., Gong A.Y., Deng S., Li M., Wang Y., Mathy N.W., Feng Y., Xiao L., Chen X.M. Cryptosporidial infection suppresses intestinal epithelial cell mapk signaling impairing host anti-parasitic defense. Microorganisms. 2021;9:151. doi: 10.3390/microorganisms9010151.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/microorganisms9010151</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7826584</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33445463</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hofman P., Vouret-Craviari V. Microbes-induced EMT at the crossroad of inflammation and cancer. Gut Microbes. 2012;3:176–185. doi: 10.4161/gmic.20288.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4161/gmic.20288</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3427211</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22572828</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huang P., Westmoreland S.V., Jain R.K., Fukumura D. Spontaneous nonthymic tumors in SCID mice. Comp. Med. 2011;61:227–234.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3123755</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21819692</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hussein H.A.M., Walker L.R., Abdel-Raouf U.M., Desouky S.A., Montasser A.K.M., Akula S.M. Beyond RGD: virus interactions with integrins. Arch. Virol. 2015;160:2669–2681. doi: 10.1007/s00705-015-2579-8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00705-015-2579-8</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7086847</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26321473</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnston W.T., Mutalima N., Sun D., Emmanuel B., Bhatia K., Aka P., Wu X., Borgstein E., Liomba G.N., Kamiza S., Mkandawire N., Batumba M., Carpenter L.M., Jaffe H., Molyneux E.M., Goedert J.J., Soppet D., Newton R., Mbulaiteye S.M. Relationship between Plasmodium falciparum malaria prevalence, genetic diversity and endemic Burkitt lymphoma in Malawi. Sci. Rep. 2014;4:3741. doi: 10.1038/srep03741.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/srep03741</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3894552</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24434689</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kalantari N., Gorgani-Firouzjaee T., Ghaffari S., Bayani M., Ghaffari T., Chehrazi M. Association between Cryptosporidium infection and cancer: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Parasitol. Int. 2020;74 doi: 10.1016/j.parint.2019.101979.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.parint.2019.101979</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khalil I.A., Troeger C., Rao P.C., Blacker B.F., Brown A.M., Colombara D.V., Forouzanfar M.H., Hay FMedSci S.I., Reiner R.C., Jr., Khalil I.A., Troeger C., Rao P.C., Blacker B.F., Brown A., Brewer T.G., Colombara D.V., De Hostos E.L., Engmann C., Guerrant R.L.…Mokdad A.H. Morbidity, mortality, and long-term consequences associated with diarrhoea from Cryptosporidium infection in children younger than 5 years: a meta-analyses study. Lancet Glob. Health. 2018;6:e758–e768. www.thelancet.com/lancetgh</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6005120</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29903377</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Klöhn M., Schrader J.A., Brüggemann Y., Todt D., Steinmann E. Beyond the usual suspects: hepatitis e virus and its implications in hepatocellular carcinoma. Cancers. 2021;13:5867. doi: 10.3390/cancers13225867.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/cancers13225867</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8616277</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34831021</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kolářová I., Valigurová A. Hide-and-seek: a game played between parasitic protists and their hosts. Microorganisms. 2021;9:2434. doi: 10.3390/microorganisms9122434.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/microorganisms9122434</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8707157</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34946036</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kotloff K.L., Nataro J.P., Blackwelder W.C., Nasrin D., Farag T.H., Panchalingam S., Wu Y., Sow S.O., Sur D., Breiman R.F., Faruque A.S., Zaidi A.K., Saha D., Alonso P.L., Tamboura B., Sanogo D., Onwuchekwa U., Manna B., Ramamurthy T.…Levine M.M. Burden and aetiology of diarrhoeal disease in infants and young children in developing countries (the Global Enteric Multicenter Study, GEMS): a prospective, case-control study. Lancet. 2013;382:209–222. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(13)60844-2.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(13)60844-2</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23680352</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kumar A., Chatterjee I., Anbazhagan A.N., Jayawardena D., Priyamvada S., Alrefai W.A., Sun J., Borthakur A., Dudeja P.K., Alip Borthakur C. Cryptosporidium parvum disrupts intestinal epithelial barrier function via altering expression of key tight junction and adherens junction proteins. Cell. Microbiol. 2018;20 doi: 10.1111/cmi.12830.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cmi.12830</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lacroix S., Mancassola R., Naciri M., Laurent F. Cryptosporidium parvum-specific mucosal immune response in C57BL/6 neonatal and gamma interferon-deficient mice: role of tumor necrosis factor alpha in protection. Infect. Immun. 2001;69:1635–1642. doi: 10.1128/IAI.69.3.1635-1642.2001.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/IAI.69.3.1635-1642.2001</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC98067</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11179338</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lantier L., Lacroix-Lamandé S., Potiron L., Metton C., Drouet F., Guesdon W., Gnahoui-David A., Le Vern Y., Deriaud E., Fenis A., Rabot S., Descamps A., Werts C., Laurent F. Intestinal CD103+ dendritic cells are key players in the innate immune control of Cryptosporidium parvum infection in neonatal mice. PLoS Pathog. 2013;9 doi: 10.1371/journal.ppat.1003801.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.ppat.1003801</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Laurent F., Lacroix-Lamandé S. Innate immune responses play a key role in controlling infection of the intestinal epithelium by Cryptosporidium. Int. J. Parasitol. 2017;2017(47):711–721. doi: 10.1016/j.ijpara.2017.08.001.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijpara.2017.08.001</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lendner M., Daugschies A. Cryptosporidium infections: molecular advances. Parasitology. 2014;141:1511–1532. doi: 10.1017/S0031182014000237.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0031182014000237</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24679517</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li Y., Baptista R.P., Sateriale A., Striepen B., Kissinger J.C. Analysis of long non-coding RNA in Cryptosporidium parvum reveals significant stage-specific antisense transcription. Front. Cell. Infect. Microbiol. 2021;10 doi: 10.3389/fcimb.2020.608298.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fcimb.2020.608298</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu X.Q., Cohen J.I.  Virology. Vols. 479–480. Academic Press Inc.; 2015. The role of PI3K/Akt in human herpesvirus infection: from the bench to the bedside; pp. 568–577.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.virol.2015.02.040</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu J., Enomoto S., Lancto C.A., Abrahamsen M.S., Rutherford M.S. Inhibition of apoptosis in Cryptosporidium parvum-infected intestinal epithelial cells is dependent on survivin. Infect. Immun. 2008;76:3784–3792. doi: 10.1128/IAI.00308-08.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/IAI.00308-08</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2493198</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18519556</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu J., Deng M., Lancto C.A., Abrahamsen M.S., Rutherford M.S., Enomoto S. Biphasic modulation of apoptotic pathways in Cryptosporidium parvum-infected human intestinal epithelial cells. Infect. Immun. 2009;77:837–849. doi: 10.1128/IAI.00955-08.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/IAI.00955-08</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2632021</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19075026</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martin K.H., Slack J.K., Boerner S.A., Martin C.C., Parsons J.T. Integrin connections map: to infinity and beyond. Science. 2002;296:1652–1653. doi: 10.1126/science.296.5573.1652.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.296.5573.1652</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12040184</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mead J.R., Arrowood M.J., Sidwell R.W., Healey M.C. Chronic Cryptosporidium parvum infections in congenitally immunodeficient SCID and nude mice. J. Infect. Dis. 1991;163:1297–1304.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2037795</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mele R., Gomez Morales M.A., Tosini F., Pozio E. Cryptosporidium parvum at different developmental stages modulates host cell apoptosis in vitro. Infect. Immun. 2004;72:6061–6067. doi: 10.1128/IAI.72.10.6061-6067.2004.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/IAI.72.10.6061-6067.2004</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC517591</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15385510</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ming Z., Zhou R., Chen X.-M. Regulation of host epithelial responses to Cryptosporidium infection by microRNAs. Parasite Immunol. 2017;39 doi: 10.1111/pim.12408.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/pim.12408</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mirhashemi M.E., Noubary F., Chapman-Bonofiglio S., Tzipori S., Huggins G.S., Widmer G. Transcriptome analysis of pig intestinal cell monolayers infected with Cryptosporidium parvum asexual stages. Parasit. Vectors. 2018;11:176. doi: 10.1186/s13071-018-2754-3.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13071-018-2754-3</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5848449</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29530089</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moore P.S., Chang Y. Why do viruses cause cancer? Highlights of the first century of human tumour virology. Nat. Rev. Cancer. 2010;10:878–889. doi: 10.1038/nrc2961.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrc2961</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3718018</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21102637</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nakamura H., Mukai M., Komatsu K., Tanaka-Okamoto M., Itoh Y., Ishizaki H., Tatsuta M., Inoue M., Miyoshi J. Transforming growth factor-β1 induces LMO7 while enhancing the invasiveness of rat ascites hepatoma cells. Cancer Lett. 2005;220:95–99. doi: 10.1016/j.canlet.2004.07.023.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.canlet.2004.07.023</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15737692</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ooshio T., Irie K., Morimoto K., Fukuhara A., Imai T., Takai Y. Involvement of LMO7 in the association of two cell-cell adhesion molecules, nectin and E-cadherin, through afadin and α-actinin in epithelial cells. J. Biol. Chem. 2004;279:31365–31373. doi: 10.1074/jbc.M401957200.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.M401957200</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15140894</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Osman M., Benamrouz S., Guyot K., Baydoun M., Frealle E., Chabe M., Gantois N., Delaire B., Goffard A., Aoun A., Jurdi N., Dabboussi F., Even G., Slomianny C., Gosset P., Hamze M., Creusy C., Viscogliosi E., Certad G. High association of Cryptosporidium spp. infection with colon adenocarcinoma in Lebanese patients. PLoS One. 2017;12 doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0189422.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0189422</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Perkins M.E., Riojas Y.A., Wu T.W., Le Blancq S.M. CpABC, a Cryptosporidium parvum ATP-binding cassette protein at the host-parasite boundary in intracellular. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 1999;A. 96:5734–5739. www.pnas.org</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pinto D.J., Vinayak S. Cryptosporidium: host-parasite interactions and pathogenesis. Curr. Clin. Microbiol. Rep. 2021;8:62–67. doi: 10.1007/s40588-021-00159-7/Published.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40588-021-00159-7/Published</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7868307</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33585166</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Plattner F., Soldati-Favre D. Hijacking of host cellular functions by the apicomplexa. Annu. Rev. Microbiol. 2008;62:471–487. doi: 10.1146/annurev.micro.62.081307.162802.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev.micro.62.081307.162802</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18785844</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ryan U., Zahedi A., Feng Y., Xiao L. An update on zoonotic Cryptosporidium species and genotypes in humans. Animals. 2021;19(11):3307. doi: 10.3390/ani11113307.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ani11113307</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sawant M., Baydoun M., Creusy C., Chabé M., Viscogliosi E., Certad G., Benamrouz-Vanneste S. Cryptosporidium and colon cancer: cause or consequence? Microorganisms. 2020;8:1665. doi: 10.3390/microorganisms8111665.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/microorganisms8111665</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sawant M., Benamrouz-Vanneste S., Mouray A., Bouquet P., Gantois N., Creusy C., Duval E., Mihalache A., Gosset P., Chabé M., Hot D., Viscogliosi E., Certad G. Persistent Cryptosporidium parvum infection leads to the development of the tumor microenvironment in an experimental mouse model: results of a microarray approach. Microorganisms. 2021;9:2569. doi: 10.3390/microorganisms9122569.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/microorganisms9122569</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8704780</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34946170</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scarth J.A., Patterson M.R., Morgan E.L., Macdonald A. The human papillomavirus oncoproteins: a review of the host pathways targeted on the road to transformation. J Gen Virol. 2021;102:1540. doi: 10.1099/jgv.0.001540.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1099/jgv.0.001540</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shlomai A., de Jong Y.P., Rice C.M. Virus associated malignancies: the role of viral hepatitis in hepatocellular carcinoma. Semin. Cancer Biol. 2014;26:78–88. doi: 10.1016/j.semcancer.2014.01.004.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.semcancer.2014.01.004</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4048791</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24457013</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Siddiqui I.A., Pei Y., Arora A., Al Moustafa A.-E., Cyprian F.S., Al-Farsi H.F., Vranic S., Akhtar S. Epstein-Barr virus and Human Papillomaviruses interactions and their roles in the initiation of epithelial-mesenchymal transition and cancer progression. Front. Oncol. 2018;8:111. doi: 10.3389/fonc.2018.00111.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fonc.2018.00111</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5938391</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29765906</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stephens J., Cosyns M., Jones M., Hayward A. Liver and bile duct pathology following Cryptosporidium parvum infection of immunodeficient mice. Hepatology. 1999;30:27–35.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10385635</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sulżyc-Bielicka V., Kołodziejczyk L., Jaczewska S., Bielicki D., Safranow K., Bielicki P., Kładny J., Rogowski W. Colorectal cancer and Cryptosporidium spp. infection. PLoS One. 2018;13(4) doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0195834.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0195834</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Valigurová A., Jirků M., Koudela B., Gelnar M., Modrý D., Šlapeta J. Cryptosporidia: epicellular parasites embraced by the host cell membrane. Int. J. Parasitol. 2008;38(8–9) doi: 10.1016/j.ijpara.2007.11.003.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijpara.2007.11.003</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang Y., Gong A.-Y., Ma S., Chen X., Li Y., Su C.-J., Norall D., Chen J., Strauss-Soukup J.K., Chen X.-M. Delivery of parasite RNA transcripts into infected epithelial cells during Cryptosporidium infection and its potential impact on host gene transcription. J. Infect. Dis. 2017;636:215. doi: 10.1093/infdis/jiw607.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/infdis/jiw607</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu Y., Wei F., Tang L., Liao Q., Wang H., Shi L., Gong Z., Zhang W., Zhou M., Xiang B., Wu X., Li X., Li Y., Li G., Xiong W., Zeng Z., Xiong F., Guo C. Herpesvirus acts with the cytoskeleton and promotes cancer progression. J. Cancer. 2019;10(10) doi: 10.7150/jca.30222.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7150/jca.30222</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zamaraev A.V., Zhivotovsky B., Kopeina G.S. Viral infections: negative regulators of apoptosis and oncogenic factors. Biochem. Mosc. 2020;85(10) doi: 10.1134/S0006297920100077.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1134/S0006297920100077</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang H., Guo F., Zhu G. Involvement of host cell integrin 2 in Cryptosporidium parvum. Infection. 2012 doi: 10.1128/IAI.05862-11.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/IAI.05862-11</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang N., Yu X., Zhang H., Cui L., Li X., Zhang X., Gong P., Li J., Li Z., Wang X., Li X., Li T., Liu X., Yu Y., Zhang X. Prevalence and genotyping of Cryptosporidium parvum in gastrointestinal cancer patients. J. Cancer. 2020;11(11):3334–3339. doi: 10.7150/jca.42393.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7150/jca.42393</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7097938</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32231739</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang G., Zhang Y., Niu Z., Wang C., Xie F., Li J., Zhang S., Qi M., Jian F., Ning C., Zhang L., Wang R. Cryptosporidium parvum upregulates miR-942-5p expression in HCT-8 cells via TLR2/TLR4-NF-κB signaling. Parasit. Vectors. 2020;13(1):435. doi: 10.1186/s13071-020-04312-x.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13071-020-04312-x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7461316</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32867835</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhou R., Hu G., Liu J., Gong A.-Y., Drescher K.M., Chen X.-M. NF-kappaB p65-dependent transactivation of miRNA genes following Cryptosporidium parvum infection stimulates epithelial cell immune responses. PLoS Pathog. 2009;5(12) doi: 10.1371/journal.ppat.1000681.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.ppat.1000681</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
