<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35493764</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>03</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2589-5559</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>4</Volume>
            <Issue>6</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>JHEP reports : innovation in hepatology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>JHEP Rep</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Deprescribing zolpidem reduces falls and fractures in patients with cirrhosis.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>100478</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>100478</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">100478</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jhepr.2022.100478</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND &amp; AIMS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Benzodiazepines are associated with an increased risk of harm in patients with cirrhosis. However, stopping benzodiazepines must be done with care to avoid withdrawal or other unintended consequences. The impact of deprescribing on patients with cirrhosis is unknown.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">We emulated a hypothetical 3-year trial of benzodiazepine deprescription among Medicare enrollees with compensated cirrhosis who lacked other life-limiting diagnoses. All received continuous benzodiazepine prescriptions for the 6-months prior to their diagnosis of cirrhosis. During a 90-day landmark period following their diagnosis of cirrhosis, patients were classified as complete deprescribers (no benzodiazepines dispensed), continuous users, or partial deprescribers. We used inverse probability treatment weighting to compare complete deprescribers to continuous users of traditional benzodiazepines and zolpidem. Outcomes accounted for competing risk of mortality and included incident decompensation (hepatic encephalopathy, ascites, or variceal bleeding), fractures, falls, and alcohol-related hospitalizations.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">There were 1,651 and 1,463 continuous users of traditional benzodiazepines and zolpidem, respectively, and 728 complete deprescribers. Patients were aged a median of 68 years, 24% had alcohol-related cirrhosis. There was no difference in the risk of death or decompensation for continuous users and deprescribers. Among deprescribers of traditional benzodiazepines, there was no improvement in the risk of falls or fractures. However, compared to continuous zolpidem users, deprescribers had a lower risk of falls (23.2% <i>vs.</i> 31%, <i>p</i> = 0.04) and fractures (21% <i>vs.</i> 29%, <i>p</i> = 0.02).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Deprescribing zolpidem reduces the risk of falls and fractures. However, deprescribing benzodiazepines does not improve the risk of decompensation. Efforts to safely address the indications for benzodiazepines such as insomnia and anxiety are urgently needed.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="LAY SUMMARY" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Many people with cirrhosis have anxiety, depression, and sleep disorders. Increasingly, patients with cirrhosis are treated with sedating medications called benzodiazepines, including valium, alprazolam ('Xanax'), clonopin, and the sleep-aid zolpidem ('Ambien'), which can cause falls, broken bones, and maybe other brain disorders. For this reason, many researchers are interested in trials of 'deprescribing' (stopping) benzodiazepines. However, no trials have been performed. We used health record data to simulate a trial of deprescribing. We found that stopping benzodiazepines may reduce the chance of falls or broken bones, but it does not improve survival or liver health.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tapper</LastName>
            <ForeName>Elliot B</ForeName>
            <Initials>EB</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, University of Michigan, MI, United States.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhao</LastName>
            <ForeName>Zhe</ForeName>
            <Initials>Z</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, University of Michigan, MI, United States.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Winder</LastName>
            <ForeName>G Scott</ForeName>
            <Initials>GS</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, University of Michigan, MI, United States.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Parikh</LastName>
            <ForeName>Neehar D</ForeName>
            <Initials>ND</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, University of Michigan, MI, United States.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>03</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>JHEP Rep</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101761237</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2589-5559</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ascites</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">HE, hepatic encephalopathy</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hepatic Encephalopathy</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">IPTW, inverse propensity treatment weighted</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Liver disease</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">NAFLD, non-alcoholic fatty liver disease</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sHR, subdistribution hazard ratio</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">varices</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>Elliot Tapper has served as a consultant to Norvartis, Axcella, and Allergan, has served on advisory boards for Mallinckrodt, Bausch Health, Kaleido, Novo Nordisk, and has received unrestricted research grants from Gilead and Valeant. No other author has a conflict of interest. Please refer to the accompanying ICMJE disclosure forms for further details.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>24</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35493764</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9052149</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhepr.2022.100478</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">S2589-5559(22)00050-7</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tapper E.B., Henderson J.B., Parikh N.D., Ioannou G.N., Lok A.S. Incidence of and risk factors for hepatic encephalopathy in a population-based cohort of Americans with cirrhosis. Hepatol Commun. 2019</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Obiora E., Hubbard R., Sanders R.D., Myles P.R. The impact of benzodiazepines on occurrence of pneumonia and mortality from pneumonia: a nested case-control and survival analysis in a population-based cohort. Thorax. 2013;68:163–170.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23220867</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bajaj J.S., Acharya C., Fagan A., White M.B., Gavis E., Heuman D.M., et al.  Proton pump inhibitor initiation and withdrawal affects gut microbiota and readmission risk in cirrhosis. Am J Gastroenterol. 2018;1</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tapper E.B., Risech-Neyman Y., Sengupta N. Psychoactive medications increase the risk of falls and fall-related injuries in hospitalized patients with cirrhosis. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2015;13:1670–1675.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25818078</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thomson M.J., Lok A.S., Tapper E.B. Appropriate and potentially inappropriate medication use in decompensated cirrhosis. Hepatology. 2020</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tapper E.B., Nikirk S., Parikh N., Zhao L. Falls are common, morbid, and predictable in patients with cirrhosis. J Hepatol. 2021</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Olfson M., King M., Schoenbaum M. Benzodiazepine use in the United States. JAMA psychiatry. 2015;72:136–142.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25517224</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Glass J., Lanctôt K.L., Herrmann N., Sproule B.A., Busto U.E. Sedative hypnotics in older people with insomnia: meta-analysis of risks and benefits. Bmj. 2005;331:1169.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1285093</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16284208</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Williams S., Louissaint J., Nikirk S., Bajaj J.S., Tapper E.B. Deprescribing medications that may increase the risk of hepatic encephalopathy: a qualitative study of patients with cirrhosis and their doctors. United Eur Gastroenterol J. 2020 2050640620975224.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tannenbaum C., Martin P., Tamblyn R., Benedetti A., Ahmed S. Reduction of inappropriate benzodiazepine prescriptions among older adults through direct patient education: the EMPOWER cluster randomized trial. JAMA Intern Med. 2014;174:890–898.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24733354</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martin P., Tamblyn R., Benedetti A., Ahmed S., Tannenbaum C. Effect of a pharmacist-led educational intervention on inappropriate medication prescriptions in older adults: the D-PRESCRIBE randomized clinical trial. Jama. 2018;320:1889–1898.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6248132</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30422193</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hernán M.A., Sauer B.C., Hernández-Díaz S., Platt R., Shrier I. Specifying a target trial prevents immortal time bias and other self-inflicted injuries in observational analyses. J Clin Epidemiol. 2016;79:70–75.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5124536</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27237061</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hernán M.A., Robins J.M. Using big data to emulate a target trial when a randomized trial is not available. Am J Epidemiol. 2016;183:758–764.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4832051</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26994063</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Admon A.J., Donnelly J.P., Casey J.D., Janz D.R., Russell D.W., Joffe A.M., et al.  Emulating a novel clinical trial using existing observational data. Predicting results of the PreVent study. Ann Am Thorac Soc. 2019;16:998–1007.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6774748</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31038996</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Villanueva C., Albillos A., Genescà J., Garcia-Pagan J.C., Calleja J.L., Aracil C., et al.  β blockers to prevent decompensation of cirrhosis in patients with clinically significant portal hypertension (PREDESCI): a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled, multicentre trial. The Lancet. 2019;393:1597–1608.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rakoski M.O., McCammon R.J., Piette J.D., Iwashyna T.J., Marrero J.A., Lok A.S., et al.  Burden of cirrhosis on older Americans and their families: analysis of the health and retirement study. Hepatology. 2012;55:184–191.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3462487</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21858847</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mellinger J.L., Shedden K., Winder G.S., Tapper E., Adams M., Fontana R.J., et al.  The high burden of alcoholic cirrhosis in privately insured persons in the United States. Hepatology. 2018</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Allen A.M., Therneau T.M., Larson J.J., Coward A., Somers V.K., Kamath P.S. Nonalcoholic fatty liver disease incidence and impact on metabolic burden and death: a 20 year-community study. Hepatology. 2018;67:1726–1736.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5866219</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28941364</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li F., Morgan K.L., Zaslavs ky AM. Balancing covariates via propensity score weighting. J Am Stat Assoc. 2018;113:390–400.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fine J.P., Gray R.J. A proportional hazards model for the subdistribution of a competing risk. J Am Stat Assoc. 1999;94:496–509.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee P.-C., Yang Y.-Y., Lin M.-W., Hou M.-C., Huang C.-S., Lee K.-C., et al.  Benzodiazepine-associated hepatic encephalopathy significantly increased healthcare utilization and medical costs of Chinese cirrhotic patients: 7-year experience. Dig Dis Sci. 2014;59:1603–1616.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24482035</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ezaz G., Murphy S.L., Mellinger J., Tapper E.B. Increased morbidity and mortality associated with falls among patients with cirrhosis. Am J Med. 2018</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hill E.L., Cumming R.G., Lewis R., Carrington S., Couteur D.G.L. Sleep disturbances and falls in older people. Journals Gerontol Ser A: Biol Sci Med Sci. 2007;62:62–66.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tapper E.B., Baki J., Parikh N.D., Lok A.S. Frailty, psychoactive medications, and cognitive dysfunction are associated with poor patient-reported outcomes in cirrhosis. Hepatology. 2018</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tapper E.B., Zhao L., Nikirk S., Baki J., Parikh N.D., Lok A.S., et al.  Incidence and bedside predictors of the first episode of overt hepatic encephalopathy in patients with cirrhosis. Off J Am Coll Gastroenterol ACG. 2020</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Murphy S.L., Tapper E.B., Blackwood J., Richardson J.K. Why do individuals with cirrhosis fall? A mechanistic model for fall assessment, treatment, and research. Dig Dis Sci. 2018:1–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29159680</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parr J.M., Kavanagh D.J., Cahill L., Mitchell G., Young R.M. Effectiveness of current treatment approaches for benzodiazepine discontinuation: a meta-analysis. Addiction. 2009;104:13–24.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tapper E.B., Aberasturi D., Zhao Z., Hsu C.Y., Parikh N.D. Outcomes after hepatic encephalopathy in population-based cohorts of patients with cirrhosis. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2020</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
