<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35499330</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>24</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1098-5336</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>88</Volume>
            <Issue>10</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>24</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Applied and environmental microbiology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Appl Environ Microbiol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Viral Proteins Involved in the Adsorption Process of Deep-Purple, a Siphovirus Infecting Members of the Bacillus cereus Group.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e0247821</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e0247821</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1128/aem.02478-21</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The infection of a bacterium by a tailed phage starts from the adsorption process, which consists of a specific and strong interaction between viral proteins called receptor binding proteins (RBPs) and receptors located on the bacterial surface. In addition to RBPs, other tail proteins, such as evolved distal tail (evoDit) proteins and tail lysins, harboring carbohydrate binding modules (CBMs) have been shown to facilitate the phage adsorption by interacting with host polysaccharides. In this work, the proteins involved in the adsorption of Deep-Purple, a siphovirus targeting bacteria of the Bacillus cereus group, were studied. Bioinformatic analysis of Deep-Purple tail protein region revealed that it contains two proteins presenting CBM domains: Gp28, an evoDit protein, and Gp29, the potential RBP. The implication of both proteins in the adsorption of Deep-Purple particles was confirmed through cell wall decoration assays. Interestingly, whereas RBP-Gp29 exhibited the same host spectrum as Deep-Purple, evoDit-Gp28 was able to bind to many B. cereus group strains, including some that are not sensitive to the phage infection. Using immunogold microscopy, both proteins were shown to be located in the phage baseplate. Additionally, an <i>in silico</i> analysis of the tail regions encoded by several <i>Siphoviridae</i> infecting the B. cereus group was performed. It revealed that although the tail organization displayed by Deep-Purple is the most prevalent, different tail arrangements are observed, suggesting that distinct baseplate organization and adsorption mechanisms are encountered in siphoviruses targeting the B. cereus group. <b>IMPORTANCE</b> The B. cereus group is a complex cluster of closely related species, among which certain strains can be pathogenic (i.e., Bacillus anthracis, Bacillus cereus <i>sensu stricto</i>, and Bacillus cytotoxicus). Nowadays, phages are receiving increasing attention for applications in controlling and detecting such pathogens. Thus, understanding the molecular mechanisms governing the phage adsorption to its bacterial host is paramount as this step is a key determinant of the phage host spectrum. Until now, the knowledge regarding the adsorption process of tailed phage targeting the B. cereus groups was mainly restricted to the phage gamma infecting B. anthracis. With this work, we provide novel insights into the adsorption of Deep-Purple, a siphovirus infecting the B. cereus group. We showed that this phage recognizes polysaccharides and relies on two different viral proteins for its successful adsorption.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Leprince</LastName>
            <ForeName>Audrey</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8068-1365</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Laboratory of Food and Environmental Microbiology, Earth and Life Institute, Université catholique de Louvain, Louvain-la-Neuve, Belgium.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nuytten</LastName>
            <ForeName>Manon</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Laboratory of Food and Environmental Microbiology, Earth and Life Institute, Université catholique de Louvain, Louvain-la-Neuve, Belgium.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mahillon</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jacques</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4463-1328</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Laboratory of Food and Environmental Microbiology, Earth and Life Institute, Université catholique de Louvain, Louvain-la-Neuve, Belgium.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>02</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Appl Environ Microbiol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>7605801</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0099-2240</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Siphoviridae</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">adsorption</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">distal tail protein</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">phages</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">receptor binding protein</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
          <Hour>9</Hour>
          <Minute>3</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35499330</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/aem.02478-21</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
