<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35505465</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>04</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2036</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>03</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Alimentary pharmacology &amp; therapeutics</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Aliment Pharmacol Ther</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Systematic review-Pancreatic involvement in inflammatory bowel disease.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/apt.16949</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Inflammatory bowel disease (IBD) is a chronic inflammatory immune-mediated disorder of the gut with frequent extra-intestinal complications. Pancreatic involvement in IBD is not uncommon and comprises a heterogeneous group of conditions, including acute pancreatitis (AP), chronic pancreatitis (CP), autoimmune pancreatitis (AIP) and pancreatic exocrine insufficiency (PEI); however, data on such an association remain sparse and heterogeneous.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHOD" NlmCategory="METHODS">PubMed/MEDLINE and EMBASE databases were searched for studies investigating pancreatic involvement in patients with IBD.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Four thousand one hundred and twenty-one records were identified and 547 screened; finally, 124 studies were included in the review. AP is the most frequent pancreatic manifestation in IBD; the majority of AP cases in IBD are due to gallstones and drugs but cases of idiopathic AP are increasingly reported. AIP is a rare disease, but a strong association with IBD has been demonstrated, especially for type 2 and ulcerative colitis. The pathogenetic link between IBD and AIP remains unclear, but an immune-mediated pathway seems plausible. An association between CP and PEI with IBD has also been suggested, but data are to date scarce and conflicting.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This is the first systematic review of the association between IBD and pancreatic diseases. Gallstones and drugs should be considered the most probable causes of AP in IBD, with type 2 AIP also being possible.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Authors. Alimentary Pharmacology &amp; Therapeutics published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Massironi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sara</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3214-8192</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medicine and Surgery, University of Milano-Bicocca, Monza, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology and Center for Autoimmune Liver Diseases, European Reference Network on Hepatological Diseases (ERN RARE-LIVER), San Gerardo Hospital, Monza, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Fanetti</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ilaria</ForeName>
            <Initials>I</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Gastroenterology and Endoscopy Unit, ASST Ovest Milanese, Legnano Hospital, Legnano, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Viganò</LastName>
            <ForeName>Chiara</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medicine and Surgery, University of Milano-Bicocca, Monza, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology and Center for Autoimmune Liver Diseases, European Reference Network on Hepatological Diseases (ERN RARE-LIVER), San Gerardo Hospital, Monza, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Pirola</LastName>
            <ForeName>Lorena</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medicine and Surgery, University of Milano-Bicocca, Monza, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology and Center for Autoimmune Liver Diseases, European Reference Network on Hepatological Diseases (ERN RARE-LIVER), San Gerardo Hospital, Monza, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Fichera</LastName>
            <ForeName>Maria</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medicine and Surgery, University of Milano-Bicocca, Monza, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology and Center for Autoimmune Liver Diseases, European Reference Network on Hepatological Diseases (ERN RARE-LIVER), San Gerardo Hospital, Monza, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Cristoferi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Laura</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medicine and Surgery, University of Milano-Bicocca, Monza, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology and Center for Autoimmune Liver Diseases, European Reference Network on Hepatological Diseases (ERN RARE-LIVER), San Gerardo Hospital, Monza, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Capurso</LastName>
            <ForeName>Gabriele</ForeName>
            <Initials>G</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Pancreas Translational &amp; Clinical Research Center, Pancreato-Biliary Endoscopy &amp; Endosonography Division, San Raffaele Scientific Institute IRCCS, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Invernizzi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Pietro</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3262-1998</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medicine and Surgery, University of Milano-Bicocca, Monza, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology and Center for Autoimmune Liver Diseases, European Reference Network on Hepatological Diseases (ERN RARE-LIVER), San Gerardo Hospital, Monza, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Danese</LastName>
            <ForeName>Silvio</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7341-1351</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Gastroenterology and Endoscopy, IRCCS Ospedale San Raffaele and Vita-Salute San Raffaele University, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>03</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Aliment Pharmacol Ther</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8707234</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0269-2813</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>31</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>31</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
          <Hour>0</Hour>
          <Minute>3</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35505465</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/apt.16949</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vavricka SR, Schoepfer A, Scharl M, Lakatos PL, Navarini A, Rogler G. Extraintestinal manifestations of inflammatory bowel disease. Inflamm Bowel Dis. 2015;21(8):1982-92.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fousekis FS, Theopistos VI, Katsanos KH, Christodoulou DK. Pancreatic involvement in inflammatory bowel disease: a review. J Clin Med Res. 2018;10(10):743-51.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ramos LR, Sachar DB, DiMaio CJ, Colombel JF, Torres J. Inflammatory bowel disease and pancreatitis: a review. J Crohns Colitis. 2016;10(1):95-104.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Page MJ, Moher D, Bossuyt PM, Boutron I, Hoffmann TC, Mulrow CD, et al. PRISMA 2020 explanation and elaboration: updated guidance and exemplars for reporting systematic reviews. BMJ. 2021;372:n160.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wells GASB, O'Connell D. The Newcastle-Ottawa scale (NOS) for assessing the quality of nonrandomised studies in meta-analyses. Ottawa: Ottawa Hospital Research Institute; 2014. http://www.ohri.ca/programs/clinical_epidemiology/oxford.asp</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Spanier BW, Dijkgraaf MG, Bruno MJ. Epidemiology, aetiology and outcome of acute and chronic pancreatitis: an update. Best Pract Res Clin Gastroenterol. 2008;22(1):45-63.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mathews SC, Izmailyan S, Brito FA, Yamal JM, Mikhail O, Revere FL. Prevalence and financial burden of digestive diseases in a commercially insured population. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2021;S1542-3565(21):00711-4.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen YT, Su JS, Tseng CW, Chen CC, Lin CL, Kao CH. Inflammatory bowel disease on the risk of acute pancreatitis: a population-based cohort study. J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2016;31(4):782-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bermejo F, Lopez-Sanroman A, Taxonera C, Gisbert JP, Pérez-Calle JL, Vera I, et al. Acute pancreatitis in inflammatory bowel disease, with special reference to azathioprine-induced pancreatitis. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2008;28(5):623-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weber P, Seibold F, Jenss H. Acute pancreatitis in Crohn's disease. J Clin Gastroenterol. 1993;17(4):286-91.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rasmussen HH, Fonager K, Sørensen HT, Pedersen L, Dahlerup JF, Steffensen FH. Risk of acute pancreatitis in patients with chronic inflammatory bowel disease. A Danish 16-year nationwide follow-up study. Scand J Gastroenterol. 1999;34(2):199-201.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>G G, de Paredes A, et al. Idiopathic acute pancreatitis in patients with inflammatory bowel disease: a multicenter cohort study. Pancreatology. 2020;20:331-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Broide E, Dotan I, Weiss B, Wilschanski M, Yerushalmi B, Klar A, et al. Idiopathic pancreatitis preceding the diagnosis of inflammatory bowel disease is more frequent in pediatric patients. J Pediatr Gastroenterol Nutr. 2011;52(6):714-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pedersen JE, Ängquist LH, Jensen CB, Kjaergaard JS, Jess T, Allin KH. Risk of pancreatitis in patients with inflammatory bowel disease - a meta-analysis. Dan Med J. 2020;67(3):A08190427.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tél B, Stubnya B, Gede N, Varjú P, Kiss Z, Márta K, et al. Inflammatory bowel diseases elevate the risk of developing acute pancreatitis: a meta-analysis. Pancreas. 2020;49(9):1174-81.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Banks PA, Bollen TL, Dervenis C, Gooszen HG, Johnson CD, Sarr MG, et al. Classification of acute pancreatitis--2012: revision of the Atlanta classification and definitions by international consensus. Gut. 2013;62(1):102-11.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang FM, Xu CF, Shan GD, Chen HT, Xu GQ. Is gallstone disease associated with inflammatory bowel diseases? A meta-analysis. J Dig Dis. 2015;16(11):634-41.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parente F, Pastore L, Bargiggia S, Cucino C, Greco S, Molteni M, et al. Incidence and risk factors for gallstones in patients with inflammatory bowel disease: a large case-control study. Hepatology. 2007;45(5):1267-74.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fagagnini S, Heinrich H, Rossel JB, Biedermann L, Frei P, Zeitz J, et al. Risk factors for gallstones and kidney stones in a cohort of patients with inflammatory bowel diseases. PLoS One. 2017;12(10):e0185193.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maurer P, Haag K, Roth M, Kuder C, Schölmerich J. No evidence for abnormal gallbladder emptying in Crohn's disease. Hepatogastroenterology. 1996;43(10):807-12.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pitt HA, King W III, Mann LL, Roslyn JJ, Berquist WE, Ament ME, et al. Increased risk of cholelithiasis with prolonged total parenteral nutrition. Am J Surg. 1983;145(1):106-12.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Antonini F, Pezzilli R, Angelelli L, Macarri G. Pancreatic disorders in inflammatory bowel disease. World J Gastrointest Pathophysiol. 2016;7(3):276-82.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lankisch PG, Droge M, Gottesleben F. Drug induced acute pancreatitis: incidence and severity. Gut. 1995;37(4):565-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Trivedi CD, Pitchumoni CS. Drug-induced pancreatitis: an update. J Clin Gastroenterol. 2005;39(8):709-16.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weersma RK, Peters FTM, Oostenbrug LE, van den Berg AP, van Haastert M, Ploeg RJ, et al. Increased incidence of azathioprine-induced pancreatitis in Crohn's disease compared with other diseases. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2004;20(8):843-50.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Floyd A, Pedersen L, Nielsen GL, Thorlacius-Ussing O, Sorensen HT. Risk of acute pancreatitis in users of azathioprine: a population-based case-control study. Am J Gastroenterol. 2003;98(6):1305-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peixoto A et al. Azathioprine-induced acute pancreatitis in inflammatory bowel disease : natural history and severity spectrum. Acta Gastroenterol Belg. 2017;80(1):87-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Teich N, Mohl W, Bokemeyer B, Bündgens B, Büning J, Miehlke S, et al. Azathioprine-induced acute pancreatitis in patients with inflammatory bowel diseases-a prospective study on incidence and severity. J Crohns Colitis. 2016;10(1):61-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sturdevant RA et al. Azathioprine-related pancreatitis in patients with Crohn's disease. Gastroenterology. 1979;77(4 Pt 2):883-6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Present DH, Korelitz BI, Wisch N, Glass JL, Sachar DB, Pasternack BS. Treatment of Crohn's disease with 6-mercaptopurine. A long-term, randomized, double-blind study. N Engl J Med. 1980;302(18):981-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nogueira JR, Freedman MA. Acute pancreatitis as a complication of Imuran therapy in regional enteritis. Gastroenterology. 1972;62(5):1040-1.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Timmer A et al. Azathioprine and 6-mercaptopurine for maintenance of remission in ulcerative colitis. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2016;5:Cd000478.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ledder O, Lemberg DA, Day AS. Thiopurine-induced pancreatitis in inflammatory bowel diseases. Expert Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2015;9(4):399-403.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eskazan T, Bozcan S, Atay K, Yildirim S, Demir N, Celik S, et al. Frequency, predisposing factors, and clinical outcome of azathioprine-induced pancreatitis among patients with inflammatory bowel disease: results from a tertiary referral center. Pancreas. 2021;50(9):1274-80.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wilson A, Jansen LE, Rose RV, Gregor JC, Ponich T, Chande N, et al. HLA-DQA1-HLA-DRB1 polymorphism is a major predictor of azathioprine-induced pancreatitis in patients with inflammatory bowel disease. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2018;47(5):615-20.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heap GA et al. HLA-DQA1-HLA-DRB1 variants confer susceptibility to pancreatitis induced by thiopurine immunosuppressants. Nat Genet. 2014;46(10):1131-4.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu YP, Wu HY, Yang X, Xu HQ, Li YC, Shi DC, et al. Association between thiopurine S-methyltransferase polymorphisms and thiopurine-induced adverse drug reactions in patients with inflammatory bowel disease: a meta-analysis. PLoS One. 2015;10(3):e0121745.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wilson A, Wang Q, Choi YH, Ponich T, Gregor JC, Chande N, et al. Pretreatment HLADQA1-HLADRB1 testing for the prevention of azathioprine-induced pancreatitis in inflammatory bowel disease: a prospective cohort study. Clin Transl Gastroenterol. 2021;12(4):e00332.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Teich N, Bokemeyer B, Mohl W, Walldorf J, Bruns T, Schmidt C, et al. Blood group B is associated with azathioprine-induced acute pancreatitis in patients with IBD. Gut. 2017;66(8):1531-2.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Block MB, Genant HK, Kirsner JB. Pancreatitis as an adverse reaction to salicylazosulfapyridine. N Engl J Med. 1970;282(7):380-2.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meczker A, Miko A, Hegyi P. 5-ASA induces mild acute pancreatitis. Case report and review of the literature. J Gastrointestin Liver Dis. 2018;27(2):189-94.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Munk EM, Pedersen L, Floyd A, Norgard B, Rasmussen HH, Sorensen HT. Inflammatory bowel diseases, 5-aminosalicylic acid and sulfasalazine treatment and risk of acute pancreatitis: a population-based case-control study. Am J Gastroenterol. 2004;99(5):884-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ransford RA, Langman MJ. Sulphasalazine and mesalazine: serious adverse reactions re-evaluated on the basis of suspected adverse reaction reports to the committee on safety of medicines. Gut. 2002;51(4):536-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garau P, Orenstein SR, Neigut DA, Kocoshis SA. Pancreatitis associated with olsalazine and sulfasalazine in children with ulcerative colitis. J Pediatr Gastroenterol Nutr. 1994;18(4):481-5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Isaacs KL, Murphy D. Pancreatitis after rectal administration of 5-aminosalicylic acid. J Clin Gastroenterol. 1990;12(2):198-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Russo L, Schneider G, Gardiner MH, Lanes S, Streck P, Rosen S. Role of pharmacoepidemiology studies in addressing pharmacovigilance questions: a case example of pancreatitis risk among ulcerative colitis patients using mesalazine. Eur J Clin Pharmacol. 2014;70(6):709-17.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fernandez J et al. Acute pancreatitis after long-term 5-aminosalicylic acid therapy. Am J Gastroenterol. 1997;92(12):2302-3.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Faintuch J, Mott CB, Machado MC. Pancreatitis and pancreatic necrosis during sulfasalazine therapy. Int Surg. 1985;70(3):271-2.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pitchumoni CS, Rubin A, Das K. Pancreatitis in inflammatory bowel diseases. J Clin Gastroenterol. 2010;44(4):246-53.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Werlang, M.E., M.D. Lewis, and M.J. Bartel, Tumor necrosis factor alpha inhibitor-induced acute pancreatitis, In ACG Case Rep J. 2017: United States p e103.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Picardo S, So K, Venugopal K, Chin M. Vedolizumab-induced acute pancreatitis: the first reported clinical case. BMJ Case Rep. 2018; bcr2017222554.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li WD, Jia L, Ou Y, Jiang SM, Qiu JH, Huang YX et al. Infliximab: protective effect to intestinal barrier function of rat with acute necrosis pancreatitis at early stage. Pancreas. 2013;42(2):366-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huang YX, Li WD, Jia L, Qiu JH, Jiang SM, Ou Y, et al. Infliximab enhances the therapeutic effectiveness of octreotide on acute necrotizing pancreatitis in rat model. Pancreas. 2012;41(6):849-54.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Norman JG, Fink GW, Messina J, Carter G, Franz MG. Timing of tumor necrosis factor antagonism is critical in determining outcome in murine lethal acute pancreatitis. Surgery. 1996;120(3):515-21.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thiéfin G, Morelet A, Heurgué A, Diebold MD, Eschard JP. Infliximab-induced hepatitis: absence of cross-toxicity with etanercept. Joint Bone Spine. 2008;75(6):737-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Simons-Linares CR, Elkhouly MA, Salazar MJ. Drug-induced acute pancreatitis in adults: an update. Pancreas. 2019;48(10):1263-73.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koutroubakis IE, Oustamanolakis P, Malliaraki N, Karmiris K, Chalkiadakis I, Ganotakis E, et al. Effects of tumor necrosis factor alpha inhibition with infliximab on lipid levels and insulin resistance in patients with inflammatory bowel disease. Eur J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2009;21(3):283-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Spanakis E, Sidiropoulos P, Papadakis J, Ganotakis E, Katsikas G, Karvounaris S, et al. Modest but sustained increase of serum high density lipoprotein cholesterol levels in patients with inflammatory arthritides treated with infliximab. J Rheumatol. 2006;33(12):2440-6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Youssef I et al. Metronidazole-induced pancreatitis: is there Underrecognition? A case report and systematic review of the literature. Case Rep Gastrointest Med. 2019;2019:4840539.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barbulescu A, Oskarsson V, Lindblad M, Ljung R, Brooke HL. Oral metronidazole use and risk of acute pancreatitis: a population-based case-control study. Clin Epidemiol. 2018;10:1573-81.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sura ME, Heinrich KA, Suseno M. Metronidazole-associated pancreatitis. Ann Pharmacother. 2000;34(10):1152-5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Caplan A, Fett N, Rosenbach M, Werth VP, Micheletti RG. Prevention and management of glucocorticoid-induced side effects: a comprehensive review: gastrointestinal and endocrinologic side effects. J Am Acad Dermatol. 2017;76(1):11-6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sadr-Azodi O, Mattsson F, Bexlius TS, Lindblad M, Lagergren J, Ljung R. Association of oral glucocorticoid use with an increased risk of acute pancreatitis: a population-based nested case-control study. JAMA Intern Med. 2013;173(6):444-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dwivedi P, Kumar RR, Dhooria A, Adarsh MB, Malhotra S, Kakkar N, et al. Corticosteroid-associated lupus pancreatitis: a case series and systematic review of the literature. Lupus. 2019;28(6):731-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chrousos GA et al. Side effects of glucocorticoid treatment. Experience of the optic neuritis treatment trial. JAMA. 1993;269(16):2110-2.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wolfe D, Kanji S, Yazdi F, Barbeau P, Rice D, Beck A, et al. Drug induced pancreatitis: a systematic review of case reports to determine potential drug associations. PLoS One. 2020;15(4):e0231883.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meczker Á, Hanák L, Párniczky A, Szentesi A, Erőss B, Hegyi P, et al. Analysis of 1060 cases of drug-induced acute pancreatitis. Gastroenterology. 2020;159(5):1958-1961.e8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Almarri, N.M., Alobaidli A.J., Almarhabi A.A., Alshammari M.A., Acute pancreatitis as an initial presentation of Crohn's disease: a case report, in J Family Med Prim Care. 2019, Copyright: (c) 2019 Journal of Family Medicine and Primary Care.: India. p. 3752-3754, 8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iida T, Wagatsuma K, Hirayama D, Yokoyama Y, Nakase H. The etiology of pancreatic manifestations in patients with inflammatory bowel disease. J Clin Med. 2019;8(7):916.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ananthakrishnan AN, Cagan A, Gainer VS, Cheng SC, Cai T, Szolovits P, et al. Mortality and extraintestinal cancers in patients with primary sclerosing cholangitis and inflammatory bowel disease. J Crohns Colitis. 2014;8(9):956-63.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Legge DA, Hoffman HN 2nd, Carlson HC. Pancreatitis as a complication of regional enteritis of the duodenum. Gastroenterology. 1971;61(6):834-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meltzer SJ, Korelitz BI. Pancreatitis and duodenopancreatic reflux in Crohn's disease. Case report and review of the literature. J Clin Gastroenterol. 1988;10(5):555-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gschwantler M, Kogelbauer G, Klose W, Bibus B, Tscholakoff D, Weiss W. The pancreas as a site of granulomatous inflammation in Crohn's disease. Gastroenterology. 1995;108(4):1246-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Spiceland CM, Lodhia N. Endoscopy in inflammatory bowel disease: role in diagnosis, management, and treatment. World J Gastroenterol. 2018;24(35):4014-20.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aktas H, Mensink P, Haringsma J, Kuipers E. Low incidence of hyperamylasemia after proximal double-balloon enteroscopy: has the insertion technique improved? Endoscopy. 2009;41(8):670-3.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zepeda-Gomez S et al. Risk of hyperamylasemia and acute pancreatitis after double-balloon enteroscopy: a prospective study. Endoscopy. 2011;43(9):766-70.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Feng N, Dai J, Lu H, Li XB, Gao YJ, Ge ZZ. Hyperamylasemia is associated with increased intestinal permeability in patients undergoing diagnostic oral double-balloon enteroscopy. World J Gastroenterol. 2014;20(2):539-45.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pata C, Akyüz U, Erzin Y, Mutlu N, Mercan A, Dirican A. Post-procedure elevated amylase and lipase levels after double-balloon enteroscopy: relations with the double-balloon technique. Dig Dis Sci. 2010;55(7):1982-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Domagk D, Mensink P, Aktas H, Lenz P, Meister T, Luegering A, et al. Single- vs. double-balloon enteroscopy in small-bowel diagnostics: a randomized multicenter trial. Endoscopy. 2011;43(6):472-6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim TJ, Kim ER, Chang DK, Kim YH, Hong SN. Comparison of the efficacy and safety of single- versus double-balloon Enteroscopy performed by Endoscopist experts in single-balloon Enteroscopy: a single-center experience and meta-analysis. Gut Liver. 2017;11(4):520-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lipka S, Rabbanifard R, Kumar A, Brady P. Single versus double balloon enteroscopy for small bowel diagnostics: a systematic review and meta-analysis. J Clin Gastroenterol. 2015;49(3):177-84.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Latorre R, López-Albors O, Soria F, Morcillo E, Esteban P, Pérez-Cuadrado-Robles E, et al. Evidences supporting the vascular etiology of post-double balloon enteroscopy pancreatitis: study in porcine model. World J Gastroenterol. 2017;23(34):6201-11.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fricker ZP, Lichtenstein DR. Primary Sclerosing cholangitis: a concise review of diagnosis and management. Dig Dis Sci. 2019;64(3):632-42.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boonstra K, Beuers U, Ponsioen CY. Epidemiology of primary sclerosing cholangitis and primary biliary cirrhosis: a systematic review. J Hepatol. 2012;56(5):1181-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Karlsen TH, Folseraas T, Thorburn D, Vesterhus M. Primary sclerosing cholangitis - a comprehensive review. J Hepatol. 2017;67(6):1298-323.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ji SG et al. Genome-wide association study of primary sclerosing cholangitis identifies new risk loci and quantifies the genetic relationship with inflammatory bowel disease. Nat Genet. 2017;49(2):269-73.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goldin E, Libson E, Wengrower D, Antal S, Kovacs Z, Rachmilewitz D. Severe acute pancreatitis as the presenting symptom of primary sclerosing cholangitis: treatment by endoscopic insertion of a biliary stent. Int Surg. 1990;75(1):58-60.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matsushita M, Nagasawa M, Sato Y, Souda KI, Kobayashi Y. Primary sclerosing cholangitis associated with limy bile and acute pancreatitis. Pancreatology. 2005;5(4-5):466-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>von Seth E, Arnelo U, Enochsson L, Bergquist A. Primary sclerosing cholangitis increases the risk for pancreatitis after endoscopic retrograde cholangiopancreatography. Liver Int. 2015;35(1):254-62.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shimosegawa T, Chari ST, Frulloni L, Kamisawa T, Kawa S, Mino-Kenudson M, et al. International consensus diagnostic criteria for autoimmune pancreatitis: guidelines of the International Association of Pancreatology. Pancreas. 2011;40(3):352-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Majumder S, Takahashi N, Chari ST. Autoimmune Pancreatitis. Dig Dis Sci. 2017;62(7):1762-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tsen A, Alishahi Y, Rosenkranz L. Autoimmune pancreatitis and inflammatory bowel disease: an updated review. J Clin Gastroenterol. 2017;51(3):208-14.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sah, R.P., Chari S.T., Pannala R., Sugumar A., Clain J.E., Levy M.J., Pearson R.K., Smyrk T.C., Petersen B.T., Topazian M.D., Takahashi N., Farnell M.B., Vege S.S., Differences in clinical profile and relapse rate of type 1 versus type 2 autoimmune pancreatitis. Gastroenterology, 2010. 139(1): p. 140-8; quiz e12-3.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hart PA, Zen Y, Chari ST. Recent advances in autoimmune pancreatitis. Gastroenterology. 2015;149(1):39-51.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kanno A, Masamune A, Okazaki K, Kamisawa T, Kawa S, Nishimori I, et al. Nationwide epidemiological survey of autoimmune pancreatitis in Japan in 2011. Pancreas. 2015;44(4):535-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ueki T, Kawamoto K, Otsuka Y, Minoda R, Maruo T, Matsumura K, et al. Prevalence and clinicopathological features of autoimmune pancreatitis in Japanese patients with inflammatory bowel disease. Pancreas. 2015;44(3):434-40.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Park SH, Kim D, Ye BD, Yang SK, Kim JH, Yang DH, et al. The characteristics of ulcerative colitis associated with autoimmune pancreatitis. J Clin Gastroenterol. 2013;47(6):520-5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barthet M, Hastier P, Bernard JP, Bordes G, Frederick J, Allio S, et al. Chronic pancreatitis and inflammatory bowel disease: true or coincidental association? Am J Gastroenterol. 1999;94(8):2141-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ravi K, Chari ST, Vege SS, Sandborn WJ, Smyrk TC, Loftus EV Jr. Inflammatory bowel disease in the setting of autoimmune pancreatitis. Inflamm Bowel Dis. 2009;15(9):1326-30.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schneider A, Hirth M, Weiss C, Weidner P, Antoni C, Thomann A, et al. Prevalence of inflammatory bowel disease in alcoholic, non-alcoholic and autoimmune pancreatitis. Z Gastroenterol. 2018;56(5):469-78.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kamisawa T, Chari ST, Giday SA, Kim MH, Chung JB, Lee KT, et al. Clinical profile of autoimmune pancreatitis and its histological subtypes: an international multicenter survey. Pancreas. 2011;40(6):809-14.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Srinath AI, Gupta N, Husain SZ. Probing the Association of Pancreatitis in inflammatory bowel disease. Inflamm Bowel Dis. 2016;22(2):465-75.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lorenzo D, Maire F, Stefanescu C, Gornet JM, Seksik P, Serrero M, et al. Features of autoimmune pancreatitis associated with inflammatory bowel diseases. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2018;16(1):59-67.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sakai Y, Kobayashi M. Lymphocyte 'homing' and chronic inflammation. Pathol Int. 2015;65(7):344-54.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Notohara K, Burgart LJ, Yadav D, Chari S, Smyrk TC. Idiopathic chronic pancreatitis with periductal lymphoplasmacytic infiltration: clinicopathologic features of 35 cases. Am J Surg Pathol. 2003;27(8):1119-27.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zamboni G, Luettges J, Capelli P, Frulloni L, Cavallini G, Pederzoli P, et al. Histopathological features of diagnostic and clinical relevance in autoimmune pancreatitis: a study on 53 resection specimens and 9 biopsy specimens. Virchows Arch. 2004;445(6):552-63.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Song TJ, Kim JH, Kim MH, Jang JW, Park DH, Lee SS, et al. Comparison of clinical findings between histologically confirmed type 1 and type 2 autoimmune pancreatitis. J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2012;27(4):700-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kloppel G et al. Autoimmune pancreatitis: the clinicopathological characteristics of the subtype with granulocytic epithelial lesions. J Gastroenterol. 2010;45(8):787-93.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Topal F, Saritas Yuksel E, Ekinci N, Pekdiker M, Cakalagaoglu F, Alper E, et al. The prevalence of IgG4-positive plasma cell infiltrates in inflammatory bowel disease patients without autoimmune pancreatitis. Turk J Gastroenterol. 2014;25(5):558-62.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sandanayake NS, Church NI, Chapman MH, Johnson GJ, Dhar DK, Amin Z, et al. Presentation and management of post-treatment relapse in autoimmune pancreatitis/immunoglobulin G4-associated cholangitis. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2009;7(10):1089-96.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chiabrando F, Lanzillotta M, Palumbo D, Pedica F, Caruso M, Capurso G, et al. Treating type 2 autoimmune pancreatitis with colchicine: a case series. Ann Intern Med. 2021;174(12):1775-6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barthet M, Lesavre N, Desplats S, Panuel M, Gasmi M, Bernard JP, et al. Frequency and characteristics of pancreatitis in patients with inflammatory bowel disease. Pancreatology. 2006;6(5):464-71.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupte A, Goede D, Tuite R, Forsmark CE. Chronic pancreatitis. BMJ. 2018;361:k2126.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Axon AT, Ashton MG, Lintott DJ. Chronic pancreatitis and inflammatory bowel disease. Clin Radiol. 1979;30(2):179-82.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen YL, Hsu CW, Cheng CC, Yiang GT, Lin CS, Lin CL, et al. Increased subsequent risk of inflammatory bowel disease association in patients with chronic pancreatitis: a nationwide population-based cohort study. Curr Med Res Opin. 2017;33(6):1077-82.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singh VK, Haupt ME, Geller DE, Hall JA, Diez PMQ. Less common etiologies of exocrine pancreatic insufficiency. World J Gastroenterol. 2017;23(39):7059-76.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maconi G, Dominici R, Molteni M, Ardizzone S, Bosani M, Ferrara E, et al. Prevalence of pancreatic insufficiency in inflammatory bowel diseases. Assessment by fecal elastase-1. Dig Dis Sci. 2008;53(1):262-70.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Piontek M, Hengels KJ, Strohmeyer G. Crohn's disease: what about the pancreas? J Clin Gastroenterol. 1990;12(5):491-3.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hegnhoj J, Hansen CP, Rannem T, Sobirk H, Andersen LB, Andersen JR. Pancreatic function in Crohn's disease. Gut. 1990;31(9):1076-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Seibold F, Weber P, Jenss H, Wiedmann KH. Antibodies to a trypsin sensitive pancreatic antigen in chronic inflammatory bowel disease: specific markers for a subgroup of patients with Crohn's disease. Gut. 1991;32(10):1192-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Seibold F, Mork H, Tanza S, Muller A, Holzhuter C, Weber P, et al. Pancreatic autoantibodies in Crohn's disease: a family study. Gut. 1997;40(4):481-4.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hedstrom A et al. Pancreatic exocrine insufficiency and Crohn's disease. Minerva Gastroenterol Dietol. 2019;19:S52.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Toda N, Akahane M, Kiryu S, Matsubara Y, Yamaji Y, Okamoto M, et al. Pancreas duct abnormalities in patients with ulcerative colitis: a magnetic resonance pancreatography study. Inflamm Bowel Dis. 2005;11(10):903-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Capurso G, Traini M, Piciucchi M, Signoretti M, Arcidiacono PG. Exocrine pancreatic insufficiency: prevalence, diagnosis, and management. Clin Exp Gastroenterol. 2019;12:129-39.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Loser C, Mollgaard A, Folsch UR. Faecal elastase 1: a novel, highly sensitive, and specific tubeless pancreatic function test. Gut. 1996;39(4):580-6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Partelli S, Frulloni L, Minniti C, Bassi C, Barugola G, D’Onofrio M, et al. Faecal elastase-1 is an independent predictor of survival in advanced pancreatic cancer. Dig Liver Dis. 2012;44(11):945-51.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dominguez-Munoz JE et al. Potential for screening for pancreatic exocrine insufficiency using the fecal Elastase-1 test. Dig Dis Sci. 2017;62(5):1119-30.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Keller J, Aghdassi AA, Lerch MM, Mayerle JV, Layer P. Tests of pancreatic exocrine function - clinical significance in pancreatic and non-pancreatic disorders. Best Pract Res Clin Gastroenterol. 2009;23(3):425-39.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jung YS, Han M, Park S, Kim WH, Cheon JH. Cancer risk in the early stages of inflammatory bowel disease in Korean patients: a Nationwide population-based study. J Crohns Colitis. 2017;11(8):954-62.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yu J, Refsum E, Helsingen LM, Folseraas T, Ploner A, Wieszczy P, et al. Risk of hepato-pancreato-biliary cancer is increased by primary sclerosing cholangitis in patients with inflammatory bowel disease: a population-based cohort study. United European Gastroenterol J. 2022;10:212-24.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Katz S, Bank S, Greenberg RE, Lendvai S, Lesser M, Napolitano B. Hyperamylasemia in inflammatory bowel disease. J Clin Gastroenterol. 1988;10(6):627-30.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bokemeyer B. Asymptomatic elevation of serum lipase and amylase in conjunction with Crohn's disease and ulcerative colitis. Z Gastroenterol. 2002;40(1):5-10.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Seibold F, Scheurlen M, Müller A, Jenss H, Weber P. Impaired pancreatic function in patients with Crohn's disease with and without pancreatic autoantibodies. J Clin Gastroenterol. 1996;22(3):202-6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heikius B, Niemelä S, Lehtola J, Karttunen TJ. Elevated pancreatic enzymes in inflammatory bowel disease are associated with extensive disease. Am J Gastroenterol. 1999;94(4):1062-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stöcker W, Otte M, Ulrich S, Normann D, Finkbeiner H, Stöcker K, et al. Autoimmunity to pancreatic juice in Crohn's disease. Results of an autoantibody screening in patients with chronic inflammatory bowel disease. Scand J Gastroenterol Suppl. 1987;139:41-52.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pavlidis P et al. Ileal inflammation may trigger the development of GP2-specific pancreatic autoantibodies in patients with Crohn's disease. Clin Dev Immunol. 2012;2012:640835.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bogdanos DP, Rigopoulou EI, Smyk DS, Roggenbuck D, Reinhold D, Forbes A, et al. Diagnostic value, clinical utility and pathogenic significance of reactivity to the molecular targets of Crohn's disease specific-pancreatic autoantibodies. Autoimmun Rev. 2011;11(2):143-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bogdanos DP, Roggenbuck D, Reinhold D, Wex T, Pavlidis P, von Arnim U, et al. Pancreatic-specific autoantibodies to glycoprotein 2 mirror disease location and behaviour in younger patients with Crohn's disease. BMC Gastroenterol. 2012;12:102.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smyk DS et al. Autoantibodies in autoimmune pancreatitis. Int J Rheumatol. 2012;2012:940831.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gross S, Bakker SF, van Bodegraven AA, van Hoogstraten IMW, Gelderman KA, Bouma G, et al. Increased IgA glycoprotein-2 specific antibody titres in refractory celiac disease. J Gastrointestin Liver Dis. 2014;23(2):127-33.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tornai T, Tornai D, Sipeki N, Tornai I, Alsulaimani R, Fechner K, et al. Loss of tolerance to gut immunity protein, glycoprotein 2 (GP2) is associated with progressive disease course in primary sclerosing cholangitis. Sci Rep. 2018;8(1):399.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heikius B, Niemelä S, Lehtola J, Karttunen T, Lähde S. Hepatobiliary and coexisting pancreatic duct abnormalities in patients with inflammatory bowel disease. Scand J Gastroenterol. 1997;32(2):153-61.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
