<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35507637</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>16</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1522-2683</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>04</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Electrophoresis</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Electrophoresis</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Development and validation of capillary zone electrophoresis and high-performance liquid chromatography methods for the determination of oral anticoagulant edoxaban in pharmaceutical tablets.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/elps.202200024</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The incidence of thrombotic complications in SARS-CoV-2 infections has become a global concern; thus, anticoagulants are an integral part of the treatment. Edoxaban (EDX) is an oral anticoagulant suitable for pharmacologic thromboprophylaxis. Herein, two novel analytical methods for EDX determination in tablets are developed and validated using capillary zone electrophoresis (CZE) and high-performance liquid chromatography (HPLC). Operating conditions such as the electrolyte's concentration and pH value, injection time, volume, and the capillary temperature, were optimized. The methods were successfully validated by establishing the linearity, intra- and inter-day precisions (relative standard deviation [%]), accuracy, and robustness. Adequate separation of excipients and degradation products of EDX generated by stress degradation conditions demonstrated the stability-indicating capability of the methods. The analytical procedures were linear in the range of 25-125 µg/ml (r &gt; 0.999), with the limits of detection and quantification of 3.26 and 10.87 µg/ml for CZE and 0.740 and 2.78 µg/ml for HPLC. Although both methodologies are suitable for determining EDX in tablets, CZE provides a greener alternative due to low-cost analysis using less organic solvents and minimizing waste generation.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 Wiley-VCH GmbH.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Oliveira Rocha</LastName>
            <ForeName>Manoelly</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1783-6624</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Laboratory of Pharmaceutical Quality Control, Universidade Federal do Rio Grande do Sul, Porto Alegre, Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Chemistry Institute, Universidade Federal do Rio Grande do Sul, Porto Alegre, Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bordignon Primieri</LastName>
            <ForeName>Gabriele</ForeName>
            <Initials>G</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Laboratory of Pharmaceutical Quality Control, Universidade Federal do Rio Grande do Sul, Porto Alegre, Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ribeiro Wingert</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nathalie</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3802-1344</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Faculty of Pharmacy, Universidade Federal da Bahia, Salvador, Bahia, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Arguello Da Silva</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jacqueline</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6918-1597</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Chemistry Institute, Universidade Federal do Rio Grande do Sul, Porto Alegre, Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Steppe</LastName>
            <ForeName>Martin</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2053-6350</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Laboratory of Pharmaceutical Quality Control, Universidade Federal do Rio Grande do Sul, Porto Alegre, Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>04</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>Germany</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Electrophoresis</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8204476</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0173-0835</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">capillary zone electrophoresis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">edoxaban</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">high-performance liquid chromatography</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">quality control</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
          <Hour>13</Hour>
          <Minute>46</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35507637</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/elps.202200024</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Langella V, Bottino R, Asti A, Maresca G, Di Palma G, Pomponi D, et al. Edoxaban for the treatment of pulmonary embolism in hospitalized COVID-19 patients. Expert Rev Clin Pharmacol. 2021;14(10):1289-94.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>O'Connell C, Escalante CP, Goldhaber SZ, McBane R, Connors JM, Raskob GE. Treatment of cancer-associated venous thromboembolism with low-molecular-weight heparin or direct oral anticoagulants: patient selection, controversies, and caveats. Oncologist. 2021;26(1):8-16.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>European Medicines Agency (EMA). Lixiana®, “Summary of product characteristics”. 2020 [updated February]. https://www.ema.europa.eu/en/documents/product-information/lixiana-epar-product-information_en.pdf</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Food and Drug Administration (FDA). Savaysa® (edoxaban tosylate) tablets prescribing information. 2015 [updated January]. https://www.accessdata.fda.gov/drugsatfda_docs/label/2015/206316lbl.pdf</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gous T, Couchman L, Patel JP, Paradzai C, Arya R, Flanagan JR. Measurement of the direct oral anticoagulants apixaban, dabigatran, edoxaban, and rivaroxaban in human plasma using turbulent flow liquid chromatography with high-resolution mass spectrometry. Ther Drug Monit. 2014;36(5):597-605.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang, WL, Lou D, Zhang DT, Zhang I, Huang HJ. Determination of rivaroxaban, apixaban and edoxaban in rat plasma by UPLC-MS/MS method. J Thromb Thrombolysis. 2016;42(2):205-11.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>He L, Kochan J, Lin M, Vandell A, Brown K, Depasse F. Determination of edoxaban equivalent concentrations in human plasma by an automated anti-factor Xa chromogenic assay. Thromb Res. 2017;155:121-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wiesen MHJ, Blaich C, Streichert T, Michels G, Müller C. Paramagnetic micro-particles as a tool for rapid quantification of apixaban, dabigatran, edoxaban and rivaroxaban in human plasma by UHPLC-MS/MS. Clin Chem Lab Med. 2017;55(9):1349-59.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Foerster KI, Huppertz A, Meid AD, Müller OJ, Rizos T, Tilemann L, et al. Dried-blood-spot technique to monitor direct oral anticoagulants: clinical validation of a UPLC-MS/MS-based assay. J Anal Chem. 2018;90(15):9395-402.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hanada K, Matsumoto SI, Shibata S, Matsubara H, Tsukimura Y, Takahashi H. A quantitative LC/MSMS method for determination of edoxaban, a Xa inhibitor and its pharmacokinetic application in patients after total knee arthroplasty. Biomed Chromatogr. 2018;32(6):e4213.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wiesen MHJ, Fietz C, Jübner M, Bergmann SI, Streichert HA, Müller C, et al. Quantification of direct-acting oral anticoagulants: application of a clinically validated liquid chromatography-tandem mass spectrometry method to forensic cases. Drug Test Anal. 2021;13:419-26.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lindahl S, Dyrkorn R, Spigset O, Hegstad S. Quantification of apixaban, dabigatran, edoxaban, and rivaroxaban in human serum by UHPLC-MS/MS-method development, validation, and application. Ther Drug Monit. 2018;40(3):369-76.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gouveia F, Bicker J, Santos J, Rocha M, Alves G, Falcão A, et al. Development, validation and application of a new HPLC-DAD method for simultaneous quantification of apixaban, dabigatran, edoxaban and rivaroxaban in human plasma. J Pharm Biomed Anal. 2020;181:113109.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kuhn J, Gripp T, Flieder T, Hammerschmidt A, Hendig D, Faust I, et al. Measurement of apixaban, dabigatran, edoxaban and rivaroxaban in human plasma using automated online solid-phase extraction combined with ultra-performance liquid chromatography-tandem mass spectrometry and its comparison with coagulation assays. Clin Chim Acta. 2018;486:347-56.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reddy PS, Jagarlapudi VSK, Sekaran CB. Determination of edoxaban in Bulk and in tablet dosage form by stability indicating high-performance liquid chromatography. Pharm Sci. 2016;22(1):35-41.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fakhari AR, Nojavan S, Haghgoo S, Mohammadi A. Development of a stability-indicating CE assay for the determination of amlodipine enantiomers in commercial tablets. Electrophoresis. 2008;29:4583-92.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Remínek R, Foret F. Capillary electrophoretic methods for quality control analyses of pharmaceuticals: a review. Electrophoresis. 2020;42:19-37.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>ICH-Expert-Working-Group. ICH Topic Q2 (R1) validation of analytical procedures: text and methodology. 2005. https://database.ich.org/sites/default/files/Q2_R1__Guideline.pdf</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>The United States Pharmacopeia 41 edition. Rockville: United States Pharmacopeia Convention; 2019.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shrivastava A, Gupta VP. Methods for the determination of limit of detection and limit of quantitation of the analytical methods. Chron Young Sci. 2011;2:21-5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ayish NS, Marzouk HM, El-Zeany BA, Fayed AS. A novel nanoparticles-based electrochemical sensing platform for sensitive detection of oral anticoagulant; edoxaban in human plasma. Electroanalysis. 2022;34:1-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Suntornsuk L. Recent advances of capillary electrophoresis in pharmaceutical analysis. Anal Bioanal Chem. 2010;398(1):29-52.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ferreira SLC, Caires AO, Borges TS, Lima AMDS, Silva LOB, dos Santos WNL. Robustness evaluation in analytical methods optimized using experimental designs. Microchem J. 2017;131:163-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>El-Deeb S, Wätzig H, El-Hady DA, Albishri HM, de Sänger - van de Griend C, Scriba GKE. Recent advances in capillary electrophoretic migration techniques for pharmaceutical analysis. Electrophoresis. 2014;35:170-89.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mufusama JP, Hoellein L, Feineis D, Holzgrabe U, Bringmann G. Capillary zone electrophoresis for the determination of amodiaquine and three of its synthetic impurities in pharmaceutical formulations. Electrophoresis. 2018;39:2530-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maciel EVS, de Toffoli AL, Sobieski E, Nazário CED, Lanças FM. Miniaturized liquid chromatography focusing on analytical columns and mass spectrometry: a review. Anal Chim Acta. 2020;1103:11-31.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
