<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35505569</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>05</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>12</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1525-6049</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>44</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Dec</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Renal failure</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Ren Fail</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>A new model to predict acute kidney injury after cardiac surgery in patients with renal insufficiency.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>767</StartPage>
          <EndPage>776</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>767-776</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1080/0886022X.2022.2071297</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">To establish a simple model for predicting postoperative acute kidney injury (AKI) requiring renal replacement therapy (RRT) in patients with renal insufficiency (CKD stages 3-4) who underwent cardiac surgery.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A total of 330 patients were enrolled. Among them, 226 were randomly selected for the development group and the remaining 104 for the validation group. The primary outcome was AKI requiring RRT. A nomogram was constructed based on the multivariate analysis with variables selected by the application of the least absolute shrinkage and selection operator. Meanwhile, the discrimination, calibration, and clinical power of the new model were assessed and compared with those of the Cleveland Clinic score and Simplified Renal Index (SRI) score in the validation group. Results: The rate of RRT in the development group was 10.6% (<i>n</i> = 24), while the rate in the validation group was 14.4% (<i>n</i> = 15). The new model included four variables such as postoperative creatinine, aortic cross-clamping time, emergency, and preoperative cystatin C, with a C-index of 0.851 (95% CI, 0.779-0.924). In the validation group, the areas under the receiver operating characteristic curves for the new model, SRI score, and Cleveland Clinic score were 0.813, 0.791, and 0.786, respectively. Furthermore, the new model demonstrated greater clinical net benefits compared with the Cleveland Clinic score or SRI score.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">We developed and validated a powerful predictive model for predicting severe AKI after cardiac surgery in patients with renal insufficiency, which would be helpful to assess the risk for severe AKI requiring RRT.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xijian</ForeName>
            <Initials>X</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Nephrology, Affiliated Hospital of Nantong University, Nantong Jiangsu, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Guo</LastName>
            <ForeName>Naifeng</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Nephrology, Affiliated Hospital of Nantong University, Nantong Jiangsu, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ying</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Epidemiology and Medical Statistics, Nantong University School of Public Health, Nantong Jiangsu, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Dai</LastName>
            <ForeName>Houyong</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7736-7108</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Nephrology, Affiliated Hospital of Nantong University, Nantong Jiangsu, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Ren Fail</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8701128</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0886-022X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D058186" MajorTopicYN="Y">Acute Kidney Injury</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000453" MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006348" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cardiac Surgical Procedures</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015233" MajorTopicYN="N">Models, Statistical</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Acute kidney injury</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cardiac surgery</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">renal insufficiency</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">renal replacement therapy</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">risk model</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors report no conflicts of interest. The authors alone are responsible for the content and writing of the paper.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
          <Hour>1</Hour>
          <Minute>12</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35505569</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9090423</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/0886022X.2022.2071297</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Balkan B, Magin H.. 
What are the factors affecting the progression of kidney failure, mortality and morbidity after cardiac surgery in patients with chronic kidney disease?
J Card Surg. 2021;36(6):2021–2028.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33694184</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nicolini F, Agostinelli A, Vezzani A, et al. . 
The evolution of cardiovascular surgery in elderly patient: a review of current options and outcomes. Biomed Res Int. 2014;2014:736298.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4000933</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24812629</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parikh DS, Swaminathan M, Archer LE, et al. . 
Perioperative outcomes among patients with end-stage renal disease following coronary artery bypass surgery in the USA. Nephrol Dial Transplant. 2010;25(7):2275–2283.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2902896</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20103500</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wiedemann D, Bernhard D, Laufer G, et al. . 
The elderly patient and cardiac surgery – a mini-review. Gerontology. 2010;56(3):241–249.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19828936</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kurth MJ, McBride WT, McLean G, et al. . 
Acute kidney injury risk in orthopaedic trauma patients pre and post surgery using a biomarker algorithm and clinical risk score. Sci Rep. 2020;10(1):20005.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7673130</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33203963</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McBride WT, Prasad PS, Armstrong M, et al. . 
Cytokine phenotype, genotype, and renal outcomes at cardiac surgery. Cytokine. 2013;61(1):275–284.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23137784</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ortega-Loubon C, Fernández-Molina M, Carrascal-Hinojal Y, et al. . 
Cardiac surgery-associated acute kidney injury. Ann Card Anaesth. 2016;19(4):687–698.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5070330</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27716701</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leacche M, Rawn JD, Mihaljevic T, et al. . 
Outcomes in patients with normal serum creatinine and with artificial renal support for acute renal failure developing after coronary artery bypass grafting. Am J Cardiol. 2004;93(3):353–356.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14759390</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thakar CV, Arrigain S, Worley S, et al. . 
A clinical score to predict acute renal failure after cardiac surgery. J Am Soc Nephrol. 2005;16(1):162–168.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15563569</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wijeysundera DN, Karkouti K, Dupuis JY, et al. . 
Derivation and validation of a simplified predictive index for renal replacement therapy after cardiac surgery. JAMA. 2007;297(16):1801–1809.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17456822</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Husain-Syed F, Quattrone MG, Ferrari F, et al. . 
Clinical and operative determinants of acute kidney injury after cardiac surgery. Cardiorenal Med. 2020;10(5):340–352.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32599584</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Levey AS, Stevens LA, Schmid CH, et al. . 
A new equation to estimate glomerular filtration rate. Ann Intern Med. 2009;150(9):604–612.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2763564</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19414839</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tibshirani R.
The lasso method for variable selection in the cox model. Statist. Med. 1997;16(4):385–395.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xie HY, Zhu Y, Yao XD, et al. . 
Development of a nomogram to predict non-organ-confined bladder urothelial cancer before radical cystectomy. Int Urol Nephrol. 2012;44(6):1711–1719.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22941751</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>DeLong ER, DeLong DM, Clarke-Pearson DL.. 
Comparing the areas under two or more correlated receiver operating characteristic curves: a nonparametric approach. Biometrics. 1988;44(3):837–845.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3203132</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vickers AJ, Cronin AM, Elkin EB, et al. . 
Extensions to decision curve analysis, a novel method for evaluating diagnostic tests, prediction models and molecular markers. BMC Med Inf Decis Making. 2008;8:53.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kellum JA, Prowle JR.. 
Paradigms of acute kidney injury in the intensive care setting. Nat Rev Nephrol. 2018;14(4):217–230.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29355173</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bruetto RG, Rodrigues FB, Torres US, et al. . 
Renal function at hospital admission and mortality due to acute kidney injury after myocardial infarction. PLOS One. 2012;7(4):e35496.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3335121</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22539974</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Howell NJ, Keogh BE, Bonser RS, et al. . 
Mild renal dysfunction predicts in-hospital mortality and post-discharge survival following cardiac surgery. Eur J Cardiothorac Surg. 2008;34(2):390–395; discussion 5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18502144</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ibáñez J, Riera M, Saez de Ibarra JI, et al. . 
Effect of preoperative mild renal dysfunction on mortality and morbidity following valve cardiac surgery. Interact Cardiovasc Thorac Surg. 2007;6(6):748–752.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17890235</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lysak N, Bihorac A, Hobson C.. 
Mortality and cost of acute and chronic kidney disease after cardiac surgery. Curr Opin Anaesthesiol. 2017;30(1):113–117.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5303614</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27841788</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koyner JL, Garg AX, Coca SG, et al. . 
Biomarkers predict progression of acute kidney injury after cardiac surgery. JASN. 2012;23(5):905–914.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3338298</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22383693</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hu P, Chen Y, Wu Y, et al. . 
Development and validation of a model for predicting acute kidney injury after cardiac surgery in patients of advanced age. J Card Surg. 2021;36(3):806–814.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7898501</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33314365</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lin H, Hou J, Tang H, et al. . 
A novel nomogram to predict perioperative acute kidney injury following isolated coronary artery bypass grafting surgery with impaired left ventricular ejection fraction. BMC Cardiovasc Disord. 2020;20(1):517.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7731767</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33302875</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hu P, Mo Z, Chen Y, et al. . 
Derivation and validation of a model to predict acute kidney injury following cardiac surgery in patients with normal renal function. Ren Fail. 2021;43(1):1205–1213.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8354173</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34372744</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Djavan B, Remzi M, Zlotta A, et al. . 
Novel artificial neural network for early detection of prostate cancer. J Clin Oncol. 2002;20(4):921–929.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11844812</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eastham JA, May R, Robertson JL, et al. . 
Development of a nomogram that predicts the probability of a positive prostate biopsy in men with an abnormal digital rectal examination and a prostate-specific antigen between 0 and 4 ng/mL 1. Urology. 1999;54(4):709–713.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10510933</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garzotto M, Hudson RG, Peters L, et al. . 
Predictive modeling for the presence of prostate carcinoma using clinical, laboratory, and ultrasound parameters in patients with prostate specific antigen levels &lt; or = 10 ng/mL. Cancer. 2003;98(7):1417–1422.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14508828</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lopez-Corona E, Ohori M, Scardino PT, et al. . 
A nomogram for predicting a positive repeat prostate biopsy in patients with a previous negative biopsy session. J Urol. 2003;170(4 Part 1):1184–1188. discussion 8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14501721</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tangri N, Stevens LA, Schmid CH, et al. . 
Changes in dietary protein intake has no effect on serum cystatin C levels independent of the glomerular filtration rate. Kidney Int. 2011;79(4):471–477.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4557795</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20980977</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grubb A, Björk J, Lindström V, et al. . 
A cystatin C-based formula without anthropometric variables estimates glomerular filtration rate better than creatinine clearance using the Cockcroft-Gault formula. Scand J Clin Lab Invest. 2005;65(2):153–162.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16025838</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Larsson A, Malm J, Grubb A, et al. . 
Calculation of glomerular filtration rate expressed in mL/min from plasma cystatin C values in mg/L. Scand J Clin Lab Invest. 2004;64(1):25–30.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15025426</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sjöström P, Tidman M, Jones I.. 
Determination of the production rate and non-renal clearance of cystatin C and estimation of the glomerular filtration rate from the serum concentration of cystatin C in humans. Scand J Clin Lab Invest. 2005;65(2):111–124.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16025834</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saydam O, Türkmen E, Portakal O, et al. . 
Emerging biomarker for predicting acute kidney injury after cardiac surgery: cystatin C. Turk J Med Sci. 2018;48(6):1096–1103.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30541232</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yuan SM.
Acute kidney injury after pediatric cardiac surgery. Pediatr Neonatol. 2019;60(1):3–11.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29891225</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang RR, He M, Gui X, et al. . 
A nomogram based on serum cystatin C for predicting acute kidney injury in patients with traumatic brain injury. Ren Fail. 2021;43(1):206–215.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7833079</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33478333</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lassnigg A, Schmid ER, Hiesmayr M, et al. . 
Impact of minimal increases in serum creatinine on outcome in patients after cardiothoracic surgery: do we have to revise current definitions of acute renal failure?. Crit Care Med. 2008;36(4):1129–1137.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18379238</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chertow GM, Burdick E, Honour M, et al. . 
Acute kidney injury, mortality, length of stay, and costs in hospitalized patients. J Am Soc Nephrol. 2005;16(11):3365–3370.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16177006</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Day JR, Taylor KM.. 
The systemic inflammatory response syndrome and cardiopulmonary bypass. Int J Surg. 2005;3(2):129–140.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17462274</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>O'Neal JB, Shaw AD, Billings FT.. 
Acute kidney injury following cardiac surgery: current understanding and future directions. Crit Care. 2016;20(1):187.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4931708</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27373799</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Granata A, Insalaco M, Di Pietro F, et al. . 
Atheroembolism renal disease: diagnosis and etiologic factors. Clin Ter. 2012;163(4):313–322.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23007816</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swinkels BM, Ten Berg JM, Kelder JC, et al. . 
Effect of aortic cross-clamp time on late survival after isolated aortic valve replacement. Interact Cardiovasc Thorac Surg. 2021;32(2):222–228.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8906723</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33491739</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iasonos A, Schrag D, Raj GV, et al. . 
How to build and interpret a nomogram for cancer prognosis. J Clin Oncol. 2008;26(8):1364–1370.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18323559</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McBride WT, Kurth MJ, McLean G, et al. . 
Stratifying risk of acute kidney injury in pre and post cardiac surgery patients using a novel biomarker-based algorithm and clinical risk score. Sci Rep. 2019;9(1):16963.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6861253</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31740699</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
