<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35506263</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>04</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1866-0452</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Issue>Forthcoming</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>13</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Deutsches Arzteblatt international</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Dtsch Arztebl Int</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Clinical Practice Guideline: Recommendations for the Outpatient Drug Treatment of Patients With COVID-19.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">arztebl.m2022.0203</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3238/arztebl.m2022.0203</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">One of the purposes of outpatient treatment for COVID-19 patients is to prevent severe disease courses and hospitalization. There is a need for evidence-based recommendations to be applied in primary care and specialized outpatient settings.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This guideline was developed on the basis of publications that were retrieved by a systematic search for randomized controlled trials in the Cochrane COVID-19 trial registry. The quality of evidence was assessed with GRADE, and structured consensus generation was carried out with MAGICapp.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Unvaccinated COVID-19 outpatients with at least one risk factor for a severe disease course may be treated in the early phase of the disease with sotrovimab, remdesivir, or nirmatrelvir/ritonavir. Molnupiravir may also be used for such patients if no other clinically appropriate treatment options are available. Immunosuppressed persons with COVID-19 who are at high risk, and whose response to vaccination is expected to be reduced, ought to be treated with sotrovimab. It should be noted, however, that the clinical efficacy of sotrovimab against infections with the omicron subtype BA.2 is uncertain at the currently used dose, as the drug has displayed reduced activity against this subtype in vitro. COVID-19 patients at risk of a severe course may be offered budesonide inhalation, according to an off-label recommendation of the German College of General Practitioners and Family Physicians (other medical societies do not recommend either for or against this treatment). Thromboembolism prophylaxis with low-molecular-weight heparin may be given to elderly patients or those with a pre-existing illness. No recommendation is made concerning fluvoxamine or colchicine. Acetylsalicylic acid, azithromycin, ivermectin, systemic steroids, and vitamin D should not be used for the outpatient treatment of COVID-19.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Drug treatment is now available for outpatients with COVID-19 in the early phase. Nearly all of the relevant trials have been conducted in unvaccinated subjects; this needs to be kept in mind in patient selection.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kaduszkiewicz</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hanna</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kochen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Michael M</ForeName>
            <Initials>MM</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kluge</LastName>
            <ForeName>Stefan</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Malin</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jakob J</ForeName>
            <Initials>JJ</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Weibel</LastName>
            <ForeName>Stephanie</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Skoetz</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nicole</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <CollectiveName>guideline group</CollectiveName>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>Germany</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Dtsch Arztebl Int</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101475967</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1866-0452</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
          <Hour>3</Hour>
          <Minute>33</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35506263</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3238/arztebl.m2022.0203</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">arztebl.m2022.0203</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
