<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35506373</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>04</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2162-3279</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>04</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Brain and behavior</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Brain Behav</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Epidemiological profile and clinical characteristics of 491 Brazilian patients with neurofibromatosis type 1.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e2599</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e2599</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/brb3.2599</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Neurofibromatosis type 1 (NF1) is a chronic and progressive autosomal dominant genetic and sporadic disease characterized by cutaneous and neurological abnormalities. Plexiform neurofibroma (PN), a significant cause of clinical complications in NF-1, is a benign tumor of the peripheral nerve sheath that involves multiple nerve fascicles. Although there is an important number of patients who are affected by NF1 in Brazil, there is little data on the behavior of the disease in the national literature as well as in other low- and middle-income countries.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We performed a retrospective analysis of 491 patients with NF1 followed at two reference centers in Brazil.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Approximately 38% of patients had PNs, resulting in reduced life quality. The median patient age with PNs was 30 years (range: 6 to 83 years). Head and neck, and extremity were the main affected locations with 35.8 and 30.6%, respectively. PNs were classified as asymptomatic in 25.1% of patients, while 52.5% presented symptomatic and inoperable tumors. The most common manifestations related to PNs were disfigurement and orthopedic involvement. Twenty patients developed neoplasms and ten (50%) presented with malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumors (MPNST). The prevalence of MPNST in our study was 2.9%.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Patients with NF1 experience clinically significant morbidity, especially when it is associated with PN. Though there are many patients affected by NF1 in Brazil and other low- and middle-income countries, there is little data available in the corresponding literature. Our results are comparable to the previous results reported from higher-income countries and international registries.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Authors. Brain and Behavior published by Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Darrigo Junior</LastName>
            <ForeName>Luiz Guilherme</ForeName>
            <Initials>LG</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6007-8908</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Departament of Pediatrics, Ribeirão Preto Medical School, University of São Paulo, São Paulo, São Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ferraz</LastName>
            <ForeName>Victor Evangelista de Faria</ForeName>
            <Initials>VEF</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Departament of Genetics, Ribeirão Preto Medical School, University of São Paulo, São Paulo, São Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Cormedi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Marina Candido Visontai</ForeName>
            <Initials>MCV</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Departament of Genetics, Ribeirão Preto Medical School, University of São Paulo, São Paulo, São Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Araujo</LastName>
            <ForeName>Luissa Hikari Hayashi</ForeName>
            <Initials>LHH</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Departament of Genetics, Ribeirão Preto Medical School, University of São Paulo, São Paulo, São Paulo, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Magalhães</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mariana Prado Silva</ForeName>
            <Initials>MPS</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Immunology Department, Fundação Educacional Serra dos Órgãos (UNIFESO), Rio de Janeiro, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Carneiro</LastName>
            <ForeName>Rafaella Curis</ForeName>
            <Initials>RC</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Immunology Department, Fundação Educacional Serra dos Órgãos (UNIFESO), Rio de Janeiro, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sales</LastName>
            <ForeName>Luis Henrique Nunes</ForeName>
            <Initials>LHN</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Immunology Department, Fundação Educacional Serra dos Órgãos (UNIFESO), Rio de Janeiro, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Suchmacher</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mendel</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Immunology Department, Fundação Educacional Serra dos Órgãos (UNIFESO), Rio de Janeiro, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Cunha</LastName>
            <ForeName>Karin Soares</ForeName>
            <Initials>KS</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pathology and Post-graduation Program in Pathology, School of Medicine, Fluminense Federal University, Rio de Janeiro, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Filho</LastName>
            <ForeName>Aguinaldo Bonalumi</ForeName>
            <Initials>AB</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Hospital Naval Marcilio Dias (HNMD), Rio de Janeiro, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Azulay</LastName>
            <ForeName>David Rubem</ForeName>
            <Initials>DR</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Dermatology Service, Prof. Rubem David Azulay Dermatology Institute, Rio de Janeiro, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Geller</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mauro</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Immunology Department, Fundação Educacional Serra dos Órgãos (UNIFESO), Rio de Janeiro, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Clinical Immunology, Instituto de Pós-Graduação Médica Carlos Chagas (IPGMCC), Rio de Janeiro, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>04</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Brain Behav</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101570837</NlmUniqueID>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">gliomas</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumor</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurofibroma</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurofibromatosis type 1</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">plexiform neurofibroma</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
          <Hour>4</Hour>
          <Minute>53</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35506373</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/brb3.2599</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Batista, P. B., Bertollo, E. M. G., De Costa, D. S., Eliam, L., Cunha, K. S. G., Cunha-Melo, J. R., Darrigo Junior, L. G., Geller, M., Gianordoli-Nascimento, I. F., Madeira, L. G., Mendes, H. M., De Miranda, D. M., Mata-Machado, N. A., Morato, E. G., Pavarino, É. C., Pereira, L. B., Rezende, N. A. D. e., De Rodrigues, L. O., Sette, J. B. C., … Rodrigues, L. O. C. (2015). Neurofibromatosis: Part 2 - clinical management. Arquivos De Neuro-Psiquiatria, 73, 531-543.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bezniakow, N., Gos, M., &amp; Obersztyn, E. (2014). The RASopathies as an example of RAS/MAPK pathway disturbances: clinical presentation and molecular pathogenesis of selected syndromes. Developmental Period Medicine, 18, 285-296.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boulanger, J. M., &amp; Larbrisseau, A. (2005). Neurofibromatosis type 1 in a pediatric population: Ste-Justine's experience. Canadian Journal of Neurological Sciences, 32, 225-231.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Casey, D., Demko, S., Sinha, A., Mishra-Kalyani, P. S., Shen, Y.-L. i., Khasar, S., Goheer, M. A., Helms, W. S., Pan, L., Xu, Y., Fan, J., Leong, R., Liu, J., Yang, Y., Windsor, K., Ou, M., Stephens, O., Oh, B., Reaman, G. H., … Singh, H. (2021). FDA Approval summary: selumetinib for plexiform neurofibroma. Clin Cancer Res Off J Am Assoc Cancer Res, 27, 4142-4146.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Darrigo, L. G. Jr., Geller, M., Bonalumi Filho, A., &amp; Azulay, D. R. (2007). Prevalence of plexiform neurofibroma in children and adolescents with type I neurofibromatosis. Jornal De Pediatria, 83, 571-573.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Darrigo Junior, L. G., Bonalumi Filho, A., D'alessandro, D. S. M., &amp; Geller, M. (2008). Neurofibromatose tipo 1 na infância: Revisão dos aspectos clínicos. Rev Paul Pediatr, 26, 176-182.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Debella, K., Szudek, J., &amp; Friedman, J. M. (2000). Use of the National Institutes of Health Criteria for diagnosis of neurofibromatosis 1 in children. Pediatrics, 105, 608-614.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Declue, J. E., Cohen, B. D., &amp; Lowy, D. R. (1991). Identification and characterization of the neurofibromatosis type 1 protein product. PNAS, 88, 9914-9918.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dombi, E., Baldwin, A., Marcus, L. J., Fisher, M. J., Weiss, B., Kim, A., Whitcomb, P., Martin, S., Aschbacher-Smith, L. E., Rizvi, T. A., Wu, J., Ershler, R., Wolters, P., Therrien, J., Glod, J., Belasco, J. B., Schorry, E., Brofferio, A., Starosta, A. J., … Widemann, B. C. (2016). Activity of selumetinib in neurofibromatosis type 1-related plexiform neurofibromas. New England Journal of Medicine, 375, 2550-2560.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dombi, E., Solomon, J., Gillespie, A. J., Fox, E., Balis, F. M., Patronas, N., Korf, B. R., Babovic-Vuksanovic, D., Packer, R. J., Belasco, J., Goldman, S., Jakacki, R., Kieran, M., Steinberg, S. M., &amp; Widemann, B. C. (2007). NF1 plexiform neurofibroma growth rate by volumetric MRI: relationship to age and body weight. Neurology, 68, 643-647.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Evans, D. G., Howard, E., Giblin, C., Clancy, T., Spencer, H., Huson, S. M., &amp; Lalloo, F. (2010). Birth incidence and prevalence of tumor-prone syndromes: estimates from a UK family genetic register service. American Journal of Medical Genetics. Part A, 152A, 327-332.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Evans, D. G. R. (2002). Malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumours in neurofibromatosis 1. Journal of Medical Genetics, 39, 311-314.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fisher, M. J., Shih, C.- S., Rhodes, S. D., Armstrong, A. E., Wolters, P. L., Dombi, E., Zhang, C., Angus, S. P., Johnson, G. L., Packer, R. J., Allen, J. C., Ullrich, N. J., Goldman, S., Gutmann, D. H., Plotkin, S. R., Rosser, T., Robertson, K. A., Widemann, B. C., Smith, A. E., … Clapp, D. W. (2021). Cabozantinib for neurofibromatosis type 1-related plexiform neurofibromas: a phase 2 trial. Nature Medicine, 27, 165-173.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Geller, M., Junior, L. G. D., Filho, A. B., &amp; Ribeiro, M. G. (2009). Plexiform neurofibroma in the ear canal of a patient with type I neurofibromatosis. Braz J Otorhinolaryngol, 75, 158.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Griffiths, S., Thompson, P., Frayling, I., &amp; Upadhyaya, M. (2007). Molecular diagnosis of neurofibromatosis type 1: 2 years experience. Familial Cancer, 6, 21-34.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gross, A. M., &amp; Widemann, B. C. (2020). Clinical trial design in neurofibromatosis type 1 as a model for other tumor predisposition syndromes. Neuro-Oncol Adv, 2, i134-i140.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gross, A. M., Wolters, P. L., Dombi, E., Baldwin, A., Whitcomb, P., Fisher, M. J., Weiss, B., Kim, A., Bornhorst, M., Shah, A. C., Martin, S., Roderick, M. C., Pichard, D. C., Carbonell, A., Paul, S. M., Therrien, J., Kapustina, O., Heisey, K., Clapp, D. W., … Widemann, B. C. (2020). Selumetinib in children with inoperable plexiform neurofibromas. New England Journal of Medicine, 382, 1430-1442.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gutmann, D. H., Ferner, R. E., Listernick, R. H., Korf, B. R., Wolters, P. L., &amp; Johnson, K. J. (2017). Neurofibromatosis type 1. Nat Rev Dis Primer, 3, 17004.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hernández-Martín, A., &amp; Duat-Rodríguez, A. (2016). An update on neurofibromatosis type 1: not just Café-au-Lait spots, freckling, and neurofibromas. An update. Part I. Dermatological clinical criteria diagnostic of the disease. Actas Dermo-Sifiliograficas, 107, 454-464.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Killock, D. (2020). Selumetinib benefits children with inoperable plexiform neurofibromas. Nature Reviews Clinical Oncology, 17, 273.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>King, A. A., Debaun, M. R., Riccardi, V. M., &amp; Gutmann, D. H. (2000). Malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumors in neurofibromatosis 1. American Journal of Medical Genetics, 93, 388-392.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Korf, B. R. (1999). Plexiform neurofibromas. American Journal of Medical Genetics, 89, 31-37.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Korf, B. R. (2000). Malignancy in neurofibromatosis type 1. Oncologist, 5, 477-485.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Legius, E., Messiaen, L., &amp; Wolkenstein, P., et al. (2021). Revised diagnostic criteria for neurofibromatosis type 1 and Legius syndrome: an international consensus recommendation. Genet Med Off J Am Coll Med Genet, 23, 1506-1513.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Listernick, R., Ferner, R. E., Liu, G. T., &amp; Gutmann, D. H. (2007). Optic pathway gliomas in neurofibromatosis-1: controversies and recommendations. Annals of Neurology, 61, 189-198.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martin, S., Wolters, P., Baldwin, A., Gillespie, A., Dombi, E., Walker, K., &amp; Widemann, B. (2012). Social-emotional functioning of children and adolescents with neurofibromatosis type 1 and plexiform neurofibromas: relationships with cognitive, disease, and environmental variables. Journal of Pediatric Psychology, 37, 713-724.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mueller, S., Reddy, A. T., Dombi, E., Allen, J., Packer, R., Clapp, W., Goldman, S., Schorry, E., Tonsgard, J., Blakeley, J., Ullrich, N. J., Gross, A., Walsh, K., Thomas, C., Edwards, L., Prados, M., Korf, B., &amp; Fisher, M. J. (2020). NFB-17. Mek inhibitor binimetinib shows clinical activity in children with neurofibromatosis type 1- associated plexiform neurofibromas: a report from PNOC and the NF clinical trials consortium. Neuro-Oncology, 22, iii420-iii421.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mukhopadhyay, S., Maitra, A., &amp; Choudhury, S. (2021). Selumetinib: the first ever approved drug for neurofibromatosis-1 related inoperable plexiform neurofibroma. Current Medical Research and Opinion, 37, 789-794.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Neurofibromatosis. (1988). Conference statement. National Institutes of Health Consensus Development Conference. Archives of Neurology, May; 45(5), 575-578.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nguyen, R., Kluwe, L., Fuensterer, C., Kentsch, M., Friedrich, R. E., &amp; Mautner, V. - F. (2011). Plexiform neurofibromas in children with neurofibromatosis type 1: frequency and associated clinical deficits. Journal of Pediatrics, 159, 652-655. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpeds.2011.04.008</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Packer, R. J., Gutmann, D. H., Rubenstein, A., Viskochil, D., Zimmerman, R. A., Vezina, G., Small, J., &amp; Korf, B. (2002). Plexiform neurofibromas in NF1: toward biologic-based therapy. Neurology, 58, 1461-1470.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Perreault, S., Larouche, V., Tabori, U., Hawkin, C., Lippé, S., Ellezam, B., Décarie, J. - C., Théoret, Y., Métras, M. - É., Sultan, S., Cantin, É., Routhier, M. - È., Caru, M., Legault, G., Bouffet, É., Lafay-Cousin, L., Hukin, J., Erker, C., &amp; Jabado, N. (2019). A phase 2 study of trametinib for patients with pediatric glioma or plexiform neurofibroma with refractory tumor and activation of the MAPK/ERK pathway: TRAM-01. BMC Cancer, 19, 1250.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Prada, C. E., Rangwala, F. A., Martin, L. J., Lovell, A. M., Saal, H. M., Schorry, E. K., &amp; Hopkin, R. J. (2012). Pediatric plexiform neurofibromas: impact on morbidity and mortality in neurofibromatosis type 1. Journal of Pediatrics, 160, 461-467.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pu, L. L. Q., &amp; Vasconez, H. C. (2004). Large recurrent plexiform neurofibroma of the foot and ankle: plexiform neurofibroma of foot and ankle. Microsurgery, 24, 67-71.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rodrigues, L. O. C., Batista, P. B., Goloni-Bertollo, E. M., Souza-Costa, D. D. e., Eliam, L., Eliam, M., Cunha, K. S. G., Darrigo Junior, L. G., Ferraz Filho, J. R. L., Geller, M., Gianordoli-Nascimento, I. F., Madeira, L. G., Malloy-Diniz, L. F., Mendes, H. M., Miranda, D. M. D. e., Pavarino, E. C., Baptista-Pereira, L., Rezende, N. A., De Rodrigues, L. O., … Vidigal, P. V. T. (2014). Neurofibromatoses: Part 1-diagnosis and differential diagnosis. Arquivos De Neuro-Psiquiatria, 72, 241-250.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Staser, K., Yang, F. - C., &amp; Clapp, D. W. (2012). Pathogenesis of plexiform neurofibroma: tumor-stromal/hematopoietic interactions in tumor progression. Annu Rev Pathol, 7, 469-495.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tucker, T., Wolkenstein, P., Revuz, J., Zeller, J., &amp; Friedman, J. M. (2005). Association between benign and malignant peripheral nerve sheath tumors in NF1. Neurology, 65, 205-211.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Waggoner, D. J., Towbin, J., &amp; Gottesman, G., et al. (2000). Clinic-based study of plexiform neurofibromas in neurofibromatosis. American Journal of Medical Genetics, 1, 4.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weiss, B. D., Wolters, P. L., Plotkin, S. R., Widemann, B. C., Tonsgard, J. H., Blakeley, J., Allen, J. C., Schorry, E., Korf, B., Robison, N. J., Goldman, S., Vinks, A. A., Emoto, C., Fukuda, T., Robinson, C. T., Cutter, G., Edwards, L., Dombi, E., Ratner, N., … Fisher, M. J. (2021). NF106: a neurofibromatosis clinical trials consortium phase II trial of the MEK inhibitor mirdametinib (PD-0325901) in adolescents and adults with NF1-related plexiform neurofibromas. J Clin Oncol Off J Am Soc Clin Oncol, 39, 797-806.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wise, J. B., Patel, S. G., &amp; Shah, J. P. (2002). Management issues in massive pediatric facial plexiform neurofibroma with neurofibromatosis type 1. Head &amp; Neck, 24, 207-211.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wolters, P. L., Burns, K. M., Martin, S., Baldwin, A., Dombi, E., Toledo-Tamula, M. A., Dudley, W. N., Gillespie, A., &amp; Widemann, B. C. (2015). Pain interference in youth with neurofibromatosis type 1 and plexiform neurofibromas and relation to disease severity, social-emotional functioning, and quality of life. American Journal of Medical Genetics. Part A, 167A, 2103-2113.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu, G., O'connell, P., Viskochil, D., Cawthon, R., Robertson, M., Culver, M., Dunn, D., Stevens, J., Gesteland, R., White, R., &amp; Weiss, R. (1990). The neurofibromatosis type 1 gene encodes a protein related to GAP. Cell, 62, 599-608.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yap, Y.-S., Mcpherson, J. R., Ong, C.-K., Rozen, S. G., Teh, B.-T., Lee, A. S. G., &amp; Callen, D. F. (2014). The NF1 gene revisited: from bench to bedside. Oncotarget, 5, 5873-5892.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
