<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35501552</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>02</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1534-6277</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>01</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Current treatment options in oncology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Curr Treat Options Oncol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>High-Dose Somatostatin Analogs for the Treatment of Neuroendocrine Neoplasms: where are we Now?</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s11864-022-00983-z</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Neuroendocrine tumors (NET) represent a complex and heterogeneous group of malignancies arising from the diffuse endocrine cells and other cells derived from the neural crest. Advanced disease is observed at diagnosis in more than one-third of patients. Somatostatin analogs (SSA) are the cornerstone in advanced well-differentiated NET treatment. Unfortunately, most patients will eventually develop resistance to SSA treatment by different mechanisms that are not fully understood. In some cases of refractory carcinoid syndrome or progressive disease, the increase of SSA dose may help to reach out a symptomatic and/or tumor growth control. The clinical evidence behind above-label SSA administration is limited and should be individualized and discussed patient by patient. Some questions regarding high-dose SSA use are unsolved, such as the optimal dose to use, the frequency of administration, or the need of deepen molecular understanding that could help to adequately select patients for this approach.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Science+Business Media, LLC, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Alonso-Gordoa</LastName>
            <ForeName>Teresa</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8966-7236</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Medical Oncology Department, Hospital Universitario Ramón y Cajal, 28034, Madrid, Spain. talonsogordoa@gmail.com.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>The Ramon y Cajal Health Research Institute, 28034, Madrid, Spain. talonsogordoa@gmail.com.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Medicine School, Alcala University, 28805, Madrid, Spain. talonsogordoa@gmail.com.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Manneh</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ray</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Medical Oncology Department, University Hospital 12 de Octubre, 28041, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Sociedad de Oncología y Hematología del Cesar, Valledupar, Colombia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Grande</LastName>
            <ForeName>Enrique</ForeName>
            <Initials>E</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Medical Oncology Department, MD Anderson Cancer Center Madrid, 28033, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Molina-Cerrillo</LastName>
            <ForeName>Javier</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Medical Oncology Department, Hospital Universitario Ramón y Cajal, 28034, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>The Ramon y Cajal Health Research Institute, 28034, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Medicine School, Alcala University, 28805, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>01</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Curr Treat Options Oncol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>100900946</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1534-6277</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">High-dose somatostatin analogs</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neuroendocrine tumors</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Radionuclides</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Refractory carcinoid syndrome</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Somatostatin receptors</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
          <Hour>23</Hour>
          <Minute>25</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35501552</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11864-022-00983-z</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s11864-022-00983-z</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References and Recommended Reading</Title>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Papers of particular interest, published recently, have been highlighted as: • Of importance •• Of major importance</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>• Cives M, Strosberg JR. Gastroenteropancreatic neuroendocrine tumors. CA Cancer J Clin. 2018;68(6):471–87 Review on all the current treatment options for patients diagnosed of neuroendocrine tumors.</Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Falconi M, Eriksson B, Kaltsas G, Bartschd DK, Capdevila J, Caplin M, et al. Consensus guidelines update for the management of functional p-NETs (F-p-NETs) and non-functional p-NETs (NF-p-NETs). Neuroendocrinology. 2016;103(2):153–71.</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000443171</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>•• Pavel M, Öberg K, Falconi M, Krenning EP, Sundin A, Perren A, et al. Gastroenteropancreatic neuroendocrine neoplasms: ESMO clinical practice guidelines for diagnosis, treatment and follow-up. Ann Oncol. 2020;31(7):844–60 ESMO recommendations for the management of patients with gastroenteropancreatic neuroendocrine neoplasms.</Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>•• Chan DL, Ferone D, Albertelli M, Pavlakis N, Segelov E, Singh S. Escalated-dose somatostatin analogues for antiproliferative effect in GEPNETS: a systematic review. Endocrine. 2017;57:366–75 Review on the main reported studies concerning the assessment of high-dose SSA in patients with NET.</Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>•• Pavel M, Ćwikła JB, Lombard-Bohas C, Borbath I, Shah T, Pape UF, et al. Efficacy and safety of high-dose lanreotide autogel in patients with progressive pancreatic or midgut neuroendocrine tumours: CLARINET FORTE phase 2 study results. Eur J Cancer. 2021;157:403–14 Phase II single-arm trial on 2 different cohorts of patients with gastroenteropancreatic neuroendocrine tumors evaluating the efficacy and safety of lanreotide 120 mg/14 days after disease progression on standard lanreotide doses.</Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Weckbecker G, Lewis I, Albert R, Schmid HA, Hoyer D, Bruns C. Opportunities in somatostatin research: biological, chemical and therapeutic aspects. Nat Rev Drug Discov. 2003;2(12):999–1017.</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrd1255</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Alonso-Gordoa T, Capdevila J, Grande E. GEP-NETs update: biotherapy for neuroendocrine tumours. Eur J Endocrinol. 2015;172(1):R31–46.</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1530/EJE-14-0354</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Modlin IM, Pavel M, Kidd M. &amp; Gustafsson. Review article: somatostatin analogues in the treatment of gastroenteropancreatic neuroendocrine (carcinoid) tumours. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2010;31(2):169–88.</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19845567</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Dillon JS, Kulke MH, Hörsch D, Anthony LB, Warner RRP, Bergsland E, et al. Time to sustained improvement in bowel movement frequency with telotristat ethyl: analyses of phase III studies in carcinoid syndrome. J Gastrointest Cancer. 2021;52(1):212–221.Dillon JS, Kulke MH, Hörsch D, Anthony LB, Warner RRP, Bergsland Eet al. Time to sustained improvement in bowel movement frequency with telotristat ethyl: analyses of phase III studies in carcinoid syndrome. J Gastrointest Cancer 2021;52(1):212-221</Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Halperin DM, Shen C, Dasari A, Xu Y, Chu Y, Zhou S, Shih YCT, Yao JC. Frequency of carcinoid syndrome at neuroendocrine tumour diagnosis: a population-based study. Lancet Oncol. 2017;18(4):525–34.</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1470-2045(17)30110-9</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Caplin ME, Pavel M, Ćwikła JB, Phan AT, Raderer M, Sedláčková E, Cadiot G, Wolin EM, Capdevila J, Wall L, Rindi G, Langley A, Martinez S, Blumberg J, Ruszniewski P. Lanreotide in metastatic enteropancreatic neuroendocrine tumors. N Engl J Med. 2014;371(3):224–33.</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1316158</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Rinke A, Muller HH, Schade-Brittinger C, Klose KJ, Barth P, Wied M, et al. Placebo-controlled, double-blind, prospective, randomized study on the effect of octreotide LAR in the control of tumor growth in patients with metastatic neuroendocrine midgut tumors: a report from the PROMID study group. J Clin Oncol. 2009;27(28):4656–63.</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2009.22.8510</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Horsch D, Baudin E, Singh S, Caplin ME, Ferone D, Wolin EM, et al. Lanreotide autogel/depot (LAN) in patients with advanced bronchopulmonary (BP) neuroendocrine tumors (NETs): results from the phase III SPINET study. Ann Oncol. 2021;32(suppl_5):S906–20. https://doi.org/10.1016/annonc/annonc678 .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/annonc/annonc678</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Hofland LJ, Lamberts SW. The pathophysiological consequences of somatostatin receptor internalization and resistance. Endocr Rev. 2003;24:28–47.</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/er.2000-0001</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Córdoba-Chacón J, Gahete MD, Durán-Prado M, Luque RM, Castaño JP. Truncated somatostatin receptors as new players in somatostatin-cortistatin pathophysiology. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 2011;1220:6–15.</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1749-6632.2011.05985.x</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Molina-Cerrillo J, Alonso-Gordoa T, Martínez-Sáez O, Grande E. Inhibition of peripheral synthesis of serotonin as a new target in neuroendocrine tumors. Oncologist. 2016 Jun;21(6):701–7.</Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Woltering EA, Salvo VA, O’Dorisio TM, Lyons J, Li G, Zhou Y, et al. Clinical value of monitoring plasma octreotide levels during chronic octreotide long-acting repeatable therapy in carcinoid patients. Pancreas. 2008;37(1):94–100.</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MPA.0b013e31816907ab</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Astruc B, Marbach P, Bouterfa H, Denot C, Safari M, Vitaliti A, Sheppard M. Long-acting octreotide and prolonged-release lanreotide formulations have different pharmacokinetic profiles. J Clin Pharmacol. 2005;45:836–44.</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0091270005277936</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Eriksson B, Renstrup J, Imam H, Oberg K. High-dose treatment with lanreotide of patients with advanced neuroendocrine gastrointestinal tumors: clinical and biological effect. Ann Oncol. 1997;8:1041–4.</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1023/A:1008205415035</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Imam H, Eriksson B, Lukinius A, Janson ET, Lindgren PG, Wilander E, Öberg K. Induction of apoptosis in neuroendocrine tumors of the digestive system during treatment with somatostatin analogs. Acta Oncol. 1997;36(6):607–14.</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/02841869709001323</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Al-Efraij K, Aljama MA, Kennecke HF. Association of dose escalation of octreotide long-acting release on clinical symptoms and tumor markers and response among patients with neuroendocrine tumors. Cancer Med. 2015 Jun;4(6):864–70.</Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>• Lau SC, Abdel-Rahman O, Cheung WY. Improved survival with higher doses of octreotide long-acting release in gastroenteropancreatic neuroendocrine tumors. Med Oncol. 2018;35(9):123 Retrospective study evaluating the role of increasing the dose of octreotide LAR. The study suggests an improvement in symptom control and survival in the group of patients receiving higher doses of SSA.</Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Strosberg JR, Benson AB, Huynh L, Duh MS, Goldman J, Sahai V, Rademaker AW, Kulke MH. Clinical benefits of above-standard dose of octreotide LAR in patients with neuroendocrine tumors for control of carcinoid syndrome symptoms: a multicenter retrospective chart review study. Oncologist. 2014;19(9):930–6.</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1634/theoncologist.2014-0120</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Strosberg J, Weber J, Feldman M, Goldman J, Almhanna K, Kvols L. Above-label doses of octreotide-LAR in patients with metastatic small intestinal carcinoid tumors. Gastrointest Cancer Res. 2013 May;6(3):81–5.</Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>• Diamantopoulos LN, Laskaratos FM, Kalligeros M, Shah R, Navalkissoor S, Gnanasegaran G, Banks J, Smith J, Jacobs B, Galanopoulos M, Mandair D, Caplin M, Toumpanakis C. Antiproliferative effect of above-label doses of somatostatin analogs for the management of gastroenteropancreatic neuroendocrine tumors. Neuroendocrinology (Basel). 2021;111(7):650–9 One of the largest retrospective studies assessing the role of reducing the SSA administration interval, from 4-weekly to 3-weekly, in patients with well differentiated neuroendocrine tumors. The study identified potential factors associated with PFS after above-label SSA, such as pancreatic primary tumor origin, higher Ki-67 and extended tumor burden.</Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Chadha MK, Lombardo J, Mashtare T, Wilding GE, Litwin A, Raczyk C, et al. High-dose octreotide acetate for management of gastroenteropancreatic neuroendocrine tumors. Anticancer Res. 2009;29(10):4127–30.</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19846960</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>• Lamberti G, Faggiano A, Brighi N, Tafuto S, Ibrahim T, Brizzi MP, et al. Nonconventional doses of somatostatin analogs in patients with progressing well-differentiated neuroendocrine tumor. J Clin Endocrinol Metab. 2020;105(1):dgz035 Retrospective study evaluating the role of SSA dose escalation in patients with neuroendocrine tumors. The study does not identify differences in outcomes between the use of dose density increase compared with dose intensity increase when treating patients with high-dose SSA.</Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Faiss S, Räth U, Mansmann U, Caird D, Clemens N, Riecken EO, Wiedenmann B. Ultra-high-dose Lanreotide treatment in patients with metastatic neuroendocrine gastroenteropancreatic tumors. Digestion. 1999;60(5):469–76.</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000007693</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Ferolla P, Faggiano A, Grimaldi F, Ferone D, Scarpelli G, Ramundo V, Severino R, Bellucci MC, Camera LM, Lombardi G, Angeletti G, Colao A. Shortened interval of long-acting octreotide administration is effective in patients with well-differentiated neuroendocrine carcinomas in progression on standard doses. J Endocrinol Investig. 2012;35(3):326–31.</Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Welin SV, Janson ET, Sundin A, Stridsberg M, Lavenius E, Granberg D, Skogseid B, Oberg KE, Eriksson BK. High-dose treatment with a long-acting somatostatin analogue in patients with advanced midgut carcinoid tumours. Eur J Endocrinol. 2004;151(1):107–12.</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1530/eje.0.1510107</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Wolin EM, Jarzab B, Eriksson B, Walter T, Toumpanakis C, Morse MA, Tomassetti P, Weber MM, Fogelman D, Ramage J, Poon D, Gadbaw B, Li J, Pasieka JL, Mahamat A, Swahn F, Newell-Price J, Mansoor W, Öberg K. Phase III study of pasireotide long-acting release in patients with metastatic neuroendocrine tumors and carcinoid symptoms refractory to available somatostatin analogues. Drug Des Devel Ther. 2015;9:5075–86.</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/DDDT.S84177</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Strosberg J, El-Haddad G, Wolin E, Hendifar A, Yao J, Chasen B, et al. Phase 3 trial of (177)Lu-Dotatate for midgut neuroendocrine tumors. N Engl J Med. 2017 Jan 12;376(2):125–35.</Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>• Strosberg JR, Caplin ME, Kunz PL, Ruszniewski PB, Bodei L, Hendifar A, et al. 177 Lu-Dotatate plus long-acting octreotide versus high-dose long-acting octreotide in patients with midgut neuroendocrine tumours (NETTER-1): final overall survival and long-term safety results from an open-label, randomised, controlled, phase 3 trial. Lancet Oncol. 2021;22(12):1752–63 Phase III Trial evaluating the role of 177LuDOTATATE compared with high-dose octreotide in patients with well differentiated midgut neuroendocrine tumors. The primary endpoint of PFS was achieved.</Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Strosberg J, Kunz PL, Hendifar A, Yao J, Bushnell D, Kulke MH, et al. Impact of liver tumour burden, alkaline phosphatase elevation, and target lesion size on treatment outcomes with 177 Lu-Dotatate: an analysis of the NETTER-1 study. Eur J Nucl Med Mol Imaging. 2020 Sep;47(10):2372–82.</Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Dasari A, Shen C, Halperin D, Zhao B, Zhou S, Xu Y, Shih T, Yao JC. Trends in the incidence, prevalence, and survival outcomes in patients with neuroendocrine tumors in the United States. JAMA Oncol. 2017;3(10):1335–42.</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaoncol.2017.0589</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
