<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35507442</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>04</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1531-8257</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>04</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Movement disorders : official journal of the Movement Disorder Society</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Mov Disord</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Serum Neurofilament Light Chain in Wilson's Disease: A Promising Indicator but Unparallel to Real-Time Treatment Response.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/mds.29039</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Wilson's disease (WD) currently lacks a promising indicator that could reflect neurological impairment and monitor treatment outcome. We aimed to investigate whether serum neurofilament light chain (sNfL) functions as a candidate for disease assessment and treatment monitoring of WD.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We assessed preclinical and manifested WD patients' sNfL levels compared to controls and analyzed the differences between patients with various clinical symptoms. We then explored the correlation between clinical scales and sNfL levels. And repeated measurements were performed in 34 patients before and after treatment.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">WD patients with neurological involvement had significantly higher sNfL levels than both hepatic patients and controls. Positive correlations were found between Unified Wilson's Disease Rating Scale scores and sNfL and between semiquantitative magnetic resonance imaging scales and sNfL levels in WD patients. However, in the treatment follow-up analysis, the trend of sNfL before and after treatment disaccorded with clinical response.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">These findings suggest that sNfL levels can be an ideal indicator for the severity of neurological involvement but fail to evaluate change in disease condition after treatment. © 2022 International Parkinson and Movement Disorder Society.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 International Parkinson and Movement Disorder Society.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Rou-Min</ForeName>
            <Initials>RM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology and Department of Medical Genetics in Second Affiliated Hospital, and Key Laboratory of Medical Neurobiology of Zhejiang Province, Zhejiang University School of Medicine, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Xu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Wan-Qing</ForeName>
            <Initials>WQ</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology and Department of Medical Genetics in Second Affiliated Hospital, and Key Laboratory of Medical Neurobiology of Zhejiang Province, Zhejiang University School of Medicine, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zheng</LastName>
            <ForeName>Zi-Wei</ForeName>
            <Initials>ZW</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology and Department of Medical Genetics in Second Affiliated Hospital, and Key Laboratory of Medical Neurobiology of Zhejiang Province, Zhejiang University School of Medicine, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Guo-Min</ForeName>
            <Initials>GM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology and Department of Medical Genetics in Second Affiliated Hospital, and Key Laboratory of Medical Neurobiology of Zhejiang Province, Zhejiang University School of Medicine, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mei-Yan</ForeName>
            <Initials>MY</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology and Department of Medical Genetics in Second Affiliated Hospital, and Key Laboratory of Medical Neurobiology of Zhejiang Province, Zhejiang University School of Medicine, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ke</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hua-Zhen</ForeName>
            <Initials>HZ</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology and Department of Medical Genetics in Second Affiliated Hospital, and Key Laboratory of Medical Neurobiology of Zhejiang Province, Zhejiang University School of Medicine, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Xia</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nan</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology and Department of Medical Genetics in Second Affiliated Hospital, and Key Laboratory of Medical Neurobiology of Zhejiang Province, Zhejiang University School of Medicine, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Dong</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yi</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology and Department of Medical Genetics in Second Affiliated Hospital, and Key Laboratory of Medical Neurobiology of Zhejiang Province, Zhejiang University School of Medicine, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Zhi-Ying</ForeName>
            <Initials>ZY</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2106-572X</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology and Department of Medical Genetics in Second Affiliated Hospital, and Key Laboratory of Medical Neurobiology of Zhejiang Province, Zhejiang University School of Medicine, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>NHC and CAMS Key Laboratory of Medical Neurobiology, MOE Frontier Science Center for Brain Research and Brain-Machine Integration, School of Brain Science and Brain Medicine, Zhejiang University, Hangzhou, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>CAS Center for Excellence in Brain Science and Intelligence Technology, Shanghai, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>04</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Mov Disord</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8610688</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0885-3185</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Wilson's disease</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">indicator</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurofilament light chain</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurological impairment</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">treatment monitoring</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>33</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35507442</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mds.29039</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sandahl TD, Laursen TL, Munk DE, Vilstrup H, Weiss KH, Ott P. The prevalence of Wilson's disease: an update. Hepatology 2020;71:722-732.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xie J-J, Wu Z-Y. Wilson's disease in China. Neurosci Bull 2017;33:323-330.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ala A, Walker AP, Ashkan K, Dooley JS, Schilsky ML. Wilson's disease. Lancet 2007;369:397-408.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dong Y, Wang R-M, Yang G-M, Yu H, Xu W-Q, Xie J-J, et al. Role for biochemical assays and Kayser-Fleischer rings in diagnosis of Wilson's disease. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol 2021;19:590-596.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schilsky ML. Wilson disease: diagnosis, treatment, and follow-up. Clin Liver Dis 2017;21:755-767.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chinese Society of Parkinson's Disease and Movement Disorders, Chinese Society of Neurogenetics. Chinese guidelines for diagnosis and treatment of Wilson's disease. Chin J Neurol 2021;54(4):310-319.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ryan A, Nevitt SJ, Tuohy O, Cook P. Biomarkers for diagnosis of Wilson's disease. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 2019;11:38-40.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Walshe JM. The pattern of urinary copper excretion and its response to treatment in patients with Wilson's disease. QJ Med 2011;104:775-778.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Członkowska A, Litwin T, Dzieżyc K, Karliński M, Bring J, Bjartmar C. Characteristics of a newly diagnosed polish cohort of patients with neurological manifestations of Wilson disease evaluated with the unified Wilson's disease rating scale. BMC Neurol 2018;18:34-40.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dusek P, Smolinski L, Redzia-Ogrodnik B, Golebiowski M, Skowronska M, Poujois A, et al. Semiquantitative scale for assessing brain MRI abnormalities in Wilson disease: a validation study. Mov Disord 2020;35:994-1001.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yuan A, Rao MV, Veeranna N, Nixon RA. Neurofilaments and neurofilament proteins in health and disease. Cold Spring Harb Perspect Biol 2017;9:a018309</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li QF, Dong Y, Yang L, Xie JJ, Ma Y, Du YC, et al. Neurofilament light chain is a promising serum biomarker in spinocerebellar ataxia type 3. Mol Neurodegener 2019;14(1):39-44.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shahim P, Politis A, van der Merwe A, Moore B, Ekanayake V, Lippa SM, et al. Time course and diagnostic utility of NfL, tau, GFAP, and UCH-L1 in subacute and chronic TBI. Neurology 2020;95:e623-e636.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang L, Shao YR, Li XY, Ma Y, Dong Y, Wu ZY. Association of the level of neurofilament light with disease severity in patients with spinocerebellar ataxia type 2. Neurology 2021;97:e2404-e2413.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shribman S, Heller C, Burrows M, Heslegrave A, Swift I, Foiani MS, et al. Plasma neurofilament light as a biomarker of neurological involvement in Wilson's disease. Mov Disord 2021;36:503-508.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dong Y, Ni W, Chen WJ, Wan B, Zhao GX, Shi JQ, et al. Spectrum and classification of ATP7B variants in a large cohort of Chinese patients with Wilson's disease guides genetic diagnosis. Theranostics 2016;6:638-649.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scheltens P, Pasquier F, Weerts JG, Barkhof F, Leys D. Qualitative assessment of cerebral atrophy on MRI: inter- and intra-observer reproducibility in dementia and normal aging. Eur Neurol 1997;37:95-99.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kapoor R, Smith KE, Allegretta M, Arnold DL, Carroll W, Comabella M, et al. Serum neurofilament light as a biomarker in progressive multiple sclerosis. Neurology 2020;95:436-444.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bridel C, van Wieringen WN, Zetterberg H, Tijms BM, Teunissen CE, the NFL Group, et al. Diagnostic value of cerebrospinal fluid neurofilament light protein in neurology: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA Neurol 2019;76:1035-1048.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gaetani L, Blennow K, Calabresi P, Di Filippo M, Parnetti L, Zetterberg H. Neurofilament light chain as a biomarker in neurological disorders. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry 2019;90:870-881.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Członkowska A, Litwin T, Dusek P, Ferenci P, Lutsenko S, Medici V, et al. Wilson disease. Nat Rev Dis Primers 2018;4(1):1-21.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bandmann O, Weiss KH, Kaler SG. Wilson's disease and other neurological copper disorders. Lancet Neurol 2015;14:103-113.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu ZY, Wang N, Lin MT, Fang L, Murong SX, Yu L. Mutation analysis and the correlation between genotype and phenotype of Arg778Leu mutation in chinese patients with Wilson disease. Arch Neurol 2001;58:971-976.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu Z, Wang N, Murong S, Lin M. Identification and analysis of mutations of the Wilson disease gene in Chinese population. Chin Med J 2000;113:40-43.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhu M, Dong Y, Ni W, Wu Z-Y. Defective roles of ATP7B missense mutations in cellular copper tolerance and copper excretion. Mol Cell Neurosci 2015;67:31-36.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dusek P, Litwin T, Członkowska A. Neurologic impairment in Wilson disease. Ann Transl Med 2019;7:S64</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
