<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35506703</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>16</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1556-4029</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>04</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of forensic sciences</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Forensic Sci</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Evaluation of extraction parameters in authentic hair reference material using statistical design of experiments.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/1556-4029.15051</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Optimal methods for forensic hair analysis are often debated, especially regarding extraction parameters that include incubation time, temperature, and size of extracted hair particles. To assess hair pretreatment parameters for analysis of drugs of abuse, the statistical technique known as Design of Experiments (DoE) is useful. DoE evaluates both the individual roles and the combinatorial associations between multiple variables and overall drug extraction efficiency. Previous reports have focused on incorporated hair reference material (HRM), which is prepared in the lab at a specified drug concentration. In contrast, authentic HRM, which is prepared by diluting hair from drug users with blank hair to achieve specific drug concentrations, is an effective matrix for standardization of forensic hair testing, since the drug is incorporated into the hair matrix via uptake from systemic distribution. In the present study, extraction parameters for authentic HRM samples containing multiple drugs (diazepam, alprazolam, cocaine, methamphetamine, oxycodone, hydrocodone, and morphine) and metabolites (nordiazepam, cocaethylene, norcocaine, hydroxycocaine, and 6-monoacetylmorphine) were optimized based on recovery using a 2<sup>3</sup> full factorial DoE matrix. The factors evaluated included extraction solvent volume/sample weight ratio (12.5 or 25 μL/mg), particle size (pulverized or cut into 1 mm snippets), and extraction time (2 or 24 h) using solvent swelling. DoE analysis revealed significant differences in the optimal combinations of extraction parameters for maximum recovery. However, for the majority of drugs and metabolites, the most effective extraction method consisted of pulverizing hair prior to a 2-h extraction with a 12.5 μL/mg extraction solvent volume/sample weight ratio.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 American Academy of Forensic Sciences.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Spear</LastName>
            <ForeName>Brianna</ForeName>
            <Initials>B</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Chemistry &amp; Biochemistry, Florida International University, Miami, Florida, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>DeCaprio</LastName>
            <ForeName>Anthony P</ForeName>
            <Initials>AP</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Chemistry &amp; Biochemistry, Florida International University, Miami, Florida, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>International Forensic Research Institute, Florida International University, Miami, Florida, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>04</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Forensic Sci</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0375370</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0022-1198</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">authentic hair reference material</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">forensic hair analysis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hair extraction method</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">statistical design of experiments</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
          <Hour>9</Hour>
          <Minute>12</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35506703</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1556-4029.15051</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kintz P, Salomone A, Vincenti M. Hair analysis in clinical and forensic toxicology. Cambridge, MA: Academic Press; 2015. p. 241-63.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Polettini A, Cone EJ, Gorelick DA, Huestis MA. Incorporation of methamphetamine and amphetamine in human hair following controlled oral methamphetamine administration. Anal Chim Acta. 2012;726:35-43. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.aca.2012.01.042</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cappelle D, De Keukeleire S, Neels H, Been F, De Doncker M, Dom G, et al. Keratinous matrices for the assessment of drugs of abuse consumption: a correlation study between hair and nails. Drug Test Anal. 2018;10(7):1110-8. https://doi.org/10.1002/dta.2356</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mantinieks D, Wright P, Di Rago M, Gerostamoulos D. A systematic investigation of forensic hair decontamination procedures and their limitations. Drug Test Anal. 2019;11(10):1542-55. https://doi.org/10.1002/dta.2681</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Davies C, Gautam L, Grela A, Morrissey J. Variability associated with interpreting drugs within forensic hair analysis: a three-stage interpretation. J Appl Toxicol. 2020;40(7):868-88. https://doi.org/10.1002/jat.3959</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ropero-Miller JD, Stout PR. Development and production of reference materials for control and calibration of hair drug testing final report. Washington, DC: National Institute of Justice; 2008. Report No. p. 224523.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cooper GA, Kronstrand R, Kintz P. Society of Hair Testing guidelines for drug testing in hair. Forensic Sci Int. 2012;218(1-3):20-4. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.forsciint.2011.10.024</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hewavitharana AK. Matrix matching in liquid chromatography-mass spectrometry with stable isotope labelled internal standards-is it necessary? J Chromatogr A. 2011;1218(2):359-61. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chroma.2010.11.047</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Montgomery DC. Design and analysis of experiments. 8th ed. Danvers, MA: Wiley; 2013. p. 233-348.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aijala JC, Wu W, DeCaprio AP. Application of statistical design of experiments to assess pre-treatment parameters in forensic hair analysis for amphetamine. Forensic Chem. 2020;20:100265. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.forc.2020.100265</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aijala JC, Wu W, DeCaprio AP. Assessing hair decontamination protocols for diazepam, heroin, cocaine, and Δ9-tetrahydrocannabinol by statistical design of experiments. J Anal Toxicol. 2021;45(5):498-505. https://doi.org/10.1093/jat/bkaa110</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gunnar T, Ariniemi K, Lillsunde P. Validated toxicological determination of 30 drugs of abuse as optimized derivatives in oral fluid by long column fast gas chromatography/electron impact mass spectrometry. J Mass Spectrom. 2005;40(6):739-53. https://doi.org/10.1002/jms.846</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miller EI, Wylie FM, Oliver JS. Simultaneous detection and quantification of amphetamines, diazepam and its metabolites, cocaine and its metabolites, and opiates in hair by LC-ESI-MS-MS using a single extraction method. J Anal Toxicol. 2008;32(7):457-69. https://doi.org/10.1093/jat/32.7.457</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>ANSI/ASB Standard 036. Standard practices for method validation in forensic toxicology, 1st edn. Colorado Springs, CO: AAFS Standards Board, LLC; 2019. https://www.aafs.org/sites/default/files/media/documents/036_Std_e1.pdf. Accessed 18 April 2022.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aleksa K, Walasek P, Fulga N, Kapur B, Gareri J, Koren G. Simultaneous detection of seventeen drugs of abuse and metabolites in hair using solid phase micro extraction (SPME) with GC/MS. Forensic Sci Int. 2012;218(1-3):31-6. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.forsciint.2011.10.002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baumgartner MR, Guglielmello R, Fanger M, Kraemer T. Analysis of drugs of abuse in hair: evaluation of the immunochemical method VMA-T vs. LC-MS/MS or GC-MS. Forensic Sci Int. 2012;215(1-3):56-9. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.forsciint.2011.08.025</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coulter C, Tuyay J, Taruc M, Moore C. Semi-quantitative analysis of drugs of abuse, including tetrahydrocannabinol in hair using aqueous extraction and immunoassay. Forensic Sci Int. 2010;196(1-3):70-3. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.forsciint.2009.12.025</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Domínguez-Romero JC, García-Reyes JF, Molina-Díaz A. Screening and quantitation of multiclass drugs of abuse and pharmaceuticals in hair by fast liquid chromatography electrospray time-of-flight mass spectrometry. J Chromatogr B. 2011;879(22):2034-42. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jchromb.2011.05.034</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eisenbeiss L, Steuer AE, Binz TM, Baumgartner MR, Kraemer TJA. (un)targeted hair metabolomics: first considerations and systematic evaluation on the impact of sample preparation. Anal Bioanal Chem. 2019;411(17):3963-77. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00216-019-01873-4</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mueller A, Jungen H, Iwersen-Bergmann S, Raduenz L, Lezius S, Andresen-Streichert H. Determination of ethyl glucuronide in human hair samples: a multivariate analysis of the impact of extraction conditions on quantitative results. Forensic Sci Int. 2017;271:43-8. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.forsciint.2016.12.011</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alladio E, Biosa G, Seganti F, Di Corcia D, Salomone A, Vincenti M, et al. Systematic optimisation of ethyl glucuronide extraction conditions from scalp hair by design of experiments and its potential effect on cut-off values appraisal. Drug Test Anal. 2018;10(9):1394-403. https://doi.org/10.1002/dta.2405</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salomone A, Baumgartner M, Lombardo T, Alladio E, Di Corcia D, Vincenti M. Effects of various sample pretreatment procedures on ethyl glucuronide quantification in hair samples: comparison of positivity rates and appraisal of cut-off values. Forensic Sci Int. 2016;267:60-5. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.forsciint.2016.08.012</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>da Rosa Chagas AG, Spinelli E, Fiaux SB, da Silva BA, Rodrigues SV. Particle-size distribution (PSD) of pulverized hair: a quantitative approach of milling efficiency and its correlation with drug extraction efficiency. Forensic Sci Int. 2017;277:188-96. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.forsciint.2017.06.008</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ishiyama I, Nagai T, Toshida S. Detection of basic drugs (methamphetamine, antidepressants, and nicotine) from human hair. J Forensic Sci. 1983;28(2):380-5. https://doi.org/10.1520/JFS11518J</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
