<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35503000</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>15</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2672</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>03</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of applied microbiology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Appl Microbiol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Ketoprofen, piroxicam and indomethacin-suppressed quorum sensing and virulence factors in Acinetobacter baumannii.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jam.15609</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Quorum sensing (QS) inhibition is a promising strategy to suppress bacterial virulence and control infection caused by Gram-negative and Gram-positive bacteria. This study explores the QS inhibiting activity of the non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs (NSAIDs) in Acinetobacter baumannii.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS AND RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Ketoprofen, piroxicam and indomethacin revealed QS inhibition via elimination of violacein production of the reporter strain Chromobacterium violaceum ATCC 12472 without affecting bacterial growth. The minimal inhibitory concentration (MIC) of ketoprofen, piroxicam and indomethacin was determined against A. baumannii strains ATCC 17978, ATCC 19606, A1, A11 and A27 by the microbroth dilution method. The MICs of ketoprofen against tested isolates were 0.7-6.25 mg ml<sup>-1</sup> , piroxicam MICs were 1.25-2.5 mg ml<sup>-1</sup> , and indomethacin MICs were 3.12-12.5 mg ml<sup>-1</sup> . Those compounds significantly inhibited QS-associated virulence factors such as biofilm formation, and surface motility, as well as, significantly increased bacterial tolerance to oxidative stress without affecting bacterial growth. On the molecular level, the three compounds significantly inhibited the transcription of QS regulatory genes abaI/abaR and biofilm-regulated genes cusD and pgaB. Molecular docking analysis revealed the potent binding affinity of the three compounds with AbaI via hydrogen and/or hydrophobic bonds.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">These results indicate that NSAIDs, ketoprofen, piroxicam and indomethacin, could be potential inhibitors of the QS and could suppress the QS-related virulence factors of A. baumannii.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="SIGNIFICANCE AND IMPACT" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Ketoprofen, piroxicam and indomethacin could provide promising implications and strategies for combating the virulence and pathogenesis of A. baumannii.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 Society for Applied Microbiology.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Elshaer</LastName>
            <ForeName>Soha Lotfy</ForeName>
            <Initials>SL</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Microbiology and Immunology, Faculty of Pharmacy, Mansoura University, Mansoura, Egypt.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Shaldam</LastName>
            <ForeName>Moataz A</ForeName>
            <Initials>MA</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0420-4364</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutical Chemistry, Faculty of Pharmacy, Kafrelsheikh University, Kafr El Sheikh, Egypt.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Shaaban</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mona I</ForeName>
            <Initials>MI</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3044-6102</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Microbiology and Immunology, Faculty of Pharmacy, Mansoura University, Mansoura, Egypt.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>03</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Appl Microbiol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9706280</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1364-5072</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">biofilm</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">motility</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">oxidative stress</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">quorum quenching</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">quorum sensing inhibition</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
          <Hour>9</Hour>
          <Minute>53</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35503000</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jam.15609</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alves, S., Duarte, A., Sousa, S. &amp; Domingues, F.C. (2016) Study of the major essential oil compounds of Coriandrum sativum against Acinetobacter baumannii and the effect of linalool on adhesion, biofilms and quorum sensing. Biofouling, 32, 155-165.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Anbazhagan, D., Mansor, M., Yan, G.O.S., Yusof, M.Y., Hassan, H. &amp; Sekaran, S.D. (2012) Detection of quorum sensing signal molecules and identification of an autoinducer synthase gene among biofilm forming clinical isolates of Acinetobacter spp. PLoS One, 7, e36696.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Askoura, M., Saleh, M. &amp; Abbas, H. (2020) An innovative role for tenoxicam as a quorum sensing inhibitor in Pseudomonas aeruginosa. Archives of Microbiology, 202, 555-565.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bhargava, N., Sharma, P. &amp; Capalash, N. (2014) Pyocyanin stimulates quorum sensing-mediated tolerance to oxidative stress and increases persister cell populations in Acinetobacter baumannii. Infection and Immunity, 82, 3417-3425.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bhargava, N., Singh, S.P., Sharma, A., Sharma, P. &amp; Capalash, N. (2015) Attenuation of quorum sensing-mediated virulence of Acinetobacter baumannii by Glycyrrhiza glabra flavonoids. Future Microbiology, 10, 1953-1968.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bhattacharya, S.P., Mitra, A., Bhattacharya, A. &amp; Sen, A. (2020) Quorum quenching activity of pentacyclic triterpenoids leads to inhibition of biofilm formation by Acinetobacter baumannii. Biofouling, 36, 922-937.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chabane, Y.N., Mlouka, M.B., Alexandre, S., Nicol, M., Marti, S., Pestel-Caron, M. et al. (2014) Virstatin inhibits biofilm formation and motility of Acinetobacter baumannii. BMC Microbiology, 14, 62.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chow, J.Y., Yang, Y., Tay, S.B., Chua, K.L. &amp; Yew, W.S. (2014) Disruption of biofilm formation by the human pathogen Acinetobacter baumannii using engineered quorum-quenching lactonases. Antimicrobial Agents and Chemotherapy, 58, 1802-1805.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clemmer, K.M., Bonomo, R.A. &amp; Rather, P.N. (2011) Genetic analysis of surface motility in Acinetobacter baumannii. Microbiology (Reading), 157, 2534-2544.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>CLSI (Clinical Laboratory Standard Institute). (2015) Performance standards for antimicrobial susceptibility testing twenty-fifth informational supplement CLSI document M100-S25. Wayne, PA: CLSI.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dai, L., Wu, T.-Q., Xiong, Y.-S., Ni, H.-B., Ding, Y., Zhang, W.-C. et al. (2019) Ibuprofen-mediated potential inhibition of biofilm development and quorum sensing in Pseudomonas aeruginosa. Life Sciences, 237, 116947.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dong, Y.-H., Wang, L.-H. &amp; Zhang, L.-H. (2007) Quorum-quenching microbial infections: mechanisms and implications. Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society B: Biological Sciences, 362, 1201-1211.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ellis, D., Cohen, B., Liu, J. &amp; Larson, E. (2015) Risk factors for hospital-acquired antimicrobial-resistant infection caused by Acinetobacter baumannii. Antimicrobial Resistance and Infection Control, 4, 40.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>El-Mowafy, M., Elgaml, A. &amp; Shaaban, M. (2019) New approaches for competing microbial resistance and virulence. In: Blumenberg, M., Shaaban, M. &amp; Elgaml, A. (Eds.) Microorganisms. London, UK: IntechOpen.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>El-Mowafy, S.A., Abd El Galil, K.H., El-Messery, S.M. &amp; Shaaban, M.I. (2014) Aspirin is an efficient inhibitor of quorum sensing, virulence and toxins in Pseudomonas aeruginosa. Microbial Pathogenesis, 74, 25-32.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Espinal, P., Marti, S. &amp; Vila, J. (2012) Effect of biofilm formation on the survival of Acinetobacter baumannii on dry surfaces. The Journal of Hospital Infection, 80, 56-60.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gala, V.C., John, N.R., Bhagwat, A.M., Datar, A.G., Kharkar, P.S. &amp; Desai, K.B. (2016) Attenuation of quorum sensing-regulated behaviour by Tinospora cordifolia extract and identification of its active constituents. The Indian Journal of Medical Research, 144, 92-103.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harding, C.M., Hennon, S.W. &amp; Feldman, M.F. (2018) Uncovering the mechanisms of Acinetobacter baumannii virulence. Nature Reviews. Microbiology, 16, 91-102.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harding, C.M., Tracy, E.N., Carruthers, M.D., Rather, P.N., Actis, L.A. &amp; Munson, R.S. (2013) Acinetobacter baumannii strain M2 produces type IV pili which play a role in natural transformation and twitching motility but not surface-associated motility. mBio, 4, e00360-13.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heindorf, M., Kadari, M., Heider, C., Skiebe, E. &amp; Wilharm, G. (2014) Impact of Acinetobacter baumannii superoxide dismutase on motility, virulence, oxidative stress resistance and susceptibility to antibiotics. PLoS One, 9, e101033.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jothipandiyan, S., Suresh, D., Sankaran, S.V., Thamotharan, S., Shanmugasundaram, K., Vincent, P. et al. (2022) Heteroleptic pincer palladium (II) complex coated orthopedic implants impede the AbaI/AbaR quorum sensing system and biofilm development by Acinetobacter baumannii. Biofouling, 38, 55-70.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khadke, S.K., Lee, J.-H., Kim, Y.-G., Raj, V. &amp; Lee, J.J.B. (2021) Assessment of antibiofilm potencies of nervonic and oleic acid against Acinetobacter baumannii using in vitro and computational approaches. Biomedicines, 9, 1133.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Laskowski, R.A. &amp; Swindells, M.B. (2011) LigPlot+: multiple ligand-protein interaction diagrams for drug discovery. Journal of Chemical Information &amp; Modeliing, 51(2778), 2786.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Livak, K.J. &amp; Schmittgen, T.D. (2001) Analysis of relative gene expression data using real-time quantitative PCR and the 2(-Delta Delta C[T]) method. Methods, 25, 402-408.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Loehfelm, T.W., Luke, N.R. &amp; Campagnari, A.A. (2008) Identification and characterization of an Acinetobacter baumannii biofilm-associated protein. Journal of Bacteriology, 190, 1036-1044.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lopez, M., Mayer, C., Fernandez-Garcia, L., Blasco, L., Muras, A., Ruiz, F.M. et al. (2017) Quorum sensing network in clinical strains of A. baumannii: AidA is a new quorum quenching enzyme. PLoS One, 12, e0174454.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Luís, Â., Duarte, A., Gominho, J., Domingues, F.C. &amp; Duarte, A.P. (2016) Chemical composition, antioxidant, antibacterial and anti-quorum sensing activities of Eucalyptus globulus and Eucalyptus radiata essential oils. Industrial Crops and Products, 79, 274-282.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maeda, T., García-Contreras, R., Pu, M., Sheng, L., Garcia, L.R., Tomás, M. et al. (2012) Quorum quenching quandary: resistance to antivirulence compounds. The ISME Journal, 6, 493-501.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maidak, B.L., Cole, J.R., Lilburn, T.G., Parker, C.T., Jr., Saxman, P.R., Stredwick, J.M. et al. (2000) The RDP (ribosomal database project) continues. Nucleic Acids Research, 28, 173-174.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mayer, C., Muras, A., Romero, M., Lopez, M., Tomas, M. &amp; Otero, A. (2018) Multiple quorum quenching enzymes are active in the nosocomial pathogen Acinetobacter baumannii ATCC17978. Frontiers in Cellular and Infection Microbiology, 8, 310.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McClean, K.H., Winson, M.K., Fish, L., Taylor, A., Chhabra, S.R., Camara, M. et al. (1997) Quorum sensing and Chromobacterium violaceum: exploitation of violacein production and inhibition for the detection of N-acylhomoserine lactones. Microbiology (Reading), 143(Pt 12), 3703-3711.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McLean, R.J., Pierson, L.S., 3rd &amp; Fuqua, C. (2004) A simple screening protocol for the identification of quorum signal antagonists. Journal of Microbiological Methods, 58, 351-360.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mion, S., Carriot, N., Lopez, J., Plener, L., Ortalo-Magné, A., Chabrière, E. et al. (2021) Disrupting quorum sensing alters social interactions in Chromobacterium violaceum. NPJ Biofilms Microbiomes, 7, 40.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morohoshi, T., Fukamachi, K., Kato, M., Kato, N. &amp; Ikeda, T. (2010) Regulation of the violacein biosynthetic gene cluster by acylhomoserine lactone-mediated quorum sensing in Chromobacterium violaceum ATCC 12472. Bioscience, Biotechnology, and Biochemistry, 74, 2116-2119.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morohoshi, T., Kato, M., Fukamachi, K., Kato, N. &amp; Ikeda, T. (2008) N-acylhomoserine lactone regulates violacein production in Chromobacterium violaceum type strain ATCC 12472. FEMS Microbiology Letters, 279, 124-130.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Naga, N.G., EL-Badan, D.E., Rateb, H.S., Ghanem, K.M. &amp; Shaaban, M.I. (2021) Quorum sensing inhibiting activity of cefoperazone and its metallic derivatives on Pseudomonas aeruginosa. Frontiers in Cellular and Infection Microbiology, 11, 716789.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nicol, M., Alexandre, S., Luizet, J.B., Skogman, M., Jouenne, T., Salcedo, S.P. et al. (2018) Unsaturated fatty acids affect quorum sensing communication system and inhibit motility and biofilm formation of Acinetobacter baumannii. International Journal of Molecular Sciences, 19, 214.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Niu, C., Clemmer, K.M., Bonomo, R.A. &amp; Rather, P.N. (2008) Isolation and characterization of an autoinducer synthase from Acinetobacter baumannii. Journal of Bacteriology, 190, 3386-3392.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paes Leme, R.C. &amp; Da Silva, R.B. (2021) Antimicrobial activity of non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs on biofilm: current evidence and potential for drug repurposing. Frontiers in Microbiology, 12, 707629.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paluch, E., Rewak-Soroczyńska, J., Jędrusik, I., Mazurkiewicz, E. &amp; Jermakow, K.J.A.M. (2020) Prevention of biofilm formation by quorum quenching. Applied Microbiology &amp; Biotechnology, 104, 1871-1881.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Papenfort, K. &amp; Bassler, B.L. (2016) Quorum sensing signal-response systems in gram-negative bacteria. Nature Reviews. Microbiology, 14, 576-588.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Perez-Varela, M., Corral, J., Aranda, J. &amp; Barbe, J. (2019) Roles of efflux pumps from different superfamilies in the surface-associated motility and virulence of Acinetobacter baumannii ATCC 17978. Antimicrobial Agents and Chemotherapy, 63, e02190-18.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rio, D. C., Ares, M., JR., Hannon, G. J. &amp; Nilsen, T. W. 2010. Purification of RNA using TRIzol (TRI reagent). Cold Spring Harbor Protocols, 6, pdb-prot5439.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saipriya, K., Swathi, C., Ratnakar, K. &amp; Sritharan, V. (2020) Quorum-sensing system in Acinetobacter baumannii: a potential target for new drug development. Journal of Applied Microbiology, 128, 15-27.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saroj, S.D. &amp; Rather, P.N. (2013) Streptomycin inhibits quorum sensing in Acinetobacter baumannii. Antimicrobial Agents and Chemotherapy, 57, 1926-1929.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Seleem, N.M., Abd El Latif, H.K., Shaldam, M.A. &amp; EL-Ganiny, A. (2020) Drugs with new lease of life as quorum sensing inhibitors: for combating MDR Acinetobacter baumannii infections. European Journal of Clinical Microbiology &amp; Infectious Diseases, 39, 1687-1702.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Seleem, N.M., Atallah, H., Abd El Latif, H.K., Shaldam, M.A. &amp; EL-Ganiny, A.M. (2021) Could the analgesic drugs, paracetamol and indomethacin, function as quorum sensing inhibitors? Microbial Pathogenesis, 158, 105097.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sievers, F. &amp; Higgins, D.G. (2014) Clustal omega, accurate alignment of very large numbers of sequences. Methods in Molecular Biology, 1079, 105-116.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stacy, D.M., Welsh, M.A., Rather, P.N. &amp; Blackwell, H.E. (2012) Attenuation of quorum sensing in the pathogen Acinetobacter baumannii using non-native N-acyl homoserine lactones. ACS Chemical Biology, 7, 1719-1728.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stepanovic, S., Vukovic, D., Dakic, I., Savic, B. &amp; Svabic-Vlahovic, M. (2000) A modified microtiter-plate test for quantification of staphylococcal biofilm formation. Journal of Microbiological Methods, 40, 175-179.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Subhadra, B., Oh, M.H. &amp; Choi, C.H. (2016) Quorum sensing in Acinetobacter: with special emphasis on antibiotic resistance, biofilm formation and quorum quenching. Journal of Applied Microbiology, 2, 27-41.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tajani, A.S., Jangi, E., Davodi, M., Golmakaniyoon, S., Ghodsi, R., Soheili, V. et al. (2021) Anti-quorum sensing potential of ketoprofen and its derivatives against Pseudomonas aeruginosa: insights to in silico and in vitro studies. Archives of Microbiology, 203, 5123-5132.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tomaras, A.P., Dorsey, C.W., Edelmann, R.E. &amp; Actis, L.A. (2003) Attachment to and biofilm formation on abiotic surfaces by Acinetobacter baumannii: involvement of a novel chaperone-usher pili assembly system. Microbiology (Reading), 149, 3473-3484.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tomaras, A.P., Flagler, M.J., Dorsey, C.W., Gaddy, J.A. &amp; Actis, L.A. (2008) Characterization of a two-component regulatory system from Acinetobacter baumannii that controls biofilm formation and cellular morphology. Microbiology (Reading), 154, 3398-3409.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Trott, O. &amp; Olson, A.J. (2010) AutoDock Vina: improving the speed and accuracy of docking with a new scoring function, efficient optimization and multithreading. Journal of Computational Chemistry, 31, 455-461.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ulusoy, S. &amp; Bosgelmez-Tinaz, G.J.D.R. (2013) Nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs reduce the production of quorum sensing regulated virulence factors and swarming motility in human pathogen Pseudomonas aeruginosa. Drug Research, 63, 409-413.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vijayakumar, S., Rajenderan, S., Laishram, S., Anandan, S., Balaji, V. &amp; Biswas, I. (2016) Biofilm formation and motility depend on the nature of the Acinetobacter baumannii clinical isolates. Frontiers in Public Health, 4, 105.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vogel, J., Jansen, L., Setroikromo, R., Cavallo, F.M., Van Dijl, J.M. &amp; Quax, W.J. (2022) Fighting Acinetobacter baumannii infections with the acylase PvdQ. Microbes and Infection, 24, 104951.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wisplinghoff, H., Schmitt, R., Wohrmann, A., Stefanik, D. &amp; Seifert, H. (2007) Resistance to disinfectants in epidemiologically defined clinical isolates of Acinetobacter baumannii. The Journal of Hospital Infection, 66, 174-181.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Woodford, N., Ellington, M.J., Coelho, J.M., Turton, J.F., Ward, M.E., Brown, S. et al. (2006) Multiplex PCR for genes encoding prevalent OXA carbapenemases in Acinetobacter spp. International Journal of Antimicrobial Agents, 27, 351-353.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>World Medical Association. (2013) World Medical Association Declaration of Helsinki: ethical principles for medical research involving human subjects. JAMA, 310, 2191-2194.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang, K., Yang, X., Yang, J., Qiao, X., Li, F., Liu, X. et al. (2020) Alcohol dehydrogenase modulates quorum sensing in biofilm formations of Acinetobacter baumannii. Microbial Pathogenesis, 148, 104451.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang, Y., Brackman, G. &amp; Coenye, T. (2017) Pitfalls associated with evaluating enzymatic quorum quenching activity: the case of MomL and its effect on Pseudomonas aeruginosa and Acinetobacter baumannii biofilms. PeerJ, 5, e3251.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhong, S. &amp; He, S. (2021) Quorum sensing inhibition or quenching in Acinetobacter baumannii: the novel therapeutic strategies for new drug development. Frontiers in Microbiology, 12, 558003.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
