<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35511098</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>09</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>09</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1538-1145</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>28</Volume>
            <Issue>3</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>01</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of psychiatric practice</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Psychiatr Pract</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>How an Understanding of the Function of the Locus Coeruleus Led to Use of Dexmedetomidine to Treat Agitation in Bipolar Disorder: Example of Rational Development of Psychiatric Medications.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>227</StartPage>
          <EndPage>233</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>227-233</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/PRA.0000000000000634</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>This column reviews &gt;50 years of research on the functions subsumed by the locus coeruleus (LC) (also called the central adrenergic system). A major role of the LC is monitoring acid-base balance in the brain and responding by regulating blood-brain permeability to water and other small molecules and cerebral blood flow. The LC, through its downward projections, also regulates and coordinates respiratory and cardiac functions. Through its effect regionally or more globally depending on the stimulus and its magnitude, the LC can regulate the extracellular space in the brain, which in turn can alter ionic concentrations and thus the sensitivity of neurons to signaling. As a result of these far-reaching effects, the LC has been implicated in brain functions ranging from sleep and wakefulness to psychiatric conditions such as hyperarousal/hypervigilance, fear, agitation, anxiety, and panic attacks. This understanding of the brain functions subsumed by the LC has, in turn, led to the most recent development in the use of dexmedetomidine, an alpha-2 adrenergic agonist, to treat agitation in patients with bipolar disorder. This column also illustrates a theme discussed in a series of previous columns concerning the successful development of novel psychiatric/central nervous system drugs on the basis of an understanding of relatively simple circuits or mechanisms that underlie pathologic behavior.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Preskorn</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sheldon H</ForeName>
            <Initials>SH</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>PRESKORN: Kansas University School of Medicine-Wichita, Wichita, KS.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>01</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Psychiatr Pract</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>100901141</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1527-4160</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D058647">Adrenergic alpha-2 Receptor Agonists</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>67VB76HONO</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D020927">Dexmedetomidine</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D058647" MajorTopicYN="N">Adrenergic alpha-2 Receptor Agonists</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001007" MajorTopicYN="N">Anxiety</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001714" MajorTopicYN="Y">Bipolar Disorder</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D020927" MajorTopicYN="Y">Dexmedetomidine</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008125" MajorTopicYN="N">Locus Coeruleus</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
          <Hour>11</Hour>
          <Minute>13</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35511098</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PRA.0000000000000634</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">00131746-202205000-00006</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Preskorn SH, Zeller S, Citrome L, et al. Effect of sublingual dexmedetomidine vs placebo on acute agitation associated with bipolar disorder: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA. 2022;327:727–736.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tubbs RS, Loukas M, Shoja MM, et al. Félix Vicq d’Azyr (1746-1794): early founder of neuroanatomy and royal French physician. Childs Nerv Syst. 2011;27:1031–1034.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swanson LW. Neuroanatomical Terminology: A Lexicon of Classical Origins and Historical Foundations. Oxford, UK: Oxford University Press; 2014.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swanson LW, Hartman BK. The central adrenergic system: an immunofluorescence study of the location of the cell bodies and their efferent connections in the rat utilizing dopamine-beta-hydroxylase as a marker. J Comp Neurol. 1975;163:467–506.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hartman BK, Swanson LW, Kaplan GP, et al. Anatomical evidence for central catecholaminergic innervation of the cerebral microvasculature. J Cereb Blood Flow Metab. 1981;1:S307–S308.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clark HB, Hartman BK, Raichle ME, et al. Measurement of cerebral vascular extraction fractions in the rat using intracarotid injection techniques. Brain Res. 1981;208:311–323.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clark HB, Hartman BK, Raichle ME, et al. An intravenous technique for the measurement of cerebral vascular extraction fraction in the rat. J Cereb Blood Flow Metab. 1982;2:187–196.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Irwin GH, Preskorn SH. A dual label radiotracer technique for the simultaneous measurement of cerebral blood flow and the single-transit cerebral extraction of diffusion-limited compounds in rats. Brain Res. 1982;249:23–30.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kent T, Preskorn SH. A modified method for the simultaneous determination of regional single-transit brain extraction of diffusion-limited compounds and cerebral blood flow: utilization of non-invasive measurement of transit time. Brain Res. 1985;335:251–255.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Preskorn SH, Hartman BK, Raichle ME, et al. The effect of dibenzazepines (tricyclic antidepressants) on cerebral capillary permeability in the rat in vivo. J Pharmacol Exp Ther. 1980;213:313–320.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Preskorn SH, Hartman BK, Raichle ME, et al. Central adrenergic regulation of cerebral microvascular permeability and blood flow: pharmacologic evidence. Adv Exp Med Biol. 1980;131:127–138.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Preskorn SH, Hartman BK, Clark HB. Long-term antidepressant treatment: alterations in cerebral capillary permeability. Psychopharmacology (Berl). 1980;70:1–4.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Preskorn SH, Irwin GH, Simpson S, et al. Medical therapies for mood disorders alter the blood-brain barrier. Science. 1981;213:469–471.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Preskorn SH, Raichle ME, Hartman BK. Antidepressants alter cerebrovascular permeability and metabolic rate in primates. Science. 1982;217:250–252.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Glotzbach RK, Preskorn SH. Brain concentrations of tricyclic antidepressants: single-dose kinetics and relationship to plasma concentrations in chronically dosed rats. Psychopharmacology (Berl). 1982;78:25–27.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Preskorn SH, Hartman BK, Irwin GH, et al. Role of the central adrenergic system in mediating amitriptyline-induced alteration in the mammalian blood-brain barrier in vivo. J Pharmacol Exp Ther. 1982;223:388–395.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Preskorn SH, Irwin G, Simpson S, et al. Modulation of cerebral fluid dynamics: alpha and beta adrenergic mechanisms. J Cereb Blood Flow Metab. 1981;1:S373–S374.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kent TA, Preskorn SH, Solnick JV, et al. Differential effects of central biogenic amines on cerebral blood flow and the blood-brain barrier. J Cereb Blood Flow Metab. 1983;3:S228–S229.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hughes C, Kent T, Campbell J, et al. Cerebral blood flow and cerebrovascular permeability in an inescapable shock (learned helplessness) animal model of depression. Pharmacol Biochem Behav. 1984;21:891–894.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Preskorn SH, Kent TA, Glotzbach RK, et al. Cerebromicrocirculatory defects in animal model of depression. Psychopharmacology (Berl). 1984;84:196–199.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kent T, Preskorn SH, Glotzbach RK, et al. Amitriptyline normalizes tetrabenazine-induced changes in cerebral microcirculation. Biol Psychiatry. 1986;21:483–491.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kent T, Nagy G, Oke A, et al. Effect of CO2 on a brain extracellular space marker and evidence of its neuronal modulation. Brain Res. 1985;342:141–144.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Preskorn SH, Hartman BK. The effect of tricyclic antidepressants on cerebral fluid dynamics. Biol Psychiatry. 1979;14:235–250.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elam M, Vao T, Thoren PI, et al. Hypercapnia and hypoxia: chemoreceptor mediated control of the locus coeruleus neurons and splanchnic, sympathetic nerves. Brain Res. 1981;222:373–381.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Drevets WC, Videen T, Preskorn SH, et al. A functional anatomical study of unipolar depression. J Neurosci. 1992;12:3628–3641.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cohen ME, White PD. Life situations, emotions, and neurocirculatory asthenia (anxiety neurosis, neurasthenia, effort syndrome). Psychosom Med. 1951;13:335–357.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pitts FN, McClure JN. Lactate metabolism in anxiety neurosis. N Engl J Med. 1967;227:1329–1336.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Klein DF. False suffocation alarms, spontaneous panics, and related conditions. An integrative hypothesis. Arch Gen Psychiatry. 1993;50:306–317.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wemmie JA. Neurobiology of panic and pH chemosensation in the brain. Dialogues Clin Neurosci. 2011;13:475–483.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Spaer CB, Scammel TE, Lu J. Hypothalamic regulation of sleep and circadian rhythms. Nature. 2006;437:1257–1262.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tononi G, Cirreli C Charney DS, Nestler EJ. The neurobiology of sleep. Neurobiology of Mental Illness, Third Edition. Oxford, UK: Oxford University Press; 2009:1370–1386.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Richelson E. Pharmacology of antidepressants—characteristics of the ideal drug. Mayo Clin Proc. 1994;69:1069–1081.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Vivo M, Seth S, Sharma S, et al. Dexmedetomidine–highly favorable pharmacokinetic and pharmacological features for a CNS therapeutic drug adaptation to stress. Poster presented at the Annual Meeting of the American College of Neuropsychopharmacology, Orlando, FL, December 7-11, 2019.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Audinot V, Fabry N, Nicolas J-P, et al. Ligand modulation of [35S]GTPgS binding at human a2A, a2B and a2C adrenoceptors. Cell Signal. 2002;14:829–837. Available at: https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Frederic-Bornancin/publication/257313794_Ligand_modulation_of_35SGTPgS_binding_at_human_a2A_a2B_and_a2C_adrenoceptors/links/5a07253da6fdcc65eab3a6af/Ligand-modulation-of-35SGTPgS-binding-at-human-a2A-a2B-and-a2C-adrenoceptors.pdf. Accessed March 27, 2020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Preskorn SH. CNS drug development: lessons from the development of ondansetron, aprepitant, ramelteon, varenicline, lorcaserin, and suvorexant. Part I. J Psychiatr Pract. 2014;20:460–465.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Preskorn SH. CNS drug development: lessons learned Part 2. Symptoms, not syndromes as targets consistent with the NIMH research domain approach. J Psychiatr Pract. 2015;21:60–66.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Preskorn SH. Psychiatric and central nervous system drugs developed over the last decade: what are the implications for the field? J Psychiatr Pract. 2017;23:352–360.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Preskorn SH. CNS drug development, lessons learned, part 4: the role of brain circuitry and genes—tasimelteon as an example. J Psychiatr Pract. 2017;23:425–430.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Preskorn S. CNS drug development, lessons learned, part 5: how preclinical and human safety studies inform the approval and subsequent use of a new drug—suvorexant as an example. J Psychiatr Pract. 2018;24:104–110.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
