<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35517580</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>07</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2590-0064</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>15</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Materials today. Bio</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Mater Today Bio</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>The impact of bacterial contamination on the host response towards fully absorbable poly-4-hydroxybutyrate and nonabsorbable polypropylene pelvic floor implants.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>100268</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>100268</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">100268</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.mtbio.2022.100268</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Polypropylene (PP) implants for the vaginal surgical correction of pelvic organ prolapse (POP) are known for adverse events, like vaginal or visceral exposures. It is hypothesized that this is a result of a prolonged inflammatory response. One of the triggering factors of prolonged inflammation might be bacterial contamination. A possible solution might lie in an absorbable biomaterial, which provides initial mechanical support while being gradually replaced by the host tissue. With this study we aimed to compare the host response, in a subcutaneous mouse implant infection model, to delayed absorbable poly-4-hydroxybutyrate (P4HB) and a latest generation PP implant. By comparing non-infected to <i>Staphylococcus aureus</i> infected mice, we assessed how bacterial contamination affects the host response and its role in the development of complications. Further, we included sham surgery as a control, mimicking the wound response in native tissue repair. Despite the higher surface area of the P4HB implants, the clearance of infection was similarly delayed in the presence of a P4HB or PP implant, as compared to sham. Further, the host response towards P4HB and PP was quite comparable, yet collagen deposition was significantly increased around infected P4HB implants at early time points. Adverse event rates were similar, though implant exposures were only seen in infected mice and more often with PP (11.1%) than P4HB implants (5.6%). Infected mice overall had significantly higher levels of infiltration of inflammatory cells and lower levels of vascularization and collagen deposition compared to non-infected mice. Thus, for both P4HB and PP, bacterial contamination negatively affected mesh integration by increased inflammation and an increased adverse event rate. Altogether, our results from this subcutaneous mouse implant infection study suggest that P4HB could be a promising degradable alternative to PP, warranting further research to study its potential as a new surgical solution for women with POP.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 Published by Elsevier Ltd.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Verhorstert</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kim W J</ForeName>
            <Initials>KWJ</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Amsterdam UMC, University of Amsterdam, Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Meibergdreef 9, Amsterdam, the Netherlands.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Amsterdam Reproduction and Development, Amsterdam, the Netherlands.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Riool</LastName>
            <ForeName>Martijn</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Amsterdam UMC, University of Amsterdam, Department of Medical Microbiology and Infection Prevention, Amsterdam Institute for Infection and Immunity, Meibergdreef 9, Amsterdam, the Netherlands.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bulten</LastName>
            <ForeName>Tess</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Amsterdam UMC, University of Amsterdam, Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Meibergdreef 9, Amsterdam, the Netherlands.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Guler</LastName>
            <ForeName>Zeliha</ForeName>
            <Initials>Z</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Amsterdam UMC, University of Amsterdam, Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Meibergdreef 9, Amsterdam, the Netherlands.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Amsterdam Reproduction and Development, Amsterdam, the Netherlands.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>de Boer</LastName>
            <ForeName>Leonie</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Amsterdam UMC, University of Amsterdam, Department of Medical Microbiology and Infection Prevention, Amsterdam Institute for Infection and Immunity, Meibergdreef 9, Amsterdam, the Netherlands.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Roovers</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jan-Paul W R</ForeName>
            <Initials>JWR</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Amsterdam UMC, University of Amsterdam, Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Meibergdreef 9, Amsterdam, the Netherlands.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Amsterdam Reproduction and Development, Amsterdam, the Netherlands.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zaat</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sebastian A J</ForeName>
            <Initials>SAJ</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Amsterdam UMC, University of Amsterdam, Department of Medical Microbiology and Infection Prevention, Amsterdam Institute for Infection and Immunity, Meibergdreef 9, Amsterdam, the Netherlands.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>04</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Mater Today Bio</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101757228</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2590-0064</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Biomaterial-associated infection</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mesh</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pelvic floor</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pelvic organ prolapse (POP)</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Poly-4-hydroxybutyrate (P4HB)</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Polypropylene (PP)</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors declare the following financial interests/personal relationships which may be considered as potential competing interests: J.P.W.R Roovers reports financial support and equipment, drugs, or supplies were provided by Tepha Inc. and Coloplast.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>50</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35517580</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9062440</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mtbio.2022.100268</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">S2590-0064(22)00066-7</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fritel X., et al.  Symptomatic pelvic organ prolapse at midlife, quality of life, and risk factors. Obstet. Gynecol. 2009;113(3):609–616.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2850374</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19300324</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hendrix S.L., et al.  Pelvic organ prolapse in the Women's Health Initiative: gravity and gravidity. Am. J. Obstet. Gynecol. 2002;186(6):1160–1166.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12066091</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nygaard I., et al.  Prevalence of symptomatic pelvic floor disorders in US women. JAMA. 2008;300(11):1311–1316.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2918416</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18799443</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abdel-Fattah M., et al.  Primary and repeat surgical treatment for female pelvic organ prolapse and incontinence in parous women in the UK: a register linkage study. BMJ Open. 2011;1(2):e000206.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Denman M.A., et al.  Reoperation 10 Years after surgically managed pelvic organ prolapse and urinary incontinence. Am. J. Obstet. Gynecol. 2008;198(5):555.e1–555.e5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18355779</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Olsen A.L., et al.  Epidemiology of surgically managed pelvic organ prolapse and urinary incontinence. Obstet. Gynecol. 1997;89(4):501–506.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9083302</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dällenbach P. To mesh or not to mesh: a review of pelvic organ reconstructive surgery. Int J Womens Health. 2015;7:331–343.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4386830</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25848324</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mangir N., et al.  Landmarks in vaginal mesh development: polypropylene mesh for treatment of SUI and POP. Nat. Rev. Urol. 2019;16(11):675–689.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31548731</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gigliobianco G., et al.  Biomaterials for pelvic floor reconstructive surgery: how can we do better? BioMed Res. Int. 2015;2015:1–20. 968087.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ng-Stollmann N., et al.  The international discussion and the new regulations concerning transvaginal mesh implants in pelvic organ prolapse surgery. Int Urogynecol J. 2020;31(10):1997–2002.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7497328</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32696186</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>(FDA), U.S.F.a.D.A . 2021. FDA's Activities: Urogynecologic Surgical Mesh.https://www.fda.gov/medical-devices/urogynecologic-surgical-mesh-implants/fdas-activities-urogynecologic-surgical-mesh 09/02/2021 [cited 2022 22-03-2022]; Available from:</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>FDA . 2016. Obstetrical and Gynecological Devices; Reclassification of Surgical Mesh for Transvaginal Pelvic Organ Prolapse Repair.https://www.federalregister.gov/documents/2016/01/05/2015-33165/obstetrical-and-gynecological-devices-reclassification-of-surgical-mesh-for-transvaginal-pelvic [cited 2022 08-04-2022]; Available from:</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>NVOG, Standpunt . 2020. Transvaginale Mesh Zorg in Nederland; p. 3. Nederlandse Vereniging voor Obstetrie &amp; Gynaecologie: Utrecht.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>FDA . 2019. Urogynecologic Surgical Mesh Implants.https://www.fda.gov/medical-devices/implants-and-prosthetics/urogynecologic-surgical-mesh-implants [cited 2019 23-05-2019]; Available from:</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Medsafe . 2018. New Zealand Medicines and Medical Devices Safety Authority. Surgical Mesh Implants: Regulatory action on Surgical Mesh Products.https://www.medsafe.govt.nz/hot/alerts/UrogynaecologicaSurgicalMeshImplants.asp 28-06-2018 [cited 2021 21-04-2021]; Available from:</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scientific Committee on Emerging and Newly Identified Health Risks (SCENIHR). Opinion on the Safety of Surgical Meshes Used in Urogynecological Surgery 2015, Scientific Committees.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Slack M., et al.  A standardized description of graft-containing meshes and recommended steps before the introduction of medical devices for prolapse surgery. Consensus of the 2nd IUGA Grafts Roundtable: optimizing safety and appropriateness of graft use in transvaginal pelvic reconstructive surgery. Int Urogynecol J. 2012;23(Suppl 1):S15–S26.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22395289</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mangir N., et al.  Complications related to use of mesh implants in surgical treatment of stress urinary incontinence and pelvic organ prolapse: infection or inflammation? World J. Urol. 2019;38:73–80.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6954150</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30759272</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Culligan P., et al.  Bacterial colony counts during vaginal surgery. Infect. Dis. Obstet. Gynecol. 2003;11(3):161–165.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1852279</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15022877</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vollebregt A., Troelstra A., van der Vaart C.H. Bacterial colonisation of collagen-coated polypropylene vaginal mesh: are additional intraoperative sterility procedures useful? Int. UrogynEcol. J. Pelvic Floor Dysfunct. 2009;20(11):1345–1351.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2762530</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19727538</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Daghighi S., et al.  Infection resistance of degradable versus non-degradable biomaterials: an assessment of the potential mechanisms. Biomaterials. 2013;34(33):8013–8017.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23915949</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mellia J.A., et al.  Outcomes of poly-4-hydroxybutyrate mesh in ventral hernia repair: a systematic review and pooled analysis. Plast Reconstr Surg Glob Open. 2020;8(12):e3158.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7787297</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33425570</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Diedrich C.M., et al.  Fully absorbable poly-4-hydroxybutyrate implants exhibit more favorable cell-matrix interactions than polypropylene. Mater Sci Eng C Mater Biol Appl. 2021;120:111702.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33545861</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verhorstert K.W.J., et al.  In vitro bacterial adhesion and biofilm formation on fully absorbable poly-4-hydroxybutyrate and nonabsorbable polypropylene pelvic floor implants. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces. 2020;12(48):53646–53653.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7716345</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33210919</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Diedrich C.M., et al.   Bjog; 2021. Evaluation of the Short-Term Host Response and Biomechanics of an Absorbable Poly-4-Hydroxybutyrate Scaffold in a Sheep Model Following Vaginal Implantation.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deeken C.R., Matthews B.D. Characterization of the mechanical strength, resorption properties, and histologic characteristics of a fully absorbable material (Poly-4-hydroxybutyrate-PHASIX mesh) in a porcine model of hernia repair. ISRN Surg. 2013:1–12. 2013: p. 238067.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arciola C.R., Campoccia D., Montanaro L. Implant infections: adhesion, biofilm formation and immune evasion. Nat. Rev. Microbiol. 2018;16(7):397–409.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29720707</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Riool M., et al.  Staphylococcus epidermidis originating from titanium implants infects surrounding tissue and immune cells. Acta Biomater. 2014;10(12):5202–5212.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25153780</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Riool M., et al.  A chlorhexidine-releasing epoxy-based coating on titanium implants prevents Staphylococcus aureus experimental biomaterial-associated infection. Eur. Cell. Mater. 2017;33:143–157.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28197990</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Percie du Sert N., et al.  The ARRIVE guidelines 2.0: updated guidelines for reporting animal research. J. Physiol. 2020;105:1459–1466.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>ARRIVE  . 2021. The ARRIVE Essential 10: Compliance Questionnaire; p. 2.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van Zutphen, L.F.M., Chapter 12 Design of animal experiments, in Principles of Laboratory Animal Science - Revised Edition. Elsevier: Amsterdam. p. 229.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>RANDOM.ORG  Random Sequence Generator. 1998-2021. https://www.random.org/sequences/ [cited 2020; Available from:</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li D., et al.  Quantitative mouse model of implant-associated osteomyelitis and the kinetics of microbial growth, osteolysis, and humoral immunity. J. Orthop. Res. 2008;26(1):96–105.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2701346</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17676625</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dijksteel G.S., et al.  SPS-neutralization in tissue samples for efficacy testing of antimicrobial peptides. BMC Infect. Dis. 2019;19(1):1093.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6937930</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31888515</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Keane T.J., et al.  Preparation and characterization of a biologic scaffold from esophageal mucosa. Biomaterials. 2013;34(28):6729–6737.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3727430</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23777917</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hympanova L., et al.   Eur Urol Focus; 2018. Assessment of Electrospun and Ultra-lightweight Polypropylene Meshes in the Sheep Model for Vaginal Surgery.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Manfredo Vieira S., et al.  Translocation of a gut pathobiont drives autoimmunity in mice and humans. Science. 2018;359(6380):1156–1161.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5959731</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29590047</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Devriese L.A., et al.  Characterization and identification of Enterococcus species isolated from the intestines of animals. Int. J. Syst. Bacteriol. 1987;37(3):3.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moriarty F., Zaat S.A., Busscher H.J.  1 ed. Springer; 2012. Biomaterials Associated Infection: Immunological Aspects and Antimicrobial Strategies.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pineda Molina C., et al.  4-Hydroxybutyrate promotes endogenous antimicrobial peptide expression in macrophages. Tissue Eng. 2019;25(9–10):693–706.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hympánová L., et al.  Assessment of electrospun and ultra-lightweight polypropylene meshes in the sheep model for vaginal surgery. Eur. Urol. Focus. 2020;6(1):190–198.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30049658</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huffaker R.K., et al.  Histologic response of porcine collagen-coated and uncoated polypropylene grafts in a rabbit vagina model. Am. J. Obstet. Gynecol. 2008;198(5):582.e1–582.e7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18295174</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lo T.S., et al.  The immunohistochemical and urodynamic evaluation towards the collagen-coated and non-coated polypropylene meshes implanted in the pelvic wall of the rats. Sci. Rep. 2016;6:38960.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5172279</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27991501</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elci G.G., et al.  Histopathological and mechanical properties of different meshes in a rat model of pelvic prolapse surgery. E. J. Med. 2017;22(2):45–52.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verhorstert K.W.J., et al.  Animal experimental research assessing urogynecologic surgical mesh implants: outcome measures describing the host response, a systematic review and meta-analysis. Neurourol. Urodyn. 2021;40(5):1107–1119.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8359983</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33951222</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Patel H., Ostergard D.R., Sternschuss G. Polypropylene mesh and the host response. Int Urogynecol J. 2012;23(6):669–679.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22430945</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>O’Shaughnessy D., et al.  Evaluation of the histological and biomechanical properties of poly-4-hydroxybutyrate scaffold for pelvic organ prolapse, compared with polypropylene mesh in a rabbit model. Int Urogynecol J. 2021 doi: 10.1113/EP088870.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/EP088870</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roy S., et al.  Staphylococcus aureus biofilm infection compromises wound healing by causing deficiencies in granulation tissue collagen. Ann. Surg. 2020;271(6):1174–1185.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7065840</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30614873</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mellano E.M., et al.  The role of chronic mesh infection in delayed-onset vaginal mesh complications or recurrent urinary tract infections: results from explanted mesh cultures. Female Pelvic Med. Reconstr. Surg. 2016;22(3):166–171.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26829350</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mamy L., et al.  Correlation between shrinkage and infection of implanted synthetic meshes using an animal model of mesh infection. Int Urogynecol J. 2011;22(1):47–52.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20821311</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Busscher H.J., et al.  Biomaterial-associated infection: locating the finish line in the race for the surface. Sci. Transl. Med. 2012;4(153):153rv10.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guillaume O., et al.  A critical review of the in vitro and in vivo models for the evaluation of anti-infective meshes. Hernia. 2018;22(6):961–974.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30168006</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boelens J.J., et al.  Subcutaneous abscess formation around catheters induced by viable and nonviable Staphylococcus epidermidis as well as by small amounts of bacterial cell wall components. J. Biomed. Mater. Res. 2000;50(4):546–556.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10756313</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Christensen G.D., et al.  Experimental foreign body infections in mice challenged with slime-producing Staphylococcus epidermidis. Infect. Immun. 1983;40(1):407–410.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC264861</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6339407</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Urbankova I., et al.  Transvaginal mesh insertion in the ovine model. JoVE. 2017;125(7):27.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aghaei-Ghareh-Bolagh B., et al.  A novel tropoelastin-based resorbable surgical mesh for pelvic organ prolapse repair. Mater. Today Biol. 2020;8:100081.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lai C., et al.  Development of a cellulose-based prosthetic mesh for pelvic organ prolapse treatment: in vivo long-term evaluation in an Ewe vagina model. Mater. Today Biol. 2021;12:100172.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
