<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35510815</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>05</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2753</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>05</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of evaluation in clinical practice</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Eval Clin Pract</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>The presence of a urinary catheter is an important predictor of in-hospital mortality in internal medicine patients.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jep.13694</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="RATIONALE AND OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Mortality rates are used to assess the quality of hospital care after appropriate adjustment for case-mix. Urinary catheters are frequent in hospitalized adults and might be a marker of patient frailty and illness severity. However, we know of no attempts to estimate the predictive value of indwelling catheters for specific patient outcomes. The objective of the present study was to (a) identify the variables associated with the presence of a urinary catheter and (b) determine whether it predicts in-hospital mortality after adjustment for these variables.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The study population included all acutely admitted adult patients in 2020 (exploratory cohort) and January-October 2021 (validation cohort) to internal medicine, cardiology and intensive care departments at the Laniado Hospital, a regional hospital with 400 beds in Israel. There were no exclusion criteria. The predictor variables were the presence of a urinary catheter on admission, age, gender, comorbidities and admission laboratory test results. We used bivariate and multivariate logistic regression to test the associations between the presence of a urinary catheter and mortality after adjustment for the remaining independent variables on admission.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The presence of a urinary catheter was associated with other independent variables. In 2020, the odds of in-hospital mortality in patients with a urinary catheter before and after adjustment for the remaining predictors were 14.3 (11.6-17.7) and 6.05 (4.78-7.65), respectively. Adding the presence of a urinary catheter to the prediction logistic regression model increased its c-statistic from 0.887 (0.880-0.894) to 0.907 (0.901-0.913). The results of the validation cohort reduplicated those of the exploratory cohort.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The presence of a urinary catheter on admission is an important and independent predictor of in-hospital mortality in acutely hospitalized adults in internal medicine departments.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Shimoni</LastName>
            <ForeName>Zvi</ForeName>
            <Initials>Z</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine B, Laniado Hospital, Netanya, Israel.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Ruth and Bruce Rappaport School of Medicine, Technion University, Haifa, Israel.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Froom</LastName>
            <ForeName>Paul</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5126-8590</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Clinical Utility Department, Sanz Medical Center, Laniado Hospital, Netanya, Israel.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Public Health, University of Tel Aviv, Tel Aviv-Yafo, Israel.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Silke</LastName>
            <ForeName>Bernard</ForeName>
            <Initials>B</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Internal Medicine, St. James' Hospital, Dublin, Ireland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Benbassat</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jochanan</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Hebrew University-Hadassah Faculty of Medicine, Jerusalem, Israel.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>05</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Eval Clin Pract</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9609066</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1356-1294</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Israel</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">c-statistic</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">in-hospital mortality</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">urinary catheter</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
          <Hour>8</Hour>
          <Minute>32</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35510815</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jep.13694</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cecil E, Bottle A, Esmail A, Vincent C, Aylin P. What is the relationship between mortality alerts and other indicators of quality of care? A national cross-sectional study. J Health Serv Res Policy. 2020;25:13-21.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pine M, Norusis M, Jones B, Rosenthal G. Predictions of hospital mortality rates. Ann Intern Med. 1997;126:347-354.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>D′Hoore W, Sicotte C, Tilquin C. Risk adjustment in outcome assessment: the Charlson comorbidity index. Methods Inf Med. 1993;32:382-387.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marshall G, Shroyer A, Grover F, Hammermeister K. Time-series monitors of outcomes: a new dimension for measuring quality of care. Med Care. 1998;36:348-356.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moreno R, Miranda D, Fidler V, van Schlifgaarde R. Evaluation of two outcome prediction models on an independent database. Crit Care Med. 1998;26:50-61.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Prytherch DR, Sirl JS, Schmidt P, Featherstone PI, Weaver PC, Smith GB. The use of routine laboratory data to predict in-hospital death in medical admissions. Resuscitation. 2005;66:203-207.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hucker TR, Mitchell GP, Blake LD, et al. Identifying the sick: can biochemical measurements be used to aid decision making on presentation to the accident and emergency department. Br J Anaesth. 2005;94:735-741.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jollis J, Ancukiewicz M, DeLong E, Pryor DB, Muhibaier L, Mark D. Discordance of databases designed for claims payment versus clinical information systems: implications for outcomes research. Ann Intern Med. 1993;119:844-850.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dans P. Looking for answers in the wrong places [Editorial]. Ann Intern Med. 1993;119:855-857.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Knaus WA, Draper EA, Wagner DP, Zimmerman JE. APACHE II: a severity of disease classification system. Crit Care Med. 1985;13:818-829.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rossi PD, Bilotta C, Consonni D, et al. Predictors of clinical events occurring during hospital stay among elderly patients admitted to medical wards in Italy. Eur J Intern Med. 2016;32:38-42. doi:10.1016/j.ejim.2016.04.003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Greene MT, Fakih MG, Fowler KE, et al. Regional variation in urinary catheter use and catheter-associated urinary tract infection: results from a national collaborative. Infect Control Hosp Epidemiol. 2014;35(S3):S99-S106.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Russo PL, Stewardson AJ, Cheng AC, Bucknall T, Mitchell BG. Prevalence of device use and transmission-based precautions in nineteen large Australian acute care public hospitals: secondary outcomes from a national healthcare associated infection point prevalence survey. Infect Dis Health. 2020;25:262-267.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berardelli M, De Rango F, Morelli M, et al. Urinary incontinence in the elderly and in the oldest old: correlation with frailty and mortality. Rejuvenation Res. 2013;16:206-211.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Condon M, Mannion E, Collins G, et al. Prevalence and predictors of continence containment products and catheter use in an acute hospital: a cross-sectional study. Geriatr Nurs. 2021;42:433-439.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>DuBeau CE, Kuchel GA, Johnson T II, Palmer MH, Wagg A. Incontinence in the frail elderly: report from the 4th International Consultation on Incontinence. Neurourol Urodyn. 2010;29:165-178.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Froom P, Shimoni Z, Benbassat J, Silke B. A simple index predicting mortality in acutely hospitalized patients. QJM. 2021;27(114):99-104.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shimoni Z, Froom P, Benbassat J. Parameters of the complete blood count predict in hospital mortality. Int J Lab Hematol. 2022;44:88-95.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Subramaniam S, Aalberg JJ, Soriano RP, Divino CM. New 5-factor modified frailty index using American College of Surgeons NSQIP data. J Am Coll Surg. 2018;226:173-181.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Conway R, Byrne D, O'Riordan D, Silke B. Comparative influence of acute illness severity and comorbidity on mortality. Eur J Intern Med. 2020;72:42-46.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Faisal M, Scally AJ, Jackson N, et al. Development and validation of a novel computer-aided score to predict the risk of in-hospital mortality for acutely ill medical admissions in two acute hospitals using their first electronically recorded blood test results and vital signs: a cross-sectional study. BMJ Open. 2018;8:e022939.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schwartz N, Sakhnini A, Bisharat N. Predictive modeling of inpatient mortality in departments of internal medicine. Intern Emerg Med. 2018;13:205-11.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>O'Sullivan E, Callely E, O'Riordan D, Bennett K, Silke B. Predicting outcomes in emergency medical admissions-role of laboratory data and co-morbidity. Acute Med. 2012;2:59-65.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Laan BJ, Vos MC, Maaskant JM, van Berge Henegouwen MI, Geerlings SE. Prevalence and risk factors of inappropriate use of intravenous and urinary catheters in surgical and medical patients. J Hosp Infect. 2020;105:698-704.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shackley DC, Whytock C, Parry G, et al. Variation in the prevalence of urinary catheters: a profile of National Health Service patients in England. BMJ Open. 2017;7:e013842.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Burman LG, Fryklund B, Nystrum B. Use of indwelling urinary tract catheters in Swedish hospitals. Infect Control. 1987;8:507-511.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
