<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35515509</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>07</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">1930-0433</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>17</Volume>
            <Issue>6</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Radiology case reports</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Radiol Case Rep</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Bilateral striopallidal calcinosis secondary to systemic lupus erythematosus.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>2257</StartPage>
          <EndPage>2261</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>2257-2261</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.radcr.2022.03.114</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Bilateral symmetric striatopallidal calcinosis with or without deposits in dentate nucleus, thalamus, and white matter is reported in patients ranging from asymptomatic, metabolic, toxic, and genetic autosomal dominant, familial or sporadic forms. Of the connective tissue diseases, it has been reported in very few cases in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus, many incorrectly labeled as Fahr syndrome without even having hypoparathyroidism. Here we describe a 30-year-old female patient with neuropsychiatric systemic lupus erythematosus manifested at diagnosis with mood disorders and anxiety, and 1-year later develops Lupus headache; Incidentally, an aneurism of the right middle cerebral artery and bilateral and symmetric calcifications of the caudate and lenticular nuclei were noted; this finding is a rarely reported manifestation of neuropsychiatric systemic lupus erythematosus. A review of the literature based on this case was carried out in electronic databases. There are approximately 29 patients reported in the literature, with calcifications in the basal ganglia associated with systemic lupus erythematosus occurs almost exclusively in young women (96.5%) with a mean age of 33.36 years (2 months-76 years), with a race predilection for Asians (65.5%). Regarding the neuropsychiatric syndromes defined by the American College of Rheumatology, the most frequently associated are movement disorders; followed by cognitive dysfunction, seizure disorders, mood disorders, cerebrovascular disease, psychosis, and acute confusional state, transverse myelitis, and demyelinating syndrome. The mean duration time of the SLE to detection of the basal ganglia calcification is 7.62 years (3 days-31 years).</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Inc. on behalf of University of Washington.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Betancur</LastName>
            <ForeName>Juan Felipe</ForeName>
            <Initials>JF</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Internal Medicine Department, Clínica Medellín QuirónSalud/Salúd SURA, Carrera 65B No. 30 - 95, Medellín, Colombia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Goméz-Puerta</LastName>
            <ForeName>José A</ForeName>
            <Initials>JA</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Rheumatology Department, Hospital Clínic Barcelona, Barcelona, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Llano</LastName>
            <ForeName>Juan Felipe</ForeName>
            <Initials>JF</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Clinical Research Department, Clínica Medellín QuirónSalud, Medellín, Colombia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lopéz-Ochoa</LastName>
            <ForeName>Gustavo Adolfo</ForeName>
            <Initials>GA</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Clinical Research Department, Clínica Medellín QuirónSalud, Medellín, Colombia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ramirez</LastName>
            <ForeName>Beatriz</ForeName>
            <Initials>B</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Epidemiology Department, Clínica Medellín QuirónSalud, Medellín, Colombia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Martinez</LastName>
            <ForeName>Oscar David</ForeName>
            <Initials>OD</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Neurology Department, Clínica Medellín QuirónSalud, Medellín, Colombia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>04</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Radiol Case Rep</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101467888</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1930-0433</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Basal ganglia calcification</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bilateral striopallidadodentate calcinosis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Central nervous system</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lupus erythematosus</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Systemic</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Systemic lupus erythematosus</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>35</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35515509</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9061246</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.radcr.2022.03.114</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">S1930-0433(22)00287-4</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hanly JG. Diagnosis and management of neuropsychiatric SLE. Nat Rev Rheumatol [Internet] 2014;10(6):338–347. doi: 10.1038/nrrheum.2014.15.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrrheum.2014.15</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sibbitt WL, Sibbitt RR, Brooks WM. Neuroimaging in neuropsychiatric systemic lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum. 1999;42(10):2026–2038.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10524673</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cañas CA, Tobón GJ. Multiple brain calcifications in a patient with systemic lupus erythematosus. Clin Rheumatol. 2008;27(SUPPL. 2):63–65.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Filloux V, Marotte H, Miossec P. Cerebral calcifications in an elderly lupus patient. Ann R. 2003;62:283–284.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Manyam BV. What is and what is not “Fahr's disease. Park Relat Disord. 2005;11(2):73–80.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martinovic-Kaliterna D, Radic M, Radic J, Kovacic V, Fabijanic D. Massive cerebral calcifications (Fahr's disease) in a patient with systemic lupus erythematosus and no major neuropsychological abnormality. Isr Med Assoc J. 2013;15(10):654–655.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24266097</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sumadiono DP. Fahr's syndrome in teenage girls with systemic lupus erythematosus: a case report. Indones J Med Heal. 2020;11(3):290–294.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jankovic M, Zmak L, Krajinovic V, Viskovic K, Sestan Crnek S, Obrovac M, et al.  A fatal Mycobacterium chelonae infection in an immunosuppressed patient with systemic lupus erythematosus and concomitant Fahr's syndrome. J Infect Chemother. 2011;17(2):264–267.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20803049</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gonzalez-Scarano F, Lisak RP, Bilaniuk LT, Zimmerman RA, Atkins PC, Zweiman B. Cranial computed tomography in the diagnosis of systemic lupus erythematosus. Ann Neurol. 1979;5(2):158–165.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">426479</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Anderson JR. Intracerebral calcification in a case of systemic lupus erythematosus with neurological manifestations. Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol. 1981;7(2):161–166.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7231643</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nordstrom DM, West SG, Andersen PA. Basal ganglia calcifications in central nervous system lupus erythematosus. Arthritis Rheum. 1985;28(12):1412–1416.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4084330</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maeda M, Kitamura Y, Takata M, Nakamura Y, Masuda S, Nishida K, et al.  [A case of systemic lupus erythematosus demonstrating basal ganglia calcifications, coronary stenosis and selective IgA deficiency] Nihon Naika Gakkai Zasshi. 1986;75(1):83–88.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3701176</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tamatani M, Moriguchi A, Otsuka A, Morimoto S, Ogihara T, Hashimoto K, et al.  A case of SLE with calcinosis universalis and basal ganglia calcification. Jpn J Clin Immun. 1992;15(1):94–101.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yamamoto K, Nogaki H, Takase Y, Morimatsu M. Systemic lupus erythematosus associated with marked intracranial calcification. Am J Neuroradiol. 1992;13(5):1340–1342.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8335234</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1414826</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raymond AA, Zariah AA, Samad SA, Chin CN, Kong NCT. Brain calcification in patients with cerebral lupus. Lupus. 1996;5(2):123–128.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8743125</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matsumoto R, Shintaku M, Suzuki S, Kato T. Cerebral perivenous calcification in neuropsychiatric lupus erythematosus: a case report. Neuroradiology. 1998;40(9):583–586.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9808316</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mathur A, Choudhary HR. Systemic lupus erythematosus causing cerebral infarction and basal ganglion calcification: a case report. Neurol India. 2000;48(1):91.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Prendivile JS, Cabral DA, Poskitt KJ, Sheila A, Sargent M. Central nervous system involvement in neonatal lupus erythematosus. Pediatr Dermatol. 2003;20(1):60–67.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12558850</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shimojima Y, Gono T, Hoshi K, Yamamoto K, Yoshida K, Matsuda M, et al.  Neuropsychiatric systemic lupus erythematosus associated with anti-phospholipid syndrome, showing massive intracranial calcifications. No To Shinkei. 2003;55(10):885–888.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14635517</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Andres RH, Schroth G, Remonda L. Neurological picture. Extensive cerebral calcification in a patient with systemic lupus erythematosus. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2008;79(4):365.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18344390</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Masuda Y, Uchiyama Y, Hashimoto S, Uchiyama S, Iwata M. Symmetrical progressive intracranial calcification in a patient with SLE. Intern Med. 2010;49(4):351.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20154445</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sesé Bartoll E, Araújo Loperena O, Creus Gras C, Pedrol Clotet E. [Cerebral calcifications in systemic lupus erythematosus] Med Clin (Barc) 2013;141(5):232.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23561243</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chang RSK, Leung CYW, Leong HS. Bilateral striatopallidodentate calcinosis associated with systemic lupus erythematosus: case report and review of literature. J Neurol Sci [Internet] 2015;358(1–2):518–519. doi: 10.1016/j.jns.2015.09.373.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jns.2015.09.373</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garg T, Sanke S, Chander R, Agarwal S, Ahmed R. Infantile systemic lupus erythematosus with cerebral calcification and delayed development. Indian J Pediatr. 2018;85:394–395.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29152684</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang Y-X, Li H-F, Zheng Y, Wu L, Wu Z-Y, Ding M-P. Diffuse intracranial calcification, deep medullary vein engorgement, and symmetric white matter involvement in a patient with systemic lupus erythematosus. CNS Neurosci Therap. 2020;26:278–280.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6978252</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31651083</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tsubouchi S, Hayashi H, Tahara K, Ishii K, Yasuda T, Yamamoto Y, et al.  Clinical presentation of a neuropsychiatric lupus patient with symmetrical basal ganglia lesions containing cytotoxic oedema cores surrounded by vasogenic oedema. Mod Rheumatol Case Reports [Internet] 2020;4(1):39–46. doi: 10.1080/24725625.2019.1651955.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/24725625.2019.1651955</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ogasawara A, Kakeda S, Watanabe K, Ide S, Ueda I, Murakami Y, et al.  Quantitative susceptibility mapping in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus: detection of abnormalities in normal-appearing basal ganglia. Eur Radiol. 2016;26(4):1056–1063.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26228900</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sarbu N, Bargalló N, Cervera R. Advanced and conventional magnetic resonance imaging in neuropsychiatric lupus. F1000Research. 2015;4:1–14.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5754746</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29333228</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
