<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35510157</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>07</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">1178-6973</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>15</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Infection and drug resistance</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Infect Drug Resist</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Urinary Antigen Testing for Respiratory Infections: Current Perspectives on Utility and Limitations.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>2219</StartPage>
          <EndPage>2228</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>2219-2228</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2147/IDR.S321168</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Pneumonia is a leading cause of hospitalization and death due to infection worldwide. <i>Streptococcus pneumoniae</i> and <i>Legionella pneumophila</i> remain among the most commonly identified bacterial pathogens. Unfortunately, more than half of all pneumonia cases today lack an etiologic diagnosis due to limitations in traditional microbiological methods like blood and sputum cultures, which are affected by poor sample collection, prior antibiotic administration, and delayed processing. Urinary antigen tests (UATs) for <i>S. pneumoniae</i> and <i>L. pneumophila</i> have emerged as powerful tools for improving the diagnosis of bacterial respiratory infections, enabling physicians to administer early directed therapy and improve antimicrobial stewardship. UATs are simple, rapid, and non-invasive diagnostic tests with high specificity (&gt;90%) and moderate sensitivity (&lt;80%). The potential impact of urinary antigen testing is especially significant for respiratory infections caused by <i>Legionella</i>. While all recommended community-acquired pneumonia (CAP) therapies are adequate for treating pneumococcal pneumonia, only certain antibiotics are effective against <i>Legionella</i>. Delayed therapy for <i>Legionella</i> is associated with worse clinical outcomes, which underscores the importance of rapid diagnostic methods like UATs. Despite their potential impact, current American Thoracic Society and Infectious Diseases Society of America (ATS/IDSA) guidelines argue against the routine use of urinary antigen testing for <i>S. pneumoniae</i> and <i>L. pneumophila</i>, except in patients with severe CAP and those with epidemiological risk factors for <i>Legionella</i>. Further research is necessary to evaluate the impact of early targeted treatment due to positive UAT results, as well as optimal strategies for UAT utilization. The purpose of this review is to summarize the UATs available for bacterial respiratory infections, describe current guidelines on their usage, and assess their impact on clinical outcomes and targeted therapy.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 Kim et al.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kim</LastName>
            <ForeName>Priscilla</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6462-2843</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Cleveland Clinic Lerner College of Medicine of Case Western Reserve University, Cleveland, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Deshpande</LastName>
            <ForeName>Abhishek</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Center for Value-Based Care Research, Cleveland Clinic, Cleveland, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Rothberg</LastName>
            <ForeName>Michael B</ForeName>
            <Initials>MB</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Center for Value-Based Care Research, Cleveland Clinic, Cleveland, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>04</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Infect Drug Resist</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101550216</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1178-6973</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Legionella pneumophila</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Streptococcus pneumoniae</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">impact</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pneumonia</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">urinary antigen test</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>AD is a consultant for Merck. MBR reports grants paid to his institution from The Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ). The authors report no other conflicts of interest in this work.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
          <Hour>2</Hour>
          <Minute>37</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35510157</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9058651</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/IDR.S321168</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">321168</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jain S, Self WH, Wunderink RG, et al. Community-Acquired Pneumonia Requiring Hospitalization among U.S. Adults. N Engl J Med. 2015;373(5):415–427. doi:10.1056/NEJMoa1500245</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1500245</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4728150</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26172429</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Viasus D, Calatayud L, McBrown MV, Ardanuy C, Carratala J. Urinary antigen testing in community-acquired pneumonia in adults: an update. Expert Rev Anti Infect Ther. 2019;17(2):107–115. doi:10.1080/14787210.2019.1565994</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14787210.2019.1565994</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30618315</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Torres A, Cilloniz C, Niederman MS, et al. Pneumonia. Nat Rev Dis Primer. 2021;7(1):25. doi:10.1038/s41572-021-00259-0</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41572-021-00259-0</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Laijen W, Snijders D, Boersma WG. Pneumococcal urinary antigen test: diagnostic yield and impact on antibiotic treatment. Clin Respir J. 2017;11(6):999–1005.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26780500</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van der Eerden MM, Vlaspolder F, de Graaff CS, Groot T, Jansen HM, Boersma WG. Value of intensive diagnostic microbiological investigation in low- and high-risk patients with community-acquired pneumonia. Eur J Clin Microbiol Infect Dis. 2005;24(4):241–249. doi:10.1007/s10096-005-1316-8</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10096-005-1316-8</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15902529</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Waterer GW, Wunderink RG. The influence of the severity of community-acquired pneumonia on the usefulness of blood cultures. Respir Med. 2001;95(1):78–82. doi:10.1053/rmed.2000.0977</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/rmed.2000.0977</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11207022</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chalasani NP, Valdecanas MAL, Gopal AK, McGowan JE, Jurado RL. Clinical Utility of Blood Cultures in Adult Patients with Community-Acquired Pneumonia Without Defined Underlying Risks. Chest. 1995;108(4):932–936. doi:10.1378/chest.108.4.932</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1378/chest.108.4.932</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7555163</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Falguera M, Trujillano J, Caro S, et al. A Prediction Rule for Estimating the Risk of Bacteremia in Patients with Community‐Acquired Pneumonia. Clin Infect Dis. 2009;49(3):409–416. doi:10.1086/600291</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1086/600291</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19555286</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Campbell SG, Marrie TJ, Anstey R, Dickinson G, Ackroyd-Stolarz S. The Contribution of Blood Cultures to the Clinical Management of Adult Patients Admitted to the Hospital With Community-Acquired Pneumonia. Chest. 2003;123(4):1142–1150. doi:10.1378/chest.123.4.1142</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1378/chest.123.4.1142</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12684305</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Corbo J, Friedman B, Bijur P, Gallagher EJ. Limited usefulness of initial blood cultures in community acquired pneumonia. Emerg Med J. 2004;4:446–448.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Campbell SG. Utility of blood cultures in the management of adults with community acquired pneumonia discharged from the emergency department. Emerg Med J. 2003;20(6):521–523. doi:10.1136/emj.20.6.521</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/emj.20.6.521</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1726243</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14623837</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haessler S, Lindenauer PK, Zilberberg MD, et al. Blood Cultures Versus Respiratory Cultures: 2 Different Views of Pneumonia. Clin Infect Dis. 2020;71(7):1604–1612. doi:10.1093/cid/ciz1049</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/ciz1049</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7882190</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31665249</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Benenson RS, Kepner AM, Pyle DN, Cavanaugh S. Selective Use of Blood Cultures in Emergency Department Pneumonia Patients. J Emerg Med. 2007;33(1):1–8. doi:10.1016/j.jemermed.2006.12.034</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jemermed.2006.12.034</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17630066</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hyams C, Williams OM, Williams P. Urinary antigen testing for pneumococcal pneumonia: is there evidence to make its use uncommon in clinical practice?
ERJ Open Research. 2020;6(1):00223–2019.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Molinos L, Zalacain R, Menéndez R, et al. Sensitivity, specificity, and positivity predictors of the pneumococcal urinary antigen test in community-acquired pneumonia. Ann Am Thorac Soc. 2015;12(10):1482–1489.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26288389</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schimmel JJ, Haessler S, Imrey P, et al. Pneumococcal Urinary Antigen Testing in United States Hospitals: a Missed Opportunity for Antimicrobial Stewardship. Clin Infect Dis. 2020;71(6):1427–1434.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7901240</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31587039</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ogawa H, Kitsios GD, Iwata M, Terasawa T. Sputum Gram Stain for Bacterial Pathogen Diagnosis in Community-acquired Pneumonia: a Systematic Review and Bayesian Meta-analysis of Diagnostic Accuracy and Yield. Clin Infect Dis off Publ Infect Dis Soc Am. 2020;71(3):499–513. doi:10.1093/cid/ciz876</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/ciz876</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Couturier MR, Graf EH, Griffin AT. Urine Antigen Tests for the Diagnosis of Respiratory Infections. Clin Lab Med. 2014;34(2):219–236. doi:10.1016/j.cll.2014.02.002</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cll.2014.02.002</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24856525</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Song JY, Eun BW, Nahm MH. Diagnosis of Pneumococcal Pneumonia: current Pitfalls and the Way Forward. Infect Chemother. 2013;45(4):351. doi:10.3947/ic.2013.45.4.351</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3947/ic.2013.45.4.351</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3902818</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24475349</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marcos MA, Anta MT, Bellacasa JP, et al. Rapid urinary antigen test for diagnosis of pneumococcal community-acquired pneumonia in adults. Eur Respir J. 2003;21(2):209–214. doi:10.1183/09031936.03.00058802</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/09031936.03.00058802</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12608431</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dochez AR, Avery OT. The elaboration of specific soluble substance by Pneumococcus during growth. J Exp Med. 1917;26(4):477–493.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2125788</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19868163</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harris AM, Beekmann SE, Polgreen PM, Moore MR. Rapid urine antigen testing for Streptococcus pneumoniae in adults with community-acquired pneumonia: clinical use and barriers. Diagn Microbiol Infect Dis. 2014;79(4):454–457. doi:10.1016/j.diagmicrobio.2014.05.008</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.diagmicrobio.2014.05.008</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5800492</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24938760</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Athlin S, Iversen A, Özenci V. Comparison of the ImmuView and the BinaxNOW antigen tests in detection of Streptococcus pneumoniae and Legionella pneumophila in urine. Eur J Clin Microbiol Infect Dis. 2017;36(10):1933–1938. doi:10.1007/s10096-017-3016-6</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10096-017-3016-6</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5602076</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28589425</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jorgensen CS, Uldum SA, Sorensen JF, Skovsted IC, Otte S, Elverdal PL. Evaluation of a new lateral flow test for detection of Streptococcus pneumoniae and Legionella pneumophila urinary antigen. J Microbiol Methods. 2015;116:33–36. doi:10.1016/j.mimet.2015.06.014</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mimet.2015.06.014</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26141796</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Athlin S, Altun O, Eriksen HB, Özenci V, Strålin K. The Uni-Gold&lt;sup&gt;TM{{sup}} Streptococcus pneumoniae urinary antigen test: an interassay comparison with the BinaxNOW® Streptococcus pneumoniae test on consecutive urine samples and evaluation on patients with bacteremia. Eur J Clin Microbiol Infect Dis. 2015;34(8):1583–1588. doi:10.1007/s10096-015-2390-1</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10096-015-2390-1</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25926305</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wong AYW, Johnsson ATA, Ininbergs K, Athlin S, Özenci V. Comparison of Four Streptococcus pneumoniae Urinary Antigen Tests Using Automated Readers. Microorganisms. 2021;9(4):827. doi:10.3390/microorganisms9040827</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/microorganisms9040827</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8070120</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33924729</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Burgos J, Garcia-Pérez JN, Lauro SG, et al. Usefulness of Sofia Pneumococcal FIA® test in comparison with BinaxNOW® Pneumococcal test in urine samples for the diagnosis of pneumococcal pneumonia. Eur J Clin Microbiol Infect Dis. 2018;37(7):1289–1295. doi:10.1007/s10096-018-3248-0</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10096-018-3248-0</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29651615</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schimmel JJ, Haessler S, Imrey P, et al. Pneumococcal Urinary Antigen Testing in United States Hospitals: a Missed Opportunity for Antimicrobial Stewardship. Clin Infect Dis. 2020;71(6):1427–1434. doi:10.1093/cid/ciz983</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/ciz983</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7901240</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31587039</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mandell LA, Wunderink RG, Anzueto A, et al. Infectious Diseases Society of America/American Thoracic Society Consensus Guidelines on the Management of Community-Acquired Pneumonia in Adults. Clin Infect Dis. 2007;44(Supplement_2):S27–S72. doi:10.1086/511159</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1086/511159</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7107997</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17278083</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Metlay J, Waterer G, Long A, et al. Diagnosis and Treatment of Adults With Community-Acquired Pneumonia. An official clinical practice guideline of the American Thoracic Society and Infectious Diseases Society of America. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2019;200(7):e45–67. doi:10.1164/rccm.201908-1581ST</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1164/rccm.201908-1581ST</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6812437</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31573350</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Falguera M, Ruiz-Gonzalez A, Schoenenberger JA, et al. Prospective, randomised study to compare empirical treatment versus targeted treatment on the basis of the urine antigen results in hospitalised patients with community-acquired pneumonia. Thorax. 2010;65(2):101–106. doi:10.1136/thx.2009.118588</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/thx.2009.118588</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19703825</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Costantini E, Allara E, Patrucco F, Faggiano F, Hamid F, Balbo PE. Adherence to guidelines for hospitalized community-acquired pneumonia over time and its impact on health outcomes and mortality. Intern Emerg Med. 2016;11(7):929–940. doi:10.1007/s11739-016-1445-3</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11739-016-1445-3</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27098057</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Uematsu H, Hashimoto H, Iwamoto T, Horiguchi H, Yasunaga H. Impact of guideline-concordant microbiological testing on outcomes of pneumonia. Int J Qual Health Care. 2014;26(1):100–107. doi:10.1093/intqhc/mzt078</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/intqhc/mzt078</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rosón B, Fernández-Sabé N, Carratalà J, et al. Contribution of a urinary antigen assay (Binax NOW) to the early diagnosis of pneumococcal pneumonia. Clin Infect Dis off Publ Infect Dis Soc Am. 2004;38(2):222–226. doi:10.1086/380639</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1086/380639</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bellew S, Grijalva CG, Williams DJ, et al. Pneumococcal and Legionella Urinary Antigen Tests in Community-acquired Pneumonia: prospective Evaluation of Indications for Testing. Clin Infect Dis. 2019;68(12):2026–2033. doi:10.1093/cid/ciy826</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/ciy826</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7182343</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30265290</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hyams C, Williams OM, Williams P. Urinary antigen testing for pneumococcal pneumonia: is there evidence to make its use uncommon in clinical practice?
ERJ Open Res. 2020;6(1):223–02019. doi:10.1183/23120541.00223-2019</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/23120541.00223-2019</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>West DM, McCauley LM, Sorensen JS, Jephson AR, Dean NC. Pneumococcal urinary antigen test use in diagnosis and treatment of pneumonia in seven Utah hospitals. ERJ Open Res. 2016;2(4):00011–02016. doi:10.1183/23120541.00011-2016</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/23120541.00011-2016</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5152836</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28053969</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Troy LK, Wong KKH, Barnes DJ. Prevalence and Utility of Positive Pneumococcal Urinary Antigen Tests in Australian Patients with Community-Acquired Pneumonia. ISRN Infect Dis. 2012;2013:e518205. doi:10.5402/2013/518205</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5402/2013/518205</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dinh A, Duran C, Davido B, et al. Cost effectiveness of pneumococcal urinary antigen in Emergency Department: a pragmatic real-life study. Intern Emerg Med. 2018;13(1):69–73. doi:10.1007/s11739-016-1586-4</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11739-016-1586-4</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27988829</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Andreo F, Prat C, Ruiz-Manzano J, et al. Persistence of Streptococcus pneumoniae urinary antigen excretion after pneumococcal pneumonia. Eur J Clin Microbiol Infect Dis. 2009;28(2):197–201. doi:10.1007/s10096-008-0606-3</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10096-008-0606-3</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18830727</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abbott. BinaxNOW Streptococcus pneumoniae antigen card; 2021. Available from:
https://www.globalpointofcare.abbott/en/product-details/binaxnow-streptococcus-pneumoniae-us.html. Accessed November
10, 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sinclair A, Xie X, Teltscher M, Dendukuri N. Systematic Review and Meta-Analysis of a Urine-Based Pneumococcal Antigen Test for Diagnosis of Community-Acquired Pneumonia Caused by Streptococcus pneumoniae. J Clin Microbiol. 2013;51(7):2303–2310. doi:10.1128/JCM.00137-13</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JCM.00137-13</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3697702</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23678060</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Horita N, Miyazawa N, Kojima R, et al. Sensitivity and specificity of the Streptococcus pneumoniae urinary antigen test for unconcentrated urine from adult patients with pneumonia: a meta-analysis. Respirology. 2013;18(8):1177–1183. doi:10.1111/resp.12163</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/resp.12163</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23910720</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Molinos L, Zalacain R, Menéndez R, et al. Sensitivity, Specificity, and Positivity Predictors of the Pneumococcal Urinary Antigen Test in Community-Acquired Pneumonia. Ann Am Thorac Soc. 2015;12(10):1482–1489. doi:10.1513/AnnalsATS.201505-304OC</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1513/AnnalsATS.201505-304OC</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26288389</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shoji H, Domenech A, Simonetti AF, et al. The Alere BinaxNOW Pneumococcal Urinary Antigen Test: diagnostic Sensitivity for Adult Pneumococcal Pneumonia and Relationship to Specific Serotypes. J Clin Microbiol. 2018;56(2):e00787–17. doi:10.1128/JCM.00787-17</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JCM.00787-17</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ito A, Ishida T, Tachibana H, Nakanishi Y, Yamazaki A, Washio Y. Time Trend of the Sensitivity of the Pneumococcal Urinary Antigen Test for Diagnosing Pneumococcal Community-Acquired Pneumonia: an Analysis of 15-Year, Prospective Cohort Data. Infect Dis Ther. 2021;2:45. doi:10.1007/s40121-021-00508-5</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40121-021-00508-5</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Briones ML, Blanquer J, Ferrando D, Blasco ML, Gimeno C, Marín J. Assessment of analysis of urinary pneumococcal antigen by immunochromatography for etiologic diagnosis of community-acquired pneumonia in adults. Clin Vaccine Immunol CVI. 2006;13(10):1092–1097. doi:10.1128/CVI.00090-06</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/CVI.00090-06</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1595326</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17028212</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sordé R, Falcó V, Lowak M, et al. Current and Potential Usefulness of Pneumococcal Urinary Antigen Detection in Hospitalized Patients With Community-Acquired Pneumonia to Guide Antimicrobial Therapy. Arch Intern Med. 2011;171(2):166–172.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20876397</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Viasus D, Simonetti AF, Garcia-Vidal C, Niubó J, Dorca J, Carratalà J. Impact of antibiotic de-escalation on clinical outcomes in community-acquired pneumococcal pneumonia. J Antimicrob Chemother. 2017;72(2):547–5553. doi:10.1093/jac/dkw441</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jac/dkw441</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27798219</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Viasus D, Vecino-Moreno M, De La Hoz JM, Carratalà J. Antibiotic stewardship in community-acquired pneumonia. Expert Rev Anti Infect Ther. 2017;15(4):351–359. doi:10.1080/14787210.2017.1274232</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14787210.2017.1274232</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28002979</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carugati M, Franzetti F, Wiemken T, et al. De-escalation therapy among bacteraemic patients with community-acquired pneumonia. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2015;21(10):936.e11–936.e18. doi:10.1016/j.cmi.2015.06.015</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cmi.2015.06.015</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yamana H, Matsui H, Tagami T, Hirashima J, Fushimi K, Yasunaga H. De-escalation versus continuation of empirical antimicrobial therapy in community-acquired pneumonia. J Infect. 2016;73(4):314–325. doi:10.1016/j.jinf.2016.07.001</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jinf.2016.07.001</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27394401</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kadri SS. A Reappraisal of Streptococcal Urinary Antigen Testing for Antibiotic Stewardship. Clin Infect Dis. 2020;71(6):1435–1437. doi:10.1093/cid/ciz989</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cid/ciz989</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7486842</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31587033</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mandell L. Prospective randomised study to compare empirical treatment versus targeted treatment on the basis of the urine antigen results in hospitalised patients with community-acquired pneumonia. Thorax. 2010;65(2):93–94. doi:10.1136/thx.2009.124156</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/thx.2009.124156</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20147586</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Greenfield A, Marsh K, Siegfried J, et al. Impact of Streptococcus pneumoniae Urinary Antigen Testing in Patients with Community-acquired Pneumonia Admitted within a Large Academic Health System. Open Forum Infect Dis. 2021;1:ofab522.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Engel MF, Velzen M, Hoepelman AIM, Thijsen S, Oosterheert JJ. Positive urinary antigen tests for Streptococcus pneumoniae in community-acquired pneumonia: a 7-year retrospective evaluation of health care cost and treatment consequences. Eur J Clin Microbiol Infect Dis. 2013;32(4):485–492. doi:10.1007/s10096-012-1761-0</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10096-012-1761-0</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23111919</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marchello C, Dale AP, Thai TN, Han DS, Ebell MH. Prevalence of Atypical Pathogens in Patients With Cough and Community-Acquired Pneumonia: a Meta-Analysis. Ann Fam Med. 2016;14(6):552–566. doi:10.1370/afm.1993</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1370/afm.1993</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5389400</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28376442</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Engel MF, van Manen L, Hoepelman AIM, Thijsen S, Oosterheert JJ. Diagnostic, therapeutic and economic consequences of a positive urinary antigen test for Legionella spp. in patients admitted with community-acquired pneumonia: a 7-year retrospective evaluation. J Clin Pathol. 2013;66(9):797–802. doi:10.1136/jclinpath-2012-201209</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jclinpath-2012-201209</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23775436</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yu VL, Stout JE. Rapid Diagnostic Testing for Community-Acquired Pneumonia: can Innovative Technology for Clinical Microbiology Be Exploited?
Chest. 2009;136(6):1618–1621. doi:10.1378/chest.09-0939</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1378/chest.09-0939</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7130296</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19995763</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Walser SM, Gerstner DG, Brenner B, Höller C, Liebl B, Herr CEW. Assessing the environmental health relevance of cooling towers – a systematic review of legionellosis outbreaks. Int J Hyg Environ Health. 2014;217(2–3):145–154. doi:10.1016/j.ijheh.2013.08.002</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijheh.2013.08.002</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24100053</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sopena N, Sabrià M, Pedro-Botet ML, et al. Factors Related to Persistence of Legionella Urinary Antigen Excretion in Patients with Legionnaires’ Disease. Eur J Clin Microbiol Infect Dis. 2002;21(12):845–848. doi:10.1007/s10096-002-0839-5</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10096-002-0839-5</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12525918</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beauté J. Legionnaires’ disease in Europe, 2011 to 2015. Eurosurveillance. 2017;22(27):30566. doi:10.2807/1560-7917.ES.2017.22.27.30566</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2807/1560-7917.ES.2017.22.27.30566</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wong AYW, Johnsson ATA, Iversen A, Athlin S, Özenci V. Evaluation of Four Lateral Flow Assays for the Detection of Legionella Urinary Antigen. Microorganisms. 2021;9(3):493. doi:10.3390/microorganisms9030493</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/microorganisms9030493</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7996842</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33652772</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mercante JW, Winchell JM. Current and emerging Legionella diagnostics for laboratory and outbreak investigations. Clin Microbiol Rev. 2015;28(1):95–133. doi:10.1128/CMR.00029-14</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/CMR.00029-14</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4284297</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25567224</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yu VL, Plouffe JF, Pastoris MC, et al. Distribution of Legionella species and serogroups isolated by culture in patients with sporadic community-acquired legionellosis: an international collaborative survey. J Infect Dis. 2002;186(1):127–128. doi:10.1086/341087</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1086/341087</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12089674</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kohler RB, Winn WC, Wheat LJ. Onset and duration of urinary antigen excretion in Legionnaires disease. J Clin Microbiol. 1984;20(4):605–607.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC271393</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6490846</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yzerman EPF, den Boer JW, Lettinga KD, Schellekens J, Dankert J, Peeters M. Sensitivity of three urinary antigen tests associated with clinical severity in a large outbreak of Legionnaires’ disease in The Netherlands. J Clin Microbiol. 2002;40(9):3232–3236. doi:10.1128/JCM.40.9.3232-3236.2002</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JCM.40.9.3232-3236.2002</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC130686</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12202558</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Helbig JH, Uldum SA, Bernander S, et al. Clinical Utility of Urinary Antigen Detection for Diagnosis of Community-Acquired, Travel-Associated, and Nosocomial Legionnaires’ Disease. J Clin Microbiol. 2003;41(2):838–840. doi:10.1128/JCM.41.2.838-840.2003</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/JCM.41.2.838-840.2003</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC149701</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12574296</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Allgaier J, Lagu T, Haessler S, et al. Risk Factors, Management, and Outcomes of Legionella Pneumonia in a Large, Nationally Representative Sample. Chest. 2021;159(5):1782–1792. doi:10.1016/j.chest.2020.12.013</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chest.2020.12.013</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33352192</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Waterer GW, Baselski VS, Wunderink RG. Legionella and community-acquired pneumonia: a review of current diagnostic tests from a clinician’s viewpoint. Am J Med. 2001;110(1):41–48. doi:10.1016/S0002-9343(00)00624-0</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0002-9343(00)00624-0</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11152864</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Henry C, Boethel C, Copeland LA, Ghamande S, Arroliga AC, White HD. Clinical Utility of Testing for Legionella Pneumonia in Central Texas. Ann Am Thorac Soc. 2017;14(1):65–69. doi:10.1513/AnnalsATS.201606-501BC</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1513/AnnalsATS.201606-501BC</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27739904</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ito A, Yamamoto Y, Ishii Y, et al. Evaluation of a novel urinary antigen test kit for diagnosing Legionella pneumonia. Int J Infect Dis. 2021;103:42–47. doi:10.1016/j.ijid.2020.10.106</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijid.2020.10.106</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33176204</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shimada T, Noguchi Y, Jackson JL, et al. Systematic Review and Meta-analysis: urinary Antigen Tests for Legionellosis. Chest. 2009;136(6):1576–1585. doi:10.1378/chest.08-2602</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1378/chest.08-2602</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19318671</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roed T, Schønheyder HC, Nielsen H. Predictors of positive or negative legionella urinary antigen test in community-acquired pneumonia. Infect Dis Lond Engl. 2015;47(7):484–490. doi:10.3109/23744235.2015.1021830</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/23744235.2015.1021830</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fiumefreddo R, Zaborsky R, Haeuptle J, et al. Clinical predictors for Legionella in patients presenting with community-acquired pneumonia to the emergency department. BMC Pulm Med. 2009;9(1):4. doi:10.1186/1471-2466-9-4</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1471-2466-9-4</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2636761</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19152698</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miyashita N, Horita N, Higa F, et al. Validation of a diagnostic score model for the prediction of Legionella pneumophila pneumonia. J Infect Chemother. 2019;25(6):407–412. doi:10.1016/j.jiac.2019.03.009</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jiac.2019.03.009</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30935766</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ito A, Ishida T, Washio Y, Yamazaki A, Tachibana H. Legionella pneumonia due to non-Legionella pneumophila serogroup 1: usefulness of the six-point scoring system. BMC Pulm Med. 2017;17(1):211. doi:10.1186/s12890-017-0559-3</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12890-017-0559-3</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5732474</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29246145</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Levcovich A, Lazarovitch T, Moran-Gilad J, et al. Complex clinical and microbiological effects on Legionnaires’ disease outcome; A retrospective cohort study. BMC Infect Dis. 2016;16:75. doi:10.1186/s12879-016-1374-9</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12879-016-1374-9</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4748635</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26864322</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lettinga KD, Verbon A, Weverling GJ, et al. Legionnaires’ disease at a Dutch flower show: prognostic factors and impact of therapy. Emerg Infect Dis. 2002;8(12):1448–1454. doi:10.3201/eid0812.020035</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3201/eid0812.020035</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2738521</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12498662</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lim WS, Baudouin SV, George RC, et al. BTS guidelines for the management of community acquired pneumonia in adults: update 2009. Thorax. 2009;64(Suppl 3):iii1–iii55. doi:10.1136/thx.2009.121434</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/thx.2009.121434</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19783532</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ewig S, Höffken G, Kern WV, et al. Management of Adult Community-acquired Pneumonia and Prevention - Update 2016. Pneumol Stuttg Ger. 2016;70(3):151–200. doi:10.1055/s-0042-101873</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0042-101873</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Menéndez R, Torres A, Aspa J, et al. Community acquired pneumonia: new guidelines of the Spanish Society of Chest Diseases and Thoracic Surgery (SEPAR). Arch Bronconeumol. 2010;46(10):543–558. doi:10.1016/j.arbres.2010.06.014</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.arbres.2010.06.014</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20832928</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van der Eerden MM. Comparison between pathogen directed antibiotic treatment and empirical broad spectrum antibiotic treatment in patients with community acquired pneumonia: a prospective randomised study. Thorax. 2005;60(8):672–678. doi:10.1136/thx.2004.030411</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/thx.2004.030411</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1747487</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16061709</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peci A, Winter AL, Gubbay JB. Evaluation and Comparison of Multiple Test Methods, Including Real-time PCR, for Legionella Detection in Clinical Specimens. Front Public Health. 2016;4:175. doi:10.3389/fpubh.2016.00175</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2016.00175</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5005417</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27630979</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Keše D, Obreza A, Rojko T, Kišek TC. Legionella pneumophila-Epidemiology and Characterization of Clinical Isolates, Slovenia, 2006–2020. Diagn Basel Switz. 2021;11(7):1201. doi:10.3390/diagnostics11071201</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/diagnostics11071201</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dionne M, Hatchette T, Forward K. Clinical utility of a Legionella pneumophila urinary antigen test in a large university teaching hospital. Can J Infect Dis J Can Mal Infect. 2003;14(2):85–88. doi:10.1155/2003/642159</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2003/642159</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yu VL. A clinical solution to antimicrobial resistance in community-acquired pneumonia: narrowing the spectrum of antimicrobial therapy: comment on “Current and potential usefulness of pneumococcal urinary antigen detection in hospitalized patients with community-acquired pneumonia to guide antimicrobial therapy.”. Arch Intern Med. 2011;171(2):172–173. doi:10.1001/archinternmed.2010.474</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archinternmed.2010.474</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21263107</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
