<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35511257</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>09</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>12</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2060</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>54</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Dec</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Annals of medicine</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Ann Med</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Men's experience of perpetrating intimate partner violence following disclosure of HIV status by their seropositive female intimate partners: a qualitative study.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>1126</StartPage>
          <EndPage>1139</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>1126-1139</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1080/07853890.2022.2062444</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Gender-Based (GB) intimate partner violence is a social and public health issue globally. Several risks of violence related to male sexual partners' perpetration of intimate partner violence (IPV) following the disclosure of their female intimate partners' HIV + status have been reported. No research has been conducted on male sexual partner's perspectives of perpetrating IPV following their female intimate partners' disclosure of human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) seropositive status as a risk factor for the perpetration of IPV in Ghana.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The objective of this study is to explore and describe male sexual partners' views or perspectives of perpetrating IPV following their female intimate partners' disclosure of being HIV positive in Ghana.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Interpretive phenomenological approach was used to collect and analyse data from a purposive sample of 18 Male participants whose female intimate relations informed them of being HIV + in Ghana. The sample population was taken from Ghana because such research has been reported elsewhere but none has been done in Ghana. A semi-structured interview guide was used to collect the data. The interview guide covered topics such as background information, participants' reaction to HIV positive disclosure, lived experiences of participants, and Participants' understanding of different forms of IPV.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The findings of this study reveal five main themes that emerged from the interviews which include views on the perpetration of emotional, psychological, and verbal abuse; views on the perpetration of sexual deprivation; views on the perpetration of social isolation; views on the perpetration of financial abuse and views on escalated perpetration of physical abuse.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">From the data, HIV positive status disclosure served as a risk factor for different forms of GB IPV against HIV positive women in Ghana, thus making this group more vulnerable and exposed to more GB IPV. Strategies to prevent the perpetration of IPV against women newly diagnosed as HIV positive are needed. We recommend screening all newly diagnosed HIV-positive women for abuse as an additional prevention strategy for IPV associated with disclosure of positive HIV status. KEY MESSAGESHIV positive status disclosure serves as a risk for the perpetration of IPV.Men are predisposed to violence upon hearing that their female heterosexual intimate partners are HIV positive.HIV infection information is distressful to receive from an intimate partner.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Apiribu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Felix</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Nursing and Public Health, College of Health Sciences, University of KwaZulu-Natal, Durban, South Africa.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Nursing, Faculty of Allied Health Sciences, College of Health Sciences, Kwame Nkrumah University of Science and Technology, Kumasi, Ghana.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Duma</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sinegugu Evidence</ForeName>
            <Initials>SE</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Nursing and Public Health, College of Health Sciences, University of KwaZulu-Natal, Durban, South Africa.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ncama</LastName>
            <ForeName>Busisiwe Purity</ForeName>
            <Initials>BP</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Nursing and Public Health, College of Health Sciences, University of KwaZulu-Natal, Durban, South Africa.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Ann Med</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8906388</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0785-3890</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D030881" MajorTopicYN="N">Disclosure</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015658" MajorTopicYN="Y">HIV Infections</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000066511" MajorTopicYN="Y">Intimate Partner Violence</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012307" MajorTopicYN="N">Risk Factors</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012747" MajorTopicYN="N">Sexual Partners</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000523" MajorTopicYN="N">psychology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">HIV seropositive</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Heterosexual</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">intimate partner</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">perpetrator</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">views</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>No potential conflict of interest was reported by the author(s).</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
          <Hour>11</Hour>
          <Minute>54</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35511257</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9090398</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07853890.2022.2062444</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Owusu-Addo E, Owusu-Addo SB, Antoh EF, et al. . 
Ghanaian media coverage of violence against women and girls: implications for health promotion. BMC Womens Health. 2018;18(1):129.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6108099</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30139346</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tenkorang EY, Owusu AY.. 
A life course understanding of domestic and intimate partner violence in Ghana. Child Abuse Negl. 2018;79:384–394.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29529592</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>World Health Organization 
2013. Global and regional estimates of violence against women: Prevalence and health effects of intimate partner violence and non-partner sexual violence. Geneva: World Health Organization. https://apps.who.int/iris/bitstream/handle/10665/85239/9789241564625_eng.pdf;jsessionid=</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hossain MF, Ara N, Islam MR, et al. . 
Effect of different sowing dates on yield of tomato genotypes. Int. J. Agril. Res. Innov. &amp; Tech. 2014;4(1):40–43.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aaron E, Criniti S, Bonacquisti A, et al. . 
Providing sensitive care for adult HIV-infected women with a history of childhood sexual abuse. J Assoc Nurses AIDS Care. 2013;24(4):355–367.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23790278</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>El-Bassel N, Gilbert L, Wu E, et al. . 
Relationship between drug abuse and intimate partner violence: a longitudinal study among women receiving methadone. Am J Public Health. 2005;95(3):465–470.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1449203</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15727978</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Silverman JG, Decker MR, Saggurti N, et al. . 
Intimate partner violence and HIV infection among married indian women. JAMA. 2008;300(6):703–710.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18698068</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singh V, Tolman R, Walton M, et al. . 
Characteristics of men who perpetrate intimate partner violence. J Am Board Fam Med. 2014;27(5):661–668.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25201935</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abrahams N, Devries K, Watts C, et al. . 
Worldwide prevalence of non-partner sexual violence: a systematic review. Lancet. 2014;383(9929):1648–1654.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24529867</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Campbell JC, Baty ML, Ghandour RM, et al. . 
The intersection of intimate partner violence against women and HIV/AIDS: a review. Int J Inj Contr Saf Promot. 2008;15(4):221–231.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3274697</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19051085</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stuart GL, Moore TM, Gordon KC, et al. . 
Reasons for intimate partner violence perpetration among arrested women. Violence Against Women. 2006;12(7):609–621.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16777948</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hatcher A, Stöckl H, Christofides N, et al. . 
Mechanisms linking intimate partner violence and prevention of mother-to-child transmission of HIV: a qualitative study in South Africa. Soc Sci Med. 2016;168:130–139.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27643847</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wojnar DM, Swanson KM.. 
Phenomenology: an exploration. J Holist Nurs. 2007;25(3):172–180.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17724386</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rosenthal L, Levy SR.. 
Understanding women's risk for HIV infection using social dominance theory and the four bases of gendered power. Psychol Women Quart. 2010;34(1):21–35.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jewkes R, Fulu E, Roselli T, et al. . 
Prevalence of and factors associated with non-partner rape perpetration: findings from the UN Multi-country Cross-sectional Study on Men and Violence in Asia and the Pacific. Lancet Glob Health. 2013;1(4):e208–e218.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25104346</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maman S, Campbell J, Sweat MD, et al. . 
The intersections of HIV and violence: directions for future research and interventions. Soc Sci Med. 2000;50(4):459–478.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10641800</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shamu S, Zarowsky C, Shefer T, et al. . 
Intimate partner violence after disclosure of HIV test results among pregnant women in Harare, Zimbabwe. PLoS One. 2014;9(10):e109447.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4211664</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25350001</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hatcher AM, Colvin CJ, Ndlovu N, et al. . 
Intimate partner violence among rural South African men: alcohol use, sexual decision-making, and partner communication. Cult Health Sex. 2014;16(9):1023–1039.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4490163</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24939358</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ogum Alangea D, Addo- Lartey AA, Sikweyiya Y, et al. . 
Prevalence and risk factors of intimate partner violence among women in four districts of the Central region of Ghana: Baseline findings from a cluster randomised controlled trial. PLoS One. 2018;13(7):e0200874.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6053193</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30024948</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Colombini M, James C, Ndwiga C, Integra team, et al.. 
The risks of partner violence following HIV status disclosure, and health service responses: narratives of women attending reproductive health services in Kenya. J Int AIDS Soc. 2016;19(1):20766.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4819069</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27037140</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ezebuka O, Sam-Agudu N, Erekaha S, et al. . 
Correlates of intimate partner violence among HIV-positive women in southwest Nigeria. Lancet. 2015;3:S23.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aziato L, Adejumo O.. 
Psychosocial factors influencing Ghanaian family caregivers in the post-operative care of their hospitalised patients. AJNM. 2015;16(2):112–124.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee RM.
Doing research on sensitive topics. Sage; 1993.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liamputtong P.
Researching the vulnerable: a guide to sensitive research methods. Sage; 2007.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Crotty M.
1996. Phenomenology and nursing research. Melbourne: Churchill Livingstone (Imprint of Pearson Professional Pty Ltd).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Earle V.
Phenomenology as research method or substantive metaphysics? An overview of phenomenology’s uses in nursing. Nursing_Philosophy. 2010;11:286–296.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20840140</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Merleau-Ponty M.
2002. Phenomenology of perception (2nd ed.). London: Routledge Taylor &amp; Francis Group.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wingood GM, DiClemente RJ.. 
Application of the theory of gender and power to examine HIV-related exposures, risk factors, and effective interventions for women. Health Educ Behav. 2000;27(5):539–565.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11009126</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kitzmuller G, Asplund K, Haggstrom T.. 
The long-term experience of family life after stroke. J Neurosci Nurs. 2012;44(1):E1–E13.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Langdridge D.
Gay affirmative therapy: a theoretical framework and defence. J Gay Lesbian Psychother. 2007;11(1-2):27–43.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith JA, Osborn M.. 
Interpretative phenomenological analysis. In Qualitative psychology: a practical guide to research methods. London: Sage; 2007.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saldaña J.
The coding manual for qualitative researchers. 2nd ed.
Sage; 2013.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McFarlane J, Parker B, Soeken K, et al. . Assessing for abuse during pregnancy. Severity and frequency of injuries and associated entry into prenatal care. JAMA. 1992;267(23):3176–3178.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1593739</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guba EG, Lincoln YS.. 
Competing paradigms in qualitative research. Handbook Qual Res. 1994;2(163-194):105.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Birt L, Scott S, Cavers D, et al. . 
Member checking: a tool to enhance trustworthiness or merely a nod to validation?
Qual Health Res. 2016;26(13):1802–1811.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27340178</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harper M, Cole P.. 
Member checking: Can benefits be gained similar to group therapy. Qual Rep. 2012;17(2):510–517.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dickson KS, Ameyaw EK, Darteh EKM.. 
Understanding the endorsement of wife beating in Ghana: evidence of the 2014 Ghana demographic and health survey. BMC Womens Health. 2020;20(1):25.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7011351</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32046703</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Osei-Tutu EM, Ampadu E.. 
Domestic violence against women in Ghana: the attitudes of men toward wife-beating. J Int Womens Stud. 2017;18(4):106–116.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Takyi BK, Mann J.. 
Intimate partner violence in Ghana, Africa: the perspective of men regarding wife beating. Int J Sociol Family. 2006;32(1):61–78.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tenkorang EY, Owusu AY, Yeboah EH, et al. . 
Factors influencing domestic and marital violence against women in Ghana. J Fam Viol. 2013;28(8):771–781.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Issahaku PA.
Correlates of intimate partner violence in Ghana. SAGE Open. 2017;7(2):215824401770986.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Amoakohene MI.
Violence against women in Ghana: a look at women's perceptions and review of policy and social responses. Soc Sci Med. 2004;59(11):2373–2385.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15450710</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chakraborty S, Skolnick B, Narayan RK.. 
Neuroprotection trials in traumatic brain injury. Curr Neuro Neurosci Rep. 2016;16(4):1–8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deribe K, Woldemichael K, Wondafrash M, et al. . 
Disclosure experience and associated factors among HIV positive men and women clinical service users in southwest Ethiopia. BMC Public Health. 2008;8(1):1–10.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2254612</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18173844</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Angula P, Ncama BP, Frohlich J.. 
Assessment of HIV/AIDS stigma in a rural namibian community. WJA. 2015;05(03):199–207.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jewkes RK, Dunkle K, Nduna M, et al. . 
Intimate partner violence, relationship power inequity, and incidence of HIV infection in young women in South Africa: a cohort study. The Lancet. 2010;376(9734):41–48.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Osafo J, Oppong Asante K, Ampomah CA, et al. . 
Factors contributing to divorce in Ghana: an exploratory analysis of evidence from court suits. J Divorce Remarriage. 2021; 62(4): 1–15.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ajayi LA, Soyinka-Airewele P.. 
Key triggers of domestic violence in Ghana: a victim-centered analysis. Afr Popul Stud. 2018;32(1):4097–4108.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ballantine C, Fenny A, Asante F, et al. . 
2017. Ghana: the economic and social impact of Violence Against Women and Girls (VAWG). Available at: https://www.whatworks.co.za/documents/publications/92-working-paper-no-5-pakistan-the-economic-and-social-impact-of-violece-agaist-women-ad-girls/file</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>García-Moreno C, Zimmerman C, Morris-Gehring A, et al. . 
Addressing violence against women: a call to action. Lancet. 2015;385(9978):1685–1695.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25467579</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wilson KS, Deya R, Yuhas K, et al. . 
A prospective cohort study of intimate partner violence and unprotected sex in HIV-positive female sex workers in mombasa, Kenya. AIDS Behav. 2016;20(9):2054–2064.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5605291</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27094785</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Simbayi LC, Kalichman S, Strebel A, et al. . 
Internalized stigma, discrimination, and depression among men and women living with HIV/AIDS in cape town, South Africa. Soc Sci Med. 2007;64(9):1823–1831.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4271649</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17337318</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
