<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35510701</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>17</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2958</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>05</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Molecular microbiology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Mol Microbiol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>BB0761, a MepM homolog, contributes to Borrelia burgdorferi cell division and mammalian infectivity.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/mmi.14916</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>M23 family endopeptidases play important roles in cell division and separation in a wide variety of bacteria. Recent studies have suggested that these proteins also contribute to bacterial virulence. However, the biological function of M23 peptidases in pathogenic spirochetes remains unexplored. Here, we describe Borrelia burgdorferi, the bacterial pathogen causing Lyme disease, requires a putative M23 family homolog, BB0761, for spirochete morphology and cell division. Indeed, the inactivation of bb0761 led to an aberrant filamentous phenotype as well as the impairment of B. burgdorferi growth in vitro. These phenotypes were complemented not only with B. burgdorferi bb0761, but also with the mepM gene from E. coli. Moreover, the bb0761 mutant showed a complete loss of infectivity in a murine model of Lyme borreliosis. Resistance of the mutant to osmotic and oxidative stresses was markedly reduced. Our combined results indicate that BB0761 contributes to B. burgdorferi cell division and virulence.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Thompson</LastName>
            <ForeName>Christina</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Molecular Medicine, University of South Florida, Tampa, Florida, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>George</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sierra</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Molecular Medicine, University of South Florida, Tampa, Florida, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>White</LastName>
            <ForeName>Maria L</ForeName>
            <Initials>ML</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cell Biology, Microbiology and Molecular Biology, University of South Florida, Tampa, Florida, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Eswara</LastName>
            <ForeName>Prahathees J</ForeName>
            <Initials>PJ</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4430-261X</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cell Biology, Microbiology and Molecular Biology, University of South Florida, Tampa, Florida, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ouyang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Zhiming</ForeName>
            <Initials>Z</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7427-1856</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Molecular Medicine, University of South Florida, Tampa, Florida, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <GrantList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>R35 GM133617</GrantID>
            <Acronym>GM</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIGMS NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>R35GM133617</GrantID>
            <Acronym>NH</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
        </GrantList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>05</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Mol Microbiol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8712028</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0950-382X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">
Borrelia burgdorferi
</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">gene regulation</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lyme disease</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pathogenesis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">protease</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">virulence</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>59</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35510701</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/mmi.14916</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barequet, I.S., Ben Simon, G.J., Safrin, M., Ohman, D.E. &amp; Kessler, E. (2004) Pseudomonas aeruginosa LasA protease in treatment of experimental staphylococcal keratitis. Antimicrobial Agents and Chemotherapy, 48, 1681-1687.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barthold, S.W., Beck, D.S., Hansen, G.M., Terwilliger, G.A. &amp; Moody, K.D. (1990) Lyme borreliosis in selected strains and ages of laboratory mice. The Journal of Infectious Diseases, 162, 133-138.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barthold, S.W., de Souza, M.S., Janotka, J.L., Smith, A.L. &amp; Persing, D.H. (1993) Chronic Lyme borreliosis in the laboratory mouse. The American Journal of Pathology, 143, 959-971.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barthold, S.W., Persing, D.H., Armstrong, A.L. &amp; Peeples, R.A. (1991) Kinetics of Borrelia burgdorferi dissemination and evolution of disease after intradermal inoculation of mice. The American Journal of Pathology, 139, 263-273.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blevins, J.S., Revel, A.T., Smith, A.H., Bachlani, G.N. &amp; Norgard, M.V. (2007) Adaptation of a luciferase gene reporter and lac expression system to Borrelia burgdorferi. Applied and Environmental Microbiology, 73, 1501-1513.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blevins, J.S., Xu, H., He, M., Norgard, M.V., Reitzer, L. &amp; Yang, X.F. (2009) Rrp2, a σ54-dependent transcriptional activator of Borrelia burgdorferi, activates rpoS in an enhancer-independent manner. Journal of Bacteriology, 191, 2902-2905.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bobe, J.R., Jutras, B.L., Horn, E.J., Embers, M.E., Bailey, A., Moritz, R.L. et al. (2021) Recent progress in lyme disease and remaining challenges. Frontiers in Medicine, 8, 666554.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bonis, M., Ecobichon, C., Guadagnini, S., Prevost, M.C. &amp; Boneca, I.G. (2010) A M23B family metallopeptidase of Helicobacter pylori required for cell shape, pole formation and virulence. Molecular Microbiology, 78, 809-819.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boylan, J.A., Lawrence, K.A., Downey, J.S. &amp; Gherardini, F.C. (2008) Borrelia burgdorferi membranes are the primary targets of reactive oxygen species. Molecular Microbiology, 68, 786-799.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brzozowski, R.S., White, M.L. &amp; Eswara, P.J. (2019) Live-cell fluorescence microscopy to investigate subcellular protein localization and cell morphology changes in bacteria. Journal of Visualized Experiments, (153), 59905.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Buist, G., Steen, A., Kok, J. &amp; Kuipers, O.P. (2008) LysM, a widely distributed protein motif for binding to (peptido)glycans. Molecular Microbiology, 68, 838-847.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Burgdorfer, W., Barbour, A.G., Hayes, S.F., Benach, J.L., Grunwaldt, E. &amp; Davis, J.P. (1982) Lyme disease-a tick-borne spirochetosis? Science, 216, 1317-1319.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Caimano, M.J., Eggers, C.H., Gonzalez, C.A. &amp; Radolf, J.D. (2005) Alternate sigma factor RpoS is required for the in vivo-specific repression of Borrelia burgdorferi plasmid lp54-borne ospA and lp6.6 genes. Journal of Bacteriology, 187, 7845-7852.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Caimano, M.J., Eggers, C.H., Hazlett, K.R. &amp; Radolf, J.D. (2004) RpoS is not central to the general stress response in Borrelia burgdorferi but does control expression of one or more essential virulence determinants. Infection and Immunity, 72, 6433-6445.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Caimano, M.J., Groshong, A.M., Belperron, A., Mao, J., Hawley, K.L., Luthra, A. et al. (2019) The RpoS gatekeeper in Borrelia burgdorferi: an invariant regulatory scheme that promotes spirochete persistence in reservoir hosts and niche diversity. Frontiers in Microbiology, 10, 1923.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chu, C.Y., Stewart, P.E., Bestor, A., Hansen, B., Lin, T., Gao, L. et al. (2016) Function of the Borrelia burgdorferi FtsH homolog is essential for viability both in vitro and in vivo and independent of HflK/C. mBio, 7, e00404-16.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coleman, J.L., Benach, J.L. &amp; Karzai, A.W. (2021) Endogenous and borrowed proteolytic activity in the Borrelia. Microbiology and Molecular Biology Reviews, 85, e00217-20.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coleman, J.L., Crowley, J.T., Toledo, A.M. &amp; Benach, J.L. (2013) The HtrA protease of Borrelia burgdorferi degrades outer membrane protein BmpD and chemotaxis phosphatase CheX. Molecular Microbiology, 88, 619-633.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coleman, J.L., Katona, L.I., Kuhlow, C., Toledo, A., Okan, N.A., Tokarz, R. et al. (2009) Evidence that two ATP-dependent (Lon) proteases in Borrelia burgdorferi serve different functions. PLoS Pathogens, 5, e1000676.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coleman, J.L., Toledo, A. &amp; Benach, J.L. (2016) Borrelia burgdorferi HtrA: evidence for twofold proteolysis of outer membrane protein p66. Molecular Microbiology, 99, 135-150.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coleman, J.L., Toledo, A. &amp; Benach, J.L. (2018) HtrA of Borrelia burgdorferi leads to decreased swarm motility and decreased production of pyruvate. mBio, 9, e01136-18.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Curtis, M.W., Hahn, B.L., Zhang, K., Li, C., Robinson, R.T. &amp; Coburn, J. (2018) Characterization of stress and innate immunity resistance of wild-type and Δp66 Borrelia burgdorferi. Infection and Immunity, 86, e00186-17.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Silva, A.M. &amp; Fikrig, E. (1995) Growth and migration of Borrelia burgdorferi in Ixodes ticks during blood feeding. The American Journal of Tropical Medicine and Hygiene, 53, 397-404.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dubytska, L., Godfrey, H.P. &amp; Cabello, F.C. (2006) Borrelia burgdorferi ftsZ plays a role in cell division. Journal of Bacteriology, 188, 1969-1978.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ercoli, G., Tani, C., Pezzicoli, A., Vacca, I., Martinelli, M., Pecetta, S. et al. (2015) LytM proteins play a crucial role in cell separation, outer membrane composition, and pathogenesis in nontypeable Haemophilus influenzae. mBio, 6, e02575.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Figueroa-Cuilan, W.M., Randich, A.M., Dunn, C.M., Santiago-Collazo, G., Yowell, A. &amp; Brown, P.J.B. (2021) Diversification of LytM protein functions in polar elongation and cell division of Agrobacterium tumefaciens. Frontiers in Microbiology, 12, 729307.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fraser, C.M., Casjens, S., Huang, W.M., Sutton, G.G., Clayton, R., Lathigra, R. et al. (1997) Genomic sequence of a Lyme disease spirochaete, Borrelia burgdorferi. Nature, 390, 580-586.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gherardini, F.C. (2013) Borrelia burgdorferi HtrA may promote dissemination and irritation. Molecular Microbiology, 90, 209-213.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grande, K.K., Gustin, J.K., Kessler, E. &amp; Ohman, D.E. (2007) Identification of critical residues in the propeptide of LasA protease of Pseudomonas aeruginosa involved in the formation of a stable mature protease. Journal of Bacteriology, 189, 3960-3968.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grove, A.P., Liveris, D., Iyer, R., Petzke, M., Rudman, J., Caimano, M.J. et al. (2017) Two distinct mechanisms govern RpoS-mediated repression of tick-phase genes during mammalian host adaptation by Borrelia burgdorferi, the lyme disease spirochete. mBio, 8, e01204-17.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Helble, J.D., McCarthy, J.E. &amp; Hu, L.T. (2021) Interactions between Borrelia burgdorferi and its hosts across the enzootic cycle. Parasite Immunology, 43, e12816.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hubner, A., Yang, X., Nolen, D.M., Popova, T.G., Cabello, F.C. &amp; Norgard, M.V. (2001) Expression of Borrelia burgdorferi OspC and DbpA is controlled by a RpoN-RpoS regulatory pathway. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 98, 12724-12729.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jewett, M.W., Lawrence, K., Bestor, A.C., Tilly, K., Grimm, D., Shaw, P. et al. (2007) The critical role of the linear plasmid lp36 in the infectious cycle of Borrelia burgdorferi. Molecular Microbiology, 64, 1358-1374.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kurokawa, C., Lynn, G.E., Pedra, J.H.F., Pal, U., Narasimhan, S. &amp; Fikrig, E. (2020) Interactions between Borrelia burgdorferi and ticks. Nature Reviews. Microbiology, 18, 587-600.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Labandeira-Rey, M. &amp; Skare, J.T. (2001) Decreased infectivity in Borrelia burgdorferi strain B31 is associated with loss of linear plasmid 25 or 28-1. Infection and Immunity, 69, 446-455.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liang, F.T., Xu, Q., Sikdar, R., Xiao, Y., Cox, J.S. &amp; Doerrler, W.T. (2010) BB0250 of Borrelia burgdorferi is a conserved and essential inner membrane protein required for cell division. Journal of Bacteriology, 192, 6105-6115.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maksimyan, S., Syed, M.S. &amp; Soti, V. (2021) Post-treatment lyme disease syndrome: need for diagnosis and treatment. Cureus, 13, e18703.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mason, C., Thompson, C. &amp; Ouyang, Z. (2020a) DksA plays an essential role in regulating the virulence of Borrelia burgdorferi. Molecular Microbiology, 114, 172-183.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mason, C., Thompson, C. &amp; Ouyang, Z. (2020b) The Lon-2 protease of Borrelia burgdorferi is critical for infection in the mammalian host. Molecular Microbiology, 113, 938-950.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mesnage, S., Dellarole, M., Baxter, N.J., Rouget, J.B., Dimitrov, J.D., Wang, N. et al. (2014) Molecular basis for bacterial peptidoglycan recognition by LysM domains. Nature Communications, 5, 4269.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Motaleb, M.A., Liu, J. &amp; Wooten, R.M. (2015) Spirochetal motility and chemotaxis in the natural enzootic cycle and development of Lyme disease. Current Opinion in Microbiology, 28, 106-113.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ouyang, Z., Blevins, J.S. &amp; Norgard, M.V. (2008) Transcriptional interplay among the regulators Rrp2, RpoN and RpoS in Borrelia burgdorferi. Microbiology (Reading), 154, 2641-2658.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ouyang, Z., He, M., Oman, T., Yang, X.F. &amp; Norgard, M.V. (2009) A manganese transporter, BB0219 (BmtA), is required for virulence by the Lyme disease spirochete, Borrelia burgdorferi. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 106, 3449-3454.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ouyang, Z., Narasimhan, S., Neelakanta, G., Kumar, M., Pal, U., Fikrig, E. et al. (2012) Activation of the RpoN-RpoS regulatory pathway during the enzootic life cycle of Borrelia burgdorferi. BMC Microbiology, 12, 44.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pal, U., Dai, J., Li, X., Neelakanta, G., Luo, P., Kumar, M. et al. (2008) A differential role for BB0365 in the persistence of Borrelia burgdorferi in mice and ticks. The Journal of Infectious Diseases, 197, 148-155.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pal, U., Kitsou, C., Drecktrah, D., Yas, O.B. &amp; Fikrig, E. (2021) Interactions between ticks and lyme disease spirochetes. Current Issues in Molecular Biology, 42, 113-144.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pal, U., Li, X., Wang, T., Montgomery, R.R., Ramamoorthi, N., Desilva, A.M. et al. (2004) TROSPA, an Ixodes scapularis receptor for Borrelia burgdorferi. Cell, 119, 457-468.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peters, N.T., Morlot, C., Yang, D.C., Uehara, T., Vernet, T. &amp; Bernhardt, T.G. (2013) Structure-function analysis of the LytM domain of EnvC, an activator of cell wall remodelling at the Escherichia coli division site. Molecular Microbiology, 89, 690-701.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pollack, R.J., Telford, S.R., 3rd &amp; Spielman, A. (1993) Standardization of medium for culturing Lyme disease spirochetes. Journal of Clinical Microbiology, 31, 1251-1255.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Purser, J.E. &amp; Norris, S.J. (2000) Correlation between plasmid content and infectivity in Borrelia burgdorferi. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 97, 13865-13870.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Radolf, J.D., Caimano, M.J., Stevenson, B. &amp; Hu, L.T. (2012) Of ticks, mice and men: understanding the dual-host lifestyle of Lyme disease spirochaetes. Nature Reviews. Microbiology, 10, 87-99.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ramadurai, L. &amp; Jayaswal, R.K. (1997) Molecular cloning, sequencing, and expression of lytM, a unique autolytic gene of Staphylococcus aureus. Journal of Bacteriology, 179, 3625-3631.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rawlings, N.D., Barrett, A.J., Thomas, P.D., Huang, X., Bateman, A. &amp; Finn, R.D. (2018) The MEROPS database of proteolytic enzymes, their substrates and inhibitors in 2017 and a comparison with peptidases in the PANTHER database. Nucleic Acids Research, 46, D624-D632.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Russell, T.M., Delorey, M.J. &amp; Johnson, B.J. (2013) Borrelia burgdorferi BbHtrA degrades host ECM proteins and stimulates release of inflammatory cytokines in vitro. Molecular Microbiology, 90, 241-251.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Samuels, D.S. (2011) Gene regulation in Borrelia burgdorferi. Annual Review of Microbiology, 65, 479-499.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Samuels, D.S., Lybecker, M.C., Yang, X.F., Ouyang, Z., Bourret, T.J., Boyle, W.K. et al. (2021) Gene regulation and transcriptomics. Current Issues in Molecular Biology, 42, 223-266.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schwan, T.G. (1996) Ticks and Borrelia: model systems for investigating pathogen-arthropod interactions. Infectious Agents and Disease, 5, 167-181.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Seshu, J., Boylan, J.A., Hyde, J.A., Swingle, K.L., Gherardini, F.C. &amp; Skare, J.T. (2004) A conservative amino acid change alters the function of BosR, the redox regulator of Borrelia burgdorferi. Molecular Microbiology, 54, 1352-1363.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singh, V.K., Carlos, M.R. &amp; Singh, K. (2010) Physiological significance of the peptidoglycan hydrolase, LytM, in Staphylococcus aureus. FEMS Microbiology Letters, 311, 167-175.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singh, S.K., SaiSree, L., Amrutha, R.N. &amp; Reddy, M. (2012) Three redundant murein endopeptidases catalyse an essential cleavage step in peptidoglycan synthesis of Escherichia coli K12. Molecular Microbiology, 86, 1036-1051.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Spencer, J., Murphy, L.M., Conners, R., Sessions, R.B. &amp; Gamblin, S.J. (2010) Crystal structure of the LasA virulence factor from Pseudomonas aeruginosa: substrate specificity and mechanism of M23 metallopeptidases. Journal of Molecular Biology, 396, 908-923.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Steere, A.C. (1993) Current understanding of Lyme disease. Hospital Practice (Office Ed.), 28, 37-44.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Steere, A.C., Coburn, J. &amp; Glickstein, L. (2004) The emergence of Lyme disease. The Journal of Clinical Investigation, 113, 1093-1101.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stewart, P.E., Byram, R., Grimm, D., Tilly, K. &amp; Rosa, P.A. (2005) The plasmids of Borrelia burgdorferi: essential genetic elements of a pathogen. Plasmid, 53, 1-13.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stohl, E.A., Chan, Y.A., Hackett, K.T., Kohler, P.L., Dillard, J.P. &amp; Seifert, H.S. (2012) Neisseria gonorrhoeae virulence factor NG1686 is a bifunctional M23B family metallopeptidase that influences resistance to hydrogen peroxide and colony morphology. The Journal of Biological Chemistry, 287, 11222-11233.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stohl, E.A., Dale, E.M., Criss, A.K. &amp; Seifert, H.S. (2013) Neisseria gonorrhoeae metalloprotease NGO1686 is required for full piliation, and piliation is required for resistance to H2O2- and neutrophil-mediated killing. mBio, 4, e00399-13.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Streicher, L.M. (2021) Exploring the future of infectious disease treatment in a post-antibiotic era: A comparative review of alternative therapeutics. Journal of Global Antimicrobial Resistance, 24, 285-295.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thompson, C., Mason, C., Parrilla, S. &amp; Ouyang, Z. (2020) The Lon-1 protease is required by Borrelia burgdorferi to infect the mammalian host. Infection and Immunity, 88, e00951-19.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tidhar, A., Flashner, Y., Cohen, S., Levi, Y., Zauberman, A., Gur, D. et al. (2009) The NlpD lipoprotein is a novel Yersinia pestis virulence factor essential for the development of plague. PLoS One, 4, e7023.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Troxell, B., Zhang, J.J., Bourret, T.J., Zeng, M.Y., Blum, J., Gherardini, F. et al. (2014) Pyruvate protects pathogenic spirochetes from H2O2 killing. PLoS One, 9, e84625.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Uehara, T., Dinh, T. &amp; Bernhardt, T.G. (2009) LytM-domain factors are required for daughter cell separation and rapid ampicillin-induced lysis in Escherichia coli. Journal of Bacteriology, 191, 5094-5107.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Uehara, T., Parzych, K.R., Dinh, T. &amp; Bernhardt, T.G. (2010) Daughter cell separation is controlled by cytokinetic ring-activated cell wall hydrolysis. The EMBO Journal, 29, 1412-1422.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vermassen, A., Leroy, S., Talon, R., Provot, C., Popowska, M. &amp; Desvaux, M. (2019) Cell wall hydrolases in bacteria: insight on the diversity of cell wall amidases, glycosidases and peptidases toward peptidoglycan. Frontiers in Microbiology, 10, 331.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wallace, M.J., Fishbein, S.R.S. &amp; Dantas, G. (2020) Antimicrobial resistance in enteric bacteria: current state and next-generation solutions. Gut Microbes, 12, 1799654.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wong, K.H., Shapiro, E.D. &amp; Soffer, G.K. (2021) A review of post-treatment lyme disease syndrome and chronic lyme disease for the practicing immunologist. Clinical Reviews in Allergy and Immunology, 62, 264-271.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xiang, X., Yang, Y., Du, J., Lin, T., Chen, T., Yang, X.F. et al. (2017) Investigation of ospC expression variation among Borrelia burgdorferi strains. Frontiers in Cellular and Infection Microbiology, 7, 131.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang, X.F., Alani, S.M. &amp; Norgard, M.V. (2003) The response regulator Rrp2 is essential for the expression of major membrane lipoproteins in Borrelia burgdorferi. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 100, 11001-11006.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang, L.C., Gan, Y.L., Yang, L.Y., Jiang, B.L. &amp; Tang, J.L. (2018) Peptidoglycan hydrolysis mediated by the amidase AmiC and its LytM activator NlpD is critical for cell separation and virulence in the phytopathogen Xanthomonas campestris. Molecular Plant Pathology, 19, 1705-1718.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang, Y. &amp; Li, C. (2009) Transcription and genetic analyses of a putative N-acetylmuramyl-L-alanine amidase in Borrelia burgdorferi. FEMS Microbiology Letters, 290, 164-173.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ye, M., Sharma, K., Thakur, M., Smith, A.A., Buyuktanir, O., Xiang, X. et al. (2016) HtrA, a temperature- and stationary phase-activated protease involved in maturation of a key microbial virulence determinant, facilitates Borrelia burgdorferi infection in mammalian hosts. Infection and Immunity, 84, 2372-2381.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ye, M., Zhou, Y., Lou, Y. &amp; Yang, X.F. (2016) Genome reduction of Borrelia burgdorferi: two TCS signaling pathways for two distinct host habitats. Science China. Life Sciences, 59, 19-21.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang, K., Qin, Z., Chang, Y., Liu, J., Malkowski, M.G., Shipa, S. et al. (2019) Analysis of a flagellar filament cap mutant reveals that HtrA serine protease degrades unfolded flagellin protein in the periplasm of Borrelia burgdorferi. Molecular Microbiology, 111, 1652-1670.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
