<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35510176</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>07</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2452-199X</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>19</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2023</Year>
              <Month>Jan</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Bioactive materials</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Bioact Mater</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Biomimetic manganese-based theranostic nanoplatform for cancer multimodal imaging and twofold immunotherapy.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>237</StartPage>
          <EndPage>250</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>237-250</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.bioactmat.2022.04.011</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The limited clinical response and serious side effect have been challenging in cancer immunotherapy resulting from immunosuppressive tumor microenvironment (TME) and inferior drug targeting. Herein, an active targeting TME nanoplatform capable of revising the immunosuppressive TME microenvironment is designed. Briefly, gold nanorods (GNRs) are covered with silica dioxide (SiO<sub>2</sub>) and then coated manganese dioxide (MnO<sub>2</sub>) to obtain GNRs@SiO<sub>2</sub>@MnO<sub>2</sub> (GSM). Myeloid-derived suppressor cells (MDSCs) membrane is further camouflaged on the surface of GSM to obtain GNRs@SiO<sub>2</sub>@MnO<sub>2</sub>@MDSCs (GSMM). In this system, GSMM inherits active targeting TME capacity of MDSCs. The localized surface plasmon resonance of GNRs is developed in near-infrared II window by MnO<sub>2</sub> layer coating, realizing NIR-II window photothermal imaging and photoacoustic imaging of GSMM. Based on the release of Mn<sup>2+</sup> in acidic TME, GSMM can be also used for magnetic resonance imaging. In cancer cells, Mn<sup>2+</sup> catalyzes H<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub> into ·OH for (chemodynamic therapy) CDT leading to activate cGAS-STING, but also directly acts on STING inducing secretion of type I interferons, pro-inflammatory cytokines and chemokines. Additionally, photothermal therapy and CDT-mediated immunogenic cell death of tumor cells can further enhance anti-tumor immunity via exposure of CRT, HMGB1 and ATP. In summary, our nanoplatform realizes multimodal cancer imaging and dual immunotherapy.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Authors.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhao</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yuyue</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Stomatological Hospital, Southern Medical University, Guangzhou, 510280, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Pan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yuanwei</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Biomedical Health Technology and Engineering, Shenzhen Bay Laboratory, Shenzhen, 518132, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Departments of Diagnostic Radiology, Surgery, Chemical and Biomolecular Engineering, and Biomedical Engineering, Yong Loo Lin School of Medicine and Faculty of Engineering, National University of Singapore, Singapore, 119074, Singapore.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zou</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kelong</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Stomatological Hospital, Southern Medical University, Guangzhou, 510280, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Zhou</ForeName>
            <Initials>Z</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Stomatological Hospital, Southern Medical University, Guangzhou, 510280, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Cheng</LastName>
            <ForeName>Guowang</ForeName>
            <Initials>G</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Science and Technology Innovation Center, Guangzhou University of Chinese Medicine, Guangzhou, 510405, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mai</LastName>
            <ForeName>Qiuying</ForeName>
            <Initials>Q</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Science and Technology Innovation Center, Guangzhou University of Chinese Medicine, Guangzhou, 510405, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Cui</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hao</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Stomatological Hospital, Southern Medical University, Guangzhou, 510280, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Meng</LastName>
            <ForeName>Qianfang</ForeName>
            <Initials>Q</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Biomedical Health Technology and Engineering, Shenzhen Bay Laboratory, Shenzhen, 518132, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Tongkai</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Science and Technology Innovation Center, Guangzhou University of Chinese Medicine, Guangzhou, 510405, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Rao</LastName>
            <ForeName>Lang</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Biomedical Health Technology and Engineering, Shenzhen Bay Laboratory, Shenzhen, 518132, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ma</LastName>
            <ForeName>Limin</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Medical Research Center, Guangdong Provincial People's Hospital, Guangdong Academy of Medical Sciences, Guangzhou, 510080, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Guangtao</ForeName>
            <Initials>G</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Stomatological Hospital, Southern Medical University, Guangzhou, 510280, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>04</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Bioact Mater</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101685294</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2452-199X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Biomimetic</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cancer imaging</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Immunotherapy</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Manganese ions</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">The second near-infrared window</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
          <Hour>2</Hour>
          <Minute>37</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35510176</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9048124</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bioactmat.2022.04.011</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">S2452-199X(22)00181-5</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sharma P., Siddiqui B.A., Anandhan S., Yadav S.S., Subudhi S.K., Gao J., Goswami S., Allison J.P. The Next Decade of Immune Checkpoint Therapy. Cancer Discov. 2021;11:838–857.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33811120</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta R.G., Li F., Roszik J., Lizée G. Exploiting tumor neoantigens to target cancer evolution: current challenges and promising Therapeutic approaches. Cancer Discov. 2021;11:1024–1039.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8102318</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33722796</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ni K., Luo T., Nash G.T., Lin W. Nanoscale metal-organic frameworks for cancer immunotherapy. Acc. Chem. Res. 2020;53:1739–1748.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32808760</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu Y., Bhattarai P., Dai Z. Chen X Photothermal therapy and photoacoustic imaging via nanotheranostics in fighting cancer. Chem. Soc. Rev. 2019;48:2053–2108.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6437026</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30259015</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yu G.T., Luo M.Y., Li H., Chen S., Huang B., Sun Z.J., Cui R. Zhang M molecular targeting nanoprobes with non-overlap emission in the second near-infrared window for in vivo two-color colocalization of immune cells. ACS Nano. 2019;13:12830–12839.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31621290</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>He T., Jiang C., He J., Zhang Y., He G., Wu J., Lin J., Zhou X., Huang P. Manganese-dioxide-coating-instructed plasmonic modulation of gold nanorods for activatable duplex-imaging-guided NIR-II photothermal-chemodynamic therapy. Adv. Mater. 2021;33</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu H., Hong G., Luo Z., Chen J., Chang J., Gong M., He H., Yang J., Yuan X., Li L., Mu X., Wang J., Mi W., Luo J., Xie J. Zhang XD atomic-precision gold clusters for NIR-II imaging. Adv. Mater. 2019;31</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Song C., Li Y., Li T., Yang Y., Huang Z., de la Fuente J.M., Ni J., Cui D. Long-circulating drug-dye-based micelles with ultrahigh pH-sensitivity for deep tumor penetration and superior chemo-photothermal therapy. Adv. Funct. Mater. 2020;30</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ding B., Zheng P., Ma P. Lin J manganese oxide nanomaterials: synthesis, properties, and theranostic applications. Adv. Mater. 2020;32</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Han S.I., Lee S.W., Cho M.G., Yoo J.M., Oh M.H., Jeong B., Kim D., Park O.K., Kim J., Namkoong E., Jo J., Lee N., Lim C., Soh M., Sung Y.E., Yoo J., Park K., Hyeon T. Epitaxially strained CeO(2)/Mn(3) O(4) nanocrystals as an enhanced antioxidant for radioprotection. Adv. Mater. 2020;32</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xiao B., Liu X., Chen X., Lee G.H., Song M., Yang X., Omenya F., Reed D.M., Sprenkle V., Ren Y., Sun C.J., Yang W., Amine K., Li X., Xu G., Li X. Uncommon behavior of Li doping suppresses oxygen redox in P2-type manganese-rich sodium cathodes. Adv. Mater. 2021 doi: 10.1002/adma.202107141.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202107141</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Galluzzi L., Buqué A., Kepp O., Zitvogel L., Kroemer G. Immunogenic cell death in cancer and infectious disease. Nat. Rev. Immunol. 2017;17:97–111.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27748397</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Albiin N., Kartalis N., Bergquist A., Sadigh B., Brismar T.B. Manganese chloride tetrahydrate (CMC-001) enhanced liver MRI: evaluation of efficacy and safety in healthy volunteers. Magma. 2012;25:361–368.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22399275</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Corrales L., Matson V., Flood B., Spranger S. Gajewski TF Innate immune signaling and regulation in cancer immunotherapy Cell. Res. 2017;27:96–108.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lam K.C., Araya R.E., Huang A., Chen Q., Di Modica M., Rodrigues R.R., Lopès A., Johnson S.B., Schwarz B., Bohrnsen E., Cogdill A.P., Bosio C.M., Wargo J.A., Lee M.P., Goldszmid R.S. Microbiota triggers STING-type I IFN-dependent monocyte reprogramming of the tumor microenvironment. Cell. 2021;184:5338–5356. e5321.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8650838</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34624222</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Decout A., Katz J.D., Venkatraman S., Ablasser A. The cGAS-STING pathway as a therapeutic target in inflammatory diseases. Nat. Rev. Immunol. 2021;21:548–569.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8029610</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33833439</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liang L., Yang L.L., Wang W., Ji C., Zhang L., Jia Y., Chen Y., Wang X., Tan J., Sun Z.J., Yuan Q., Tan W. Calcium phosphate-reinforced metal-organic frameworks regulate adenosine-mediated immunosuppression. Adv. Mater. 2021 doi: 10.1002/adma.202102271.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/adma.202102271</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhao Q., Gong Z., Li Z., Wang J., Zhang J., Zhao Z., Zhang P., Zheng S., Miron R.J., Yuan Q., Zhang Y. Target reprogramming lysosomes of CD8+ T cells by a mineralized metal-organic framework for cancer immunotherapy. Adv. Mater. 2021;33</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu J., Huang J., Zhang L. Lei J Multifunctional metal-organic framework heterostructures for enhanced cancer therapy. Chem. Soc. Rev. 2021;50:1188–1218.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33283806</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sun X., Zhang Y., Li J., Park K.S., Han K., Zhou X., Xu Y., Nam J., Xu J., Shi X., Wei L., Lei Y.L., Moon J.J. Amplifying STING activation by cyclic dinucleotide-manganese particles for local and systemic cancer metalloimmunotherapy. Nat. Nanotechnol. 2021 doi: 10.1038/s41565-021-00962-9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41565-021-00962-9</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lv M., Chen M., Zhang R., Zhang W., Wang C., Zhang Y., Wei X., Guan Y., Liu J., Feng K., Jing M., Wang X., Liu Y.C., Mei Q., Han W., Jiang Z. Manganese is critical for antitumor immune responses via cGAS-STING and improves the efficacy of clinical immunotherapy Cell. Res. 2020;30:966–979.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu B., Cui Y., Wang W., Li S., Lyu C., Wang S., Bao W., Wang H., Qin M., Liu Z., Wei W., Liu H. Immunomodulation-enhanced nanozyme-based tumor catalytic therapy. Adv. Mater. 2020;32</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang G., Xu L., Chao Y., Xu J., Sun X., Wu Y., Peng R., Liu Z. Hollow MnO(2) as a tumor-microenvironment-responsive biodegradable nano-platform for combination therapy favoring antitumor immune responses. Nat. Commun. 2017;8:902.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5638920</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29026068</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang Y., Xie Y., Luo J., Guo M., Hu X., Chen X., Chen Z., Lu X., Mao L., Zhang K., Wei L., Ma Y., Wang R., Zhou J., He C., Zhang Y., Zhang Y., Chen S., Shen L., Chen Y., Qiu N., Liu Y., Cui Y., Liao G., Liu Y. Chen C Engineering a self-navigated MnARK nanovaccine for inducing potent protective immunity against novel coronavirus. Nano Today. 2021;38</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meng Q.F., Zhao Y., Dong C., Liu L., Pan Y., Lai J., Liu Z., Yu G.T., Chen X., Rao L. Genetically programmable fusion cellular vesicles for cancer immunotherapy. Angew Chem. Int. Ed. Engl. 2021 doi: 10.1002/anie.202108342.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/anie.202108342</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yu G.-T., Rao L., Wu H., Yang L.-L., Bu L.-L., Deng W.-W., Wu L., Nan X., Zhang W.-F., Zhao X.-Z., Liu W. Sun Z-J myeloid-derived suppressor cell membrane-coated magnetic nanoparticles for cancer theranostics by inducing macrophage polarization and synergizing immunogenic cell death. Adv. Funct. Mater. 2018;28</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grover A., Sanseviero E., Timosenko E., Gabrilovich D.I. Myeloid-derived suppressor cells: A Propitious Road to Clinic. Cancer Discov. 2021;11:2693–2706.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34635571</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meng Q.F., Rao L., Zan M., Chen M., Yu G.T., Wei X., Wu Z., Sun Y., Guo S.S., Zhao X.Z., Wang F.B., Liu W. Macrophage membrane-coated iron oxide nanoparticles for enhanced photothermal tumor therapy. Nanotechnology. 2018;29</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meng Q.-F., Zhao Y., Dong C., Liu L., Pan Y., Lai J., Liu Z., Yu G.-T., Chen X., Rao L. Genetically programmable fusion cellular vesicles for cancer immunotherapy. Angew Chem. Int. Ed. Engl. 2021;60:26320–26326.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34661332</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang K., Meng X., Cao Y., Yang Z., Dong H., Zhang Y., Lu H., Shi Z. Zhang X metal–organic framework nanoshuttle for synergistic photodynamic and low-temperature photothermal therapy. Adv. Funct. Mater. 2018;28</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gao G., Sun X., Liang G. Nanoagent-promoted mild-temperature photothermal therapy for cancer treatment. Adv. Funct. Mater. 2021;31</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Phung C.D., Tran T.H., Choi J.Y., Jeong J.H., Ku S.K., Yong C.S. Kim JO pre- and post-transcriptional regulation of cFLIP for effective cancer therapy using pH-ultrasensitive nanoparticles. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces. 2021;13:5999–6010.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33506682</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jin M.Z., Jin W.L. The updated landscape of tumor microenvironment and drug repurposing. Signal Transduct. Targeted Ther. 2020;5:166.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang G., Ji J., Liu Z. Multifunctional MnO2 nanoparticles for tumor microenvironment modulation and cancer therapy. Wires Nanomed. Nanobiol. 2021;13</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xin L., Hu J., Xiang Y., Li C., Fu L., Li Q. Wei X carbon-based nanocomposites as fenton-like catalysts in wastewater treatment applications: A Review. Materials (Basel) 2021;14</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Qin H., He Y., Xu P., Huang D., Wang Z., Wang H., Wang Z., Zhao Y., Tian Q., Wang C. Spinel ferrites (MFe(2)O(4)): synthesis, improvement and catalytic application in environment and energy field. Adv. Colloid Interface Sci. 2021;294</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chabanon R.M., Rouanne M., Lord C.J., Soria J.-C., Pasero P., Postel-Vinay S. Targeting the DNA damage response in immuno-oncology: developments and opportunities. Nat. Rev. Cancer. 2021;21:701–717.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34376827</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krysko D.V., Garg A.D., Kaczmarek A., Krysko O., Agostinis P., Vandenabeele P. Immunogenic cell death and DAMPs in cancer therapy. Nat. Rev. Cancer. 2012;12:860–875.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23151605</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang X., Wang J., Zheng H., Xie M., Hopewell E.L., Albrecht R.A., Nogusa S., García-Sastre A., Balachandran S. Beg AA Differential requirement for the IKKβ/NF-κB signaling module in regulating TLR- versus RLR-induced type 1 IFN expression in dendritic cells. J. Immunol. 2014;193:2538–2545.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4134964</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25057006</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang J., Basagoudanavar S.H., Wang X., Hopewell E., Albrecht R., García-Sastre A., Balachandran S. Beg AA NF-kappa B RelA subunit is crucial for early IFN-beta expression and resistance to RNA virus replication. J. Immunol. 2010;185:1720–1729.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2910841</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20610653</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu S., Cai X., Wu J., Cong Q., Chen X., Li T., Du F., Ren J., Wu Y.T., Grishin N.V., Chen Z.J. Phosphorylation of innate immune adaptor proteins MAVS, STING, and TRIF induces IRF3 activation. Science. 2015;347</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang H., Zhuang Y., Hu H., Du X., Zhang C., Shi X., Wu H., Yang S. Silica-coated manganese oxide nanoparticles as a platform for targeted magnetic resonance and fluorescence imaging of cancer cells. Adv. Funct. Mater. 2010;20:1733–1741.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lei M., Fu C., Cheng X., Fu B., Wu N., Zhang Q., Fu A., Cheng J., Gao J., Zhao Z. Activated surface charge-reversal manganese oxide nanocubes with high surface-to-volume ratio for accurate magnetic resonance tumor imaging. Adv. Funct. Mater. 2017;27</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu L., He H., Luo Z., Zhou H., Liang R., Pan H., Ma Y., Cai L. In situ photocatalyzed oxygen generation with photosynthetic bacteria to enable robust immunogenic photodynamic therapy in triple-negative breast cancer. Adv. Funct. Mater. 2020;30</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li B., Hao G., Sun B., Gu Z., Xu Z.P. Engineering a therapy-induced “immunogenic cancer cell death” amplifier to boost Systemic Tumor Elimination. Adv. Funct. Mater. 2020;30</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fan M., Jia L., Pang M., Yang X., Yang Y., Kamel Elyzayati S., Liao Y., Wang H., Zhu Y., Wang Q. Injectable Adhesive hydrogel as photothermal-derived antigen reservoir for enhanced anti-tumor immunity. Adv. Funct. Mater. 2021;31</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jhunjhunwala S., Hammer C., Delamarre L. Antigen presentation in cancer: insights into tumour immunogenicity and immune evasion. Nat. Rev. Cancer. 2021;21:298–312.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33750922</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Noy R., Pollard J.W. Tumor-associated macrophages: from mechanisms to therapy. Immunity. 2014;41:49–61.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4137410</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25035953</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fu L.Q., Du W.L., Cai M.H., Yao J.Y., Zhao Y.Y. Mou XZ the roles of tumor-associated macrophages in tumor angiogenesis and metastasis. Cell. Immunol. 2020;353</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kwon J., Bakhoum S.F. The Cytosolic DNA-Sensing cGAS-STING Pathway in Cancer. Cancer Discov. 2020;10:26–39.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7151642</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31852718</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
