<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35529481</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>10</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">2167-8359</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>10</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>PeerJ</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>PeerJ</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Climate change influences on the geographic distributional potential of the spotted fever vectors <i>Amblyomma maculatum</i> and <i>Dermacentor andersoni</i>.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e13279</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e13279</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e13279</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7717/peerj.13279</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText><i>Amblyomma maculatum</i> (Gulf Coast tick), and <i>Dermacentor andersoni</i> (Rocky Mountain wood tick) are two North American ticks that transmit spotted fevers associated <i>Rickettsia</i>. <i>Amblyomma maculatum</i> transmits <i>Rickettsia parkeri</i> and <i>Francisella tularensis</i>, while <i>D. andersoni</i> transmits <i>R. rickettsii</i>, <i>Anaplasma marginale</i>, <i>Coltivirus</i> (Colorado tick fever virus), and <i>F. tularensis</i>. Increases in temperature causes mild winters and more extreme dry periods during summers, which will affect tick populations in unknown ways. Here, we used ecological niche modeling (ENM) to assess the potential geographic distributions of these two medically important vector species in North America under current condition and then transfer those models to the future under different future climate scenarios with special interest in highlighting new potential expansion areas. Current model predictions for <i>A. maculatum</i> showed suitable areas across the southern and Midwest United States, and east coast, western and southern Mexico. For <i>D. andersoni</i>, our models showed broad suitable areas across northwestern United States. New potential for range expansions was anticipated for both tick species northward in response to climate change, extending across the Midwest and New England for <i>A. maculatum</i>, and still farther north into Canada for <i>D. andersoni</i>.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>©2022 Alkishe and Peterson.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Alkishe</LastName>
            <ForeName>Abdelghafar</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Biodiversity Institute, University of Kansas, Lawrence, KS, United States of America.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Zoology Department, Faculty of Science, Univeristy of Tripoli, Tripoli, Libya.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Peterson</LastName>
            <ForeName>A Townsend</ForeName>
            <Initials>AT</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Biodiversity Institute, University of Kansas, Lawrence, KS, United States of America.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>03</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>PeerJ</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101603425</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2167-8359</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Climate change</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ecological niche modeling</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">GCMs</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gulf Coast tick</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">North America</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">RCPs</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rocky Mountain wood tick</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors declare there are no competing interests.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
          <Hour>4</Hour>
          <Minute>10</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35529481</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9074859</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.13279</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">13279</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aiello-Lammens ME, Boria RA, Radosavljevic A, Vilela B, Anderson RP. spThin: an R package for spatial thinning of species occurrence records for use in ecological niche models. Ecography. 2015;38:541–545. doi: 10.1111/ecog.01132.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ecog.01132</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alkishe A, Raghavan RK, Peterson AT. Likely geographic distributional shifts among medically important tick species and tick-associated diseases under climate change in north America: a review. Insects. 2021;12:225. doi: 10.3390/insects12030225.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/insects12030225</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8001278</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33807736</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Anderson RP, Lew D, Peterson AT. Evaluating predictive models of species’ distributions: criteria for selecting optimal models. Ecological Modelling. 2003;162:211–232. doi: 10.1016/S0304-3800(02)00349-6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0304-3800(02)00349-6</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Animal Diversity Web (ADW)  Dermacentor andersoni Rocky Mountain wood tick. Animal Diversity Web. https://animaldiversity.org/accounts/Dermacentor_andersoni/#geographic_range.  [13 September 2021];2021 </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barve N, Barve V, Jiménez-Valverde A, Lira-Noriega A, Maher SP, Peterson AT, Soberón J, Villalobos F. The crucial role of the accessible area in ecological niche modeling and species distribution modeling. Ecological Modelling. 2011;222:1810–1819. doi: 10.1016/j.ecolmodel.2011.02.011.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecolmodel.2011.02.011</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boorgula GD, Peterson AT, Foley DH, Ganta RR, Raghavan RK. Assessing the current and future potential geographic distribution of the American dog tick, Dermacentor variabilis (Say) (Acari: Ixodidae) in North America. PLOS ONE. 2020;15:e0237191.  doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0237191.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0237191</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7416948</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32776959</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>CDC  Rocky Mountain spotted fever (RMSF). Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. https://www.cdc.gov/rmsf/transmission/index.html.  [13 September 2021];2018 </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>CDC  Other spotted fever group rickettsioses. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. https://www.cdc.gov/otherspottedfever/index.html.  [13 September 2021];2019 </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>CDC  Tickborne disease surveillance data summary. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. https://www.cdc.gov/ticks/data-summary/index.html.  [20 September 2021];2021 </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cobos ME, Peterson AT, Barve N, Osorio-Olvera L. KUENM: an R package for detailed development of ecological niche models using Maxent. PeerJ. 2019;7:e6281.  doi: 10.7717/peerj.6281.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.6281</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6368831</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30755826</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cuervo PF, Flores FS, Venzal JM, Nava S. Niche divergence among closely related taxa provides insight on evolutionary patterns of ticks. Journal of Biogeography. 2021;48(11):2865–2876. doi: 10.1111/jbi.14245.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jbi.14245</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cumbie AN, Espada CD, Nadolny RM, Rose RK, Dueser RD, Hynes WL, Gaff HD. Survey of Rickettsia parkeri and Amblyomma maculatum associated with small mammals in southeastern Virginia. Ticks and Tick-Borne Diseases. 2020;11:101550. doi: 10.1016/j.ttbdis.2020.101550.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ttbdis.2020.101550</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7534852</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32993923</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dantas-Torres F, Chomel BB, Otranto D. Ticks and tick-borne diseases: A One Health perspective. Trends in Parasitology. 2012;28:437–446. doi: 10.1016/j.pt.2012.07.003.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pt.2012.07.003</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22902521</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Djalante R. Key assessments from the IPCC special report on global warming of 1.5 °C and the implications for the Sendai Framework for disaster risk reduction. Progress in Disaster Science. 2019;1:100001. doi: 10.1016/j.pdisas.2019.100001.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pdisas.2019.100001</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Escobar LE. Ecological niche modeling: an introduction for veterinarians and epidemiologists. Frontiers in Veterinary Science. 2020;7:713. doi: 10.3389/fvets.2020.519059.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fvets.2020.519059</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Florin DA, Brinkerhoff RJ, Gaff H, Jiang J, Robbins RG, Eickmeyer W, Butler J, Nielsen D, Wright C, White A. Additional US collections of the Gulf Coast tick, Amblyomma maculatum (Acari: Ixodidae), from the state of Delaware, the first reported field collections of adult specimens from the state of Maryland, and data regarding this tick from surveillance of migratory songbirds in Maryland. Systematic and Applied Acarology. 2014;19:257–262. doi: 10.11158/saa.19.3.1.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11158/saa.19.3.1</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hijmans RJ, Cameron SE, Parra JL, Jones PG, Jarvis A. Very high resolution interpolated climate surfaces for global land areas. International Journal of Climatology. 2005;25:1965–1978. doi: 10.1002/joc.1276.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/joc.1276</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jolley T. Disease-carrying coastal tick established in Illinois. https://blogs.illinois.edu/view/7447/807086.  [14 September 2021];2020 </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Molaei G, Little EA, Khalil N, Ayres BN, Nicholson WL, Paddock CD. Established population of the Gulf Coast tick, Amblyomma maculatum (Acari: Ixodidae), infected with Rickettsia parkeri (Rickettsiales: Rickettsiaceae), in Connecticut. Journal of Medical Entomology. 2021;58:1459–1462. doi: 10.1093/jme/tjaa299.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jme/tjaa299</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33458776</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nadolny RM, Gaff HD. Natural history of Amblyomma maculatum in Virginia. Ticks and Tick-Borne Diseases. 2018;9:188–195. doi: 10.1016/j.ttbdis.2017.09.003.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ttbdis.2017.09.003</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5803413</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28958704</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Owens HL, Campbell LP, Dornak LL, Saupe EE, Barve N, Soberón J, Ingenloff K, Lira-Noriega A, Hensz CM, Myers CE. Constraints on interpretation of ecological niche models by limited environmental ranges on calibration areas. Ecological Modelling. 2013;263:10–18. doi: 10.1016/j.ecolmodel.2013.04.011.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecolmodel.2013.04.011</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peterson AT.  Mapping disease transmission risk: enriching models using biogeography and ecology. Johns Hopkins University Press; Baltimore: 2014. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peterson AT, Cobos ME, Jiménez-García D. Major challenges for correlational ecological niche model projections to future climate conditions. Annals of the New York Academy of Sciences. 2018;1429:66–77. doi: 10.1111/nyas.13873.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/nyas.13873</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29923606</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peterson AT, Papeş M, Soberón J. Rethinking receiver operating characteristic analysis applications in ecological niche modeling. Ecological Modelling. 2008;213:63–72. doi: 10.1016/j.ecolmodel.2007.11.008.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecolmodel.2007.11.008</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Phillips SJ, Anderson RP, Dudík M, Schapire RE, Blair ME. Opening the black box: an open-source release of Maxent. Ecography. 2017;40:887–893. doi: 10.1111/ecog.03049.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ecog.03049</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>R Core Team  . Vienna: R Foundation for Statistical Computing; 2018. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rocklöv J, Dubrow R. Climate change: an enduring challenge for vector-borne disease prevention and control. Nature Immunology. 2020;21:479–483. doi: 10.1038/s41590-020-0648-y.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41590-020-0648-y</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7223823</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32313242</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sonenshine DE. Range expansion of tick disease vectors in North America: implications for spread of tick-borne disease. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health. 2018;15:478. doi: 10.3390/ijerph15030478.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph15030478</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Teel P, Ketchum H, Mock D, Wright R, Strey O. The Gulf Coast tick: a review of the life history, ecology, distribution, and emergence as an arthropod of medical and veterinary importance. Journal of Medical Entomology. 2010;47:707–722. doi: 10.1093/jmedent/47.5.707.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jmedent/47.5.707</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20939363</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Warren DL, Seifert SN. Ecological niche modeling in Maxent: the importance of model complexity and the performance of model selection criteria. Ecological Applications. 2011;21:335–342. doi: 10.1890/10-1171.1.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1890/10-1171.1</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21563566</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wilkinson P. The distribution of Dermacentor ticks in Canada in relation to bioclimatic zones. Canadian Journal of Zoology. 1967;45:517–537. doi: 10.1139/z67-066.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/z67-066</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6070627</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wuebbles DJ, Fahey DW, Hibbard KA, Arnold JR, De Angelo B, Doherty S, Easterling DR, Edmonds J, Edmonds T, Hall T. Washington, D.C.: U.S. Global Change ResearchClimate science special report: fourth national climate assessment (NCA4), Volume I. 2017:470 pp. doi: 10.7930/J0J964J6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7930/J0J964J6</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35529481</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>10</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">2167-8359</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>10</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>PeerJ</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>PeerJ</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Climate change influences on the geographic distributional potential of the spotted fever vectors <i>Amblyomma maculatum</i> and <i>Dermacentor andersoni</i>.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e13279</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e13279</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e13279</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7717/peerj.13279</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText><i>Amblyomma maculatum</i> (Gulf Coast tick), and <i>Dermacentor andersoni</i> (Rocky Mountain wood tick) are two North American ticks that transmit spotted fevers associated <i>Rickettsia</i>. <i>Amblyomma maculatum</i> transmits <i>Rickettsia parkeri</i> and <i>Francisella tularensis</i>, while <i>D. andersoni</i> transmits <i>R. rickettsii</i>, <i>Anaplasma marginale</i>, <i>Coltivirus</i> (Colorado tick fever virus), and <i>F. tularensis</i>. Increases in temperature causes mild winters and more extreme dry periods during summers, which will affect tick populations in unknown ways. Here, we used ecological niche modeling (ENM) to assess the potential geographic distributions of these two medically important vector species in North America under current condition and then transfer those models to the future under different future climate scenarios with special interest in highlighting new potential expansion areas. Current model predictions for <i>A. maculatum</i> showed suitable areas across the southern and Midwest United States, and east coast, western and southern Mexico. For <i>D. andersoni</i>, our models showed broad suitable areas across northwestern United States. New potential for range expansions was anticipated for both tick species northward in response to climate change, extending across the Midwest and New England for <i>A. maculatum</i>, and still farther north into Canada for <i>D. andersoni</i>.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>©2022 Alkishe and Peterson.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Alkishe</LastName>
            <ForeName>Abdelghafar</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Biodiversity Institute, University of Kansas, Lawrence, KS, United States of America.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Zoology Department, Faculty of Science, Univeristy of Tripoli, Tripoli, Libya.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Peterson</LastName>
            <ForeName>A Townsend</ForeName>
            <Initials>AT</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Biodiversity Institute, University of Kansas, Lawrence, KS, United States of America.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>03</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>PeerJ</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101603425</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2167-8359</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Climate change</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ecological niche modeling</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">GCMs</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gulf Coast tick</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">North America</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">RCPs</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rocky Mountain wood tick</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors declare there are no competing interests.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
          <Hour>4</Hour>
          <Minute>10</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35529481</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9074859</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.13279</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">13279</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aiello-Lammens ME, Boria RA, Radosavljevic A, Vilela B, Anderson RP. spThin: an R package for spatial thinning of species occurrence records for use in ecological niche models. Ecography. 2015;38:541–545. doi: 10.1111/ecog.01132.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ecog.01132</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alkishe A, Raghavan RK, Peterson AT. Likely geographic distributional shifts among medically important tick species and tick-associated diseases under climate change in north America: a review. Insects. 2021;12:225. doi: 10.3390/insects12030225.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/insects12030225</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8001278</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33807736</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Anderson RP, Lew D, Peterson AT. Evaluating predictive models of species’ distributions: criteria for selecting optimal models. Ecological Modelling. 2003;162:211–232. doi: 10.1016/S0304-3800(02)00349-6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0304-3800(02)00349-6</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Animal Diversity Web (ADW)  Dermacentor andersoni Rocky Mountain wood tick. Animal Diversity Web. https://animaldiversity.org/accounts/Dermacentor_andersoni/#geographic_range.  [13 September 2021];2021 </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barve N, Barve V, Jiménez-Valverde A, Lira-Noriega A, Maher SP, Peterson AT, Soberón J, Villalobos F. The crucial role of the accessible area in ecological niche modeling and species distribution modeling. Ecological Modelling. 2011;222:1810–1819. doi: 10.1016/j.ecolmodel.2011.02.011.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecolmodel.2011.02.011</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boorgula GD, Peterson AT, Foley DH, Ganta RR, Raghavan RK. Assessing the current and future potential geographic distribution of the American dog tick, Dermacentor variabilis (Say) (Acari: Ixodidae) in North America. PLOS ONE. 2020;15:e0237191.  doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0237191.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0237191</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7416948</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32776959</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>CDC  Rocky Mountain spotted fever (RMSF). Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. https://www.cdc.gov/rmsf/transmission/index.html.  [13 September 2021];2018 </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>CDC  Other spotted fever group rickettsioses. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. https://www.cdc.gov/otherspottedfever/index.html.  [13 September 2021];2019 </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>CDC  Tickborne disease surveillance data summary. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. https://www.cdc.gov/ticks/data-summary/index.html.  [20 September 2021];2021 </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cobos ME, Peterson AT, Barve N, Osorio-Olvera L. KUENM: an R package for detailed development of ecological niche models using Maxent. PeerJ. 2019;7:e6281.  doi: 10.7717/peerj.6281.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7717/peerj.6281</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6368831</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30755826</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cuervo PF, Flores FS, Venzal JM, Nava S. Niche divergence among closely related taxa provides insight on evolutionary patterns of ticks. Journal of Biogeography. 2021;48(11):2865–2876. doi: 10.1111/jbi.14245.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jbi.14245</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cumbie AN, Espada CD, Nadolny RM, Rose RK, Dueser RD, Hynes WL, Gaff HD. Survey of Rickettsia parkeri and Amblyomma maculatum associated with small mammals in southeastern Virginia. Ticks and Tick-Borne Diseases. 2020;11:101550. doi: 10.1016/j.ttbdis.2020.101550.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ttbdis.2020.101550</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7534852</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32993923</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dantas-Torres F, Chomel BB, Otranto D. Ticks and tick-borne diseases: A One Health perspective. Trends in Parasitology. 2012;28:437–446. doi: 10.1016/j.pt.2012.07.003.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pt.2012.07.003</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22902521</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Djalante R. Key assessments from the IPCC special report on global warming of 1.5 °C and the implications for the Sendai Framework for disaster risk reduction. Progress in Disaster Science. 2019;1:100001. doi: 10.1016/j.pdisas.2019.100001.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pdisas.2019.100001</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Escobar LE. Ecological niche modeling: an introduction for veterinarians and epidemiologists. Frontiers in Veterinary Science. 2020;7:713. doi: 10.3389/fvets.2020.519059.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fvets.2020.519059</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Florin DA, Brinkerhoff RJ, Gaff H, Jiang J, Robbins RG, Eickmeyer W, Butler J, Nielsen D, Wright C, White A. Additional US collections of the Gulf Coast tick, Amblyomma maculatum (Acari: Ixodidae), from the state of Delaware, the first reported field collections of adult specimens from the state of Maryland, and data regarding this tick from surveillance of migratory songbirds in Maryland. Systematic and Applied Acarology. 2014;19:257–262. doi: 10.11158/saa.19.3.1.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11158/saa.19.3.1</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hijmans RJ, Cameron SE, Parra JL, Jones PG, Jarvis A. Very high resolution interpolated climate surfaces for global land areas. International Journal of Climatology. 2005;25:1965–1978. doi: 10.1002/joc.1276.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/joc.1276</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jolley T. Disease-carrying coastal tick established in Illinois. https://blogs.illinois.edu/view/7447/807086.  [14 September 2021];2020 </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Molaei G, Little EA, Khalil N, Ayres BN, Nicholson WL, Paddock CD. Established population of the Gulf Coast tick, Amblyomma maculatum (Acari: Ixodidae), infected with Rickettsia parkeri (Rickettsiales: Rickettsiaceae), in Connecticut. Journal of Medical Entomology. 2021;58:1459–1462. doi: 10.1093/jme/tjaa299.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jme/tjaa299</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33458776</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nadolny RM, Gaff HD. Natural history of Amblyomma maculatum in Virginia. Ticks and Tick-Borne Diseases. 2018;9:188–195. doi: 10.1016/j.ttbdis.2017.09.003.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ttbdis.2017.09.003</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5803413</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28958704</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Owens HL, Campbell LP, Dornak LL, Saupe EE, Barve N, Soberón J, Ingenloff K, Lira-Noriega A, Hensz CM, Myers CE. Constraints on interpretation of ecological niche models by limited environmental ranges on calibration areas. Ecological Modelling. 2013;263:10–18. doi: 10.1016/j.ecolmodel.2013.04.011.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecolmodel.2013.04.011</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peterson AT.  Mapping disease transmission risk: enriching models using biogeography and ecology. Johns Hopkins University Press; Baltimore: 2014. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peterson AT, Cobos ME, Jiménez-García D. Major challenges for correlational ecological niche model projections to future climate conditions. Annals of the New York Academy of Sciences. 2018;1429:66–77. doi: 10.1111/nyas.13873.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/nyas.13873</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29923606</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peterson AT, Papeş M, Soberón J. Rethinking receiver operating characteristic analysis applications in ecological niche modeling. Ecological Modelling. 2008;213:63–72. doi: 10.1016/j.ecolmodel.2007.11.008.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ecolmodel.2007.11.008</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Phillips SJ, Anderson RP, Dudík M, Schapire RE, Blair ME. Opening the black box: an open-source release of Maxent. Ecography. 2017;40:887–893. doi: 10.1111/ecog.03049.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ecog.03049</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>R Core Team  . Vienna: R Foundation for Statistical Computing; 2018. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rocklöv J, Dubrow R. Climate change: an enduring challenge for vector-borne disease prevention and control. Nature Immunology. 2020;21:479–483. doi: 10.1038/s41590-020-0648-y.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41590-020-0648-y</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7223823</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32313242</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sonenshine DE. Range expansion of tick disease vectors in North America: implications for spread of tick-borne disease. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health. 2018;15:478. doi: 10.3390/ijerph15030478.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph15030478</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Teel P, Ketchum H, Mock D, Wright R, Strey O. The Gulf Coast tick: a review of the life history, ecology, distribution, and emergence as an arthropod of medical and veterinary importance. Journal of Medical Entomology. 2010;47:707–722. doi: 10.1093/jmedent/47.5.707.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jmedent/47.5.707</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20939363</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Warren DL, Seifert SN. Ecological niche modeling in Maxent: the importance of model complexity and the performance of model selection criteria. Ecological Applications. 2011;21:335–342. doi: 10.1890/10-1171.1.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1890/10-1171.1</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21563566</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wilkinson P. The distribution of Dermacentor ticks in Canada in relation to bioclimatic zones. Canadian Journal of Zoology. 1967;45:517–537. doi: 10.1139/z67-066.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1139/z67-066</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6070627</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wuebbles DJ, Fahey DW, Hibbard KA, Arnold JR, De Angelo B, Doherty S, Easterling DR, Edmonds J, Edmonds T, Hall T. Washington, D.C.: U.S. Global Change ResearchClimate science special report: fourth national climate assessment (NCA4), Volume I. 2017:470 pp. doi: 10.7930/J0J964J6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7930/J0J964J6</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
