<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35527789</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>18</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">0264-9993</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>113</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Aug</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Economic modelling</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Econ Model</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>COVID-19 regulations, culture, and the environment.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>105874</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>105874</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.econmod.2022.105874</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The economic and social disruptions caused by the COVID-19 pandemic are immense. Unexpectedly, a positive outcome of the stringent Covid restrictions has come in the form of air pollution reduction. Pollution reduction, however, has not happened everywhere at equal rates. Why are lockdown measures not producing this positive externality in all countries? Using satellite-based Aerosol Optical Depth data and panel analysis conducted at the country-day level, we find that the countries that have adopted stringent COVID-19 containment policies have experienced better air quality. Nonetheless, this relationship depends on the cultural orientation of a society. Our estimates indicate that the effect of policy stringency is lower in societies imbued with a collectivistic culture. The findings highlight the role of cultural differences in the successful implementation of policies and the realization of their intended outcomes. It implies that pollution mitigation policies are less likely to yield emission reduction in collectivist societies.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mohanty</LastName>
            <ForeName>Aatishya</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Economics, School of Social Sciences, Nanyang Technological University, 48 Nanyang Avenue, 639818, Singapore.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sharma</LastName>
            <ForeName>Swati</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Economics, School of Social Sciences, Nanyang Technological University, 48 Nanyang Avenue, 639818, Singapore.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>04</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Econ Model</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101085827</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0264-9993</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Culture</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Environment</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Government policy</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Individualism</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pollution</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
          <Hour>3</Hour>
          <Minute>47</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35527789</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9065757</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.econmod.2022.105874</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">S0264-9993(22)00120-1</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Anderson T.W., Rubin H. Estimation of the parameters of a single equation in a complete system of stochastic equations. Ann. Math. Stat. 1949:46–63.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ang J.B. Agricultural legacy and individualistic culture. J. Econ. Growth. 2019;24:397–425.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ang J.B., Fredriksson P.G., Sharma S. Individualism and the adoption of clean energy technology. Resour. Energy Econ. 2020;61</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ang J.B., Madsen J.B., Wang W. Rice farming, culture and democracy. Eur. Econ. Rev. 2021;136</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bavel J.J.V., Baicker K., Boggio P.S., Capraro V., Cichocka A., Cikara M., Crockett M.J., Crum A.J., Douglas K.M., Druckman J.N., Drury J., Dube O., Ellemers N., Finkel E.J., Fowler J.H., Gelfand M., Han S., Haslam S.A., Jetten J., Kitayama S., Mobbs D., Napper L.E., Packer D.J., Pennycook G., Peters E., Petty R.E., Rand D.G., Reicher S.D., Schnall S., Shariff A., Skitka L.J., Smith S.S., Sunstein C.R., Tabri N., Tucker J.A., Linden S.v.d., Lange P.v., Weeden K.A., Wohl M.J.A., Zaki J., Zion S.R., Willer R. Using social and behavioural science to support COVID-19 pandemic response. Nat. Human Behav. 2020;4:460–471.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32355299</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beugelsdijk S., De Groot H.L., Van Schaik A.B. Trust and economic growth: a robustness analysis. Oxf. Econ. Pap. 2004;56:118–134.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brewer M.B., Chen Y.-R. Where (who) are collectives in collectivism? Toward conceptual clarification of individualism and collectivism. Psychol. Rev. 2007;114:133–151.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17227184</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen K., Wang M., Huang C., Kinney P.L., Anastas P.T. Air pollution reduction and mortality benefit during the COVID-19 outbreak in China. Lancet Planet. Health. 2020;4:210–212.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cho Y.-N., Thyroff A., Rapert M.I., Park S.-Y., Lee H.J. To Be or not to Be green: exploring individualism and collectivism as antecedents of environmental behavior. J. Bus. Res. 2013;66:1052–1059.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chu D.A. Analysis of the relationship between MODIS aerosol optical depth and PM2. 5 in the summertime US. Rem. Sens. Aero. Chem. Gases Mod. Simulat./Assimilat. Appl. Air Qual. 2006;6299</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chu D.A., Kaufman Y., Zibordi G., Chern J., Mao J., Li C., Holben B. Global monitoring of air pollution over land from the earth observing system-terra moderate resolution imaging spectroradiometer (MODIS) J. Geophys. Res. Atmos. 2003;108</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cragg J.G., Donald S.G.  Econometric Theory; 1993. Testing Identifiability and Specification in Instrumental Variable Models; pp. 222–240.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dasgupta S., De Cian E. The influence of institutions, governance, and public opinion on the environment: synthesized findings from applied econometrics studies. Energy Res. Social Sci. 2018;43:77–95.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Deng J., Walker G.J., Swinnerton G. A comparison of environmental values and attitudes between Chinese in Canada and anglo-Canadians. Environ. Behav. 2006;38:22–+47.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>DNV GL  . DNV GL AS.; Høvik, Norway: 2020. Energy Transition Outlook 2020.https://www.dnv.com/energy-transition/impact-of-covid19-on-the-energy-transition.html Accessed at:</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dutheil F., Baker J.S., Navel V. COVID-19 as a factor influencing air pollution? Environ. Pollut. 2020;263</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Engel-Cox J.A., Holloman C.H., Coutant B.W., Hoff R.M. Qualitative and quantitative evaluation of MODIS satellite sensor data for regional and urban scale Air quality. Atmos. Environ. 2004;38:2495–2509.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eom K., Kim H.S., Sherman D.K., Ishii K. Cultural variability in the link between environmental concern and support for environmental action. Psychol. Sci. 2016;27:1331–1339.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27565535</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>European Space Agency  . 2020. Air Pollution Remains Low as Europeans Stay at Home.https://www.esa.int/Applications/Observing_the_Earth/Copernicus/Sentinel-5P/Air_pollution_remains_low_as_Europeans_stay_at_home Retrieved on: 9 June 2020, Accessed at:</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gautam S. The influence of COVID-19 on air quality in India: a boon or inutile. Bull. Environ. Contam. Toxicol. 2020;104:724–726.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7212731</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32394052</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gelfand M.J., Bhawuk D.P.S., Nishii L.H., Bechtold D.J.  In: Culture, Leadership, and Organizations: the GLOBE Study of 62 Societies. House R.J., Hanges P.J., Javidan M., Dorfman P.W., Gupta V., editors. Thousand Oaks, CA Sage Publications; 2004. Individualism and collectivism; pp. 437–512.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Google  COVID-19 community mobility reports. 2020. https://www.google.com/covid19/mobility/ Accessed at:</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gorodnichenko Y., Roland G.  In: Institutions and Comparative Economic Development. Aoki M., Kuran T., Roland G., editors. Palgrave Macmillan UK); London: 2012. Understanding the individualism-collectivism cleavage and its effects: lessons from cultural psychology; pp. 213–236.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gorodnichenko Y., Roland G. Culture, institutions, and the wealth of nations. Rev. Econ. Stat. 2017;99:402–416.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guiso L., Sapienza P., Zingales L. Does culture affect economic outcomes? J. Econ. Perspect. 2006;20:23–48.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta P., Christopher S.A., Wang J., Gehrig R., Lee Y., Kumar N. Satellite remote sensing of particulate matter and air quality assessment over global cities. Atmos. Environ. 2006;40:5880–5892.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gutierrez E. Using satellite imagery to measure the relationship between air quality and infant mortality: an empirical study for Mexico. Popul. Environ. 2010;31:203–222.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hale T., Webster S., Petherick A., Phillips T., Kira B.  Blavatnik School of Government; 2020. Oxford COVID-19 Government Response Tracker.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Halkos G.E., Tzeremes N.G. National culture and eco-efficiency: an application of conditional partial nonparametric frontiers. Environ. Econ. Pol. Stud. 2013;15:423–441.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Helm D. The environmental impacts of the coronavirus. Environ. Resour. Econ. 2020;76:21–38.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hofstede G.  Sage Publications; Beverly Hills, CA: 1980. Culture's Consequences: International Differences in Work-Related Values.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hofstede G., Hofstede G.J., Minkov M.  third ed. McGraw-Hill USA; New York: 2010. Cultures and Organizations: Software of the Mind. Revised and Expanded.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hu Z. Spatial analysis of MODIS aerosol optical depth, PM 2.5, and chronic coronary heart disease. Int. J. Health Geogr. 2009;8:1–10.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2642778</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19149870</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hu Z., Rao K.R. Particulate air pollution and chronic ischemic heart disease in the eastern United States: a county level ecological study using satellite aerosol data. Environ. Health. 2009;8:26.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2707366</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19523211</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hutchison K.D. Applications of MODIS satellite data and products for monitoring air quality in the state of Texas. Atmos. Environ. 2003;37:2403–2412.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hutchison K.D., Smith S., Faruqui S.J. Correlating MODIS aerosol optical thickness data with ground-based PM2. 5 observations across Texas for use in a real-time air quality prediction system. Atmos. Environ. 2005;39:7190–7203.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>IEA  . IEA; Paris ’: 2021. Covid-19 Impact on Electricity.https://www.iea.org/reports/covid-19-impact-on-electricity</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>IPCC  . Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change; Geneva, Switzerland: 2013. Working Group I Contribution to the IPCC Fifth Assessment Report (AR5) Climate Change 2013: the Physical Science Basis.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kanniah K.D., Kamarul Zaman N.A.F., Kaskaoutis D.G., Latif M.T. COVID-19's impact on the atmospheric environment in the southeast Asia region. Sci. Total Environ. 2020;736</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kashima E.S., Kashima Y. Culture and language: the case of cultural dimensions and personal pronoun use. J. Cross Cult. Psychol. 1998;29:461–486.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaufmann D., Kraay A., Mastruzzi M.  The World Bank; 2010. The Worldwide Governance Indicators: Methodology and Analytical Issues. Policy Research Working Paper Series 5430.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khoshsima M., Ahmadi-Givi F., Bidokhti A., Sabetghadam S. Impact of meteorological parameters on relation between aerosol optical indices and air pollution in a sub-urban area. J. Aerosol Sci. 2014;68:46–57.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim Y., Choi S.M.  ACR North American Advances; 2005. Antecedents of Green Purchase Behavior: an Examination of Collectivism, Environmental Concern, and PCE.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kitayama S., Mesquita B., Karasawa M. Cultural affordances and emotional experience: socially engaging and disengaging emotions in Japan and the United States. J. Pers. Soc. Psychol. 2006;91:890–903.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17059308</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kong L., Xin J., Zhang W., Wang Y. The empirical correlations between PM2.5, PM10 and AOD in the beijing metropolitan region and the PM2.5, PM10 distributions retrieved by MODIS. Environ. Pollut. 2016;216:350–360.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27294786</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kumar N., Chu A., Foster A. An empirical relationship between PM2. 5 and aerosol optical depth in Delhi metropolitan. Atmos. Environ. 2007;41:4492–4503.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lewis D. Why many countries failed at COVID contact-tracing — but some got it right. Nature. 2020;588:384–387.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33318682</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li Z., Xia X., Cribb M., Mi W., Holben B., Wang P., Chen H., Tsay S.-C., Eck T.F., Zhao F., Dutton E.G., Dickerson R.E. Aerosol optical properties and their radiative effects in northern China. J. Geophys. Res. Atmos. 2007;112</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lyu W., Wehby G.L. Community use of face masks and COVID-19: evidence from A natural experiment of state mandates in the US. Health Aff. 2020;39:1419–1425.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McCarty J.A., Shrum L. The recycling of solid wastes: personal values, value orientations, and attitudes about recycling as antecedents of recycling behavior. J. Bus. Res. 1994;30:53–62.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McCarty J.A., Shrum L. The influence of individualism, collectivism, and locus of control on environmental beliefs and behavior. J. Publ. Pol. Market. 2001;20:93–104.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration  Global monitoring laboratory. SURFRAD aerosol optical depth. 2020. https://www.esrl.noaa.gov/gmd/grad/surfrad/aod/ Retrieved on: 6 Jun 2020, Accessed at:</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nunn N., Wantchekon L. The slave trade and the origins of mistrust in africa. Am. Econ. Rev. 2011;101:3221–3252.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Olofsson A., Ohman S. General beliefs and environmental concern: Transatlantic comparisons. Environ. Behav. 2006;38:768–790.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Platnick S., Hubanks P., Meyer K., King M.D. TERRA/MODIS atmosphere L3 monthly product (08_L3). NASA MODIS adaptive processing system, goddard space flight center, USA. 2015. https://giovanni.gsfc.nasa.gov Accessed at:</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rychlak J.F.  Oxford University Press; USA: 1979. Discovering Free Will and Personal Responsibility.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sharma S., Ang J.B., Fredriksson P.G. Religiosity and climate change policies. Energy Econ. 2021;101</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shi Y., Ho H.C., Xu Y., Ng E. Improving satellite aerosol optical depth-PM2.5 correlations using land use regression with microscale geographic predictors in a high-density urban context. Atmos. Environ. 2018;190:23–34.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Snibbe A.C., Markus H.R. You can't always get what you want: educational attainment, agency, and choice. J. Pers. Soc. Psychol. 2005;88:703–720.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15796669</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stock J.H., Wright J.H. GMM with weak identification. Econometrica. 2000;68:1055–1096.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stock J.H., Yogo M.  Identification and Inference for Econometric Models: Essays in Honor of Thomar Rothenberg. Cambridge University Press; Cambridge: 2005. Testing for weak instruments in linear IV regression; pp. 80–108.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Suh E., Diener E., Oishi S., Triandis H.C. The shifting basis of life satisfaction judgments across cultures: emotions versus norms. J. Pers. Soc. Psychol. 1998;71:482–493.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Talhelm T., Zhang X., Oishi S., Shimin C., Duan D., Lan X., Kitayama S. Large-scale psychological differences within China explained by rice versus wheat agriculture. Science. 2014;344:603–608.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24812395</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tang L., Koveos P.E. A framework to update hofstede's cultural value indices: economic dynamics and institutional stability. J. Int. Bus. Stud. 2008;39:1045–1063.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tanzi V.  1994. Corruption, Governmental Activities and Markets. IMF Working Paper 94/99.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tobías A., Carnerero C., Reche C., Massagué J., Via M., Minguillón M.C., Alastuey A., Querol X. Changes in air quality during the lockdown in Barcelona (Spain) one month into the SARS-CoV-2 epidemic. Sci. Total Environ. 2020;726</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Triandis H.C.  Westview Press; Boulder, Colorado: 1995. Individualism &amp; Collectivism.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Uz I. The index of cultural tightness and looseness among 68 countries. J. Cross Cult. Psychol. 2015;46:319–335.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vu T.V.  2020. Individualism and Climate Change Policies: International Evidence. Available at: SSRN 3547076.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wagner J.A., III Studies of individualism-collectivism: effects on cooperation in groups. Acad. Manag. J. 1995;38:152–173.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>WHO Occupational and Environmental Health Team  . World Health Organization; Geneva: 2000. Guidelines for Air Quality.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xiang P., Zhang H., Geng L., Zhou K., Wu Y. Individualist-collectivist differences in climate change inaction: the role of perceived intractability. Front. Psychol. 2019;10:187.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6379328</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30809166</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xue W., Hine D.W., Marks A.D.G., Phillips W.J., Zhao S. Cultural worldviews and climate change: a view from China. Asian J. Soc. Psychol. 2016;19:134–144.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhu J., Ang J.B., Fredriksson P.G. The agricultural roots of Chinese innovation performance. Eur. Econ. Rev. 2019;118:126–147.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
