<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35524981</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>24</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1745-6584</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>07</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Ground water</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Ground Water</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Incorporating Snowmelt into Daily Estimates of Recharge Using a State-Space Model of Infiltration.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/gwat.13206</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>A state-space model (SSM) of infiltration estimates daily groundwater recharge using time-series of groundwater-level altitude and meteorological inputs (liquid precipitation, snowmelt, and evapotranspiration). The model includes diffuse and preferential flow through the unsaturated zone, where preferential flow is a function of liquid precipitation and snowmelt rates and a threshold rate, above which there is direct recharge to the water table. Model parameters are estimated over seasonal periods and the SSM is coupled with the Kalman Filter (KF) to assimilate recent observations (hydraulic head) and meteorological inputs into recharge estimates. The approach can take advantage of real-time hydrologic and meteorological data to deliver real-time recharge estimates. The model is demonstrated on daily observations from two bedrock wells in carbonate aquifers of northwestern New York (USA) between 2013 and 2018. Meteorological inputs for liquid precipitation and snowmelt are compiled from SNODAS (2021). Results for recharge during winter and spring seasons show preferential flow events to the water table from liquid precipitation, snowmelt, or a combination of the two. Recharge estimates summed annually are consistent with previous estimates of recharge reported from groundwater flow and surface-process models. Results from the SSM and KF point to errors in meteorological inputs, such as the snowmelt rate, that are not compatible with hydraulic head observations. Whereas liquid and solid precipitation are measured at discrete stations and extrapolated to 1-km<sup>2</sup> grid cells, snowmelt is a meteorological modeled outcome that may not represent conditions in the vicinity of monitoring well locations.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 National Ground Water Association. This article has been contributed to by U.S. Government employees and their work is in the public domain in the USA.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Shapiro</LastName>
            <ForeName>Allen M</ForeName>
            <Initials>AM</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6425-9607</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>U.S. Geological Survey, Water Mission Area, Earth Systems Processes Division-Water Cycle Branch, 12201 Sunrise Valley Drive, Mail Stop 431, Reston, VA, 20192, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Day-Lewis</LastName>
            <ForeName>Frederick D</ForeName>
            <Initials>FD</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3526-886X</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Pacific Northwest National Laboratory, Earth Systems Science Division, 902 Battelle Boulevard, PO Box 902, MSIN K9-69, Richland, WA, 99352, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kappel</LastName>
            <ForeName>William M</ForeName>
            <Initials>WM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>U.S. Geological Survey, NY Water Science Center, 425 Jordan Road, Troy, NY, 12180, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Williams</LastName>
            <ForeName>John H</ForeName>
            <Initials>JH</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>U.S. Geological Survey, NY Water Science Center, 425 Jordan Road, Troy, NY, 12180, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>07</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Ground Water</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9882886</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0017-467X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
          <Hour>14</Hour>
          <Minute>42</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35524981</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/gwat.13206</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Allen, R. G., L. S. Pereira, D. Raes, and M. Smith. 1998. Crop evapotranspiration: Guidelines for computing crop water requirements. FAO Irrigation and Drainage Paper 56. Food and Agricultural Organization (FAO) of the United Nations. 300 p.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arnold, J.G., R. Srinivasan, R.S. Muttiah, and J.R. Williams. 1998. Large area hydrologic modeling and assessment Part I: Model Development. Journal of the American Water Resources Association 34, no. 1: 73-89. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1752-1688.1998.tb05961.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Athans, M. 1974. The importance of Kalman filtering methods for economic systems. In Annals of Economic and Social Measurement. Cambridge, MA: National Bureau of Economic Research. vol. 3, 1st ed., 49-64. S. V. Berg http://www.nber.org/chapters/c9994</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bales, R.C., N.P. Molotch, T.H. Painter, M.D. Dettinger, R. Rice, and J. Dozier. 2006. Mountain hydrology of the western United States. Water Resources Research 42, no. 8: W08432. https://doi.org/10.1029/2005WR004387</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barnett, T.P., J.C. Adam, and D.P. Lettenmaier. 2005. Potential impacts of a warming climate on water availability in snow-dominated regions. Nature 438, no. 7066: 303-309. https://doi.org/10.1038/nature04141</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barnhart, T.B., N.P. Molotch, B. Livneh, A.A. Harpold, J.F. Knowles, and D. Schneider. 2016. Snowmelt rate dictates streamflow. Geophysical Research Letters 43, no. 15: 8006-8016. https://doi.org/10.1002/2016GL069690</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Becker, M.W. 2006. Potential for satellite remote sensing of ground water. Groundwater 44, no. 2: 306-318. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1745-6584.2005.00123.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berendrecht, W.L., and F.C. van Geer. 2016. A dynamic factor modeling framework for analyzing multiple groundwater head series simultaneously. Journal of Hydrology 536 no: 50-60 https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022169416300622</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berendrecht, W.L., A.W. Heemink, F.C. van Geer, and J.C. Gehrels. 2006. A non-linear state space approach to model groundwater fluctuations. Advances in Water Resources 29, no. 7: 959-973 http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0309170805002113</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beria, H., J.R. Larsen, A. Michelon, N.C. Ceperley, and B. Schaefli. 2020. HydroMix v1.0: a new Bayesian mixing framework for attributing uncertain hydrological sources. Geoscientific Model Development 13, no. 5: 2433-2450 https://gmd.copernicus.org/articles/13/2433/2020/</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bidwell, V.J. 1998. State-space mixing cell model of unsteady solute transport in unsaturated soil. Environmental Modelling &amp; Software 14, no. 2: 161-169 http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S136481529800067X</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Box, G.E.P., G.M. Jenkins, G.C. Reinsel, and G.M. Ljung. 2016. Time Series Analysis: Forecasting and Control (Fifth Edition). Hoboken, NJ: John Wiley &amp; Sons 669 p.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brett, C. E., and C. A. Ver Straeten. 1994. Stratigraphy and facies relationships of the Eifelian Onondaga Limestone (Middle Devonian) in western and central New York State. In Field trip guidebook: New York State Geological Association Guidebook, no. 66, 66th Annual Meeting. Rochester, NY. ed., C. E. Brett and J. Scatterday, 221-321.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brett, C. E., D. H. Tepper, W. M. Goodman, S. T. LoDuca, and B.-Y. Eckert. 1995. Revised stratigraphy and correlations of the Niagaran provincial series (Medina, Clinton, and Lockport groups) in the type area of western New York. U.S. Geological Survey Bulletin 2086. 10.3133/b2086. http://pubs.er.usgs.gov/publication/b2086.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bulut, Y., D. Vines-Cavanaugh, and D. Bernal. 2011. Process and measurement noise estimation for Kalman Filtering. In Structural Dynamics, Vol. 3, Conference Proceedings of the Society for Experimental Mechanics Series, ed. T. Proulx, 375-386. New York: Springer. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-1-4419-9834-7_36</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clow, D.W., L. Nanus, K.L. Verdin, and J. Schmidt. 2012. Evaluation of SNODAS snow depth and snow water equivalent estimates for the Colorado Rocky Mountains, USA. Hydrological Processes 26, no. 17: 2583-2591. https://doi.org/10.1002/hyp.9385</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cook, P.G., and J.-K. Bohlke. 2000. Determining timescales for groundwater flow and solute transport. In Environmental Tracers in Subsurface Hydrology, ed. P.G. Cook, and A.L. Herczeg, 1-30. Boston: Kluwer Academic Publishers.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Czymmek, K., L. Geohring, J. Lendrum, P. Wright, G. Albrecht, B. Brower, and Q. Ketterings. 2011. Manure Management Guidelines for Limestone Bedrock/Karst Areas of Genesee County. New York: Practices for Risk Reduction. Cornell University Animal Science Publication Series No. 240 http://nmsp.cals.cornell.edu/publications/files/Karst_2_15_2011.pdf.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Delin, G.N., R.W. Healy, D.L. Lorenz, and J.R. Nimmo. 2007. Comparison of local- to regional-scale estimates of ground-water recharge in Minnesota, USA. Journal of Hydrology 334, no. 1: 231-249 http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022169406005427</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dripps, W.R., and K.R. Bradbury. 2007. A simple daily soil-water balance model for estimating the spatial and temporal distribution of groundwater recharge in temperate humid areas. Hydrogeology Journal 15, no. 3: 433-444. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10040-007-0160-6</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Durbin, J., and S.J. Koopman. 2012. Time Series Analysis by State Space Methods. Oxford, UK: Oxford University Press 346 p.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dyson, J.S., and R.E. White. 1987. A comparison of the convection-dispersion equation and transfer function model for predicting chloride leaching through an undisturbed, structured clay soil. Journal of Soil Science 38, no. 2: 157-172. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2389.1987.tb02133.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eguchi, S., and S. Hasegawa. 2008. Determination and characterization of preferential water flow in unsaturated subsoil of Andisol. Soil Science Society of America Journal 72, no. 2: 320-330. https://doi.org/10.2136/sssaj2007.0042</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eigbe, U., M.B. Beck, H.S. Wheater, and F. Hirano. 1998. Kalman filtering in groundwater flow modelling: problems and prospects. Stochastic Hydrology and Hydraulics 12, no. 1: 15-32. https://doi.org/10.1007/s004770050007</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Flint, A.L., L.E. Flint, and M.D. Dettinger. 2008. Modeling soil moisture processes and recharge under a melting snowpack. Vadose Zone Journal 7, no. 1: 350-357. https://doi.org/10.2136/vzj2006.0135</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Flury, M., H. Flühler, W.A. Jury, and J. Leuenberger. 1994. Susceptibility of soils to preferential flow of water: A field study. Water Resources Research 30, no. 7: 1945-1954. https://doi.org/10.1029/94WR00871</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Graham, C.B., and H.S. Lin. 2011. Controls and frequency of preferential flow occurrence: A 175-event analysis. Vadose Zone Journal 10, no. 3: 816-831. https://doi.org/10.2136/vzj2010.0119</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Green, E. 2018. Forecasting Changes to Groundwater and Surface Water Flow Regimes in Western New York Under a Changing Climate. Master of Science, Department of Geology University at Buffalo, State University of New York. 128 p. https://ubir.buffalo.edu/xmlui/bitstream/handle/10477/78665/Green_buffalo_0656M_16121.pdf?sequence=1&amp;isAllowed=y.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grewal, M.S., and A.P. Andrews. 2015. Kalman Filtering: Theory and Practice Using MATLAB. Hoboken, NJ: John Wiley and Sons 617 p.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hargreaves, G.L., H. Hargreaves George, and J.P. Riley. 1985. Agricultural benefits for Senegal river basin. Journal of Irrigation and Drainage Engineering 111, no. 2: 113-124. https://doi.org/10.1061/(ASCE)0733-9437(1985)111:2(113)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harvey, A.C. 1989. Forecasting, Structural Time Series Models and the Kalman Filter. United Kingdom: Cambridge University Press 554 p.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Healy, R.W. 2010. Estimating Groundwater Recharge. Cambridge, UK: Cambridge University Press 245 p.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Healy, R.W., and P.G. Cook. 2002. Using groundwater levels to estimate recharge. Hydrogeology Journal 10, no. 1: 91-109. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10040-001-0178-0</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hendricks Franssen, H.J., and W. Kinzelbach. 2008. Real-time groundwater flow modeling with the Ensemble Kalman filter: Joint estimation of states and parameters and the filter inbreeding problem. Water Resources Research 44, no. 9: W09408. https://doi.org/10.1029/2007WR006505</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heppner, C.S., J.R. NImmo, G.J. Folmar, W.J. Gburek, and D.W. Risser. 2007. Multiple-methods investigation of recharge at a humid-region fractured rock site, Pennsylvania, USA. Hydrogeology Journal 15, no. 5: 915-927.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hill, M.C., and C.R. Tiedeman. 2007. Effective Groundwater Model Calibration: With Analysis of Data, Sensitivities, Predictions, and Uncertainty. Hoboken, New Jersey: John Wiley &amp; Sons.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hofmeister, F., L.F. Arias-Rodriguez, V. Premier, C. Marin, C. Notarnicola, M. Disse, and G. Chiogna. 2022. Intercomparison of Sentinel-2 and modelled snow cover maps in a high-elevation Alpine catchment. Journal of Hydrology X 15: 100123 https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2589915522000050</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hrudey, S.E., P. Payment, P.M. Huck, R.W. Gillham, and E.J. Hrudey. 2003. A fatal waterborne disease epidemic in Walkerton, Ontario: comparison with other waterborne outbreaks in the developed world. Water Science and Technology 47, no. 3: 7-14. https://doi.org/10.2166/wst.2003.0146</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Husain, T. 1985. Kalman filter estimation model in flood forecasting. Advances in Water Resources 8, no. 1: 15-21 http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/0309170885900752</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jackson, T.J. 2002. Remote sensing of soil moisture: Implications for groundwater recharge. Hydrogeology Journal 10, no. 1: 40-51. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10040-001-0168-2</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Janjić, T., D. McLaughlin, S.E. Cohn, and M. Verlaan. 2014. Conservation of mass and preservation of positivity with ensemble-type Kalman filter algorithms. Monthly Weather Review 142, no. 2: 755-773 https://journals.ametsoc.org/view/journals/mwre/142/2/mwr-d-13-00056.1.xml</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnson, T. D., and K. Belitz. 2019. Domestic well locations and populations served in the contiguous U.S.: datasets for decadal years 2000 and 2010. U.S. Geological Survey data release https://doi.org/10.5066/P9FSLU3B.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnson, T.D., K. Belitz, and M.A. Lombard. 2019. Estimating domestic well locations and populations served in the contiguous U.S. for years 2000 and 2010. Science of The Total Environment 687: 1261-1273 https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0048969719325963</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jury, W.A., G. Sposito, and R.E. White. 1986. A transfer function model of solute transport through soil 1. Fundamental concepts. Water Resources Research 22, no. 2: 243-247.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kalman, R.E. 1960. A new approach to linear filtering and prediction problems. Transactions of the ASME - Journal of Basic Engineering 82: 35-45.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kappel, W. M., J. E. Reddy, and J. C. Root. 2020. Statewide assessment of karst aquifers in New York with an inventory of closed-depression and focused-recharge features. U.S. Geological Survey Scientific Investigations Report 2020-5030. 74 p. 10.3133/sir20205030. http://pubs.er.usgs.gov/publication/sir20205030.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kindle, E. M., and F. B. Taylor. 1913. Niagara folio, New York. U.S. Geological Survey. Folios of the Geologic Atlas 190. 10.3133/gf190. http://pubs.er.usgs.gov/publication/gf190.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kitanidis, P.K., and R.L. Bras. 1980. Adaptive filtering through detection of isolated transient errors in rainfall-runoff models. Water Resources Research 16, no. 4: 740-748. https://doi.org/10.1029/WR016i004p00740</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kung, K.J.S. 1990. Preferential flow in a sandy vadose zone: 2. Mechanism and implications. Geoderma 46, no. 1: 59-71 http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/001670619090007V</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lappala, E.G., R.W. Healy, and E.P. Weeks. 1987. Documentation of computer program VS2D to solve the equations of fluid flow in variably saturated porous media. U.S. Geological Survey Water-Resources Investigations Report 83-4099, 184 p. https://doi.org/10.3133/wri834099 http://pubs.er.usgs.gov/publication/wri834099</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lerner, D.N. 1997. Groundwater recharge. In Geochemical Processes, Weathering and Groundwater Recharge in Catchments, eds. O.M. Saither, P. de Caritat, and A.A. Balkema, pp. 109-150. Rotterdam: CRC Press. https://doi.org/10.1201/9781003077916</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lettenmaier, D.P., and S.J. Burges. 1976. Use of state estimation techniques in water resource system modeling. Journal of the American Water Resources Association 12, no. 1: 83-99. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1752-1688.1976.tb02640.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu, J., P.J.A. Kleinman, H. Aronsson, D. Flaten, R.W. McDowell, M. Bechmann, D.B. Beegle, T.P. Robinson, R.B. Bryant, H. Liu, A.N. Sharpley, and T.L. Veith. 2018. A review of regulations and guidelines related to winter manure application. Ambio 47, no. 6: 657-670. https://doi.org/10.1007/s13280-018-1012-4</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lv, Z., J.W. Pomeroy, and X. Fang. 2019. Evaluation of SNODAS snow water equivalent in western Canada and assimilation into a cold region hydrological model. Water Resources Research 55, no. 12: 11166-11187. https://doi.org/10.1029/2019WR025333</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Markstrom, S.L., R.S. Regan, L.E. Hay, R.J. Viger, R.M. Webb, R.A. Payn, and J.H. LaFontaine. 2015. PRMS-IV, the precipitation-runoff modeling system, version 4. U.S. Geological Survey Techniques and Methods 6-B7. 169 p. https://doi.org/10.3133/tm6B7 http://pubs.er.usgs.gov/publication/tm6B7</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mercer, J.W., and C.R. Faust. 1983. Final Report on Ground-Water Flow Modeling Study of the Love Canal Area, New York. Research Triangle Park, NC: U.S. Environmental Protection Agency, Environmental Monitoring Systems Laboratory, Office of Research and Development EPA-600/4-83-048. https://nepis.epa.gov/Exe/ZyPURL.cgi?Dockey=P100VXNR.txt</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miller, J. A. 1998. Principal aquifers [of the United States]. U.S. Geological Survey Bulletin. https://doi.org/10.3133/32583. http://pubs.er.usgs.gov/publication/32583.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miller, T.S., and W.M. Kappel. 1987. Effect of Niagara power project on ground-water flow in the upper part of the Lockport Dolomite, Niagara Falls area, New York. U.S. Geological Survey Water-Resources Investigations Report 86-4130, 31 p. https://doi.org/10.3133/wri864130. http://pubs.er.usgs.gov/publication/wri864130</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mohammed, A.A., B.L. Kurylyk, E.E. Cey, and M. Hayashi. 2018. Snowmelt infiltration and macropore flow in frozen soils: Overview, knowledge gaps, and a conceptual framework. Vadose Zone Journal 17, no. 1: 180084. https://doi.org/10.2136/vzj2018.04.0084</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muldoon, M.A., M.A. Borchardt, S.K. Spencer, R.J. Hunt, and D. Owens. 2018. Using enteric pathogens to assess sources of fecal contamination in the Silurian dolomite aquifer: Preliminary results. In Karst Groundwater Contamination and Public Health, ed. W.B. White, J.S. Herman, E.K. Herman, and M. Rutigliano, 209-213. Cham: Springer International Publishing. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-51070-5_23</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muller, E.H. 1977. Late glacial and early post glacial environments in western New York. Annals of the New York Academy of Sciences 288, no. 1: 223-233. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1749-6632.1977.tb33618.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Murphy, H.M., S. McGinnis, R. Blunt, J. Stokdyk, J. Wu, A. Cagle, D.M. Denno, S. Spencer, A. Firnstahl, and M.A. Borchardt. 2020. Septic systems and rainfall influence human fecal marker and indicator organism occurrence in private wells in southeastern Pennsylvania. Environmental Science &amp; Technology 54, no. 6: 3159-3168. https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.9b05405</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA). 2018. Daily grids and area averages of temperature and precipitation for the contiguous United States, 1951-Present (nClimGrid-d and nClimDiv-d): National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, National Centers for Environmental Information, Public Beta Release-1 October 2018. Accessed on Area averages for census tracts. http://www1.ncdc.noaa.gov/pub/data/daily-grids/ (accessed January 20, 2020).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>National Weather Service (NWS). 2020. WEATHER.GOV. https://www.weather.gov/ (accessed September 22, 2020).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Newman, J., and P. McGroarty. 2019. Farms, More Productive Than Ever, Are Poisoning Drinking Water in Rural America. The Wall Street Journal. Dow Jones &amp; Company. New York, NY. 223, no. 16. https://www.wsj.com/articles/farms-more-productive-than-ever-are-poisoning-drinking-water-in-rural-america-11547826031.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nimmo, J.R. 2005. Unsaturated zone flow processes. In Encyclopedia of Hydrological Sciences: Part 13-Groundwater, ed. M.G. Anderson, and J. Bear, 2299-2322. Chichester, UK: Wiley. https://doi.org/10.1002/0470848944.hsa161 https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1002/0470848944.hsa161</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nimmo, J.R. 2021. The processes of preferential flow in the unsaturated zone. Soil Science Society of America Journal 85, no. 1: 1-27. https://doi.org/10.1002/saj2.20143</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nimmo, J.R., C. Horowitz, and L. Mitchell. 2015. Discrete-storm water-table fluctuation method to estimate episodic recharge. Groundwater 53, no. 2: 282-292. https://doi.org/10.1111/gwat.12177</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Olcott, P. G. 1995. Ground Water Atlas of the United States: Segment 12, Connecticut, Maine, Massachusetts, New Hampshire, New York, Rhode Island, Vermont. U.S. Geological Survey Hydrologic Atlas 730M. M1-M28 p. https://doi.org/10.3133/ha730M. http://pubs.er.usgs.gov/publication/ha730M.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Owens, D.W., R.J. Hunt, A.D. Firnstahl, M.A. Muldoon, and M.A. Borchardt. 2019. Automated time series measurement of microbial concentrations in groundwater-derived water supplies. Groundwater 57, no. 2: 329-336. https://doi.org/10.1111/gwat.12822</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rauch, H.E., F. Tung, and C.T. Striebel. 1965. Maximum likelihood estimates of linear dynamic systems. AIAA Journal 3, no. 8: 1445-1450. https://doi.org/10.2514/3.3166</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roth, M., G. Hendeby, C. Fritsche, and F. Gustafsson. 2017. The Ensemble Kalman filter: a signal processing perspective. EURASIP Journal on Advances in Signal Processing 2017, no. 1: 56. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13634-017-0492-x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scanlon, B.R., R.W. Healy, and P.G. Cook. 2002. Choosing appropriate techniques for quantifying groundwater recharge. Hydrogeology Journal 10, no. 1: 18-39. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10040-001-0176-2</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schattan, P., G. Schwaizer, J. Schöber, and S. Achleitner. 2020. The complementary value of cosmic-ray neutron sensing and snow covered area products for snow hydrological modelling. Remote Sensing of Environment 239: 111603 https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0034425719306236</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schilling, O.S., Y.-J. Park, R. Therrien, and R.M. Nagare. 2019. Integrated surface and subsurface hydrological modeling with snowmelt and pore water freeze-thaw. Groundwater 57, no. 1: 63-74. https://doi.org/10.1111/gwat.12841</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shapiro, A. M. 2022. Algorithms for model parameter estimation and state estimation applied to a state-space model for one-dimensional vertical infiltration incorporating snowmelt rate as a system input. U.S. Geological Survey data release https://doi.org/10.5066/P9MRGR88.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shapiro, A.M., and F.D. Day-Lewis. 2021. Estimating and forecasting time-varying groundwater recharge in fractured rock: A state-space formulation with preferential and diffuse flow to the water table. Water Resources Research 57, no. 9: e2020WR029110. https://doi.org/10.1029/2020WR029110</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Simon, D. 2006. Optimal State Estimation: Kalman, H∞, and Nonlinear Approaches, 526. Hoboken, NJ: John Wiley and Sons.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Simon, D. 2010. Kalman filtering with state constraints: A survey of linear and nonlinear algorithms. IET Control Theory and Applications 4, no. 8: 1303-1318.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Snow Data Assimilation System (SNODAS). 2021. Snow Data Assimilation System (SNODAS) Data Products at NSIDC, Version 1. https://nsidc.org/data/g02158 (accessed March 29, 2021).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stephens, D.B., and R. Knowlton. 1986. Soil water movement and recharge through sand at a Semiarid site in New Mexico. Water Resources Research 22, no. 6: 881-889. https://doi.org/10.1029/WR022i006p00881</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thornton, J.M., T. Brauchli, G. Mariethoz, and P. Brunner. 2021. Efficient multi-objective calibration and uncertainty analysis of distributed snow simulations in rugged alpine terrain. Journal of Hydrology 598: 126241 https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0022169421002882</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Toccalino, P. L., and J. A. Hopple. 2010. Quality of Water from Public-Supply Wells in the United States, 1993-2007. Overview of Major Findings. U.S. Geological Survey Circular 1346. 10.3133/cir1346. http://pubs.er.usgs.gov/publication/cir1346.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Trost, J. J., J. L. Roth, S. M. Westenbroek, and H. W. Reeves. 2018. Simulation of potential groundwater recharge for the glacial aquifer system east of the Rocky Mountains, 1980-2011, using the Soil-Water-Balance Model. U.S. Geological Survey Scientific Investigations Report 2018-5080. 64 p. 10.3133/sir20185080. http://pubs.er.usgs.gov/publication/sir20185080.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>U.S. Geological Survey (USGS). 2020. USGS water data for the Nation: U.S. Geological Survey National Water Information System Database. 10.5066/F7P55KJN (accessed September 22, 2020).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Westenbroek, S. M., V. A. Kelson, W. R. Dripps, R. J. Hunt, and K. R. Bradbury. 2010. SWB-A modified Thornthwaite-Mather Soil-Water-Balance code for estimating groundwater recharge. U.S. Geological Survey Techniques and Methods 6-A31. 10.3133/tm6A31. http://pubs.er.usgs.gov/publication/tm6A31.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wolock, D. M. 2003. Estimated mean annual natural ground-water recharge in the conterminous United States. U.S. Geological Survey Open-File Report 2003-311. 10.3133/ofr03311. http://pubs.er.usgs.gov/publication/ofr03311.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yager, R. M. 1996. Simulated three-dimensional ground-water flow in the Lockport Group, a fractured-dolomite aquifer near Niagara Falls, New York. U.S. Geological Survey Water Supply Paper 2487. 42 p. https://pubs.er.usgs.gov/publication/wsp2487.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Young, P. 2003. Top-down and data-based mechanistic modelling of rainfall-flow dynamics at the catchment scale. Hydrological Processes 17, no. 11: 2195-2217. https://doi.org/10.1002/hyp.1328</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
