<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35526270</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>08</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2050-6414</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>08</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>United European gastroenterology journal</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>United European Gastroenterol J</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Unraveling the relationship between autoimmune pancreatitis type 2 and inflammatory bowel disease: Results from two centers and systematic review of the literature.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ueg2.12237</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The relationship between autoimmune pancreatitis (AIP) type 2 and inflammatory bowel disease (IBD) has been established and previously described within International Consensus Diagnostic Criteria. However, it is unknown if the presence of IBD changes the natural disease course of AIP type 2. Our aim was to investigate the association between AIP type 2 and IBD as well as to systematically summarize all the existing evidence in the literature.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Electronic medical record analysis was conducted in two centers (in Stockholm, Sweden, and Milan, Italy; records dated between January 2001 and June 2021). Additionally, we conducted a systematic review of the literature.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 35 patients (18 females, 51.4%) fulfilled the diagnostic criteria of AIP type 2 and were included in the study. A diagnosis of IBD was established in 29 patients (82.8%), ulcerative colitis in 17 (58.6%) and Crohn's disease in 11 (37.9%). Median follow-up was 54 months. AIP patients with IBD commonly presented with abdominal pain and/or acute pancreatitis at diagnosis, the latter was prevailing in concomitant and later IBD onset. These patients more frequently used steroids, but there were no differences in relapse rates. Concomitant onset of IBD was associated with the development of diabetes mellitus. There were no cases of colon or pancreatic malignancy during follow-up. In our systematic analysis, a total of 693 AIP type 2 patients were included from 24 single-center retrospective studies and 8 multicenter retrospective studies. A diagnosis of IBD was reported in 330 (47.8%) patients. Relapse rate was 20.0%.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Clinical and radiological remission of AIP type 2 was high, while the cumulative incidence of relapse is around 20%. Our results show that concomitance of IBD imposes no obvious risk of a different disease course for AIP type 2.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Authors. United European Gastroenterology Journal published by Wiley Periodicals LLC on behalf of United European Gastroenterology.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nikolic</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sara</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3751-2619</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medicine Huddinge, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, Clinic for Internal Medicine, University Medical Centre Maribor, Maribor, Slovenia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lanzillotta</LastName>
            <ForeName>Marco</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4522-2921</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Università Vita-Salute San Raffaele, IRCCS San Raffaele Scientific Institute, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Unit of Immunology, Rheumatology, Allergy and Rare Diseases (Unirar), IRCCS San Raffaele Scientific Institute, ss Milan, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Panic</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nikola</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5930-9884</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, University of Belgrade, Digestive Endoscopy Unit, University Clinic "Dr Dragisa Misovic", Belgrade, Serbia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Brismar</LastName>
            <ForeName>Torkel B</ForeName>
            <Initials>TB</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3409-1938</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Karolinska University Hospital, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Moro</LastName>
            <ForeName>Carlos Fernández</ForeName>
            <Initials>CF</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6863-5959</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Clinical Pathology and Cancer Diagnostics, Karolinska University Hospital, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Capurso</LastName>
            <ForeName>Gabriele</ForeName>
            <Initials>G</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0019-8753</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Pancreatic Surgery and Endosonography Division, Pancreas Translational and Clinical Research Center, IRCCS San Raffaele Scientific Institute, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Della Torre</LastName>
            <ForeName>Emanuel</ForeName>
            <Initials>E</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9192-4270</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Università Vita-Salute San Raffaele, IRCCS San Raffaele Scientific Institute, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Unit of Immunology, Rheumatology, Allergy and Rare Diseases (Unirar), IRCCS San Raffaele Scientific Institute, ss Milan, Milan, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Löhr</LastName>
            <ForeName>J-Matthias</ForeName>
            <Initials>JM</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7647-198X</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Upper Digestive Diseases, Karolinska University Hospital, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Clinical Science, Intervention, and Technology (CLINTEC), Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Vujasinovic</LastName>
            <ForeName>Miroslav</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6496-295X</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medicine Huddinge, Karolinska Institutet, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Upper Digestive Diseases, Karolinska University Hospital, Stockholm, Sweden.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>08</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>United European Gastroenterol J</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101606807</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2050-6406</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">autoimmune</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">inflammatory bowel disease</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pancreatitis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">systematic review</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
          <Hour>13</Hour>
          <Minute>53</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35526270</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ueg2.12237</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hart PA, Krishna SG, Okazaki K. Diagnosis and management of autoimmune pancreatitis. Curr Treat Options Gastroenterol. 2017;15(4):538-47. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11938-017-0147-x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Löhr JM, Beuers U, Vujasinovic M, Alvaro D, Frøkjaer JB, Buttgereit F, et al. European Guideline on IgG4-related digestive disease: UEG and SGF evidence-based recommendations. United Eur Gastroenterol. J. 2020;8(6):637-66. https://doi.org/10.1177/2050640620934911</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shimosegawa T, Chari ST, Frulloni L, Kamisawa T, Kawa S, Mino-Kenudson M, et al. International consensus diagnostic criteria for autoimmune pancreatitis: guidelines of the International Association of Pancreatology. Pancreas. 2011;40(3):352-8. https://doi.org/10.1097/mpa.0b013e3182142fd2</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Löhr JM, Vujasinovic M, Rosendahl J, Stone JH, Beuers U. IgG4-related diseases of the digestive tract. Nat Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2021;19(3):185-97. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41575-021-00529-y</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Pretis N, Frulloni L. Autoimmune pancreatitis type 2. Curr Opin Gastroenterol. 2020;36(5):417-20. https://doi.org/10.1097/mog.0000000000000655</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zen Y Type 2 autoimmune pancreatitis: consensus and controversies. Gut and Liver. 2021. https://doi.org/10.5009/gnl210241</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aziz I, Simrén M. The overlap between irritable bowel syndrome and organic gastrointestinal diseases. Lancet Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2021;6(2):139-48. https://doi.org/10.1016/s2468-1253(20)30212-0</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raine T, Bonovas S, Burisch J, Kucharzik T, Adamina M, Annese V, et al. ECCO guidelines on therapeutics in ulcerative colitis: medical treatment. J Crohn's Colitis. 2021;16(1):2-17. https://doi.org/10.1093/ecco-jcc/jjab178</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Torres J, Bonovas S, Doherty G, Kucharzik T, Gisbert JP, Raine T, et al. ECCO guidelines on therapeutics in Crohn's Disease: medical treatment. J Crohn's Colitis. 2020;14(1):4-22. https://doi.org/10.1093/ecco-jcc/jjz180</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lorenzo D, Vullierme MP, Rebours V. Antitumor necrosis factor therapy Is effective for autoimmune pancreatitis type 2. Am J Gastroenterol. 2020;115(7):1133-4. https://doi.org/10.14309/ajg.0000000000000668</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schneider A, Hirth M, Weiss C, Weidner P, Antoni C, Thomann A, et al. Prevalence of inflammatory bowel disease in alcoholic, non-alcoholic and autoimmune pancreatitis. Z Gastroenterologie. 2018;56(5):469-78.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Almeida P, Almeida C, Gompertz M, Berger Z. Association between autoimmune pancreatitis and ulcerative colitis: a report of 12 patients. Rev Esp Enferm Dig. 2020;112(9):682-7. https://doi.org/10.17235/reed.2020.6677/2019</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kawa S, Okazaki K, Notohara K, Watanabe M, Shimosegawa T. Autoimmune pancreatitis complicated with inflammatory bowel disease and comparative study of type 1 and type 2 autoimmune pancreatitis. J Gastroenterol. 2015;50(7):805-15. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00535-014-1012-5</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim JM, Hwang SW, Park SH, Song TJ, Kim MH, Lee HS, et al. Clinical course of ulcerative colitis patients who develop acute pancreatitis. World J Gastroenterol. 2017;23(19):3505-12. https://doi.org/10.3748/wjg.v23.i19.3505</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maaser C, Sturm A, Vavricka SR, Kucharzik T, Fiorino G, Annese V, et al. ECCO-ESGAR guideline for diagnostic assessment in IBD Part 1: initial diagnosis, monitoring of known IBD, detection of complications. J Crohn's Colitis. 2018;13(2):144-64K. https://doi.org/10.1093/ecco-jcc/jjy113</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Satsangi J, Silverberg MS, Vermeire S, Colombel JF. The Montreal classification of inflammatory bowel disease: controversies, consensus, and implications. Gut. 2006;55(6):749-53. https://doi.org/10.1136/gut.2005.082909</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liberati A, Altman DG, Tetzlaff J, Mulrow C, Gøtzsche PC, Ioannidis JP, et al. The PRISMA statement for reporting systematic reviews and meta-analyses of studies that evaluate healthcare interventions: explanation and elaboration. Br Med J. 2009;339(4):b2700. https://doi.org/10.7326/0003-4819-151-4-200908180-00136</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Notohara K, Burgart LJ, Yadav D, Chari S, Smyrk TC. Idiopathic chronic pancreatitis with periductal lymphoplasmacytic infiltration: clinicopathologic features of 35 cases. Am J Surg Pathol. 2003;27(8):1119-27. https://doi.org/10.1097/00000478-200308000-00009</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zamboni G, Lüttges J, Capelli P, Frulloni L, Cavallini G, Pederzoli P, et al. Histopathological features of diagnostic and clinical relevance in autoimmune pancreatitis: a study on 53 resection specimens and 9 biopsy specimens. Virchows Arch: An Int J Pathol. 2004;445(6):552-63. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00428-004-1140-z</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Park SH, Kim D, Ye BD, Yang SK, Kim JH, Yang DH, et al. The characteristics of ulcerative colitis associated with autoimmune pancreatitis. J Clin Gastroenterol. 2013;47(6):520-5. https://doi.org/10.1097/mcg.0b013e31827fd4a2</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lopez-Serrano A, Crespo J, Pascual I, Salord S, Bolado FD, Del-Pozo-Garcia AJ, et al. Diagnosis, treatment and long-term outcomes of autoimmune pancreatitis in Spain based on the International Consensus Diagnostic Criteria: a multi-centre study. Pancreatology: Off J Int Assoc Pancreatol. 2016;16(3):382-90. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pan.2016.02.006</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lorenzo D, Maire F, Stefanescu C, Gornet JM, Seksik P, Serrero M, et al. Features of autoimmune pancreatitis associated with inflammatory bowel diseases. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2018;16(1):59-67. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cgh.2017.07.033</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ueki T, Kawamoto K, Otsuka Y, Minoda R, Maruo T, Matsumura K, et al. Prevalence and clinicopathological features of autoimmune pancreatitis in Japanese patients with inflammatory bowel disease. Pancreas. 2015;44(3):434-40. https://doi.org/10.1097/mpa.0000000000000261</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hart PA, Levy MJ, Smyrk TC, Takahashi N, Abu Dayyeh BK, Clain JE, et al. Clinical profiles and outcomes in idiopathic duct-centric chronic pancreatitis (type 2 autoimmune pancreatitis): the Mayo Clinic experience. Gut. 2016;65(10):1702-9. https://doi.org/10.1136/gutjnl-2015-309275</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roque Ramos L, DiMaio CJ, Sachar DB, Atreja A, Colombel JF, Torres J. Autoimmune pancreatitis and inflammatory bowel disease: case series and review of the literature. Dig Liver Dis. 2016;48(8):893-8. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.dld.2016.05.008</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oh D, Song TJ, Moon SH, Kim DJH, Lee NJ, Hong SM, et al. Type 2 Autoimmune pancreatitis (idiopathic duct-centric pancreatitis) highlighting patients presenting as clinical acute pancreatitis: a single-center experience. Gut and Liver. 2019;13(4):461-70. https://doi.org/10.5009/gnl18429</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ku Y, Hong SM, Fujikura K, Kim SJ, Akita M, Abe-Suzuki S, et al. IL-8 expression in granulocytic epithelial lesions of idiopathic duct-centric pancreatitis (type 2 autoimmune pancreatitis). Am J Surg Pathol. 2017;41(8):1129-38. https://doi.org/10.1097/pas.0000000000000891</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rana SS, Gupta R, Nada R, Gupta P, Basher R, Mittal BR, et al. Clinical profile and treatment outcomes in autoimmune pancreatitis: a report from North India. Ann Gastroenterol. 2018;31(4):506-12.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pattabathula K, Waters PS, Hwang J, Bettington M, Singh M, Bryant RD, et al. Diagnostic and therapeutic considerations in biopsy-proven type 2 autoimmune pancreatitis: comparative analysis with biopsy-proven type 1 autoimmune pancreatitis. ANZ J Surg. 2021;91(5):907-14. https://doi.org/10.1111/ans.16445</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Detlefsen S, Zamboni G, Frulloni L, Feyerabend B, Braun F, Gerke O, et al. Clinical features and relapse rates after surgery in type 1 autoimmune pancreatitis differ from type 2: a study of 114 surgically treated European patients. Pancreatology: Off J Int Assoc Pancreatol. 2012;12(3):276-83. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pan.2012.03.055</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Song TJ, Kim JH, Kim MH, Jang JW, Park DH, Lee SS, et al. Comparison of clinical findings between histologically confirmed type 1 and type 2 autoimmune pancreatitis. J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2012;27(4):700-8. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1440-1746.2011.06934.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ikeura T, Detlefsen S, Zamboni G, Manfredi R, Negrelli R, Amodio A, et al. Retrospective comparison between preoperative diagnosis by International Consensus Diagnostic Criteria and histological diagnosis in patients with focal autoimmune pancreatitis who underwent surgery with suspicion of cancer. Pancreas. 2014;43(5):698-703. https://doi.org/10.1097/mpa.0000000000000114</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Detlefsen S, Mortensen MB, Pless TK, Cribe AS, de Muckadell OB. Laparoscopic and percutaneous core needle biopsy plays a central role for the diagnosis of autoimmune pancreatitis in a single-center study from Denmark. Pancreas. 2015;44(6):845-58. https://doi.org/10.1097/mpa.0000000000000312</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Buijs J, Cahen DL, van Heerde MJ, Rauws EA, de Buy Wenniger LJ, Hansen BE, et al. The long-term impact of autoimmune pancreatitis on pancreatic function, quality of life, and life expectancy. Pancreas. 2015;44(7):1065-71.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hart PA, Zen Y, Chari ST. Recent advances in autoimmune pancreatitis. Gastroenterology. 2015;149(1):39-51. https://doi.org/10.1053/j.gastro.2015.03.010</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sah RP, Chari ST, Pannala R, Sugumar R, Clain JE, Levy MJ, et al. Differences in clinical profile and relapse rate of type 1 versus type 2 autoimmune pancreatitis. Gastroenterology. 2010;139(1):140-8. ; quiz e12-3.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ikeura T, Manfredi R, Zamboni G, Negrelli R, Capelli P, Amodio A, et al. Application of international consensus diagnostic criteria to an Italian series of autoimmune pancreatitis. United Eur Gastroenterol. J. 2013;1(4):276-84. https://doi.org/10.1177/2050640613495196</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Notohara K, Nishimori I, Mizuno N, Okazaki K, Ito T, Kawa S, et al. Clinicopathological features of type 2 autoimmune pancreatitis in Japan: results of a multicenter survey. Pancreas. 2015;44(7):1072-7. https://doi.org/10.1097/mpa.0000000000000438</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rasch S, Phillip V, Schmid RM, Algül H. Epidemiology, clinical presentation, diagnosis and treatment of autoimmune pancreatitis: a retrospective analysis of 53 patients. Pancreatology: Off J Int Assoc Pancreatol. 2016;16(1):73-7. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pan.2015.11.006</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Detlefsen S, de Vos JD, Tanassi JT, Heegaard NHH, Fristrup C, Schaffalitzky de Muckadell OB. Value of anti-plasminogen binding peptide, anti-carbonic anhydrase II, immunoglobulin G4, and other serological markers for the differentiation of autoimmune pancreatitis and pancreatic cancer. Medicine (Baltim). 2018;97(31):e11641. https://doi.org/10.1097/md.0000000000011641</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta R, Neyaz A, Chougule A, Akita M, Zen Y, Forcione D, et al. Autoimmune pancreatitis type 2: diagnostic utility of PD-L1 immunohistochemistry. Am J Surg Pathol. 2019;43(7):898-906. https://doi.org/10.1097/pas.0000000000001282</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee HM, Deheragoda M, Harrison P, Devlin J, Sellars M, Hadzic N, et al. Autoimmune pancreatitis in children: a single centre experience in diagnosis, management and long term follow up. Pancreatology: Off J Int Assoc Pancreatol. 2019;19(1):169-76. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pan.2018.11.004</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Soliman H, Vullierme MP, Maire F, Hentic O, Ruszniewski P, Levy P, et al. Risk factors and treatment of relapses in autoimmune pancreatitis: rituximab is safe and effective. United Eur Gastroenterol. J. 2019;7(8):1073-83. https://doi.org/10.1177/2050640619862459</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barresi L, Tacelli M, Crino SF, Attili F, Petrone MC, De Nucci G, et al. Multicentric Italian survey on daily practice for autoimmune pancreatitis: clinical data, diagnosis, treatment, and evolution toward pancreatic insufficiency. United Eur Gastroenterol. J. 2020;8(6):705-15. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pan.2020.07.026</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Czakó L, Gyökeres T, Topa L, Sahin P, Takács T, Vincze A, et al. Autoimmune pancreatitis in Hungary: a multicenter nationwide study. Pancreatology: Off J Int Assoc Pancreatol. 2011;11(2):261-7. https://doi.org/10.1159/000327092</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kamisawa T, Chari ST, Giday SA, Kim MH, Chung JB, Lee KT, et al. Clinical profile of autoimmune pancreatitis and its histological subtypes: an international multicenter survey. Pancreas. 2011;40(6):809-14. https://doi.org/10.1097/mpa.0b013e3182258a15</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Balasubramanian G, Sugumar A, Smyrk TC, Takahashi N, Clain JE, Gleeson FC, et al. Demystifying seronegative autoimmune pancreatitis. Pancreatology: Off J Int Assoc Pancreatol. 2012;12(4):289-94. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pan.2012.05.003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Pretis N, Vieceli F, Brandolese A, Brozzi L, Amodio A, Frulloni L. Autoimmune pancreatitis not otherwise specified (NOS): clinical features and outcomes of the forgotten type. Hepatobiliary Pancreat Dis Int: HBPD INT. 2019;18(6):576-9. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.hbpd.2019.05.010</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wilson A, Wang Q, Choi YH, Ponich T, Gregor JC, Chande N, et al. Pretreatment HLADQA1-HLADRB1 testing for the prevention of azathioprine-induced pancreatitis in inflammatory bowel disease: a prospective cohort study. Clin Transl Gastroenterol. 2021;12(4):e00332. https://doi.org/10.14309/ctg.0000000000000332</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang L, Chari S, Smyrk TC, Deshpande V, Klöppel G, Kojima M, et al. Autoimmune pancreatitis (AIP) type 1 and type 2: an international consensus study on histopathologic diagnostic criteria. Pancreas. 2011;40(8):1172-9. https://doi.org/10.1097/mpa.0b013e318233bec5</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chiabrando F, Lanzillotta M, Palumbo D, Pedica F, Caruso M, Capurso G, et al. Treating type 2 autoimmune pancreatitis with colchicine: a case series. Ann Intern Med. 2021;174(12):1775-1776. https://doi.org/10.7326/l21-0281</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matsubayashi H, Ishiwatari H, Imai K, Kishida Y, Ito S, Hotta K, et al. Steroid therapy and steroid response in autoimmune pancreatitis. Int J Mol Sci. 2019;21(1):257. https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms21010257</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nakamura A, Ozawa M, Watanabe T, Ito T, Muraki T, Hamano H, et al. Predictive factors for autoimmune pancreatitis relapse after 3 years of maintenance therapy. Pancreas. 2018;47(10):1337-43. https://doi.org/10.1097/mpa.0000000000001173</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miki M, Fujimori N, Oono T, Kawabe K, Ohno A, Matsumoto K, et al. Relapse patterns and predictors of IgG4-related diseases involved with autoimmune pancreatitis: a single-center retrospective study of 115 patients. J Dig Dis. 2019;20(3):152-8. https://doi.org/10.1111/1751-2980.12708</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vujasinovic M, Valente R, Maier P, von Beckerath V, Haas SL, Arnelo U, et al. Diagnosis, treatment and long-term outcome of autoimmune pancreatitis in Sweden. Pancreatology: Off J Int Assoc Pancreatol. 2018;18(8):900-4. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pan.2018.09.003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salvatore S, Finazzi S, Barassi A, Verzelletti M, Tosi A, Melzi d'Eril GV, et al. Low fecal elastase: potentially related to transient small bowel damage resulting from enteric pathogens. J Pediatr Gastroenterol Nutr. 2003;36(3):392-6. https://doi.org/10.1097/00005176-200303000-00018</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
