<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35522243</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>10</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>10</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-6860</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>36</Volume>
            <Issue>6</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>FASEB journal : official publication of the Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>FASEB J</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Canonical and noncanonical regulatory roles for JAK2 in the pathogenesis of rheumatoid arthritis-associated interstitial lung disease and idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e22336</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e22336</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1096/fj.202101436R</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis (IPF) and rheumatoid arthritis-associated interstitial lung disease (RA-ILD) are two fibrotic interstitial lung diseases that share the usual interstitial pneumonia (UIP) injury pattern. Here, we report that RNA sequencing of lung biopsies from patients with RA-ILD and IPF revealed shared and distinct disease-causing pathways. Analysis of transcriptomic data identified a JAK2 related JAK/STAT signaling pathway gene signature that distinguishes RA-UIP from idiopathic UIP. This was further confirmed by immunohistostaining, which identified JAK2 phosphorylation with two distinct forms of activation: a cytoplasmic form of JAK2 activation in most IPF cases (13/20) and a nuclear form of p-JAK2 in RA-UIP (5/5) and a minority of IPF (6/20) cases. Further immunohistostaining identified STAT5A&amp;B as the downstream transcriptional activator for JAK2-mediated canonical signal transduction and phosphorylation of Tyr41 on histone H3 (H3Y41ph) as the downstream epigenetic regulation site for JAK2-mediated noncanonical signal transduction. Gene Set Enrichment Analysis (GSEA) of the RNA-Seq data further supported this shared pathogenic mechanism for the two diseases with the enrichment of STAT5A&amp;B target gene sets as well as the JAK2 regulated H3Y41ph target gene set. This regulatory role of JAK2 in the pathogenesis of pulmonary fibrosis was further demonstrated by the attenuation of bleomycin-induced murine pulmonary fibrosis using a JAK2-selective pharmacological inhibitor CEP33779. In vitro studies with normal and IPF derived lung fibroblasts revealed a central role for JAK2 as an essential intermediary molecule in TGF-β-mediated myofibroblast trans-differentiation, proliferation, and extracellular matrix protein production. These observations support a crucial role for JAK2 as an intermediary molecule in fibrotic lung disease development.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Shaohua</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine, Department of Medicine, Mayo Clinic College of Medicine and Science, Rochester, Minnesota, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Liu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mengfei</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Department of Medicine, Mayo Clinic College of Medicine and Science, Rochester, Minnesota, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Li</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xiujuan</ForeName>
            <Initials>X</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Endocrinology, Department of Medicine, First Affiliated Hospital of Chongqing Medical University, Chongqing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jie</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Pulmonary Medicine, Department of Medicine, Chongqing General Hospital, Chongqing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Faping</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Respiratory and Critical Care Medicine, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Chujie</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine, Department of Medicine, Mayo Clinic College of Medicine and Science, Rochester, Minnesota, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Roden</LastName>
            <ForeName>Anja</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Laboratory Medicine and Pathology, Mayo Clinic College of Medicine and Science, Rochester, Minnesota, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ryu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jay H</ForeName>
            <Initials>JH</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine, Department of Medicine, Mayo Clinic College of Medicine and Science, Rochester, Minnesota, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Warrington</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kenneth J</ForeName>
            <Initials>KJ</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Rheumatology, Department of Health Science Research, Mayo Clinic College of Medicine and Science, Rochester, Minnesota, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sun</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jie</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine, Department of Medicine, Mayo Clinic College of Medicine and Science, Rochester, Minnesota, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Matteson</LastName>
            <ForeName>Eric L</ForeName>
            <Initials>EL</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Rheumatology, Department of Health Science Research, Mayo Clinic College of Medicine and Science, Rochester, Minnesota, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tschumperlin</LastName>
            <ForeName>Daniel J</ForeName>
            <Initials>DJ</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Physiology and Biomedical Engineering, Mayo Clinic College of Medicine and Science, Rochester, Minnesota, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Vassallo</LastName>
            <ForeName>Robert</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2328-0255</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine, Department of Medicine, Mayo Clinic College of Medicine and Science, Rochester, Minnesota, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>FASEB J</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8804484</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0892-6638</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>EC 2.7.10.2</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="C507924">JAK2 protein, human</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>EC 2.7.10.2</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D053614">Janus Kinase 2</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001172" MajorTopicYN="Y">Arthritis, Rheumatoid</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D044127" MajorTopicYN="N">Epigenesis, Genetic</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D054990" MajorTopicYN="Y">Idiopathic Pulmonary Fibrosis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D053614" MajorTopicYN="N">Janus Kinase 2</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008168" MajorTopicYN="N">Lung</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017563" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lung Diseases, Interstitial</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Janus kinase 2</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">STAT3 transcription factor</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">STAT5 transcription factor</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">interstitial lung disease</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rheumatoid arthritis</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
          <Hour>11</Hour>
          <Minute>12</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35522243</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1096/fj.202101436R</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fisher M, Nathan SD, Hill C, et al. Predicting life expectancy for pirfenidone in idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. J Manag Care Spec Pharm. 2017;23:S17-S24.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ley B, Collard HR, King TE Jr. Clinical course and prediction of survival in idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2011;183:431-440.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim EJ, Elicker BM, Maldonado F, et al. Usual interstitial pneumonia in rheumatoid arthritis-associated interstitial lung disease. Eur Respir J. 2010;35:1322-1328.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim EJ, Collard HR, King TE Jr. Rheumatoid arthritis-associated interstitial lung disease: the relevance of histopathologic and radiographic pattern. Chest. 2009;136:1397-1405.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wolters PJ, Collard HR, Jones KD. Pathogenesis of idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. Annu Rev Pathol. 2014;9:157-179.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paulin F, Doyle TJ, Fletcher EA, Ascherman DP, Rosas IO. Rheumatoid arthritis-associated interstitial lung disease and idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis: shared mechanistic and phenotypic traits suggest overlapping disease mechanisms. Rev Invest Clin. 2015;67:280-286.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chambers RC, Mercer PF. Mechanisms of alveolar epithelial injury, repair, and fibrosis. Ann Am Thorac Soc. 2015;12(Suppl 1):S16-S20.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Noble PW. Epithelial fibroblast triggering and interactions in pulmonary fibrosis. Eur Respir Rev. 2008;17:123-129.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rajasekaran S, Rajaguru P, Sudhakar Gandhi PS. MicroRNAs as potential targets for progressive pulmonary fibrosis. Front Pharmacol. 2015;6:254.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Noth I, Zhang Y, Ma SF, et al. Genetic variants associated with idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis susceptibility and mortality: a genome-wide association study. Lancet Respir Med. 2013;1:309-317.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rabinovich EI, Kapetanaki MG, Steinfeld I, et al. Global methylation patterns in idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. PLoS One. 2012;7:e33770.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Selman M, Pardo A. Revealing the pathogenic and aging-related mechanisms of the enigmatic idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. an integral model. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2014;189:1161-1172.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>O'Shea JJ, Gadina M, Schreiber RD. Cytokine signaling in 2002: new surprises in the Jak/Stat pathway. Cell. 2002;109(Suppl):S121-S131.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parganas E, Wang D, Stravopodis D, et al. Jak2 is essential for signaling through a variety of cytokine receptors. Cell. 1998;93:385-395.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baxter EJ, Scott LM, Campbell PJ, et al. Acquired mutation of the tyrosine kinase JAK2 in human myeloproliferative disorders. Lancet. 2005;365:1054-1061.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>James C, Ugo V, Le Couédic JP, et al. A unique clonal JAK2 mutation leading to constitutive signalling causes polycythaemia vera. Nature. 2005;434:1144-1148.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kralovics R, Passamonti F, Buser AS, et al. A gain-of-function mutation of JAK2 in myeloproliferative disorders. N Engl J Med. 2005;352:1779-1790.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Milara J, Hernandez G, Ballester B, et al. The JAK2 pathway is activated in idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. Respir Res. 2018;19:24.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu F, Mih JD, Shea BS, et al. Feedback amplification of fibrosis through matrix stiffening and COX-2 suppression. J Cell Biol. 2010;190:693-706.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang J, Wang D, Wang L, et al. Profibrotic effect of IL-17A and elevated IL-17RA in idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis and rheumatoid arthritis-associated lung disease support a direct role for IL-17A/IL-17RA in human fibrotic interstitial lung disease. Am J Physiol Lung Cell Mol Physiol. 2019;316:L487-L497.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pelham RJ, Wang Y-L. Cell locomotion and focal adhesions are regulated by substrate flexibility. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1997;94:13661-13665.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shkumatov A, Thompson M, Choi KM, et al. Matrix stiffness-modulated proliferation and secretory function of the airway smooth muscle cells. Am J Physiol Lung Cell Mol Physiol. 2015;308:L1125-L1135.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raghu G, Collard HR, Egan JJ, et al. An official ATS/ERS/JRS/ALAT statement: idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis: evidence-based guidelines for diagnosis and management. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2011;183:788-824.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aletaha D, Neogi T, Silman AJ, et al. 2010 Rheumatoid arthritis classification criteria: an American College of Rheumatology/European League Against Rheumatism collaborative initiative. Arthritis Rheum. 2010;62:2569-2581.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hübner RH, Gitter W, El Mokhtari NE, et al. Standardized quantification of pulmonary fibrosis in histological samples. Biotechniques. 2008;44:507-517.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bolte S, Cordelières FP. A guided tour into subcellular colocalization analysis in light microscopy. J Microsc. 2006;224:213-232.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Feldman AL, Vasmatzis G, Asmann YW, et al. Novel TRAF1-ALK fusion identified by deep RNA sequencing of anaplastic large cell lymphoma. Genes Chromosomes Cancer. 2013;52:1097-1102.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee K, Han MR, Yeon JW, Kim B, Kim TH. Whole transcriptome analysis of myeloid dendritic cells reveals distinct genetic regulation in patients with allergies. Int J Mol Sci. 2020;21:8640.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dawson MA, Foster SD, Bannister AJ, et al. Three distinct patterns of histone H3Y41 phosphorylation mark active genes. Cell Rep. 2012;2:470-477.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dawson MA, Bannister AJ, Göttgens B, et al. JAK2 phosphorylates histone H3Y41 and excludes HP1alpha from chromatin. Nature. 2009;461:819-822.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barahmand-Pour F, Meinke A, Groner B, Decker T. Jak2-Stat5 interactions analyzed in yeast. J Biol Chem. 1998;273:12567-12575.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zouein FA, Duhé RJ, Booz GW. JAKs go nuclear: emerging role of nuclear JAK1 and JAK2 in gene expression and cell growth. Growth Factors. 2011;29:245-252.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lobie PE, Ronsin B, Silvennoinen O, Haldosén LA, Norstedt G, Morel G. Constitutive nuclear localization of Janus kinases 1 and 2. Endocrinology. 1996;137:4037-4045.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hedvat M, Huszar D, Herrmann A, et al. The JAK2 inhibitor AZD1480 potently blocks Stat3 signaling and oncogenesis in solid tumors. Cancer Cell. 2009;16:487-497.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu Y, Holdbrooks AT, De Sarno P, et al. Therapeutic efficacy of suppressing the Jak/STAT pathway in multiple models of experimental autoimmune encephalomyelitis. J Immunol. 2014;192:59-72.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stump KL, Lu LD, Dobrzanski P, et al. A highly selective, orally active inhibitor of Janus kinase 2, CEP-33779, ablates disease in two mouse models of rheumatoid arthritis. Arthritis Res Ther. 2011;13:R68.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verstovsek S, Hoffman R, Mascarenhas J, et al. A phase I, open-label, multi-center study of the JAK2 inhibitor AZD1480 in patients with myelofibrosis. Leuk Res. 2015;39:157-163.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bousoik E, Montazeri Aliabadi H. “Do we know Jack” about JAK? A closer look at JAK/STAT signaling pathway. Front Oncol. 2018;8:287.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lu P, Takai K, Weaver VM, Werb Z. Extracellular matrix degradation and remodeling in development and disease. Cold Spring Harb Perspect Biol. 2011;3(12):a005058.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jayatilaka H, Umanzor FG, Shah V, et al. Tumor cell density regulates matrix metalloproteinases for enhanced migration. Oncotarget. 2018;9:32556-32569.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu F, Zhang T, Zou S, Jiang B, Hua D. B7-H3 promotes cell migration and invasion through the Jak2/Stat3/MMP9 signaling pathway in colorectal cancer. Mol Med Rep. 2015;12:5455-5460.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shi S, Calhoun HC, Xia F, Li J, Le L, Li WX. JAK signaling globally counteracts heterochromatic gene silencing. Nat Genet. 2006;38:1071-1076.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Banerjee S, Biehl A, Gadina M, Hasni S, Schwartz DM. JAK-STAT signaling as a target for inflammatory and autoimmune diseases: current and future prospects. Drugs. 2017;77:521-546.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fragoulis GE, McInnes IB, Siebert S. JAK-inhibitors. New players in the field of immune-mediated diseases, beyond rheumatoid arthritis. Rheumatology. 2019;58:i43-i54.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McInnes IB, Schett G. Pathogenetic insights from the treatment of rheumatoid arthritis. Lancet. 2017;389:2328-2337.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Montero P, Milara J, Roger I, Cortijo J. Role of JAK/STAT in interstitial lung diseases; molecular and cellular mechanisms. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22:6211.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ballester B, Milara J, Morell A, et al. Role of JAK2/STAT3 pathway in vascular function of pulmonary fibrosis patients. Eur Respir J. 2015;46:PA4902.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Talotta R. The rationale for targeting the JAK/STAT pathway in scleroderma-associated interstitial lung disease. Immunotherapy. 2021;13:241-256.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35522243</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>10</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>10</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-6860</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>36</Volume>
            <Issue>6</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>FASEB journal : official publication of the Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>FASEB J</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Canonical and noncanonical regulatory roles for JAK2 in the pathogenesis of rheumatoid arthritis-associated interstitial lung disease and idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e22336</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e22336</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1096/fj.202101436R</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis (IPF) and rheumatoid arthritis-associated interstitial lung disease (RA-ILD) are two fibrotic interstitial lung diseases that share the usual interstitial pneumonia (UIP) injury pattern. Here, we report that RNA sequencing of lung biopsies from patients with RA-ILD and IPF revealed shared and distinct disease-causing pathways. Analysis of transcriptomic data identified a JAK2 related JAK/STAT signaling pathway gene signature that distinguishes RA-UIP from idiopathic UIP. This was further confirmed by immunohistostaining, which identified JAK2 phosphorylation with two distinct forms of activation: a cytoplasmic form of JAK2 activation in most IPF cases (13/20) and a nuclear form of p-JAK2 in RA-UIP (5/5) and a minority of IPF (6/20) cases. Further immunohistostaining identified STAT5A&amp;B as the downstream transcriptional activator for JAK2-mediated canonical signal transduction and phosphorylation of Tyr41 on histone H3 (H3Y41ph) as the downstream epigenetic regulation site for JAK2-mediated noncanonical signal transduction. Gene Set Enrichment Analysis (GSEA) of the RNA-Seq data further supported this shared pathogenic mechanism for the two diseases with the enrichment of STAT5A&amp;B target gene sets as well as the JAK2 regulated H3Y41ph target gene set. This regulatory role of JAK2 in the pathogenesis of pulmonary fibrosis was further demonstrated by the attenuation of bleomycin-induced murine pulmonary fibrosis using a JAK2-selective pharmacological inhibitor CEP33779. In vitro studies with normal and IPF derived lung fibroblasts revealed a central role for JAK2 as an essential intermediary molecule in TGF-β-mediated myofibroblast trans-differentiation, proliferation, and extracellular matrix protein production. These observations support a crucial role for JAK2 as an intermediary molecule in fibrotic lung disease development.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Shaohua</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine, Department of Medicine, Mayo Clinic College of Medicine and Science, Rochester, Minnesota, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Liu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mengfei</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Department of Medicine, Mayo Clinic College of Medicine and Science, Rochester, Minnesota, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Li</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xiujuan</ForeName>
            <Initials>X</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Endocrinology, Department of Medicine, First Affiliated Hospital of Chongqing Medical University, Chongqing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jie</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Pulmonary Medicine, Department of Medicine, Chongqing General Hospital, Chongqing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Faping</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Respiratory and Critical Care Medicine, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Chujie</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine, Department of Medicine, Mayo Clinic College of Medicine and Science, Rochester, Minnesota, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Roden</LastName>
            <ForeName>Anja</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Laboratory Medicine and Pathology, Mayo Clinic College of Medicine and Science, Rochester, Minnesota, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ryu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jay H</ForeName>
            <Initials>JH</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine, Department of Medicine, Mayo Clinic College of Medicine and Science, Rochester, Minnesota, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Warrington</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kenneth J</ForeName>
            <Initials>KJ</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Rheumatology, Department of Health Science Research, Mayo Clinic College of Medicine and Science, Rochester, Minnesota, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sun</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jie</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine, Department of Medicine, Mayo Clinic College of Medicine and Science, Rochester, Minnesota, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Matteson</LastName>
            <ForeName>Eric L</ForeName>
            <Initials>EL</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Rheumatology, Department of Health Science Research, Mayo Clinic College of Medicine and Science, Rochester, Minnesota, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tschumperlin</LastName>
            <ForeName>Daniel J</ForeName>
            <Initials>DJ</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Physiology and Biomedical Engineering, Mayo Clinic College of Medicine and Science, Rochester, Minnesota, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Vassallo</LastName>
            <ForeName>Robert</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2328-0255</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Pulmonary and Critical Care Medicine, Department of Medicine, Mayo Clinic College of Medicine and Science, Rochester, Minnesota, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>FASEB J</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8804484</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0892-6638</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>EC 2.7.10.2</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="C507924">JAK2 protein, human</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>EC 2.7.10.2</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D053614">Janus Kinase 2</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001172" MajorTopicYN="Y">Arthritis, Rheumatoid</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D044127" MajorTopicYN="N">Epigenesis, Genetic</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D054990" MajorTopicYN="Y">Idiopathic Pulmonary Fibrosis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D053614" MajorTopicYN="N">Janus Kinase 2</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008168" MajorTopicYN="N">Lung</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017563" MajorTopicYN="Y">Lung Diseases, Interstitial</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D051379" MajorTopicYN="N">Mice</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Janus kinase 2</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">STAT3 transcription factor</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">STAT5 transcription factor</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">interstitial lung disease</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rheumatoid arthritis</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
          <Hour>11</Hour>
          <Minute>12</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35522243</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1096/fj.202101436R</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fisher M, Nathan SD, Hill C, et al. Predicting life expectancy for pirfenidone in idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. J Manag Care Spec Pharm. 2017;23:S17-S24.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ley B, Collard HR, King TE Jr. Clinical course and prediction of survival in idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2011;183:431-440.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim EJ, Elicker BM, Maldonado F, et al. Usual interstitial pneumonia in rheumatoid arthritis-associated interstitial lung disease. Eur Respir J. 2010;35:1322-1328.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim EJ, Collard HR, King TE Jr. Rheumatoid arthritis-associated interstitial lung disease: the relevance of histopathologic and radiographic pattern. Chest. 2009;136:1397-1405.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wolters PJ, Collard HR, Jones KD. Pathogenesis of idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. Annu Rev Pathol. 2014;9:157-179.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paulin F, Doyle TJ, Fletcher EA, Ascherman DP, Rosas IO. Rheumatoid arthritis-associated interstitial lung disease and idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis: shared mechanistic and phenotypic traits suggest overlapping disease mechanisms. Rev Invest Clin. 2015;67:280-286.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chambers RC, Mercer PF. Mechanisms of alveolar epithelial injury, repair, and fibrosis. Ann Am Thorac Soc. 2015;12(Suppl 1):S16-S20.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Noble PW. Epithelial fibroblast triggering and interactions in pulmonary fibrosis. Eur Respir Rev. 2008;17:123-129.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rajasekaran S, Rajaguru P, Sudhakar Gandhi PS. MicroRNAs as potential targets for progressive pulmonary fibrosis. Front Pharmacol. 2015;6:254.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Noth I, Zhang Y, Ma SF, et al. Genetic variants associated with idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis susceptibility and mortality: a genome-wide association study. Lancet Respir Med. 2013;1:309-317.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rabinovich EI, Kapetanaki MG, Steinfeld I, et al. Global methylation patterns in idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. PLoS One. 2012;7:e33770.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Selman M, Pardo A. Revealing the pathogenic and aging-related mechanisms of the enigmatic idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. an integral model. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2014;189:1161-1172.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>O'Shea JJ, Gadina M, Schreiber RD. Cytokine signaling in 2002: new surprises in the Jak/Stat pathway. Cell. 2002;109(Suppl):S121-S131.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parganas E, Wang D, Stravopodis D, et al. Jak2 is essential for signaling through a variety of cytokine receptors. Cell. 1998;93:385-395.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baxter EJ, Scott LM, Campbell PJ, et al. Acquired mutation of the tyrosine kinase JAK2 in human myeloproliferative disorders. Lancet. 2005;365:1054-1061.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>James C, Ugo V, Le Couédic JP, et al. A unique clonal JAK2 mutation leading to constitutive signalling causes polycythaemia vera. Nature. 2005;434:1144-1148.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kralovics R, Passamonti F, Buser AS, et al. A gain-of-function mutation of JAK2 in myeloproliferative disorders. N Engl J Med. 2005;352:1779-1790.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Milara J, Hernandez G, Ballester B, et al. The JAK2 pathway is activated in idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis. Respir Res. 2018;19:24.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu F, Mih JD, Shea BS, et al. Feedback amplification of fibrosis through matrix stiffening and COX-2 suppression. J Cell Biol. 2010;190:693-706.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang J, Wang D, Wang L, et al. Profibrotic effect of IL-17A and elevated IL-17RA in idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis and rheumatoid arthritis-associated lung disease support a direct role for IL-17A/IL-17RA in human fibrotic interstitial lung disease. Am J Physiol Lung Cell Mol Physiol. 2019;316:L487-L497.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pelham RJ, Wang Y-L. Cell locomotion and focal adhesions are regulated by substrate flexibility. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1997;94:13661-13665.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shkumatov A, Thompson M, Choi KM, et al. Matrix stiffness-modulated proliferation and secretory function of the airway smooth muscle cells. Am J Physiol Lung Cell Mol Physiol. 2015;308:L1125-L1135.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raghu G, Collard HR, Egan JJ, et al. An official ATS/ERS/JRS/ALAT statement: idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis: evidence-based guidelines for diagnosis and management. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2011;183:788-824.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aletaha D, Neogi T, Silman AJ, et al. 2010 Rheumatoid arthritis classification criteria: an American College of Rheumatology/European League Against Rheumatism collaborative initiative. Arthritis Rheum. 2010;62:2569-2581.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hübner RH, Gitter W, El Mokhtari NE, et al. Standardized quantification of pulmonary fibrosis in histological samples. Biotechniques. 2008;44:507-517.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bolte S, Cordelières FP. A guided tour into subcellular colocalization analysis in light microscopy. J Microsc. 2006;224:213-232.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Feldman AL, Vasmatzis G, Asmann YW, et al. Novel TRAF1-ALK fusion identified by deep RNA sequencing of anaplastic large cell lymphoma. Genes Chromosomes Cancer. 2013;52:1097-1102.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee K, Han MR, Yeon JW, Kim B, Kim TH. Whole transcriptome analysis of myeloid dendritic cells reveals distinct genetic regulation in patients with allergies. Int J Mol Sci. 2020;21:8640.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dawson MA, Foster SD, Bannister AJ, et al. Three distinct patterns of histone H3Y41 phosphorylation mark active genes. Cell Rep. 2012;2:470-477.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dawson MA, Bannister AJ, Göttgens B, et al. JAK2 phosphorylates histone H3Y41 and excludes HP1alpha from chromatin. Nature. 2009;461:819-822.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barahmand-Pour F, Meinke A, Groner B, Decker T. Jak2-Stat5 interactions analyzed in yeast. J Biol Chem. 1998;273:12567-12575.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zouein FA, Duhé RJ, Booz GW. JAKs go nuclear: emerging role of nuclear JAK1 and JAK2 in gene expression and cell growth. Growth Factors. 2011;29:245-252.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lobie PE, Ronsin B, Silvennoinen O, Haldosén LA, Norstedt G, Morel G. Constitutive nuclear localization of Janus kinases 1 and 2. Endocrinology. 1996;137:4037-4045.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hedvat M, Huszar D, Herrmann A, et al. The JAK2 inhibitor AZD1480 potently blocks Stat3 signaling and oncogenesis in solid tumors. Cancer Cell. 2009;16:487-497.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu Y, Holdbrooks AT, De Sarno P, et al. Therapeutic efficacy of suppressing the Jak/STAT pathway in multiple models of experimental autoimmune encephalomyelitis. J Immunol. 2014;192:59-72.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stump KL, Lu LD, Dobrzanski P, et al. A highly selective, orally active inhibitor of Janus kinase 2, CEP-33779, ablates disease in two mouse models of rheumatoid arthritis. Arthritis Res Ther. 2011;13:R68.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verstovsek S, Hoffman R, Mascarenhas J, et al. A phase I, open-label, multi-center study of the JAK2 inhibitor AZD1480 in patients with myelofibrosis. Leuk Res. 2015;39:157-163.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bousoik E, Montazeri Aliabadi H. “Do we know Jack” about JAK? A closer look at JAK/STAT signaling pathway. Front Oncol. 2018;8:287.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lu P, Takai K, Weaver VM, Werb Z. Extracellular matrix degradation and remodeling in development and disease. Cold Spring Harb Perspect Biol. 2011;3(12):a005058.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jayatilaka H, Umanzor FG, Shah V, et al. Tumor cell density regulates matrix metalloproteinases for enhanced migration. Oncotarget. 2018;9:32556-32569.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu F, Zhang T, Zou S, Jiang B, Hua D. B7-H3 promotes cell migration and invasion through the Jak2/Stat3/MMP9 signaling pathway in colorectal cancer. Mol Med Rep. 2015;12:5455-5460.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shi S, Calhoun HC, Xia F, Li J, Le L, Li WX. JAK signaling globally counteracts heterochromatic gene silencing. Nat Genet. 2006;38:1071-1076.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Banerjee S, Biehl A, Gadina M, Hasni S, Schwartz DM. JAK-STAT signaling as a target for inflammatory and autoimmune diseases: current and future prospects. Drugs. 2017;77:521-546.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fragoulis GE, McInnes IB, Siebert S. JAK-inhibitors. New players in the field of immune-mediated diseases, beyond rheumatoid arthritis. Rheumatology. 2019;58:i43-i54.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McInnes IB, Schett G. Pathogenetic insights from the treatment of rheumatoid arthritis. Lancet. 2017;389:2328-2337.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Montero P, Milara J, Roger I, Cortijo J. Role of JAK/STAT in interstitial lung diseases; molecular and cellular mechanisms. Int J Mol Sci. 2021;22:6211.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ballester B, Milara J, Morell A, et al. Role of JAK2/STAT3 pathway in vascular function of pulmonary fibrosis patients. Eur Respir J. 2015;46:PA4902.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Talotta R. The rationale for targeting the JAK/STAT pathway in scleroderma-associated interstitial lung disease. Immunotherapy. 2021;13:241-256.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
