<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35522249</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>06</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1096-9098</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>06</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of surgical oncology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Surg Oncol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Hepatic arterial infusion pump chemotherapy combined with systemic therapy for patients with advanced colorectal liver metastases: Outcomes in a newly established program.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jso.26911</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND AND OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Colorectal liver metastasis (CRLM) is a leading cause of morbidity and mortality in patients with colorectal cancer. Hepatic arterial infusion (HAI) chemotherapy has been demonstrated to improve survival in patients with resected CRLM and to facilitate conversion of technically unresectable disease.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Between 2016 and 2018, n = 22 HAI pumps were placed for CRLM. All patients received systemic chemotherapy concurrently with HAI floxuridine/dexamethasone. Overall survival (OS) and progression-free survival (PFS) were assessed using the Kaplan-Meier method.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">HAI pumps were placed in seven patients with completely resected CRLM and 15 patients with unresectable disease. Twenty-one patients received HAI floxuridine with a median of 5 total HAI cycles (interquartile range: 4-7). Biliary sclerosis was the most common HAI-related complication (n = 5, 24%). Of the 13 patients treated to convert unresectable CRLM, 3 (23%) underwent hepatic resection with curative intent after a median of 7 HAI cycles (range: 4-10). For all HAI patients, the mean OS was 26.7 months from CRLM diagnosis, while the median PFS and hepatic PFS from pump placement were 9 and 13 months, respectively.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Concomitant HAI and systemic therapy can be utilized at multidisciplinary programs for patients with advanced CRLM, both in the adjuvant setting and to facilitate conversion of unresectable disease.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Walker</LastName>
            <ForeName>Brett S</ForeName>
            <Initials>BS</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7628-4925</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Oregon Health &amp; Science University (OHSU), Department of Surgery, Division of Surgical Oncology, Knight Cancer Institute, Portland, Oregon, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Billingsley</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kevin G</ForeName>
            <Initials>KG</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Yale School of Medicine, Yale Cancer Center, New Haven, Connecticut, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sutton</LastName>
            <ForeName>Thomas L</ForeName>
            <Initials>TL</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2894-7154</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Oregon Health &amp; Science University (OHSU), Department of Surgery, Division of Surgical Oncology, Knight Cancer Institute, Portland, Oregon, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kolbeck</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kenneth J</ForeName>
            <Initials>KJ</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>OHSU, Department of Interventional Radiology, Dotter Institute, Portland, Oregon, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Korngold</LastName>
            <ForeName>Elena K</ForeName>
            <Initials>EK</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>OHSU, Department of Diagnostic Radiology, Portland, Oregon, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nabavizadeh</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nima</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>OHSU, Department of Radiation Medicine, Portland, Oregon, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Dewey</LastName>
            <ForeName>Elizabeth N</ForeName>
            <Initials>EN</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>OHSU, Department of Surgery - Biostatistics, Portland, Oregon, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Herzig</LastName>
            <ForeName>Daniel O</ForeName>
            <Initials>DO</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>OHSU, Division of Colorectal Surgery, Department of Surgery, Portland, Oregon, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lopez</LastName>
            <ForeName>Charles D</ForeName>
            <Initials>CD</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>OHSU, Division of Hematology and Medical Oncology, Department of Medicine, Portland, Oregon, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>The Knight Cancer Institute at OHSU, Portland, Oregon, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mayo</LastName>
            <ForeName>Skye C</ForeName>
            <Initials>SC</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1631-9855</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Oregon Health &amp; Science University (OHSU), Department of Surgery, Division of Surgical Oncology, Knight Cancer Institute, Portland, Oregon, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>The Knight Cancer Institute at OHSU, Portland, Oregon, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>06</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Surg Oncol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0222643</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0022-4790</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">colorectal liver metastasis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">floxuridine</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hepatic arterial infusion pump therapy</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">liver directed therapy</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">liver tumor</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
          <Hour>11</Hour>
          <Minute>22</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35522249</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jso.26911</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Siegel RL, Miller KD, Jemal A. Cancer statistics, 2019. CA Cancer J Clin. 2019;69:7-34.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ko YJ, Karanicolas PJ. Hepatic arterial infusion pump chemotherapy for colorectal liver metastases: an old technology in a new era. Curr Oncol. 2014;21:e116-e121.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zarour LR, Anand S, Billingsley KG, et al. Colorectal cancer liver metastasis: evolving paradigms and future directions. Cell Mol Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2017;3:163-173.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Al Bandar MH, Kim NK. Current status and future perspectives on treatment of liver metastasis in colorectal cancer (review). Oncol Rep. 2017;37:2553-2564.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tomlinson JS, Jarnagin WR, DeMatteo RP, et al. Actual 10-year survival after resection of colorectal liver metastases defines cure. J Clin Oncol Off J Am Soc Clin Oncol. 2007;25:4575-4580.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shi L, Zhao J, Lu Q, et al. Initial hepatic artery infusion and systemic chemotherapy for asymptomatic colorectal cancer with un-resectable liver metastasis. Int J Clin Exp Med. 2015;8:1000-1008.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zervoudakis A, Boucher T, Kemeny NE. Treatment options in colorectal liver metastases: hepatic arterial infusion. Visc Med. 2017;33:47-53.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Venook AP, Niedzwiecki D, Lenz HJ, et al. Effect of first-line chemotherapy combined with Cetuximab or Bevacizumab on overall survival in patients with KRAS wild-type advanced or metastatic colorectal cancer: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA. 2017;317:2392-2401.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stintzing S, Modest DP, Rossius L, et al. FOLFIRI plus cetuximab versus FOLFIRI plus bevacizumab for metastatic colorectal cancer (FIRE-3): a post-hoc analysis of tumour dynamics in the final RAS wild-type subgroup of this randomised open-label phase 3 trial. Lancet Oncol. 2016;17:1426-1434.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kelly RJ, Kemeny NE, Leonard GD. Current strategies using hepatic arterial infusion chemotherapy for the treatment of colorectal cancer. Clin Colorectal Cancer. 2005;5:166-174.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ensminger WD. Intrahepatic arterial infusion of chemotherapy: pharmacologic principles. Semin Oncol. 2002;29:119-125.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mocellin S, Pilati P, Lise M, Nitti D. Meta-analysis of hepatic arterial infusion for unresectable liver metastases from colorectal cancer: the end of an era? J Clin Oncol. 2007;25:5649-5654.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McAuliffe JC, Qadan M, D'Angelica MI. Hepatic resection, hepatic arterial infusion pump therapy, and genetic biomarkers in the management of hepatic metastases from colorectal cancer. J Gastrointest Oncol. 2015;6:699-708.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Groot Koerkamp B, Sadot E, Kemeny NE, et al. Perioperative hepatic arterial infusion pump chemotherapy is associated with longer survival after resection of colorectal liver metastases: a propensity score analysis. J Clin Oncol. 2017;35:1938-1944.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Karanicolas PJ, Metrakos P, Chan K, et al. Hepatic arterial infusion pump chemotherapy in the management of colorectal liver metastases: expert consensus statement. Curr Oncol. 2014;21:e129-e136.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pak LM, Kemeny NE, Capanu M, et al. Prospective phase II trial of combination hepatic artery infusion and systemic chemotherapy for unresectable colorectal liver metastases: long term results and curative potential. J Surg Oncol. 2018;117:634-643.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gallagher DJ, Capanu M, Raggio G, Kemeny N. Hepatic arterial infusion plus systemic irinotecan in patients with unresectable hepatic metastases from colorectal cancer previously treated with systemic oxaliplatin: a retrospective analysis. Ann Oncol. 2007;18:1995-1999.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kemeny MM, Kemeny MM, Adak S, et al. Combined-modality treatment for resectable metastatic colorectal carcinoma to the liver: surgical resection of hepatic metastases in combination with continuous infusion of chemotherapy--an intergroup study. J Clin Oncol Off J Am Soc Clin Oncol. 2002;20:1499-1505.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kemeny NE, Chou JF, Boucher TM, et al. Updated long-term survival for patients with metastatic colorectal cancer treated with liver resection followed by hepatic arterial infusion and systemic chemotherapy. J Surg Oncol. 2016;113:477-484.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cercek A, Boerner T, Tan BR, et al. Assessment of hepatic arterial infusion of floxuridine in combination with systemic Gemcitabine and Oxaliplatin in patients with unresectable intrahepatic Cholangiocarcinoma: a phase 2 clinical trial. JAMA Oncol. 2019;6:60-67.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chakedis J, Beal EW, Sun S, et al. Implementation and early outcomes for a surgeon-directed hepatic arterial infusion pump program for colorectal liver metastases. J Surg Oncol. 2018;118:1065-1073.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Creasy JM, Napier KJ, Reed SA, et al. Implementation of a hepatic artery infusion program: initial patient selection and perioperative outcomes of concurrent hepatic artery infusion and systemic chemotherapy for colorectal liver metastases. Ann Surg Oncol. 2020;27:5086-5095.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Allen PJ, Nissan A, Picon AI, et al. Technical complications and durability of hepatic artery infusion pumps for unresectable colorectal liver metastases: an institutional experience of 544 consecutive cases. J Am Coll Surg. 2005;201:57-65.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>DʼAngelica MI, Correa-Gallego C, Paty PB, et al. Phase II trial of hepatic artery infusional and systemic chemotherapy for patients with unresectable hepatic metastases from colorectal cancer: conversion to resection and long-term outcomes. Ann Surg. 2015;261:353-360.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lewis HL, Bloomston M. Hepatic artery infusional chemotherapy. Surg Clin North Am. 2016;96:341-355.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kemeny N, Jarnagin W, Gonen M, et al. Phase I/II study of hepatic arterial therapy with floxuridine and dexamethasone in combination with intravenous irinotecan as adjuvant treatment after resection of hepatic metastases from colorectal cancer. J Clin Oncol Off J Am Soc Clin Oncol. 2003;21:3303-3309.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cercek A, D'Angelica M, Power D, et al. Floxuridine hepatic arterial infusion associated biliary toxicity is increased by concurrent administration of systemic bevacizumab. Ann Surg Oncol. 2014;21:479-486.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weiser MR. AJCC 8th edition: colorectal cancer. Ann Surg Oncol. 2018;25:1454-1455.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reissfelder C, Rahbari NN, Koch M, et al. Validation of prognostic scoring systems for patients undergoing resection of colorectal cancer liver metastases. Ann Surg Oncol. 2009;16:3279-3288.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clavien PA, Barkun J, de Oliveira ML, et al. The Clavien-Dindo classification of surgical complications: five-year experience. Ann Surg. 2009;250:187-196.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eisenhauer EA, Therasse P, Bogaerts J, et al. New response evaluation criteria in solid tumours: revised RECIST guideline (version 1.1). Eur J Cancer. 2009;45:228-247.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Strasberg SM. Nomenclature of hepatic anatomy and resections: a review of the Brisbane 2000 system. J Hepatobiliary Pancreat Surg. 2005;12:351-355.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kemeny N, Daly J, Reichman B, Geller N, Botet J, Oderman P. Intrahepatic or systemic infusion of fluorodeoxyuridine in patients with liver metastases from colorectal carcinoma. A randomized trial. Ann Intern Med. 1987;107:459-465.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hohn DC, Stagg RJ, Friedman MA, et al. A randomized trial of continuous intravenous versus hepatic intraarterial floxuridine in patients with colorectal cancer metastatic to the liver: the Northern California Oncology Group trial. J Clin Oncol Off J Am Soc Clin Oncol. 1989;7:1646-1654.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Onaitis M, Morse M, Hurwitz H, et al. Adjuvant hepatic arterial chemotherapy following metastasectomy in patients with isolated liver metastases. Ann Surg. 2003;237:782-788.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ito K, Ito H, Kemeny NE, et al. Biliary sclerosis after hepatic arterial infusion pump chemotherapy for patients with colorectal cancer liver metastasis: incidence, clinical features, and risk factors. Ann Surg Oncol. 2012;19:1609-1617.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kemeny N, Seiter K, Niedzwiecki D, et al. A randomized trial of intrahepatic infusion of fluorodeoxyuridine with dexamethasone versus fluorodeoxyuridine alone in the treatment of metastatic colorectal cancer. Cancer. 1992;69:327-334.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muaddi H, D'Angelica M, Wiseman JT, et al. Safety and feasibility of initiating a hepatic artery infusion pump chemotherapy program for unresectable colorectal liver metastases: a multicenter, retrospective cohort study. J Surg Oncol. 2020;123:252-260.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cercek A, Boucher TM, Gluskin JS, et al. Response rates of hepatic arterial infusion pump therapy in patients with metastatic colorectal cancer liver metastases refractory to all standard chemotherapies. J Surg Oncol. 2016;114:655-663.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vera R, Gómez ML, Ayuso JR, et al. Correlation of RECIST, computed tomography morphological response, and pathological regression in hepatic metastasis secondary to colorectal cancer: the AVAMET study. Cancers. 2020;12.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kemeny NE, Niedzwiecki D, Hollis DR, et al. Hepatic arterial infusion versus systemic therapy for hepatic metastases from colorectal cancer: a randomized trial of efficacy, quality of life, and molecular markers (CALGB 9481). J Clin Oncol Off J Am Soc Clin Oncol. 2006;24:1395-403.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vázquez-Bourgon J, Ortiz-García de la Foz V, Suarez-Pereira I, et al. Data regarding the effect of cannabis consumption on liver function in the prospective PAFIP cohort of first episode psychosis. Data Brief. 2019;27:104415.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Borini P, Guimarães RC, Borini SB. Possible hepatotoxicity of chronic marijuana usage. Sao Paulo Med J. 2004;122:110-116.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grady, D, Kaplan, S. A Lifesaving Pump for Cancer Patients Is Being Phased Out, April 25, 2018. https://www.nytimes.com/2018/04/25/health/liver-pump-cancer-medical-device.html?mc=aud_dev%26mcid=keywee%26mccr=domdesk%26kwp_0=788258%26kwp_4=2726512%26kwp_1=1156979%26dclid=CIvVwNGb9toCFZi6yAodZQMMeA</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ellis RJ, Angelos P, Jarnagin WR, Kemeny NE, Merkow RP. Abrupt discontinuation of the Codman hepatic artery infusion pump: considerations in the era of precision medicine. J Am Coll Surg. 2019;229:217-219.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Connell LC, Fiedler L, Dickinson S, et al. Hepatic arterial infusion (HAI) chemotherapy via the Medtronic pump-assessing dose delivery, response rates and toxicity. J Clin Oncol. 2020;38:e16007.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
