<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35526445</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>24</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1879-1379</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>151</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>01</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of psychiatric research</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Psychiatr Res</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Population-based signals of benzodiazepine drug interactions associated with unintentional traumatic injury.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>299</StartPage>
          <EndPage>303</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>299-303</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.jpsychires.2022.04.033</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0022-3956(22)00233-3</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Benzodiazepine receptor agonists and related medications, such as Z-drugs and dual orexin receptor antagonists (BZDs), have been associated with unintentional traumatic injury due to their central nervous system (CNS)-depressant effects. Drug-drug interactions (DDIs) may contribute to the known relationship between BZD use and unintentional traumatic injury, yet evidence is still lacking. We conducted high-throughput pharmacoepidemiologic screening using the self-controlled case series design in a large US commercial health insurance database to identify potentially clinically relevant DDI signals among new users of BZDs. We used conditional Poisson regression to estimate rate ratios (RRs) between each co-exposure (vs. not) and unintentional traumatic injury (primary outcome), typical hip fracture (secondary outcome), and motor vehicle crash (secondary outcome). We identified 48 potential DDI signals (1.1%, involving 39 unique co-dispensed drugs), i.e., with statistically significant elevated adjusted RRs for injury. Signals were strongest for DDI pairs involving zolpidem, lorazepam, temazepam, alprazolam, eszopiclone, triazolam, and clonazepam. We also identified four potential DDI signals for typical hip fracture, but none for motor vehicle crash. Many signals have biologically plausible explanations through additive or synergistic pharmacodynamic effects of co-dispensed antidepressants, opioids, or muscle relaxants on CNS depression, impaired psychomotor and cognitive function, and/or somnolence. While other signals that lack an obvious mechanism may represent true associations that place patients at risk of injury, it is also prudent to consider the roles of chance, reverse causation, and/or confounding by indication, which merit further exploration. Given the high-throughput nature of our investigation, findings should be interpreted as hypothesis generating.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Pham Nguyen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Thanh Phuong</ForeName>
            <Initials>TP</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Center for Pharmacoepidemiology Research and Training, Center for Clinical Epidemiology and Biostatistics, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA, USA; Translational Center of Excellence for Neuroepidemiology and Neurology Outcomes Research, Department of Neurology, Perelman School of Medicine, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Soprano</LastName>
            <ForeName>Samantha E</ForeName>
            <Initials>SE</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Center for Pharmacoepidemiology Research and Training, Center for Clinical Epidemiology and Biostatistics, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA, USA; Department of Biostatistics, Epidemiology, and Informatics, Perelman School of Medicine, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hennessy</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sean</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Center for Pharmacoepidemiology Research and Training, Center for Clinical Epidemiology and Biostatistics, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA, USA; Department of Biostatistics, Epidemiology, and Informatics, Perelman School of Medicine, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA, USA; Department of Systems Pharmacology and Translational Therapeutics, Perelman School of Medicine, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA, USA; Leonard Davis Institute of Health Economics, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Brensinger</LastName>
            <ForeName>Colleen M</ForeName>
            <Initials>CM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Center for Pharmacoepidemiology Research and Training, Center for Clinical Epidemiology and Biostatistics, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA, USA; Department of Biostatistics, Epidemiology, and Informatics, Perelman School of Medicine, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bilker</LastName>
            <ForeName>Warren B</ForeName>
            <Initials>WB</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Center for Pharmacoepidemiology Research and Training, Center for Clinical Epidemiology and Biostatistics, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA, USA; Department of Biostatistics, Epidemiology, and Informatics, Perelman School of Medicine, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA, USA; Department of Psychiatry, Perelman School of Medicine, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Miano</LastName>
            <ForeName>Todd A</ForeName>
            <Initials>TA</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Center for Pharmacoepidemiology Research and Training, Center for Clinical Epidemiology and Biostatistics, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA, USA; Department of Biostatistics, Epidemiology, and Informatics, Perelman School of Medicine, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Acton</LastName>
            <ForeName>Emily K</ForeName>
            <Initials>EK</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Center for Pharmacoepidemiology Research and Training, Center for Clinical Epidemiology and Biostatistics, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA, USA; Translational Center of Excellence for Neuroepidemiology and Neurology Outcomes Research, Department of Neurology, Perelman School of Medicine, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA, USA; Department of Biostatistics, Epidemiology, and Informatics, Perelman School of Medicine, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Horn</LastName>
            <ForeName>John R</ForeName>
            <Initials>JR</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pharmacy, School of Pharmacy, University of Washington, Seattle, WA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chung</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sophie P</ForeName>
            <Initials>SP</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>AthenaHealth, Inc., Watertown, MA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Dublin</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sascha</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Kaiser Permanente Washington Health Research Institute, Kaiser Permanente Washington, Seattle, WA, USA; Department of Epidemiology, School of Public Health, University of Washington, Seattle, WA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Oslin</LastName>
            <ForeName>David W</ForeName>
            <Initials>DW</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Center for Pharmacoepidemiology Research and Training, Center for Clinical Epidemiology and Biostatistics, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA, USA; Department of Psychiatry, Perelman School of Medicine, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA, USA; Mental Illness Research, Education, and Clinical Center, Corporal Michael J. Crescenz Veterans Administration Medical Center, Philadelphia, PA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wiebe</LastName>
            <ForeName>Douglas J</ForeName>
            <Initials>DJ</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biostatistics, Epidemiology, and Informatics, Perelman School of Medicine, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA, USA; Leonard Davis Institute of Health Economics, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA, USA; Penn Injury Science Center, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Leonard</LastName>
            <ForeName>Charles E</ForeName>
            <Initials>CE</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Center for Pharmacoepidemiology Research and Training, Center for Clinical Epidemiology and Biostatistics, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA, USA; Department of Biostatistics, Epidemiology, and Informatics, Perelman School of Medicine, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA, USA; Leonard Davis Institute of Health Economics, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA, USA. Electronic address: celeonar@pennmedicine.upenn.edu.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>01</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Psychiatr Res</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0376331</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0022-3956</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Benzodiazepines</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Drug interactions</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Injury</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pharmacoepidemiology</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Population health</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Self-controlled case series</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
          <Hour>18</Hour>
          <Minute>14</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35526445</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpsychires.2022.04.033</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">S0022-3956(22)00233-3</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
