<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35524921</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>07</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1534-6293</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>07</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Current neurology and neuroscience reports</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Curr Neurol Neurosci Rep</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Management of Patients with Embolic Stroke of Unknown Source: Interpreting the Evidence in the Light of Clinical Judgement.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s11910-022-01202-w</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To assess the validity of the belief that anticoagulation is not beneficial in patients with embolic stroke of unknown source (ESUS), and to asssess the benefits and safety of direct-acting oral anticoagulants (DOACs).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The failure of randomized trials to show benefit of anticoagulation in ESUS is probably due to misclassification of large artery atherosclerosis (LAA) as ESUS, as defined by a stenosis ≥ 50%. There are important differences among DOACs. There are a number of problems with dabigatran, and rivaroxaban and edoxaban are not suitable for once-daily dosing. Recent evidence from real-world practice indicates that apixaban is more effective and safer than rivaroxaban. Plaque burden should be included in the definition of LAA. Patients in whom a cardioembolic source is strongly suspected should be anticoagulated; antiplatelet agents are not significantly safer than DOACs, and are not effective in cardioembolic stroke.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Science+Business Media, LLC, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Spence</LastName>
            <ForeName>J David</ForeName>
            <Initials>JD</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7478-1098</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Stroke Prevention &amp; Atherosclerosis Research Centre, Robarts Research Institute, Western University, 1400 Western Road, London, ON, N6G 2V4, Canada. dspence@robarts.ca.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>07</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Curr Neurol Neurosci Rep</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>100931790</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1528-4042</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Anticoagulation</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Carotid plaque burden</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Clinical judgement</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cryptogenic stroke</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ESUS</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Misclassification</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Stenosis</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
          <Hour>11</Hour>
          <Minute>21</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35524921</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11910-022-01202-w</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s11910-022-01202-w</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <ReferenceList>
          <Title>Papers of particular interest, published recently, have been highlighted as: • Of importance •• Of major importance</Title>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Hart RG, Diener HC, Coutts SB, Easton JD, Granger CB, O’Donnell MJ, et al. Embolic strokes of undetermined source: the case for a new clinical construct. Lancet Neurol. 2014;13(4):429–38. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1474-4422(13)70310-7 .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1474-4422(13)70310-7</ArticleId>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24646875</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Hart RG, Sharma M, Mundl H, Kasner SE, Bangdiwala SI, Berkowitz SD, et al. Rivaroxaban for stroke prevention after embolic stroke of undetermined source. N Engl J Med. 2018;378(23):2191–201. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMoa1802686 .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1802686</ArticleId>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29766772</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Diener HC, Sacco RL, Easton JD, Granger CB, Bernstein RA, Uchiyama S, et al. Dabigatran for prevention of stroke after embolic stroke of undetermined source. N Engl J Med. 2019;380(20):1906–17. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMoa1813959 .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1813959</ArticleId>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31091372</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Kasner SE, Swaminathan B, Lavados P, Sharma M, Muir K, Veltkamp R, et al. Rivaroxaban or aspirin for patent foramen ovale and embolic stroke of undetermined source: a prespecified subgroup analysis from the NAVIGATE ESUS trial. Lancet Neurol. 2018;17(12):1053–60. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1474-4422(18)30319-3 .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1474-4422(18)30319-3</ArticleId>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30274772</ArticleId>
              <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6662613</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Fuentes B, Gutierrez-Zuniga R, Diez-Tejedor E. It’s time to say goodbye to the ESUS construct. Front Neurol. 2020;11:653. https://doi.org/10.3389/fneur.2020.00653 .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2020.00653</ArticleId>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32733368</ArticleId>
              <ArticleId IdType="pmc">7358305</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Sackett DL, Rosenberg WM, Gray JA, Haynes RB, Richardson WS. Evidence based medicine: what it is and what it isn’t. BMJ. 1996;312(7023):71–2. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.312.7023.71 .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.312.7023.71</ArticleId>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8555924</ArticleId>
              <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2349778</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>• Spence JD. The need for clinical judgement in the application of evidence-based medicine. BMJ Evid Based Med. 2019. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjebm-2019-111300 . This paper discusses the importance of clinical judgement in applying the results of clinical trials to individual patients, and the hazards of relying on flawed trials.</Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Glagov S, Weisenberg E, Zarins CK, Stankunavicius R, Kolettis GJ. Compensatory enlargement of human atherosclerotic coronary arteries. N Engl J Med. 1987;316:1371–5. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJM198705283162204 .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJM198705283162204</ArticleId>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3574413</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Bogiatzi C, Wannarong T, McLeod AI, Heisel M, Hackam D, Spence JD. SPARKLE (Subtypes of Ischaemic Stroke Classification System), incorporating measurement of carotid plaque burden: a new validated tool for the classification of ischemic stroke subtypes. Neuroepidemiology. 2014;42(4):243–51. https://doi.org/10.1159/000362417 .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000362417</ArticleId>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24862944</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Spence JD, Eliasziw M, DiCicco M, Hackam DG, Galil R, Lohmann T. Carotid plaque area: a tool for targeting and evaluating vascular preventive therapy. Stroke. 2002;33(12):2916–22. https://doi.org/10.1161/01.str.0000042207.16156.b9 .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1161/01.str.0000042207.16156.b9</ArticleId>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12468791</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>• Zhang H, Li Z, Dai Y, Guo E, Zhang C, Wang Y. Ischaemic stroke etiological classification system: the agreement analysis of CISS, SPARKLE and TOAST. Stroke Vasc Neurol. 2019;4(3):123–8. https://doi.org/10.1136/svn-2018-000226 . This study reports that the CISS and SPARKLE stroke subtype classifications that include plaque burden in the definition of Large Artery Atherosclerosis (LAA) identify more LAA and fewer ESUS cases.</Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Gao S, Wang YJ, Xu AD, Li YS, Wang DZ. Chinese ischemic stroke subclassification. Front Neurol. 2011;2:6. https://doi.org/10.3389/fneur.2011.00006 .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2011.00006</ArticleId>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21427797</ArticleId>
              <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3052771</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Kamel H, Merkler AE, Iadecola C, Gupta A, Navi BB. Tailoring the approach to embolic stroke of undetermined source: a review. JAMA Neurol. 2019;76(7):855–61. https://doi.org/10.1001/jamaneurol.2019.0591 .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaneurol.2019.0591</ArticleId>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30958521</ArticleId>
              <ArticleId IdType="pmc">8078183</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>•• Kamel H, Navi BB, Merkler AE, Baradaran H, Diaz I, Parikh NS, et al. Reclassification of ischemic stroke etiological subtypes on the basis of high-risk nonstenosing carotid plaque. Stroke. 2020;51(2):504–10. https://doi.org/10.1161/STROKEAHA.119.027970 . This study reports that identifying high-risk plaque by MRI results in reclassification of stroke subtypes, with ESUS patients being reclassified as LAA, and others being classified as multiple causes.</Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>•• Kopczak A, Schindler A, Bayer-Karpinska A, Koch ML, Sepp D, Zeller J, et al. Complicated carotid artery plaques as a cause of cryptogenic stroke. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2020;76(19):2212–22. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacc.2020.09.532 . This study reports that identifying high-risk plaque by MRI results in reclassification of stroke subtypes, with ESUS patients being reclassified as LAA, and others being classified as multiple causes.</Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>• Spence JD. Anticoagulation in patients with embolic stroke of unknown source. Int J Stroke. 2019;14(4):334–6. https://doi.org/10.1177/1747493019826363 . This paper presents the rationale for anticoagulating patients in whom a cardioembolic source is strongly suspected.</Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Ozdemir AO, Tamayo A, Munoz C, Dias B, Spence JD. Cryptogenic stroke and patent foramen ovale: clinical clues to paradoxical embolism. J Neurol Sci. 2008;275(1–2):121–7. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jns.2008.08.018 .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jns.2008.08.018</ArticleId>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18822432</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Ozdemir O, Beletsky V, Hachinski V, Spence JD. Cerebrovascular events on awakening, patent foramen ovale and obstructive sleep apnea syndrome. J Neurol Sci. 2008;268(1–2):193–4. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jns.2007.11.010 .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jns.2007.11.010</ArticleId>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18086476</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Weitz JI, Lensing AWA, Prins MH, Bauersachs R, Beyer-Westendorf J, Bounameaux H, et al. Rivaroxaban or aspirin for extended treatment of venous thromboembolism. N Engl J Med. 2017;376(13):1211–22. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMoa1700518 .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1700518</ArticleId>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28316279</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Connolly SJ, Eikelboom J, Joyner C, Diener HC, Hart R, Golitsyn S, et al. Apixaban in patients with atrial fibrillation. N Engl J Med. 2011;364(9):806–17. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMoa1007432 .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1007432</ArticleId>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21309657</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Deykin D. Thrombogenesis. N Engl J Med. 1967;276(11):622–8. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJM196703162761107 .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJM196703162761107</ArticleId>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6018451</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Caplan LR, Fisher M. The endothelium, platelets, and brain ischemia. Rev Neurol Dis. 2007;4(3):113–21.</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17943063</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Connolly SJ, Eikelboom JW, Ng J, Hirsh J, Yusuf S, Pogue J, et al. Net clinical benefit of adding clopidogrel to aspirin therapy in patients with atrial fibrillation for whom vitamin K antagonists are unsuitable. Ann Intern Med. 2011;155(9):579–86. https://doi.org/10.7326/0003-4819-155-9-201111010-00004 .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7326/0003-4819-155-9-201111010-00004</ArticleId>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22041946</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Lilja JJ, Neuvonen M, Neuvonen PJ. Effects of regular consumption of grapefruit juice on the pharmacokinetics of simvastatin. Br J Clin Pharmacol. 2004;58(1):56–60. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2125.2004.02095.x .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2125.2004.02095.x</ArticleId>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15206993</ArticleId>
              <ArticleId IdType="pmc">1884539</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Lilja JJ, Kivisto KT, Neuvonen PJ. Grapefruit juice increases serum concentrations of atorvastatin and has no effect on pravastatin. Clin Pharmacol Ther. 1999;66(2):118–27. https://doi.org/10.1053/cp.1999.v66.100453001 .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/cp.1999.v66.100453001</ArticleId>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10460065</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Reilly PA, Lehr T, Haertter S, Connolly SJ, Yusuf S, Eikelboom JW, et al. The effect of dabigatran plasma concentrations and patient characteristics on the frequency of ischemic stroke and major bleeding in atrial fibrillation patients: the RE-LY Trial (Randomized Evaluation of Long-Term Anticoagulation Therapy). J Am Coll Cardiol. 2014;63(4):321–8. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jacc.2013.07.104 .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jacc.2013.07.104</ArticleId>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24076487</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>Vrijens B, Heidbuchel H. Non-vitamin K antagonist oral anticoagulants: considerations on once- vs. twice-daily regimens and their potential impact on medication adherence. Europace. 2015;17(4):514–23. https://doi.org/10.1093/europace/euu311 .</Citation>
            <ArticleIdList>
              <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/europace/euu311</ArticleId>
              <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25694538</ArticleId>
            </ArticleIdList>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>• Bonaca MP, Bauersachs RM, Anand SS, Debus ES, Nehler MR, Patel MR, et al. Rivaroxaban in peripheral artery disease after revascularization. N Engl J Med. 2020;382(21):1994–2004. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJMoa2000052 . This paper shows that rivaroxaban is now taken twice daily.</Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>•• Ray WA, Chung CP, Stein CM, Smalley W, Zimmerman E, Dupont WD, et al. Association of rivaroxaban vs apixaban with major ischemic or hemorrhagic events in patients with atrial fibrillation. JAMA. 2021;326(23):2395–404. https://doi.org/10.1001/jama.2021.21222 . This study reports that apixaban reduces more cardiovascular events and causes less bleeding than rivaroxaban.</Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>•• Fralick M, Colacci M, Schneeweiss S, Huybrechts KF, Lin KJ, Gagne JJ. Effectiveness and safety of apixaban compared with rivaroxaban for patients with atrial fibrillation in routine practice: a cohort study. Ann Intern Med. 2020. https://doi.org/10.7326/M19-2522 . This study reports that apixaban reduces more cardiovascular events and causes less bleeding than rivaroxaban.</Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>•• Zhou M, Azarpazhooh MR, Spence JD, Hashem S, Ma W, Cheng X, et al. Deep learning-based carotid plaque segmentation from B-mode ultrasound images. Ultrasound in Medicine and Biology. 2021;online June 30. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ultrasmedbio.2021.05.023 . This study reports a new highly reproducible and fast automated method for measuring carotid plaque burden, that will make it easier to add plaque burden to the definition of Large Artery Atherosclerosis.</Citation>
          </Reference>
          <Reference>
            <Citation>•• Zhou R, Guo F, Azarpazhooh MR, Hashemi S, Cheng X, Spence JD, et al. Deep learning-based measurement of total plaque area in B-mode ultrasound images. IEEE J Biomed Health Inform. 2021;25(8):2967–77. https://doi.org/10.1109/JBHI.2021.3060163 . This study reports a new highly reproducible and fast automated method for measuring carotid plaque burden that will make it easier to add plaque burden to the definition of large artery atherosclerosis.</Citation>
          </Reference>
        </ReferenceList>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
