<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35529889</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>10</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2667-3215</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>2</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Dec</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>SSM. Qualitative research in health</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>SSM Qual Res Health</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Migrants as 'vulnerable groups' in the COVID-19 pandemic: A critical discourse analysis of a taken-for-granted label in academic literature.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>100076</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>100076</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.ssmqr.2022.100076</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The COVID-19 pandemic affects different people unequally, and migrants are frequently among the groups considered particularly vulnerable. However, conceptualizations of 'vulnerability' are often ambiguous and poorly defined. Using critical discourse analysis methods, this article analyses the academic use of the term 'vulnerable' applied to migrants in the context of the COVID-19 pandemic across public health and social science disciplines. Our findings indicate that the concept of vulnerability is frequently applied to migrants in the COVID-19 context as a descriptor with seemingly taken-for-granted applicability. Migrants are considered vulnerable for a wide variety of reasons, most commonly relating to exposure to and risk of contracting COVID-19; poverty or low socio-economic status; precarity; access to healthcare; discrimination; and language barriers. Drivers of migrants' vulnerability were frequently construed as immutable societal characteristics. Additionally, our analysis revealed widespread generalization in the use of the notion of vulnerability, with limited consideration of the heterogeneity among and between diverse groups of migrants. Conceptualizations of migrants' vulnerability in the COVID-19 pandemic were sometimes used to advance seemingly contradictory policy implications or conclusions, and migrants' own views and lived experiences were often marginalized or excluded within these discourses. Our analysis highlights that although some definable groups of people are certainly more likely to suffer harm in crisis situations like the COVID-19 pandemic, the use of 'vulnerable' as a fixed descriptor has potentially negative implications. As an alternative, we suggest thinking about vulnerability as the dynamic outcome of a process of 'vulnerabilisation' shaped by social order and power relations.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Molenaar</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jil</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Centre for Migration and Intercultural Studies (CeMIS), University of Antwerp, Stadscampus, S.LN55.202, Lange Nieuwstraat 55, B-2000, Antwerp, Belgium.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Van Praag</LastName>
            <ForeName>Lore</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Centre for Migration and Intercultural Studies (CeMIS), University of Antwerp, Stadscampus, S.LN55.202, Lange Nieuwstraat 55, B-2000, Antwerp, Belgium.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>04</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>SSM Qual Res Health</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9918300877606676</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2667-3215</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Critical discourse analysis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Migrants</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Power</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Vulnerability</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
          <Hour>4</Hour>
          <Minute>16</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35529889</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9052635</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ssmqr.2022.100076</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">S2667-3215(22)00038-5</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Anderson B., Blinder S.  The Migration Observatory at the University of Oxford; 2019. Who Counts as a migrant? Definitions and their consequences [Briefing]https://migrationobservatory.ox.ac.uk/resources/briefings/who-counts-as-a-migrant-definitions-and-their-consequences/</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bambra C., Riordan R., Ford J., Matthews F. The COVID-19 pandemic and health inequalities. Journal of Epidemiology &amp; Community Health. 2020;74(11):964–968. doi: 10.1136/jech-2020-214401.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jech-2020-214401</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7298201</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32535550</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brown K. ‘Vulnerability’: Handle with care. Ethics and Social Welfare. 2011;5(3):313–321. doi: 10.1080/17496535.2011.597165.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/17496535.2011.597165</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Burton-Jeangros C., Duvoisin A., Lachat S., Consoli L., Fakhoury J., Jackson Y. The impact of the Covid-19 pandemic and the lockdown on the health and living conditions of undocumented migrants and migrants undergoing legal status regularization. Frontiers in Public Health. 2020;8:940. doi: 10.3389/fpubh.2020.596887.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2020.596887</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Butler J.  Routledge; London and New York: 2004. Undoing gender.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Butler J. Performativity, precarity and sexual politics. AIBR: Revista de Antropología Iberoamericana. 2009;4(3):i–xiii. doi: 10.11156/aibr.040305.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11156/aibr.040305</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Castañeda H., Holmes S.M., Madrigal D.S., Young M.-E.D., Beyeler N., Quesada J. Immigration as a social determinant of health. Annual Review of Public Health. 2015;36(1):375–392. doi: 10.1146/annurev-publhealth-032013-182419.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev-publhealth-032013-182419</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clark E., Fredricksid K., Woc-Colburn L., Bottazzi M.E., Weatherheadid J. Disproportionate impact of the COVID-19 pandemic on immigrant communities in the United States. PLoS Neglected Tropical Diseases. 2020;14(7):1–9. doi: 10.1371/journal.pntd.0008484.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pntd.0008484</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Colindres C., Cohen A., Susana Caxaj C. Migrant agricultural workers’ health, safety and access to protections: A descriptive survey identifying structural gaps and vulnerabilities in the interior of British Columbia, Canada. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health. 2021;18(7) doi: 10.3390/ijerph18073696.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph18073696</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cramarenco R.E. On migrants and COVID-19 pandemic—an analysis. On-line Journal Modelling the New Europe. 2020;23:1–21. doi: 10.24193/OJMNE.2020.34.05.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.24193/OJMNE.2020.34.05</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cross F.L., Gonzalez Benson O. The coronavirus pandemic and immigrant communities: A crisis that demands more of the social work profession. Affilia - Journal of Women and Social Work. 2021;36(1):113–119. doi: 10.1177/0886109920960832.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0886109920960832</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cukier W., Bauer R., Middleton C.  In: Information systems research: Relevant theory and informed practice. Kaplan B., Truex D.P., Wastell D., Wood-Harper A.T., DeGross J.I., editors. Springer US; 2004. Applying Habermas' validity claims as a standard for critical discourse analysis; pp. 233–258.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/1-4020-8095-6_14</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cukier W., Ngwenyama O., Bauer R., Middleton C. A critical analysis of media discourse on information technology: Preliminary results of a proposed method for critical discourse analysis. Information Systems Journal. 2009;19(2):175–196. doi: 10.1111/j.1365-2575.2008.00296.x.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2575.2008.00296.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dant T.  Routledge; London and New York: 1991. Knowledge, ideology, and discourse: A sociological perspective.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Nardi S., Phillips M. The plight of racialised minorities during a pandemic: Migrants and refugees in Italy and Australia. Equality, Diversity and Inclusion. 2021 doi: 10.1108/EDI-08-2020-0248. Scopus.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/EDI-08-2020-0248</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Denzin N.K., Lincoln Y.S.  The Sage handbook of qualitative research. 3rd ed. Sage Publications Ltd; London: 2005. Introduction: The discipline and practice of qualitative research; pp. 1–32.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van Dijk T.A. Aims of critical discourse analysis. Japanese Discourse. 1995;1:17–27.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van Dijk T.A. Discourse semantics and ideology. Discourse &amp; Society. 1995;6(2):243–289. doi: 10.1177/0957926595006002006.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0957926595006002006</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elisabeth M., Maneesh P.-S., Michael S. Refugees in Sweden during the Covid-19 Pandemic—the need for a new perspective on health and integration. Frontiers in Public Health. 2020 doi: 10.3389/fpubh.2020.574334. 8. Scopus.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpubh.2020.574334</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fairclough N.  2nd ed. Routledge; London and New York: 2013. Critical discourse analysis: The critical study of language.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Falicov C., Niño A., D’Urso S. Expanding possibilities: Flexibility and solidarity with under-resourced immigrant families during the COVID-19 pandemic. Family Process. 2020;59(3):865–882. doi: 10.1111/famp.12578.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/famp.12578</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7405176</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32663315</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Falkenhain M., Flick U., Hirseland A., Naji S., Seidelsohn K., Verlage T. Setback in labour market integration due to the Covid-19 crisis? An explorative insight on forced migrants’ vulnerability in Germany. European Societies. 2021;23(S1):S448–S463. doi: 10.1080/14616696.2020.1828976.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14616696.2020.1828976</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fassani F., Mazza J.  Publications Office of the European Union Luxembourg; 2020. A vulnerable workforce: Migrant workers in the COVID-19 pandemic.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fineman M. The vulnerable subject: Anchoring equality in the human condition. Yale Journal of Law and Feminism. 2008;20(1) https://digitalcommons.law.yale.edu/yjlf/vol20/iss1/2</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fleck L.  University of Chicago Press; 1979. Genesis and development of a scientific fact.https://press.uchicago.edu/ucp/books/book/chicago/G/bo25676016.html</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Forester J.  In: Beyond method: Strategies for social research. Morgan G., editor. Sage; London: 1983. Critical theory and organizational analysis; pp. 234–346.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Foucault M.  1st ed. Pantheon Books; 1970. The Order of Things: An archaeology of the human sciences.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4324/9781315660301</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garoon J.P., Duggan P.S. Discourses of disease, discourses of disadvantage: A critical analysis of national pandemic influenza preparedness plans. Social Science &amp; Medicine. 2008;67(7):1133–1142. doi: 10.1016/j.socscimed.2008.06.020.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.socscimed.2008.06.020</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18656294</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gkiouleka A., Huijts T. Intersectional migration-related health inequalities in Europe: Exploring the role of migrant generation, occupational status &amp; gender. Social Science &amp; Medicine. 2020;267:113218. doi: 10.1016/j.socscimed.2020.113218.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.socscimed.2020.113218</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32732096</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Greenaway C., Hargreaves S., Barkati S., Coyle C.M., Gobbi F., Veizis A., Douglas P. COVID-19: Exposing and addressing health disparities among ethnic minorities and migrants. Journal of Travel Medicine. 2021;27(7) doi: 10.1093/JTM/TAAA113.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/JTM/TAAA113</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grotti V., Malakasis C., Quagliariello C., Sahraoui N. Shifting vulnerabilities: Gender and reproductive care on the migrant trail to Europe. Comparative Migration Studies. 2018;6(1):23. doi: 10.1186/s40878-018-0089-z.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40878-018-0089-z</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6061107</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30101080</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Habermas J.  Beacon Press; Boston: 1984. The theory of communicative action: Reason and the rationalization of society.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Habermas J.  MIT Press; 2003. Truth and justification. B. Fultner, Trans.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hammersley M. Conversation analysis and discourse analysis: Methods or paradigms? Discourse &amp; Society. 2003;14(6):751–781. doi: 10.1177/09579265030146004.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/09579265030146004</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harrison M., Sanders T.  In: Supporting safer communities: Housing, crime and neighbourhoods. Newburn T., Dearling A., Somerville P., editors. Chartered Institute of Housing; 2006. Vulnerable people and the development of “regulatory therapy; pp. 155–168.http://www.cih.org/</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>IOM  . International Organization for Migration; 2019. Glossary on migration (No. 34)https://www.iom.int/glossary-migration-2019</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jara-Labarthé V., Cisneros Puebla C.A.… Migrants in Chile: Social crisis and the pandemic (or sailing over troubled water) Qualitative Social Work. 2021;20(1–2):284–288. doi: 10.1177/1473325020973363.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1473325020973363</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8261345</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34253973</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jayaweera H., Anderson B.  Centre on Migration, Policy and Society; 2008. Migrant workers and vulnerable employment: A review of existing data.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jones S., Tvedten I. What does it mean to be poor? Investigating the qualitative-quantitative divide in Mozambique. World Development. 2019;117:153–166. doi: 10.1016/j.worlddev.2019.01.005.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.worlddev.2019.01.005</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Katz A.S., Hardy B.-J., Firestone M., Lofters A., Morton-Ninomiya M.E. Vagueness, power and public health: Use of ‘vulnerable‘ in public health literature. Critical Public Health. 2020;30(5):601–611. doi: 10.1080/09581596.2019.1656800.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/09581596.2019.1656800</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kawachi I. COVID-19 and the ‘rediscovery’ of health inequities. International Journal of Epidemiology. 2020;49(5):1415–1418. doi: 10.1093/ije/dyaa159.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ije/dyaa159</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7543525</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32974663</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kline N.S. Rethinking COVID-19 vulnerability: A call for LGTBQ+ Im/migrant health equity in the United States during and after a pandemic. Health Equity. 2020;4(1):239–242. doi: 10.1089/heq.2020.0012.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/heq.2020.0012</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7310200</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32587935</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krieger N. Epidemiology and the web of causation: Has anyone seen the spider? Social Science &amp; Medicine. 1994;39(7):887–903. doi: 10.1016/0277-9536(94)90202-X.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0277-9536(94)90202-X</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7992123</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kuhn T.S.  4th ed. University of Chicago Press; 2012. The structure of scientific revolutions.https://press.uchicago.edu/ucp/books/book/chicago/S/bo13179781.html</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lansdown G.  In: Children's childhoods: Observed and experienced. Mayall B., editor. Psychology Press; 1994. Childrens rights; pp. 33–45.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maďarová Z., Hardoš P., Ostertágová A. What makes life grievable? Discursive distribution of vulnerability in the pandemic. Czech Journal of International Relations. 2020;55(4):11–30. doi: 10.32422/mv-cjir.1737.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.32422/mv-cjir.1737</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martuscelli P.N.  American Behavioral Scientist; 2021. How are forcibly displaced people affected by the COVID-19 pandemic outbreak? Evidence from Brazil.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mboya A. Vulnerability and the climate change regime. UCLA Journal of Environmental Law and Policy. 2018;36(1) https://escholarship.org/uc/item/5zx443v9</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Molobe I.D., Odukoya O.O., Isikekpei B.C., Marsiglia F.F. Migrant communities and the COVID-19 response in sub-Saharan Africa. The Pan African Medical Journal. 2020;35(Suppl 2) doi: 10.11604/pamj.supp.2020.35.2.22863.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11604/pamj.supp.2020.35.2.22863</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Munari S.C., Wilson A.N., Blow N.J., Homer C.S.E., Ward J.E. Rethinking the use of ‘vulnerable. Australian &amp; New Zealand Journal of Public Health. 2021 doi: 10.1111/1753-6405.13098. n/a(n/a)</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1753-6405.13098</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>OECD  . Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development; 2021. International migration outlook 2021.https://www.oecd-ilibrary.org/social-issues-migration-health/international-migration-outlook-2021_29f23e9d-en</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Orcutt M., Patel P., Burns R., Hiam L., Aldridge R., Devakumar D., Kumar B., Spiegel P., Abubakar I. Global call to action for inclusion of migrants and refugees in the COVID-19 response. The Lancet. 2020;395(10235):1482–1483. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30971-5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30971-5</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Page M.J., McKenzie J.E., Bossuyt P.M., Boutron I., Hoffmann T.C., Mulrow C.D., Shamseer L., Tetzlaff J.M., Akl E.A., Brennan S.E., Chou R., Glanville J., Grimshaw J.M., Hróbjartsson A., Lalu M.M., Li T., Loder E.W., Mayo-Wilson E., McDonald S., Moher D. The PRISMA 2020 statement: An updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. PLoS Medicine. 2021;18(3) doi: 10.1371/journal.pmed.1003583.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pmed.1003583</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parmar A. Panic publishing: An unwarranted consequence of the COVID-19 pandemic. Psychiatry Research. 2020;294:113525. doi: 10.1016/j.psychres.2020.113525.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psychres.2020.113525</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7577937</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33142146</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Phillips T.  The Guardian; 2021. ‘Hunger has returned’: Covid piles further misery on Brazil's vulnerable.http://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jul/22/brazil-rio-coronavirus-hunger-poverty July 22.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Quandt S.A., LaMonto N.J., Mora D.C., Talton J.W., Laurienti P.J., Arcury T.A. COVID-19 pandemic among immigrant Latinx farmworker and non-farmworker families: A Rural–Urban comparison of economic, educational, healthcare, and immigration concerns. New Solutions. 2021;31(1):30–47. doi: 10.1177/1048291121992468.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1048291121992468</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8899720</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33557699</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ralli M., Cedola C., Urbano S., Morrone A., Ercoli L. Homeless persons and migrants in precarious housing conditions and COVID-19 pandemic: Peculiarities and prevention strategies. European Review for Medical and Pharmacological Sciences. 2020;24(18):9765–9767. doi: 10.26355/eurrev_202009_23071.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.26355/eurrev_202009_23071</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33015824</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rodriguez J.D. The relevance of the ethics of vulnerability in bioethics. Les Ateliers de l’Éthique/the Ethics Forum. 2017;12(2–3):154–179. doi: 10.7202/1051280ar.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7202/1051280ar</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sahin O., Salim H., Suprun E., Richards R., MacAskill S., Heilgeist S., Rutherford S., Stewart R.A., Beal C.D. Developing a preliminary causal loop diagram for understanding the wicked complexity of the COVID-19 pandemic. Systems. 2020;8(2):20. doi: 10.3390/systems8020020.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/systems8020020</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sanfelici M. The impact of the COVID-19 crisis on marginal migrant populations in Italy. American Behavioral Scientist. 2021;65(10):1323–1341.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Serafini R.A., Powell S.K., Frere J.J., Saali A., Krystal H.L., Kumar V., Katz C.L. Psychological distress in the face of a pandemic: An observational study characterizing the impact of COVID-19 on immigrant outpatient mental health. Psychiatry Research. 2021;295 doi: 10.1016/j.psychres.2020.113595.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psychres.2020.113595</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith J.A., Basabose J.D., Brockett M., Browne D.T., Shamon S., Stephenson M. Family medicine with refugee newcomers during the COVID-19 pandemic. The Journal of the American Board of Family Medicine : JABFM. 2021;34:S210–S216. doi: 10.3122/jabfm.2021.S1.200115.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3122/jabfm.2021.S1.200115</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33622840</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sözer H. Categories that blind us, categories that bind them: The deployment of vulnerability notion for Syrian refugees in Turkey. Journal of Refugee Studies. 2019 doi: 10.1093/jrs/fez020.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jrs/fez020</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Spiritus-Beerden E., Verelst A., Devlieger I., Langer Primdahl N., Botelho Guedes F., Chiarenza A., De Maesschalck S., Durbeej N., Garrido R., Gaspar de Matos M., Ioannidi E., Murphy R., Oulahal R., Osman F., Padilla B., Paloma V., Shehadeh A., Sturm G., van den Muijsenbergh M., Derluyn I. Mental health of refugees and migrants during the COVID-19 pandemic: The role of experienced discrimination and daily stressors. International Journal of Environmental Research and Public Health. 2021;18(12):6354. doi: 10.3390/ijerph18126354.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijerph18126354</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8296172</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34208243</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stevens P., A.J., Dworkin A.G.  The Palgrave handbook of race and ethnic inequalities in education. Palgrave Macmillan; 2019. Researching race and ethnic inequalities in education: Key findings and future directions; pp. 1237–1270.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tagliacozzo S., Pisacane L., Kilkey M. The interplay between structural and systemic vulnerability during the COVID-19 pandemic: Migrant agricultural workers in informal settlements in Southern Italy. Journal of Ethnic and Migration Studies. 2021;47(9) doi: 10.1080/1369183X.2020.1857230.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/1369183X.2020.1857230</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>The Lancet COVID-19 will not leave behind refugees and migrants. The Lancet. 2020;395(10230):1090. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30758-3.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30758-3</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thurner S., Hanel R., Klimek P.  Oxford University Press; Oxford: 2018. Introduction to the theory of complex systems.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ullah A.A., Nawaz F., Chattoraj D. Locked up under lockdown: The COVID-19 pandemic and the migrant population. Social Sciences &amp; Humanities Open. 2021;3(1):100126. doi: 10.1016/j.ssaho.2021.100126.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ssaho.2021.100126</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7985246</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34173510</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>UN Global Compact  . 2020, April 29. COVID-19 and human rights: Protecting the most vulnerable. UN global Compact academy.https://unglobalcompact.org/academy/covid-19-and-human-rights-protecting-the-most-vulnerable</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vladeck B.C. How useful is ‘Vulnerable’ as A concept? Health Affairs. 2007;26(5):1231–1234. doi: 10.1377/hlthaff.26.5.1231.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1377/hlthaff.26.5.1231</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17848430</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wall J., Stahl B., Salam A. Critical discourse analysis as a review methodology: An empirical example. Communications of the Association for Information Systems. 2015;37 doi: 10.17705/1CAIS.03711.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17705/1CAIS.03711</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang F., Tian C., Qin W. The impact of epidemic infectious diseases on the wellbeing of migrant workers: A systematic review. International Journal of Wellbeing. 2020;10(3) https://www.internationaljournalofwellbeing.org/index.php/ijow/article/view/1301 Article 3.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wishart G. The sexual abuse of people with learning difficulties: Do we need a social model approach to vulnerability? The Journal of Adult Protection. 2003;5(3):14–27. doi: 10.1108/14668203200300021.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/14668203200300021</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wodak R.  1st ed. Longman; London: 1996. Disorders of discourse.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zarowsky C., Haddad S., Nguyen V.-K. Beyond ‘vulnerable groups’: Contexts and dynamics of vulnerability. Global Health Promotion. 2013;20(1_suppl):3–9. doi: 10.1177/1757975912470062.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1757975912470062</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
