<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35523920</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>06</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1867-108X</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>07</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Japanese journal of radiology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Jpn J Radiol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Clinical utility of computed tomography-based evaluation of trunk muscles in primary sclerosing cholangitis.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s11604-022-01283-0</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Sarcopenia is well recognized as a prognostic factor of chronic liver diseases. However, its impact on the clinical course of primary sclerosing cholangitis (PSC) is unclear. This study aimed to clarify the importance of trunk muscles evaluated by computed tomography (CT) in the pathophysiology of patients with PSC.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="MATERIALS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">22 PSC patients (12 men, mean age 42.8 years) were enrolled in this study. Patients who died of hepatic failure or had to receive liver transplantation were defined as event group. 44 age- and gender-matched individuals without hepatic disorder were served as controls. At the level of third lumbar vertebrae, the area of psoas muscle and trunk muscle as well as the CT values of multifidus muscle and subcutaneous fat were evaluated. Based on these, skeletal muscle index (SMI), psoas muscle mass index (PMI) and intramuscular adipose tissue content (IMAC) were calculated. Then we analyzed the relationship between these parameters and laboratory data, Fibrosis-4 index, MELD score and Mayo risk score.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">At baseline evaluation, SMI and PMI were statistically lower in male PSC patients compared with those in controls (P &lt; 0.05). In male PSC, regarding the laboratory data, PMI was associated with total bilirubin, ALT, ALP, and platelet count (P &lt; 0.05). We found close relationship between PMI and MELD score (R<sup>2</sup> = 0.42, P = 0.02). PMI also decreased statistically in male Event group than in non-event group (4.85 vs 7.20, P = 0.01).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Skeletal muscle mass evaluated by CT scan can be suitable for evaluating clinical and prognostic marker in male PSC.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022. The Author(s) under exclusive licence to Japan Radiological Society.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kikuchi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yuka</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of General Internal Medicine, Hiroshima University Hospital, 1-2-3 Kasumi, Minami-ku, Hiroshima-shi, Hiroshima, 734-8551, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Miyamori</LastName>
            <ForeName>Daisuke</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of General Internal Medicine, Hiroshima University Hospital, 1-2-3 Kasumi, Minami-ku, Hiroshima-shi, Hiroshima, 734-8551, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kanno</LastName>
            <ForeName>Keishi</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3133-7154</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of General Internal Medicine, Hiroshima University Hospital, 1-2-3 Kasumi, Minami-ku, Hiroshima-shi, Hiroshima, 734-8551, Japan. kkanno@hiroshima-u.ac.jp.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tazuma</LastName>
            <ForeName>Susumu</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology, JA Onomichi General Hospital, Hiroshima, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kimura</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hiroaki</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Rehabilitation Medicine, Hiroshima University Hospital, Hiroshima, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yoshimura</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kenichi</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Medical Center for Translational and Clinical Research, Hiroshima University, Hiroshima, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Serikawa</LastName>
            <ForeName>Masahiro</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Gastroenterology and Metabolism, Graduate School of Biomedical and Health Science, Hiroshima University, Hiroshima, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chayama</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kazuaki</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Collaborative Research Laboratory of Medical Innovation, Graduate School of Biomedical and Health Sciences, Hiroshima University, Hiroshima, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ito</LastName>
            <ForeName>Masanori</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of General Internal Medicine, Hiroshima University Hospital, 1-2-3 Kasumi, Minami-ku, Hiroshima-shi, Hiroshima, 734-8551, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>07</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>Japan</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Jpn J Radiol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101490689</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1867-1071</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Muscular atrophy</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Primary sclerosing cholangitis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Psoas muscle</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Skeletal muscle</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
          <Hour>23</Hour>
          <Minute>24</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35523920</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11604-022-01283-0</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s11604-022-01283-0</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Isayama H, Tazuma S, Kokudo N, Tanaka A, Tsuyuguchi T, Nakazawa T, et al. PSC guideline committee Members: Ministry of Health, Labour and Welfare (Japan) Research Project, The Intractable Hepatobiliary Disease Study Group. Clinical guidelines for primary sclerosing cholangitis 2017. J Gastroenterol 2018;53:1006–34.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tanaka A, Takikawa H. Geoepidemiology of primary sclerosing cholangitis: a critical review. J Autoimmun. 2013;46:35–40.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jaut.2013.07.005</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Karlsen TH, Folseraas T, Thorburn D, Vesterhus M. Primary sclerosing cholangitis—a comprehensive review. J Hepatol. 2017;67:1298–323.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhep.2017.07.022</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rosenberg IH. Sarcopenia: origins and clinical relevance. J Nutr. 1997;127(5 Suppl):990S-S991.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jn/127.5.990S</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Englesbe MJ, Patel SP, He K, Lynch RJ, Schaubel DE, Harbaugh C, et al. Sarcopenia and mortality after liver transplantation. J Am Coll Surg. 2010;211:271–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jamcollsurg.2010.03.039</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tandon P, Ney M, Irwin I, Ma MM, Gramlich L, Bain VG, et al. Severe muscle depletion in patients on the liver transplant wait list: its prevalence and independent prognostic value. Liver Transpl. 2012;18:1209–16.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/lt.23495</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koo BK, Kim D, Joo SK, Kim JH, Chang MS, Kim BG, et al. Sarcopenia is an independent risk factor for non-alcoholic steatohepatitis and significant fibrosis. J Hepatol. 2017;66:123–31.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhep.2016.08.019</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cruz-Jentoft AJ, Baeyens JP, Bauer JM, Boirie Y, Cederholm T, Landi F, et al. Sarcopenia: European consensus on definition and diagnosis. Age Ageing. 2010;39:412–23.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ageing/afq034</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muscaritoli M, Anker SD, Argilés J, Aversa Z, Bauer JM, Biolo G, et al. Consensus definition of sarcopenia, cachexia and pre-cachexia: joint document elaborated by Special Interest Groups (SIG) “cachexia-anorexia in chronic wasting diseases” and “nutrition in geriatrics.” Clin Nutr. 2010;29:154–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clnu.2009.12.004</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen LK, Liu LK, Woo J, Assantachai P, Auyeung TW, Bahyah KS, et al. Sarcopenia in Asia: consensus report of the Asian Working Group for Sarcopenia. J Am Med Dir Assoc. 2014;15:95–101.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jamda.2013.11.025</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dasarathy S, Merli M. Sarcopenia from mechanism to diagnosis and treatment in liver disease. J Hepatol. 2016;65:1232–44.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhep.2016.07.040</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Albano D, Messina C, Vitale J, Sconfienza LM. Imaging of sarcopenia: old evidence and new insights. Eur Radiol. 2020;30:2199–208.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00330-019-06573-2</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kitajima Y, Hyogo H, Sumida Y, Eguchi Y, Ono N, Kuwashiro T, et al. Severity of non-alcoholic steatohepatitis is associated with substitution of adipose tissue in skeletal muscle. J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2013;28:1507–14.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jgh.12227</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hamaguchi Y, Kaido T, Okumura S, Fujimoto Y, Ogawa K, Mori A, et al. Impact of quality as well as quantity of skeletal muscle on outcomes after liver transplantation. Liver Transpl. 2014;20:1413–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/lt.23970</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nishikawa H, Shiraki M, Hiramatsu A, Moriya K, Hino K, Nishiguchi S. Japan Society of Hepatology guidelines for sarcopenia in liver disease (1st edition): recommendation from the working group for creation of sarcopenia assessment criteria. Hepatol Res. 2016;46:951–63.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/hepr.12774</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cruz-Jentoft AJ, Bahat G, Bauer J, Boirie Y, Bruyère O, Cederholm T, et al. Sarcopenia: revised European consensus on definition and diagnosis. Age Ageing. 2019;48:16–31.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30312372</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vallet-Pichard A, Mallet V, Nalpas B, Verkarre V, Nalpas A, Dhalluin-Venier V, et al. FIB-4: an inexpensive and accurate marker of fibrosis in HCV infection. Comparison with liver biopsy and fibrotest. Hepatology. 2007;46:32–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hep.21669</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shah A, Lydecker A, Murray K, Tetri BN, Contos MJ, Sanyal AJ. NASH Clinical Research Network. Comparison of noninvasive markers of fibrosis in patients with nonalcoholic fatty liver disease. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol 2009;7:1104–12.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shetty K, Rybicki L, Carey WD. The Child-Pugh classification as a prognostic indicator for survival in primary sclerosing cholangitis. Hepatology. 1997;25:1049–53.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hep.510250501</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kamath PS, Kim WR. Advanced Liver Disease Study Group. The model for end-stage liver disease (MELD). Hepatology. 2007;45:797–805.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hep.21563</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim WR, Therneau TM, Wiesner RH, Poterucha JJ, Benson JT, Malinchoc M, et al. A revised natural history model for primary sclerosing cholangitis. Mayo Clin Proc. 2000;75:688–94.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0025-6196(11)64614-4</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Misu H, Takayama H, Saito Y, Mita Y, Kikuchi A, Ishii KA, et al. Deficiency of the hepatokine selenoprotein P increases responsiveness to exercise in mice through upregulation of reactive oxygen species and AMP-activated protein kinase in muscle. Nat Med. 2017;23:508–16.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nm.4295</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hamaguchi Y, Kaido T, Okumura S, Kobayashi A, Hammad A, Tamai Y, et al. Proposal for new selection criteria considering pre-transplant muscularity and visceral adiposity in living donor liver transplantation. J Cachexia Sarcopenia Muscle. 2018;9:246–54.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcsm.12276</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hamaguchi Y, Kaido T, Okumura S, Kobayashi A, Shirai H, Yagi S, et al. Impact of skeletal muscle mass index, intramuscular adipose tissue content, and visceral to subcutaneous adipose tissue area ratio on early mortality of living donor liver transplantation. Transplantation. 2017;101:565–74.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/TP.0000000000001587</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huguet A, Latournerie M, Debry PH, Jezequel C, Legros L, Rayar M, et al. The psoas muscle transversal diameter predicts mortality in patients with cirrhosis on a waiting list for liver transplantation: a retrospective cohort study. Nutrition. 2018;51–2:73–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nut.2018.01.008</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hamaguchi Y, Kaido T, Okumura S, Kobayashi A, Hammad A, Tamai Y, et al. Proposal for new diagnostic criteria for low skeletal muscle mass based on computed tomography imaging in Asian adults. Nutrition. 2016;32:1200–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nut.2016.04.003</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Masuda T, Shirabe K, Ikegami T, Harimoto N, Yoshizumi T, Soejima Y, et al. Sarcopenia is a prognostic factor in living donor liver transplantation. Liver Transpl. 2014;20:401–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/lt.23811</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Durand F, Buyse S, Francoz C, et al. Prognostic value of muscle atrophy in cirrhosis using psoas muscle thickness on computed tomography. J Hepatol. 2014;60:1151–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhep.2014.02.026</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tanimoto Y, Watanabe M, Kono R, Hirota C, Takasaki K, Kono K. Aging changes in muscle mass of Japanese. Jpn J Geriatr. 2010;47:52–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3143/geriatrics.47.52</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yamada Y, Kimura M, Nakamura E, Masuo Y, Oda S. Limb muscle mass decrease with aging in Japanese men and women aged 15–97yr. Jpn J Phys Fit Sports Med. 2007;56:461–72.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Takayama K, Kita T, Nakamura H, Kanematsu F, Yasunami T, Sakanaka H, et al. New predictive index for lumbar paraspinal muscle degeneration associated with aging. Spine (Phila Pa 1976). 2016;41:E84-90.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/BRS.0000000000001154</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kjaer P, Bendix T, Sorensen J, Korsholm L, Leboeuf-Yde C. Are MRI-defined fat infiltrations in the multifidus muscles associated with low back pain? BMC Med. 2007;5:2.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1741-7015-5-2</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang C, Bai L. Sarcopenia in the elderly: basic and clinical issues. Geriatr Gerontol Int. 2012;12:388–96.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1447-0594.2012.00851.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
