<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35526163</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>10</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>11</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">1082-6742</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>36</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of avian medicine and surgery</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Avian Med Surg</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Effect of the Prolactin Inhibitor Cabergoline and the Gonadotropin Releasing-Hormone Agonist Deslorelin in the Suppression of Plasma Prolactin Concentrations and Egg Laying in Quail (<i>Coturnix japonica</i>).</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>39</StartPage>
          <EndPage>52</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>39-52</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1647/20-00075</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Egg binding and excessive laying frequently affect avian patients, and in many cases the treatment includes suppression of egg production. Currently, for the suppression of egg production in avian patients, a gonadotropin-releasing hormone agonist, in the form of a deslorelin implant, is often used. However, the commercially available deslorelin implants have an undesired delayed onset, as well as a potential brief increase in gonadotropin secretion after administration ("flare-up" effect) that can lead to oviposition before the actual suppression of gonadotropins. The objective of this study was to investigate whether the prolactin inhibitor cabergoline suppresses ovulation and whether it could be used to bridge the time until the onset of effect by the deslorelin implant. We measured the effect of cabergoline (30 µg/kg PO q24h × 14 days), deslorelin implants (4.7 mg SC), and a combination of both on egg laying and plasma prolactin concentrations in 37 quail (<i>Coturnix japonica</i>) over 6 weeks. Quail were divided into 4 groups: group DesCab (deslorelin implant and cabergoline oral; n = 9); group DesPlac (deslorelin implant and placebo oral; n = 9); group PlacCab (placebo implant and cabergoline oral; n = 9); and group PlacPlac (placebo implant and placebo oral; n = 10). Regular egg laying stopped in 100% (9/9) of birds in group DesCab and 78% (7/ 9) of birds in group DesPlac within 5 days of placing the deslorelin implant. No bird ceased egg production in group PlacCab (0/9), and 10% of birds ceased egg production intermittently in group PlacPlac (1/10). Treatment with the deslorelin implant (<i>P</i> &lt; .001) and with cabergoline (<i>P</i> = .04) had a significant (negative) influence on plasma prolactin concentrations compared with the baseline. The interaction of deslorelin and cabergoline treatment, as well as time after initiation of treatment, did not have a significant effect on plasma prolactin concentrations. These results show that daily oral cabergoline has no significant influence on egg laying and only a minor biologically nonsignificant effect on lowering the relative plasma prolactin concentrations in quail.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Rückl</LastName>
            <ForeName>Anna</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Clinic for Zoo Animals, Exotic Pets and Wildlife, Vetsuisse Faculty, University of Zurich, 8057 Zurich, Switzerland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Thompson</LastName>
            <ForeName>Donald L</ForeName>
            <Initials>DL</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Animal Sciences, Animal and Food Sciences Lab, Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, LA 70803, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hatt</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jean-Michel</ForeName>
            <Initials>JM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Clinic for Zoo Animals, Exotic Pets and Wildlife, Vetsuisse Faculty, University of Zurich, 8057 Zurich, Switzerland, jmhatt@vetclinics.uzh.ch.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D000081262">Randomized Controlled Trial, Veterinary</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Avian Med Surg</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9512497</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1082-6742</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>08AN7WA2G0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D017329">Triptorelin Pamoate</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>9002-62-4</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D011388">Prolactin</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>LL60K9J05T</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000077465">Cabergoline</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>TKG3I66TVE</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="C066438">deslorelin</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000077465" MajorTopicYN="N">Cabergoline</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003370" MajorTopicYN="Y">Coturnix</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D010058" MajorTopicYN="N">Oviposition</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011388" MajorTopicYN="N">Prolactin</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011784" MajorTopicYN="Y">Quail</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017329" MajorTopicYN="N">Triptorelin Pamoate</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000031" MajorTopicYN="N">analogs &amp; derivatives</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Coturnix japonica</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Japanese quail</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">avian</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cabergoline</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">deslorelin implant</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prolactin</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">suppression of oviposition</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>4</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35526163</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1647/20-00075</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rosen LB. Avian reproductive disorders. <i>J Exot Pet Med</i>. 2012;21(2):124–131.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stout JD. Common emergencies in pet birds. <i>Vet Clin North Am Exot Anim Pract</i>. 2016;19(2):513–541.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scagnelli AM, Tully TN. Reproductive disorders in parrots. <i>Vet Clin North Am Exot Anim Pract</i>. 2017;20(2):485–507.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mans C, Pilny A. Use of GnRH-agonists for medical management of reproductive disorders in birds. <i>Vet Clin North Am Exot Anim Pract</i>. 2014;17(1):23–33.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Van Sant F, Sundaram A. Retrospective study of deslorelin acetate implants in clinical practice. <i>Proc Annu Conf Assoc Avian Vet</i>. 2013:211–220.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cook K, Riggs G. Clinical report: gonadotropic releasing hormone agonist implants. <i>Proc Annu Conf Assoc Avian Vet</i>. 2007:309–315.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Petritz OA, Sanchez-Migallon Guzman D, Paul-Murphy J, et al. Evaluation of the efficacy and safety of single administration of 4.7-mg deslorelin acetate implants on egg production and plasma sex hormones in Japanese quail (<i>Coturnix coturnix japonica</i>). <i>Am J Vet Res</i>. 2013;74(2):316–323.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Petritz OA, Guzman DS-M, Hawkins MG, et al. Comparison of two 4.7-milligram to one 9.4-milligram deslorelin acetate implants on egg production and plasma progesterone concentrations in Japanese quail (<i>Coturnix coturnix japonica</i>). <i>J Zoo Wildl Med</i>. 2015;46(4):789–797.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chitty J, Raftery A, Lawrie A. Use of cabergoline in companion psittacine birds. <i>Proc Annu Conf Assoc Avian Vet</i>. 2006:65–68.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Plumb DC. <i>Plumb's Veterinary Drug Handbook</i>. 6th ed. Stockholm, WI: Blackwell Publishing; 2008.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reddy IJ, David CG, Raju SS. Effect of suppression of plasma prolactin on luteinizing hormone concentration, intersequence pause days and egg production in domestic hen. <i>Domest Anim Endocrinol</i>. 2007;33(2):167–175.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smiley KO, Adkins-Regan E. Lowering prolactin reduces post-hatch parental care in male and female zebra finches (<i>Taeniopygia guttata</i>). <i>Horm Behav</i>. 2018; 98:103–114.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cottin M, Chastel O, Kato A, et al. Decreasing prolactin levels leads to a lower diving effort but does not affect breeding success in Adélie penguins. <i>Horm Behav</i>. 2014;65(2):134–141.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smiley KO, Adkins-Regan E. Prolactin is related to individual differences in parental behavior and reproductive success in a biparental passerine, the zebra finch (<i>Taeniopygia guttata</i>). <i>Gen Comp Endocrinol</i>. Posted online August 1 2016;234:88–94. doi: 10.1001/jama.2019.17965</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Youngren OM, el Halawani ME, Silsby JL, Phillips RE. Intracranial prolactin perfusion induces incubation behavior in turkey hens. <i>Biol Reprod</i>. 1991;44(3):425–431.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Camper PM, Burke WH. The effect of prolactin on reproductive function in female Japanese quail (<i>Coturnix coturnix japonica</i>). <i>Poult Sci</i>. 1977;56(4):1130–1134.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alexander B, Wolfson A. Prolactin and sexual maturation in the Japanese quail, <i>Coturnix coturnix japonica</i>. <i>Poult Sci</i>. 1970;49(3):632–640.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zadworny D, Shimada K, Ishida H, Sato K. Gonadotropin-stimulated estradiol production in small ovarian follicles of the hen is suppressed by physiological concentrations of prolactin <i>in vitro</i>. <i>Gen Comp Endocrinol</i>. 1989;74(3):468–473.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Buntin JD, Tesch D. Effects of intracranial prolactin administration on maintenance of incubation readiness, ingestive behavior, and gonadal condition in ring doves. <i>Horm Behav</i>. 1985;19(2):188–203.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>El Halawani ME, Silsby JL, Rozenboim I, Pitts GR. Increased egg production by active immunization against vasoactive intestinal peptide in the turkey (<i>Meleagris gallopavo</i>). <i>Biol Reprod</i>. 1995;52(1):179–183.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>El Halawani ME, Pitts GR, Sun S, et al. Active immunization against vasoactive intestinal peptide prevents photo-induced prolactin secretion in turkeys. <i>Gen Comp Endocrinol</i>. 1996;104(1):76–83.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>El-Halawani ME, Whiting SE, Silsby JL, et al. Active immunization with vasoactive intestinal peptide in turkey hens. <i>Poult Sci</i>. 2000;79(3):349–354.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reddy IJ, David CG, Singh K. Relationship between intersequence pauses, laying persistency and concentration of prolactin during the productive period in white Leghorn hens. <i>Asian-Australas J Anim Sci</i>. 2005;18(5):686–691.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reddy IJ, David CG, Sarma PV, Singh K. The possible role of prolactin in laying performance and steroid hormone secretion in domestic hen (<i>Gallus domesticus</i>). <i>Gen Comp Endocrinol</i>. 2002;127(3):249–255.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li WL, Liu Y, Yu YC, et al. Prolactin plays a stimulatory role in ovarian follicular development and egg laying in chicken hens. <i>Domest Anim Endocrinol</i>. 2011;41(2):57–66.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>March JB, Sharp PJ, Wilson PW, Sang HM. Effect of active immunization against recombinant-derived chicken prolactin fusion protein on the onset of broodiness and photoinduced egg laying in bantam hens. <i>J Reprod Fertil</i>. 1994;101(1):227–233.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scanes CG, Chadwick A, Bolton NJ. Radioimmunoassay of prolactin in the plasma of the domestic fowl. <i>Gen Comp Endocrinol</i>. 1976;30(1):12–20.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cowan ML, Martin GB, Monks DJ, et al. Inhibition of the reproductive system by deslorelin in male and female pigeons (<i>Columba livia</i>). <i>J Avian Med Surg</i>. 2014;28(2):102–108.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Summa NM, Guzman DS-M, Wils-Plotz EL, et al. Evaluation of the effects of a 4.7-mg deslorelin acetate implant on egg laying in cockatiels (<i>Nymphicus hollandicus</i>). <i>Am J Vet Res</i>. 2017;78(6):745–751.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Noonan B, Johnson P, De Matos R. Evaluation of egg-laying suppression effects of the GnRH agonist deslorelin in domestic chickens. <i>Proc Annu Conf Assoc Avian Vet</i>. 2012:321.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bédécarrats GY, Shimizu M, Guémené D. Gonadotropin releasing hormones and their receptors in avian species. <i>J Poult Sci</i>. 2006;43(3):199–214.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Millar RP, Lu Z-L, Pawson AJ, et al. Gonadotropin-releasing hormone receptors. <i>Endocr Rev</i>. 2004;25(2):235–275.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Doneley B. Reproduction. In: Chitty J, Monks D, eds. <i>BSAVA Manual of Avian Practice</i>. Gloucester, UK: British Small Animal Veterinary Association; 2018:54–67.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Angelier F, Chastel O. Stress, prolactin and parental investment in birds: a review. <i>Gen Comp Endocrinol</i>. 2009;163(1):142–148.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Angelier F, Wingfield JC, Tartu S, Chastel O. Does prolactin mediate parental and life-history decisions in response to environmental conditions in birds? A review. <i>Horm Behav</i>. Posted online Jan 2016;77:18–29 doi: 10.1016/j.yhbeh.2015.07.014</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clarke IJ, Doughton BW. Effect of various anaesthetics on resting plasma concentrations of luteinizing hormone, follicle-stimulating hormone and prolactin in ovariectomized ewes. <i>J Endocrinol</i>. 1983;98(1):79–89.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Noel GL, Suh HK, Stone JG, Frantz AG. Human prolactin and growth hormone release during surgery and other conditions of stress. <i>J Clin Endocrinol Metab</i>. 1972;35(6):840–851.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mujagić Z, Čičko E, Vegar-Brozović V, Prašo M. Serum levels of cortisol and prolactin in patients treated under total intravenous anesthesia with propofol-fentanyl and under balanced anesthesia with isoflurane-fentanyl. <i>Open Med</i>. 2008;3(4):459–463.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Neill JD. Effect of “stress” on serum prolactin and luteinizing hormone levels during the estrous cycle of the rat. <i>Endocrinology</i>. 1970;87(6):1192–1197.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nazian SJ. Serum concentrations of reproductive hormones after administration of various anesthetics to immature and young adult male rats. <i>Proc Soc Exp Biol Med</i>. 1988;187(4):482–487.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scanes CG, Harvey S, Chadwick A, et al. Diurnal variations in serum luteinizing hormone, growth hormone, and prolactin concentrations in intact and pinealectomised chickens. <i>Gen Comp Endocrinol</i>. 1980;41(2):266–269.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lea RW, Sharp PJ, Chadwick A. Daily variations in the concentrations of plasma prolactin in broody bantams. <i>Gen Comp Endocrinol</i>. 1982;48(2):275–284.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Henare SJ, Kikuchi M, Talbot RT, Cockrem JF. Changes in plasma gonadotrophins, 17β-oestradiol, progesterone, prolactin, thyroxine and triiodothyronine concentrations in female Japanese quail (<i>Coturnix coturnix japonica</i>) of a heavy body weight line during photo-induced ovarian growth and regression. <i>Br Poult Sci</i>. 2012;53(4):520–530.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smiley KO. Prolactin and avian parental care: new insights and unanswered questions. <i>Horm Behav</i>. 2019;111:114–130.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hiyama G, Kansaku N, Kinoshita M, et al. Changes in post-translational modifications of prolactin during development and reproductive cycles in the chicken. <i>Gen Comp Endocrinol</i>. 2009;161(2):238–245.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kansaku N, Shimada K, Terada O, Saito N. Prolactin, growth hormone, and luteinizing hormone-β subunit gene expression in the cephalic and caudal lobes of the anterior pituitary gland during embryogenesis and different reproductive stages in the chicken. <i>Gen Comp Endocrinol</i>. 1994;96(2):197–205.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Freeman ME, Kanyicska B, Lerant A, Nagy G. Prolactin: structure, function, and regulation of secretion. <i>Physiol Rev</i>. 2000;80(4):1523–1631.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Denef C. Paracrinicity: the story of 30 years of cellular pituitary crosstalk. <i>J Neuroendocrinol</i>. 2008;20(1):1–70.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Villalobos C, Núñez L, Frawley LS, et al. Multiresponsiveness of single anterior pituitary cells to hypothalamic-releasing hormones: a cellular basis for paradoxical secretion. <i>Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A</i>. 1997;94(25):14132–14137.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Andries M, Denef C. Gonadotropin-releasing hormone influences the release of prolactin and growth hormone from intact rat pituitary in vitro during a limited period in neonatal life. <i>Peptides</i>. 1995;16(3):527–532.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Denef C, Andries M. Evidence for paracrine interaction between gonadotrophs and lactotrophs in pituitary cell aggregates. <i>Endocrinology</i>. 1983;112(3):813–822.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Robberecht W, Andries M, Denef C. Stimulation of prolactin secretion from rat pituitary by luteinizing hormone-releasing hormone: evidence against mediation by angiotensin II acting through a (Sar1-Ala8)-angiotensin II–sensitive receptor. <i>Neuroendocrinology</i>. 1992;56(2):185–194.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blackwell RE, Rodgers-Neame NT, Bradley EL, Asch RH. Regulation of human prolactin secretion by gonadotropin-releasing hormone in vitro. <i>Fertil Steril</i>. 1986;46(1):26–31.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dickerman RW, Bahr JM. Molt induced by gonadotropin-releasing hormone agonist as a model for studying endocrine mechanisms of molting in laying hens. <i>Poult Sci</i>. 1989;68(10):1402–1408.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Attia YA, Burke WH, Yamani KA. Response of broiler breeder hens to forced molting by hormonal and dietary manipulations. <i>Poult Sci</i>. 1994;73(2):245–258.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Burke WH, Attia YA. Molting single comb White Leghorns with the use of the Lupron depot formulation of leuprolide acetate. <i>Poult Sci</i>. 1994;73(8):1226–1232.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Santos TC, Murakami AE, Fanhani JC, Oliveira CAL. Production and reproduction of egg- and meat-type quails reared in different group sizes. <i>Rev Bras Cienc Avic</i>. 2011;13(1):9–14.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Valiente C, Romero GG, Corrada Y, et al. Interruption of the canine estrous cycle with a low and a high dose of the GnRH antagonist, acyline. <i>Theriogenology</i>. 2009;71(3):408–411.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>García Romero G, Valiente C, Aquilano D, et al. Endocrine effects of the GnRH antagonist, acyline, in domestic dogs. <i>Theriogenology</i>. 2009;71(8):1234–1237.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Valiente C, Corrada Y, De La Sota P, et al. Comparison of two doses of the GnRH antagonist, acyline, for pregnancy termination in bitches. <i>Reprod Domest Anim</i>. 2009;44(s2):156–159.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>García Romero G, Mattioli G, Rosa D, et al. A single administration of the GnRH antagonist acyline inhibits basal and GnRH-stimulated serum testosterone concentrations in male dogs. <i>Reprod Domest Anim</i>. 2012;47(3):32–35.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Valiente C, Diaz JD, Rosa DE, et al. Effect of a GnRH antagonist on GnRH agonist–implanted anestrous bitches. <i>Theriogenology</i>. 2009;72(7):926–929.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
