<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35527016</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>08</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1347-7439</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>06</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>The Journal of veterinary medical science</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Vet Med Sci</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Characterization of multi-resistant Shigella species isolated from raw cow milk and milk products.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1292/jvms.22-0018</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>This study was organized to investigate the prevalence, antibiotic and disinfectant resistance phenotypes and genotypes as well as plasmid profiles of Shigella species isolated from raw cow milk and milk products in Egypt. Genotypic analysis was performed to determine the presence of β-lactamase encoding genes(bla<sub>TEM</sub>, bla<sub>CTX-M</sub>, bla<sub>OXA-1</sub> and bla<sub>SHV</sub>), tet(A) and qacE∆.Forty-two (7%) Shigella isolates (S. dysenteriae, S. flexneri, and S. sonnei) were recovered, with S. dysenteriae as the predominant type. Antibiotic sensitivity tests showed that 71.4% of Shigella isolates were resistant to three or more antibiotic classes (multidrug-resistant). High resistance rates were observed against tetracyclines (100%), ampicillin, amoxicillin-clavulanate (90.5%, each) and cefaclor (66.7%), while no resistance was detected against imipenem, sulfamethoxazole/trimethoprim, and azithromycin. Disinfectant susceptibility test of Shigella isolates revealed resistance to phenolic compound (vanillic acid), while 85.7% of the Shigella isolates were resistant to benzalkonium chloride. Uniplex PCR analysis declared the existence of β-lactamase encoding genes(bla<sub>TEM</sub> in all isolates and bla<sub>CTX-M</sub> in 28.6% of isolates) and, tet(A) in all isolates and 85.7% of the isolates were positive for qacE∆1, while all isolates were negative for bla<sub>OXA-1</sub> and bla<sub>SHV</sub>. All Shigella extended spectrum β-lactamases (ESBL) producers (12, 100%) were positive for the bla<sub>TEM</sub>, bla<sub>CTX-M</sub>, and qacE∆1 genes. Furthermore, plasmid profiling revealed seven distinct plasmid patterns (P1-P7), ranging from 1.26 to 33.61 kb, among all the Shigella strains; S. dysenteriae exhibited the greatest variance. The co-transfer of β-lactamase genes (bla<sub>TEM</sub> and bla<sub>CTX-M</sub>) and qacE∆1 geneswas observed by conjugation from all ESBL producers to a recipient strain.These findings indicate the emergence of Shigella species in Egypt that exhibited multi-resistance to either antibiotics (particularly ESBL producer strains) or disinfectants. Thus, the resistance of Shigella species should regularly be monitored and appropriate measures should be taken to manage this problem.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Elkenany</LastName>
            <ForeName>Rasha M</ForeName>
            <Initials>RM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Bacteriology, Mycology and Immunology, Faculty of Veterinary Medicine, Mansoura University.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Eltaysh</LastName>
            <ForeName>Rasha</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology, Faculty of Veterinary Medicine, Mansoura University.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Elsayed</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mona</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Hygiene and Zoonoses, Faculty of Veterinary Medicine, Mansoura University.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Abdel-Daim</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mohamed</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Zoology, Science College, King Saud University.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Pharmacology Department, Faculty of Veterinary Medicine, Suez Canal University.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Shata</LastName>
            <ForeName>Radwa</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Food Hygiene and Control, Faculty of Veterinary Medicine, Mansoura University.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>06</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>Japan</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Vet Med Sci</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9105360</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0916-7250</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Shigella species</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">antibiotic resistance</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dairy product</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">qacE∆1 gene</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">β-lactamase encoding gene</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
          <Hour>21</Hour>
          <Minute>43</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35527016</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1292/jvms.22-0018</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
