<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35536191</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>10</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1525-3163</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>10</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of animal science</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Anim Sci</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Improving young pig welfare on-farm: The Five Domains Model.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">skac164</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1093/jas/skac164</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Considering welfare through the "neonatal and nursery pig perspective" is an exciting approach, and one that resonates with consumers. Overlaying this with the Five Domains Model, as we suggest in this review, points to practical on-farm improvements that provide each pig the opportunity to experience positive mental states. The Five Domains Model is broken into physical and functional states, that includes Domain 1 Nutrition, Domain 2 Physical Environment, Domain 3 Health and, Domain 4 Behavioral Interaction, and Domain 5 Mental State. The Five Domains Model can build on the breadth and depth of swine welfare science to highlight opportunities to improve welfare on-farm. In Domain 1 management of increasingly large litters is considered, with examples of sow vs. artificial rearing, colostrum quality and quantity, and creep feed management strategies. Efforts can result in positive mental states such as feeling full and content and the ability to experience pleasure of drinking and food tastes/smells. Domain 2 considers space complexity and access to key resources, along with thermal and physical amenities, to promote feelings of physical comfort. Domain 3 considers pig health in three broad, yet inter-linking categories, (a) congenital and hereditary health, (b) environmental pathogen load and, (c) colostrum quality and quantity, and its effect on the microbiome. Improvements can result in a pig that displays vitality and feels healthy. Domain 4 provides the pig opportunities to express its rich behavioral repertoire, specifically positive social interactions, play, and exploration. These efforts can result in pigs feeling calm, safe, comfortable, having companionship, engaged, interested and rewarded. In conclusion, using the Five Domains Model can highlight numerous opportunities to improve current and future housing and management through the "neonatal and nursery pig perspective" with a focus on inducing positive mental states that can result in improved quality of life and welfare state.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© The Author(s) 2022. Published by Oxford University Press on behalf of the American Society of Animal Science. All rights reserved. For permissions, please e-mail: journals.permissions@oup.com.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Johnson</LastName>
            <ForeName>A K</ForeName>
            <Initials>AK</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Animal Science, Iowa State University, Ames, IA, 50001, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Iowa Pork Industry Center, Iowa State University, Ames, IA, 50001, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Rault</LastName>
            <ForeName>J-L</ForeName>
            <Initials>JL</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Animal Welfare Science, University of Veterinary Medicine, Vienna, A-1210, Austria.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Marchant</LastName>
            <ForeName>J N</ForeName>
            <Initials>JN</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>USDA-ARS Livestock Behavior Research Unit, West Lafayette, IN, 47907, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Baxter</LastName>
            <ForeName>E M</ForeName>
            <Initials>EM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Animal Behaviour and Welfare, Animal and Veterinary Sciences Research Group, SRUC, West Mains Road, Edinburgh EH9 3JG, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>O'Driscoll</LastName>
            <ForeName>K</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Pig Development Department, Animal &amp; Grassland Research and Innovation Centre, Teagasc, Moorepark, Fermoy Co. Cork, P61 C997, Ireland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Anim Sci</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8003002</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0021-8812</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Affective</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Farm</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Health</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mental</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Piglet</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Weaner</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>10</Hour>
          <Minute>43</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35536191</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jas/skac164</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">6583200</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
