<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35535441</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2125</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>10</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>British journal of clinical pharmacology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Br J Clin Pharmacol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Who prescribes quetiapine in Denmark?</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/bcp.15388</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The second-generation antipsychotic quetiapine is commonly used off-label for its anxiolytic and hypnotic properties. However, quetiapine is associated with problematic side-effects. We used Danish Medicinal Product Statistics and a 20% random sample of the Danish population's prescription fills (2001-2020) to describe the utilization of quetiapine and proportion of various prescriber types (general practitioner [GP], specialist in private practice, hospital physician and other prescribers) both in connection to first-time and subsequent prescriptions. In 2020, 92% of all quetiapine was dispensed outside hospitals and the average daily dispensed quantity of quetiapine per user corresponded to 100 mg/user/d. A GP issued 53% of first-time prescriptions and 75% of subsequent prescriptions for quetiapine in 2020. The proportion of quetiapine prescriptions issued by GPs varied by age group-from 14% among 0-17-year-olds to 93% among the ≥80-year-olds. Future initiatives on the rational use of quetiapine and related drugs, especially among adults, should target GPs.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Authors. British Journal of Clinical Pharmacology published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of British Pharmacological Society.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Højlund</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mikkel</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5786-5203</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Clinical Pharmacology, Pharmacy and Environmental Medicine, Department of Public Health, University of Southern Denmark, Odense, Denmark.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry Aabenraa, Mental Health Services in the Region of Southern Denmark, Aabenraa, Denmark.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Rasmussen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Lotte</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5962-6647</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Clinical Pharmacology, Pharmacy and Environmental Medicine, Department of Public Health, University of Southern Denmark, Odense, Denmark.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Olesen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Morten</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0937-4952</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Clinical Pharmacology, Pharmacy and Environmental Medicine, Department of Public Health, University of Southern Denmark, Odense, Denmark.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Munk-Olsen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Trine</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0786-7147</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Clinical Research, University of Southern Denmark, Odense, Denmark.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>The National Center for Register-based Research, Aarhus University, Aarhus, Denmark.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Pottegård</LastName>
            <ForeName>Anton</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9314-5679</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Clinical Pharmacology, Pharmacy and Environmental Medicine, Department of Public Health, University of Southern Denmark, Odense, Denmark.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Hospital Pharmacy Funen, Odense University Hospital, Odense, Denmark.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Br J Clin Pharmacol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>7503323</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0306-5251</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">antipsychotics</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">off-label</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prescriber</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">quetiapine</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>3</Hour>
          <Minute>12</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35535441</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/bcp.15388</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>European Medicines Agency. Summary of product characteristics: Seroquel, Seroquel XR and associated names (quetiapine). Accessed January 6, 2022. https://www.ema.europa.eu/en/documents/referral/seroquel-seroquel-xr-associated-names-article-30-referral-annex-iii_en.pdf</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ravindran AV, Al-Subaie A, Abraham G. Quetiapine: novel uses in the treatment of depressive and anxiety disorders. Expert Opin Investig Drugs. 2010;19(10):1187-1204. doi:10.1517/13543784.2010.515586</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Atkin T, Comai S, Gobbi G. Drugs for Insomnia beyond Benzodiazepines: Pharmacology, Clinical Applications, and Discovery. Pharmacol Rev. 2018;70(2):197-245. doi:10.1124/pr.117.014381</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hálfdánarson Ó, Zoëga H, Aagaard L, et al. International trends in antipsychotic use: A study in 16 countries, 2005-2014. Eur Neuropsychopharmacol. 2017;27(10):1064-1076. doi:10.1016/j.euroneuro.2017.07.001</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Højlund M, Pottegård A, Johnsen E, et al. Trends in utilization and dosing of antipsychotic drugs in Scandinavia: Comparison of 2006 and 2016. Br J Clin Pharmacol. 2019;85(7):1598-1606. doi:10.1111/bcp.13945</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kelly M, Dornan T, Pringsheim T. The lesser of two evils: a qualitative study of quetiapine prescribing by family physicians. CMAJ Open. 2018;6(2):E191-E196. doi:10.9778/cmajo.20170145</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Solmi M, Murru A, Pacchiarotti I, et al. Safety, tolerability, and risks associated with first- and second-generation antipsychotics: a state-of-the-art clinical review. Ther Clin Risk Manag. 2017;13:757-777. doi:10.2147/TCRM.S117321</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Højlund M, Andersen JH, Andersen K, Correll CU, Hallas J. Use of antipsychotics in Denmark 1997-2018: a nation-wide drug utilisation study with focus on off-label use and associated diagnoses. Epidemiol Psychiatr Sci. 2021;30:e28. doi:10.1017/S2045796021000159</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmidt M, Hallas J, Laursen M, Friis S. Data Resource Profile: Danish online drug use statistics (MEDSTAT). Int J Epidemiol. 2016;45(5):1401-1402g. doi:10.1093/ije/dyw116</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pottegård A, Olesen M, Christensen B, Christensen MB, Hallas J, Rasmussen L. Who prescribes drugs to patients: A Danish register-based study. Br J Clin Pharmacol. 2021;87(7):2982-2987. doi:10.1111/bcp.14691</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pottegård A, Schmidt SAJ, Wallach-Kildemoes H, Sørensen HT, Hallas J, Schmidt M. Data Resource Profile: The Danish National Prescription Registry. Int J Epidemiol. 2017;46(3):798-798f. doi:10.1093/ije/dyw213</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>National klinisk anbefaling for brug af beroligende laegemidler. Accessed November 23, 2021. https://www.sst.dk/da/nyheder/2021/national-klinisk-anbefaling-for-brug-af-beroligende-laegemidler</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sundheds- og aeldreministeriet. Vejledning om ordination af afhaengighedsskabende laegemidler. Published 2019. Accessed March 18, 2021. https://www.retsinformation.dk/eli/retsinfo/2019/9523</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Danish Health Data Authority. Danish Register of Medicinal Product Statistics. Accessed March 7, 2022. https://medstat.dk/en</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Højlund M, Lund LC, Andersen K, Correll CU, Hallas J. Association of Low-Dose Quetiapine and Diabetes. JAMA Netw Open. 2021;4(5):e213209. doi:10.1001/jamanetworkopen.2021.3209</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vento AE, Kotzalidis GD, Cacciotti M, et al. Quetiapine Abuse Fourteen Years Later: Where Are We Now? A Systematic Review. Subst Use Misuse. 2020;55(2):304-313. doi:10.1080/10826084.2019.1668013</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gjerden P, Bramness JG, Tvete IF, Slørdal L. The antipsychotic agent quetiapine is increasingly not used as such: dispensed prescriptions in Norway 2004-2015. Eur J Clin Pharmacol. 2017;73(9):1173-1179. doi:10.1007/s00228-017-2281-8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Müller L, Noseda R, Bertoli R, Bissig M, Ceschi A. Off-label use of quetiapine in nursing homes: Does medical specialty of prescribing physicians play a role? Br J Clin Pharmacol. 2020;25(7):1444-1445. doi:10.1111/bcp.14232</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Isoardi KZ, Polkinghorne G, Harris K, Isbister GK. Pregabalin poisoning and rising recreational use: a retrospective observational series. Br J Clin Pharmacol. 2020;86(12):2435-2440. doi:10.1111/bcp.14348</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rasmussen L, Valentin J, Gesser KM, Hallas J, Pottegård A. Validity of the Prescriber Information in the Danish National Prescription Registry. Basic Clin Pharmacol Toxicol. 2016;119(4):376-380. doi:10.1111/bcpt.12610</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee TC, Desforges P, Murray J, Saleh RR, McDonald EG. Off-label Use of Quetiapine in Medical Inpatients and Postdischarge. JAMA Intern Med. 2016;176(9):1390-1391. doi:10.1001/jamainternmed.2016.3309</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alexander SPH, Christopoulos A, Davenport AP, et al. THE CONCISE GUIDE TO PHARMACOLOGY 2021/22: G protein-coupled receptors. Br J Pharmacol. 2021;178(S1):S27-S156. doi:10.1111/bph.15538</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
