<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35535818</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>21</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1096-9861</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>10</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>The Journal of comparative neurology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Comp Neurol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>An atlas of the developing Tribolium castaneum brain reveals conservation in anatomy and divergence in timing to Drosophila melanogaster.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/cne.25335</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Insect brains are formed by conserved sets of neural lineages whose fibers form cohesive bundles with characteristic projection patterns. Within the brain neuropil, these bundles establish a system of fascicles constituting the macrocircuitry of the brain. The overall architecture of the neuropils and the macrocircuitry appear to be conserved. However, variation is observed, for example, in size, shape, and timing of development. Unfortunately, the developmental and genetic basis of this variation is poorly understood, although the rise of new genetically tractable model organisms such as the red flour beetle Tribolium castaneum allows the possibility to gain mechanistic insights. To facilitate such work, we present an atlas of the developing brain of T. castaneum, covering the first larval instar, the prepupal stage, and the adult, by combining wholemount immunohistochemical labeling of fiber bundles (acetylated tubulin) and neuropils (synapsin) with digital 3D reconstruction using the TrakEM2 software package. Upon comparing this anatomical dataset with the published work in Drosophila melanogaster, we confirm an overall high degree of conservation. Fiber tracts and neuropil fascicles, which can be visualized by global neuronal antibodies like antiacetylated tubulin in all invertebrate brains, create a rich anatomical framework to which individual neurons or other regions of interest can be referred to. The framework of a largely conserved pattern allowed us to describe differences between the two species with respect to parameters such as timing of neuron proliferation and maturation. These features likely reflect adaptive changes in developmental timing that govern the change from larval to adult brain.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Authors. The Journal of Comparative Neurology published by Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Farnworth</LastName>
            <ForeName>Max S</ForeName>
            <Initials>MS</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2418-3203</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Evolutionary Developmental Genetics, Johann-Friedrich-Blumenbach Institute, GZMB, University of Göttingen, Göttingen, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Evolution of Brains and Behaviour lab, School of Biological Sciences, University of Bristol, Bristol, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bucher</LastName>
            <ForeName>Gregor</ForeName>
            <Initials>G</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4615-6401</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Evolutionary Developmental Genetics, Johann-Friedrich-Blumenbach Institute, GZMB, University of Göttingen, Göttingen, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hartenstein</LastName>
            <ForeName>Volker</ForeName>
            <Initials>V</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9676-7393</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Molecular Cell and Developmental Biology, University of California/Los Angeles, Los Angeles, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <GrantList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>R56 NS054814</GrantID>
            <Acronym>NS</Acronym>
            <Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
        </GrantList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Comp Neurol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0406041</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0021-9967</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Drosophila melanogaster</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Tribolium castaneum</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">brain atlas</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">brain evolution</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">development</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">macroconnectivity</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tracts</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>7</Hour>
          <Minute>43</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35535818</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cne.25335</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Andrade, I. V., Riebli, N., Nguyen, B.-C. M., Omoto, J. J., Cardona, A., &amp; Hartenstein, V. (2019). Developmentally arrested precursors of pontine neurons establish an embryonic blueprint of the Drosophila central complex. Current Biology, 29(3), 412-425. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cub.2018.12.012</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bate, C. M. (1976). Pioneer neurones in an insect embryo. Nature, 260(5546), 54-56. https://doi.org/10.1038/260054a0</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bello, B. C., Izergina, N., Caussinus, E., &amp; Reichert, H. (2008). Amplification of neural stem cell proliferation by intermediate progenitor cells in Drosophila brain development. Neural Development, 3, 5. https://doi.org/10.1186/1749-8104-3-5</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berghammer, A. J., Klingler, M., &amp; Wimmer, E. A. (1999). A universal marker for transgenic insects. Nature, 402(6760), 370. https://doi.org/10.1038/46463</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bieber, A. J., Snow, P. M., Hortsch, M., Patel, N. H., Jacobs, J. R., Traquina, Z. R., Schilling, J., &amp; Goodman, C. S. (1989). Drosophila neuroglian: A member of the immunoglobulin superfamily with extensive homology to the vertebrate neural adhesion molecule L1. Cell, 59(3), 447-460. https://doi.org/10.1016/0092-8674(89)90029-9</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Biffar, L., &amp; Stollewerk, A. (2014). Conservation and evolutionary modifications of neuroblast expression patterns in insects. Developmental Biology, 388(1), 103-116. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ydbio.2014.01.028</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Biffar, L., &amp; Stollewerk, A. (2015). Evolutionary variations in the expression of dorso-ventral patterning genes and the conservation of pioneer neurons in Tribolium castaneum. Developmental Biology, 400(1), 159-167. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ydbio.2015.01.025</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Birkan, M., Schaeper, N. D., &amp; Chipman, A. D. (2011). Early patterning and blastodermal fate map of the head in the milkweed bug Oncopeltus fasciatus. Evolution &amp; Development, 13, 436-447.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boone, J. Q., &amp; Doe, C. Q. (2008). Identification of Drosophila type II neuroblast lineages containing transit amplifying ganglion mother cells. Developmental Neurobiology, 68(9), 1185-1195. https://doi.org/10.1002/dneu.20648</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bowman, S. K., Rolland, V., Betschinger, J., Kinsey, K. A., Emery, G., &amp; Knoblich, J. A. (2008). The tumor suppressors Brat and Numb regulate transit-amplifying neuroblast lineages in Drosophila. Developmental Cell, 14(4), 535-546. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.devcel.2008.03.004</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boyan, G., Liu, Y., Khalsa, S. K., &amp; Hartenstein, V. (2017). A conserved plan for wiring up the fan-shaped body in the grasshopper and Drosophila. Development Genes and Evolution, 227(4), 253-269. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00427-017-0587-2</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boyan, G. S., &amp; Reichert, H. (2011). Mechanisms for complexity in the brain: Generating the insect central complex. Trends in Neurosciences, 34(5), 247-257. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tins.2011.02.002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bressan, J. M. A., Benz, M., Oettler, J., Heinze, J., Hartenstein, V., &amp; Sprecher, S. G. (2015). A map of brain neuropils and fiber systems in the ant Cardiocondyla obscurior. Frontiers in Neuroanatomy, 8, 166. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnana.2014.00166</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Broadus, J., &amp; Doe, C. Q. (1995). Evolution of neuroblast identity: Seven-up and prospero expression reveal homologous and divergent neuroblast fates in Drosophila and Schistocerca. Development, 121(12), 3989-3996.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brown, S. J., Shippy, T. D., Miller, S., Bolognesi, R., Beeman, R. W., Lorenzen, M. D., Bucher, G., Wimmer, E. A., &amp; Klingler, M. (2009). The red flour beetle, Tribolium castaneum (Coleoptera): A model for studies of development and pest biology. Cold Spring Harbor Protocols, 2009(8), pdb.emo126. https://doi.org/10.1101/pdb.emo126</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bucher, G., Scholten, J., &amp; Klingler, M. (2002). Parental RNAi in Tribolium (Coleoptera). Current Biology, 12(3), R85-R86. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0960-9822(02)00666-8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cardona, A., Saalfeld, S., Preibisch, S., Schmid, B., Cheng, A., Pulokas, J., Tomancak, P., &amp; Hartenstein, V. (2010). An integrated micro- and macroarchitectural analysis of the Drosophila brain by computer-assisted serial section electron microscopy. PLoS Biology, 8(10), e100050. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pbio.1000502</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cardona, A., Saalfeld, S., Schindelin, J., Arganda-Carreras, I., Preibisch, S., Longair, M., Tomancak, P., Hartenstein, V., &amp; Douglas, R. J. (2012). TrakEM2 Software for Neural Circuit Reconstruction. PLoS One, 7(6), e38011. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0038011</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dreyer, D., Vitt, H., Dippel, S., Goetz, B., El Jundi, B., Kollmann, M., Huetteroth, W., Schachtner, J., Dreyer, D., Vitt, H., Dippel, S., Goetz, B., el Jundi, B., Kollmann, M., Huetteroth, W., &amp; Schachtner, J. (2010). 3D standard brain of the red flour beetle Tribolium castaneum: A tool to study metamorphic development and adult plasticity. Frontiers in Systems Neuroscience, 4, 3. https://doi.org/10.3389/neuro.06.003.2010</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dujardin, F. (1850). Mémoire sur le systéme nerveux des Insectes. Annales Des Sciences Naturelles, 3(14), 195-206.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>el Jundi, B., Pfeiffer, K., Heinze, S., &amp; Homberg, U. (2014). Integration of polarization and chromatic cues in the insect sky compass. Journal of Comparative Physiology A, 200(6), 575-589. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00359-014-0890-6</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eliason, C. M., McCullough, J. M., Andersen, M. J., &amp; Hackett, S. J. (2021). Accelerated brain shape evolution is associated with rapid diversification in an avian radiation. The American Naturalist, 197(5), 576-591. https://doi.org/10.1086/713664</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Farnworth, M. S., Eckermann, K. N., &amp; Bucher, G. (2020). Sequence heterochrony led to a gain of functionality in an immature stage of the central complex: A fly-beetle insight. PLoS Biology, 18(10), e3000881. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pbio.3000881</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Farris, S. M. (2013). Evolution of complex higher brain centers and behaviors: Behavioral correlates of mushroom body elaboration in insects. Brain, Behavior and Evolution, 82(1), 9-18. https://doi.org/10.1159/000352057</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Farris, S. M., Abrams, A. I., &amp; Strausfeld, N. J. (2004). Development and morphology of Class II Kenyon cells in the mushroom bodies of the honey bee, Apis mellifera. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 474(3), 325-339. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.20146</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Farris, S. M., &amp; Roberts, N. S. (2005). Coevolution of generalist feeding ecologies and gyrencephalic mushroom bodies in insects. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 102(48), 17394-17399. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.0508430102</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Farris, S. M., &amp; Van Dyke, J. W. (2015). Evolution and function of the insect mushroom bodies: Contributions from comparative and model systems studies. Current Opinion in Insect Science, 12, 19-25. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cois.2015.08.006</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garcia-Perez, N. C., Bucher, G., &amp; Buescher, M. (2021). Shaking hands is a homeodomain transcription factor that controls axon outgrowth of central complex neurons in the insect model Tribolium. Development, 148(19), dev199368. https://doi.org/10.1242/dev.199368</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gilles, A. F., Schinko, J. B., &amp; Averof, M. (2015). Efficient CRISPR-mediated gene targeting and transgene replacement in the beetle Tribolium castaneum. Development, 142(16), 2832-2839. https://doi.org/10.1242/dev.125054</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Godenschwege, T. A., Reisch, D., Diegelmann, S., Eberle, K., Funk, N., Heisenberg, M., Hoppe, V., Hoppe, J., Klagges, B. R. E., Martin, J.-R., Nikitina, E. A., Putz, G., Reifegerste, R., Reisch, N., Rister, J., Schaupp, M., Scholz, H., Schwärzel, M., Werner, U., … Buchner, E. (2004). Flies lacking all synapsins are unexpectedly healthy but are impaired in complex behaviour. European Journal of Neuroscience, 20(3), 611-622. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1460-9568.2004.03527.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hardcastle, B. J., Omoto, J. J., Kandimalla, P., Nguyen, B.-C. M., Keleş, M. F., Boyd, N. K., Hartenstein, V., &amp; Frye, M. A. (2021). A visual pathway for skylight polarization processing in Drosophila. ELife, 10, e63225. https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.63225</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hartenstein, V., Cruz, L., Lovick, J. K., &amp; Guo, M. (2017). Developmental analysis of the dopamine-containing neurons of the Drosophila brain. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 525(2), 363-379. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.24069</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hartenstein, V., Omoto, J. J., &amp; Lovick, J. K. (2021). The role of cell lineage in the development of neuronal circuitry and function. Developmental Biology, 475, 165-180. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ydbio.2020.01.012</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hartenstein, V., Omoto, J. J., Ngo, K. T., Wong, D., Kuert, P. A., Reichert, H., Lovick, J. K., &amp; Younossi-Hartenstein, A. (2018). Structure and development of the subesophageal zone of the Drosophila brain. I. Segmental architecture, compartmentalization, and lineage anatomy. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 526(1), 6-32. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.24287</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hartenstein, V., Younossi-Hartenstein, A., Lovick, J. K., Kong, A., Omoto, J. J., Ngo, K. T., &amp; Viktorin, G. (2015). Lineage-associated tracts defining the anatomy of the Drosophila first instar larval brain. Developmental Biology, 406(1), 14-39. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ydbio.2015.06.021</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>He, B., Buescher, M., Farnworth, M. S., Strobl, F., Stelzer, E. H., Koniszewski, N. D., Muehlen, D., &amp; Bucher, G. (2019). An ancestral apical brain region contributes to the central complex under the control of foxQ2 in the beetle Tribolium. ELife, 8, e49065. https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.49065</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heinze, S., el Jundi, B., Berg, B. G., Homberg, U., Menzel, R., Pfeiffer, K., Hensgen, R., Zittrell, F., Dacke, M., Warrant, E., Pfuhl, G., Rybak, J., &amp; Tedore, K. (2021). A unified platform to manage, share, and archive morphological and functional data in insect neuroscience. ELife, 10, e65376. https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.65376</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hofbauer, A., Ebel, T., Waltenspiel, B., Oswald, P., Chen, Y., Halder, P., Biskup, S., Lewandrowski, U., Winkler, C., Sickmann, A., Buchner, S., &amp; Buchner, E. (2009). The Wuerzburg Hybridoma Library against Drosophila brain. Journal of Neurogenetics, 23(1-2), 78-91. https://doi.org/10.1080/01677060802471627</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Honkanen, A., Adden, A., da Silva Freitas, J., &amp; Heinze, S. (2019). The insect central complex and the neural basis of navigational strategies. Journal of Experimental Biology, 222(Suppl 1), jeb188854. https://doi.org/10.1242/jeb.188854</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hortsch, M., Patel, N. H., Bieber, A. J., Traquina, Z. R., &amp; Goodman, C. S. (1990). Drosophila neurotactin, a surface glycoprotein with homology to serine esterases, is dynamically expressed during embryogenesis. Development, 110(4), 1327-1340. https://doi.org/10.1242/dev.110.4.1327</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hoskins, S. G., Homberg, U., Kingan, T. G., Christensen, T. A., &amp; Hildebrand, J. G. (1986). Immunocytochemistry of GABA in the antennal lobes of the sphinx moth Manduca sexta. Cell and Tissue Research, 244(2), 243-252. https://doi.org/10.1007/BF00219199</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hunnekuhl, V. S., Siemanowski, J., Farnworth, M. S., He, B., &amp; Bucher, G. (2020). Immunohistochemistry and fluorescent whole mount RNA in situ hybridization in larval and adult brains of Tribolium. In S. G. Sprecher (Ed.), Brain Development (Vol. 2047, pp. 233-251). Springer New York. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-1-4939-9732-9_13</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Immonen, E.-V., Dacke, M., Heinze, S., &amp; el Jundi, B. (2017). Anatomical organization of the brain of a diurnal and a nocturnal dung beetle. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 525(8), 1879-1908. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.24169</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ito, K., Shinomiya, K., Ito, M., Armstrong, J. D., Boyan, G., Hartenstein, V., Harzsch, S., Heisenberg, M., Homberg, U., Jenett, A., Keshishian, H., Restifo, L. L., Rössler, W., Simpson, J. H., Strausfeld, N. J., Strauss, R., &amp; Vosshall, L. B. (2014). A systematic nomenclature for the insect brain. Neuron, 81(4), 755-765. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2013.12.017</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ito, M., Masuda, N., Shinomiya, K., Endo, K., &amp; Ito, K. (2013). Systematic analysis of neural projections reveals clonal composition of the Drosophila brain. Current Biology, 23(8), 644-655. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cub.2013.03.015</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iwai, Y., Usui, T., Hirano, S., Steward, R., Takeichi, M., &amp; Uemura, T. (1997). Axon patterning requires D N-cadherin, a novel neuronal adhesion receptor, in the Drosophila embryonic CNS. Neuron, 19(1), 77-89. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0896-6273(00)80349-9</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kamikouchi, A., Shimada, T., &amp; Ito, K. (2006). Comprehensive classification of the auditory sensory projections in the brain of the fruit fly Drosophila melanogaster. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 499(3), 317-356. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.21075</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kebschull, J. M., Ringach, N., Richman, E. B., Friedmann, D., Kolluru, S. S., Jones, R. C., Allen, W. E., Wang, Y., Zhou, H., Cho, S. W., Chang, H., Deisseroth, K., Quake, S. R., &amp; Luo, L. (2020). Cerebellar nuclei evolved by repeatedly duplicating a conserved cell type set. BioRxiv, 2020.06.25.170118. https://doi.org/10.1101/2020.06.25.170118 bioRxiv bioRxiv</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kendroud, S., Bohra, A. A., Kuert, P. A., Nguyen, B., Guillermin, O., Sprecher, S. G., Reichert, H., VijayRaghavan, K., &amp; Hartenstein, V. (2018). Structure and development of the subesophageal zone of the Drosophila brain. II. Sensory compartments. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 526(1), 33-58. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.24316</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Klagges, B. R., Heimbeck, G., Godenschwege, T. A., Hofbauer, A., Pflugfelder, G. O., Reifegerste, R., Reisch, D., Schaupp, M., Buchner, S., &amp; Buchner, E. (1996). Invertebrate synapsins: A single gene codes for several isoforms in Drosophila. The Journal of Neuroscience: The Official Journal of the Society for Neuroscience, 16(10), 3154-3165.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kollmann, M., Schmidt, R., Heuer, C. M., &amp; Schachtner, J. (2016). Variations on a theme: Antennal lobe architecture across Coleoptera. PLoS One, 11(12), e0166253. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0166253</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koniszewski, N. D. B., Kollmann, M., Bigham, M., Farnworth, M., He, B., Büscher, M., Hütteroth, W., Binzer, M., Schachtner, J., &amp; Bucher, G. (2016). The insect central complex as model for heterochronic brain development-Background, concepts, and tools. Development Genes and Evolution, 226(3), 209-219. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00427-016-0542-7</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kumar, A., Fung, S., Lichtneckert, R., Reichert, H., &amp; Hartenstein, V. (2009). Arborization pattern of Engrailed-positive neural lineages reveal neuromere boundaries in the Drosophila brain neuropil. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 517(1), 87-104. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.22112</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Larsen, C., Shy, D., Spindler, S. R., Fung, S., Pereanu, W., Younossi-Hartenstein, A., &amp; Hartenstein, V. (2009). Patterns of growth, axonal extension and axonal arborization of neuronal lineages in the developing Drosophila brain. Developmental Biology, 335(2), 289-304. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ydbio.2009.06.015</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee, T. (2017). Wiring the Drosophila brain with individually tailored neural lineages. Current Biology, 27(2), R77-R82. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cub.2016.12.026</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee, Y.-J., Yang, C.-P., Miyares, R. L., Huang, Y.-F., He, Y., Ren, Q., Chen, H.-M., Kawase, T., Ito, M., Otsuna, H., Sugino, K., Aso, Y., Ito, K., &amp; Lee, T. (2020). Conservation and divergence of related neuronal lineages in the Drosophila central brain. ELife, 9, e53518. https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.53518</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leyva-Díaz, E., &amp; López-Bendito, G. (2013). In and out from the cortex: Development of major forebrain connections. Neuroscience, 254, 26-44. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroscience.2013.08.070</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lovick, J. K., Ngo, K. T., Omoto, J. J., Wong, D. C., Nguyen, J. D., &amp; Hartenstein, V. (2013). Postembryonic lineages of the Drosophila brain: I. Development of the lineage-associated fiber tracts. Developmental Biology, 384(2), 228-257. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ydbio.2013.07.008</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lovick, J. K., Omoto, J. J., Ngo, K. T., &amp; Hartenstein, V. (2017). Development of the anterior visual input pathway to the Drosophila central complex. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 525(16), 3458-3475. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.24277</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maddrell, S. H. P. (2018). How the simple shape and soft body of the larvae might explain the success of endopterygote insects. Journal of Experimental Biology, 221(11), jeb177535. https://doi.org/10.1242/jeb.177535</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Misof, B., Liu, S., Meusemann, K., Peters, R. S., Donath, A., Mayer, C., Frandsen, P. B., Ware, J., Flouri, T., Beutel, R. G., Niehuis, O., Petersen, M., Izquierdo-Carrasco, F., Wappler, T., Rust, J., Aberer, A. J., Aspock, U., Aspock, H., Bartel, D., … Zhou, X. (2014). Phylogenomics resolves the timing and pattern of insect evolution. Science, 346(6210), 763-767. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.1257570</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Montgomery, S. H., Rossi, M., McMillan, W. O., &amp; Merrill, R. M. (2021). Neural divergence and hybrid disruption between ecologically isolated Heliconius butterflies. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America, 118(6), e2015102118. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2015102118</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Namiki, S., &amp; Kanzaki, R. (2011). Heterogeneity in dendritic morphology of moth antennal lobe projection neurons. The Journal of Comparative Neurology, 519(17), 3367-3386. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.22754</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Omoto, J. J., Keleş, M. F., Nguyen, B. C. M., Bolanos, C., Lovick, J. K., Frye, M. A., &amp; Hartenstein, V. (2017). Visual input to the Drosophila central complex by developmentally and functionally distinct neuronal populations. Current Biology, 27(8), 1098-1110.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Omoto, J. J., Nguyen, B.-C. M., Kandimalla, P., Lovick, J. K., Donlea, J. M., &amp; Hartenstein, V. (2018). Neuronal constituents and putative interactions within the Drosophila ellipsoid body neuropil. Frontiers in Neural Circuits, 12, 103. https://doi.org/10.3389/fncir.2018.00103</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ott, S. R. (2008). Confocal microscopy in large insect brains: Zinc-formaldehyde fixation improves synapsin immunostaining and preservation of morphology in whole-mounts. Journal of Neuroscience Methods, 172(2), 220-230. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jneumeth.2008.04.031</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Panov, A. A. (1959). Structure of the insect brain at successive stages of postembryonic development. II. the central body. Entomological Review, 38, 276-283.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Perdiz, D., Mackeh, R., Poüs, C., &amp; Baillet, A. (2011). The ins and outs of tubulin acetylation: More than just a post-translational modification?. Cellular Signalling, 23(5), 763-771. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cellsig.2010.10.014</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pereanu, W., &amp; Hartenstein, V. (2006). Neural lineages of the Drosophila brain: A three-dimensional digital atlas of the pattern of lineage location and projection at the late larval stage. The Journal of Neuroscience: The Official Journal of the Society for Neuroscience, 26(20), 5534-5553. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.4708-05.2006</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pereanu, W., Kumar, A., Jennett, A., Reichert, H., &amp; Hartenstein, V. (2010). Development-based compartmentalization of the Drosophila central brain. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 518(15), 2996-3023. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.22376</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peters, R. S., Meusemann, K., Petersen, M., Mayer, C., Wilbrandt, J., Ziesmann, T., Donath, A., Kjer, K. M., Aspöck, U., Aspöck, H., Aberer, A., Stamatakis, A., Friedrich, F., Hünefeld, F., Niehuis, O., Beutel, R. G., &amp; Misof, B. (2014). The evolutionary history of holometabolous insects inferred from transcriptome-based phylogeny and comprehensive morphological data. BMC Evolutionary Biology, 14(1), 52. https://doi.org/10.1186/1471-2148-14-52</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Piovant, M., &amp; Lena, P. (1988). Membrane glycoproteins immunologically related to the human insulin receptor are associated with presumptive neuronal territories and developing neurones in Drosophila melanogaster. Development, 103(1), 145-156. https://doi.org/10.1242/dev.103.1.145</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pop, S., Chen, C.-L., Sproston, C. J., Kondo, S., Ramdya, P., &amp; Williams, D. W. (2020). Extensive and diverse patterns of cell death sculpt neural networks in insects. ELife, 9, e59566. https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.59566</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Prieto-Godino, L. L., Silbering, A. F., Khallaf, M. A., Cruchet, S., Bojkowska, K., Pradervand, S., Hansson, B. S., Knaden, M., &amp; Benton, R. (2020). Functional integration of “undead” neurons in the olfactory system. Science Advances, 6(11), eaaz7238. https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.aaz7238</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rajashekhar, K. P., &amp; Singh, R. N. (1994). Neuroarchitecture of the tritocerebrum of Drosophila melanogaster. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 349(4), 633-645. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.903490410</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Robson, S. J., &amp; Burgoyne, R. D. (1989). Differential localisation of tyrosinated, detyrosinated, and acetylated α-tubulins in neurites and growth cones of dorsal root ganglion neurons. Cell Motility, 12(4), 273-282. https://doi.org/10.1002/cm.970120408</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sansalone, G., Allen, K., Ledogar, J. A., Ledogar, S., Mitchell, D. R., Profico, A., Castiglione, S., Melchionna, M., Serio, C., Mondanaro, A., Raia, P., &amp; Wroe, S. (2020). Variation in the strength of allometry drives rates of evolution in primate brain shape. Proceedings of the Royal Society B: Biological Sciences, 287(1930), 20200807. https://doi.org/10.1098/rspb.2020.0807</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sant, H. H., &amp; Sane, S. P. (2018). The mechanosensory-motor apparatus of antennae in the Oleander hawk moth (Daphnis nerii, Lepidoptera). Journal of Comparative Neurology, 526(14), 2215-2230. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.24477</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schindelin, J., Arganda-Carreras, I., Frise, E., Kaynig, V., Longair, M., Pietzsch, T., Preibisch, S., Rueden, C., Saalfeld, S., Schmid, B., Tinevez, J.-Y., White, D. J., Hartenstein, V., Eliceiri, K., Tomancak, P., &amp; Cardona, A. (2012). Fiji: An open-source platform for biological-image analysis. Nature Methods, 9(7), 676-682. https://doi.org/10.1038/nmeth.2019</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schinko, J. B., Weber, M., Viktorinova, I., Kiupakis, A., Averof, M., Klingler, M., Wimmer, E. A., &amp; Bucher, G. (2010). Functionality of the GAL4/UAS system in Tribolium requires the use of endogenous core promoters. BMC Developmental Biology, 10(1), 53. https://doi.org/10.1186/1471-213X-10-53</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schinko, J., Posnien, N., Kittelmann, S., Koniszewski, N., &amp; Bucher, G. (2009). Single and double whole-mount in situ hybridization in red flour beetle (Tribolium) embryos. Cold Spring Harbor Protocols, 2009(8), pdb.prot5258. https://doi.org/10.1101/pdb.prot5258</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmitt-Engel, C., Schultheis, D., Schwirz, J., Ströhlein, N., Troelenberg, N., Majumdar, U., Dao, V. A., Grossmann, D., Richter, T., Tech, M., Dönitz, J., Gerischer, L., Theis, M., Schild, I., Trauner, J., Koniszewski, N. D. B., Küster, E., Kittelmann, S., Hu, Y., … Bucher, G. (2015). The iBeetle large-scale RNAi screen reveals gene functions for insect development and physiology. Nature Communications, 6(1), 7822. https://doi.org/10.1038/ncomms8822</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Snodgrass, R. (1954). Insect metamorphosis: Smithsonian miscellaneous collections, V122, No. 9 (Vol. 122). Literary Licensing.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sokoloff, A. (1972). The biology of Tribolium: With special emphasis on genetic aspects. Clarendon Press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Spindler, S. R., &amp; Hartenstein, V. (2010). The Drosophila neural lineages: A model system to study brain development and circuitry. Development Genes and Evolution, 220(1-2), 1-10. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00427-010-0323-7</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sterling, P., &amp; Laughlin, S. (2015). Principles of neural design. MIT Press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stöckl, A., Heinze, S., Charalabidis, A., el Jundi, B., Warrant, E., &amp; Kelber, A. (2016). Differential investment in visual and olfactory brain areas reflects behavioural choices in hawk moths. Scientific Reports, 6, 26041. https://doi.org/10.1038/srep26041</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Strausfeld, N. J. (2005). The evolution of crustacean and insect optic lobes and the origins of chiasmata. Arthropod Structure &amp; Development, 34(3), 235-256. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.asd.2005.04.001</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Strausfeld, N. J. (2012). Arthropod brains: Evolution, functional elegance, and historical significance. Harvard University Press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Strausfeld, N. J. (1976). Atlas of an insect brain (Berlin: Springer-Verlag).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sullivan, W., Ashburner, M., &amp; Hawley, R. S. (Eds.). (2000). Drosophila protocols. Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory Press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thomas, J. B., Bastiani, M. J., Bate, M., &amp; Goodman, C. S. (1984). From grasshopper to Drosophila: A common plan for neuronal development. Nature, 310(5974), 203-207. https://doi.org/10.1038/310203a0</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Truman, J. W., &amp; Ball, E. E. (1998). Patterns of embryonic neurogenesis in a primitive wingless insect, the silverfish, Ctenolepisma longicaudata: Comparison with those seen in flying insects. Development Genes and Evolution, 208(7), 357-368. https://doi.org/10.1007/s004270050192</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Truman, J. W., Moats, W., Altman, J., Marin, E. C., &amp; Williams, D. W. (2010). Role of Notch signaling in establishing the hemilineages of secondary neurons in Drosophila melanogaster. Development, 137(1), 53-61. https://doi.org/10.1242/dev.041749</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Truman, J. W., &amp; Riddiford, L. M. (1999). The origins of insect metamorphosis. Nature, 401(6752), 447. https://doi.org/10.1038/46737</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Urbach, R., Jussen, D., &amp; Technau, G. M. (2016). Gene expression profiles uncover individual identities of gnathal neuroblasts and serial homologies in the embryonic CNS of Drosophila. Development, 143(8), 1290-1301. https://doi.org/10.1242/dev.133546</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Urbach, R., Schnabel, R., &amp; Technau, G. M. (2003). The pattern of neuroblast formation, mitotic domains and proneural gene expression during early brain development in Drosophila. Development, 130, 3589-3606.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Urbach, R., &amp; Technau, G. M. (2003a). Early steps in building the insect brain: Neuroblast formation and segmental patterning in the developing brain of different insect species. Arthropod Structure &amp; Development, 32(1), 103-123. https://doi.org/10.1016/S1467-8039(03)00042-2</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Urbach, R., &amp; Technau, G. M. (2003b). Molecular markers for identified neuroblasts in the developing brain of Drosophila. Development, 130(16), 3621-3637. https://doi.org/10.1242/dev.00533</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wagh, D. A., Rasse, T. M., Asan, E., Hofbauer, A., Schwenkert, I., Dürrbeck, H., Buchner, S., Dabauvalle, M.-C., Schmidt, M., Qin, G., Wichmann, C., Kittel, R., Sigrist, S. J., &amp; Buchner, E. (2006). Bruchpilot, a protein with homology to ELKS/CAST, is required for structural integrity and function of synaptic active zones in Drosophila. Neuron, 49(6), 833-844. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuron.2006.02.008</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wegerhoff, R., &amp; Breidbach, O. (1992). Structure and development of the larval central complex in a holometabolous insect, the beetle Tenebrio molitor. Cell &amp; Tissue Research, 268(2), 341-358. https://doi.org/10.1007/BF00318803</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wong, D. C., Lovick, J. K., Ngo, K. T., Borisuthirattana, W., Omoto, J. J., &amp; Hartenstein, V. (2013). Postembryonic lineages of the Drosophila brain: II. Identification of lineage projection patterns based on MARCM clones. Developmental Biology, 384(2), 258-289. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ydbio.2013.07.009</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yaghmaeian Salmani, B., &amp; Thor, S. (2020). Chapter Eleven-Genetic mechanisms controlling anterior expansion of the central nervous system. In S. Small, &amp; J. Briscoe (Eds.), Current topics in developmental biology (Vol. 137, pp. 333-361). Academic Press. https://doi.org/10.1016/bs.ctdb.2019.11.005</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Younossi-Hartenstein, A., Nassif, C., Green, P., &amp; Hartenstein, V. (1996). Early neurogenesis of the Drosophila brain. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 370(3), 313-329. https://doi.org/10.1002/(SICI)1096-9861(19960701)370:3&lt;313::AID-CNE3&gt;3.0.CO;2-7</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yu, H.-H., Awasaki, T., Schroeder, M. D., Long, F., Yang, J. S., He, Y., Ding, P., Kao, J.-C., Wu, G. Y.-Y., Peng, H., Myers, G., &amp; Lee, T. (2013). Clonal development and organization of the adult Drosophila central brain. Current Biology: CB, 23(8), 633-643. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cub.2013.02.057</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhao, X., Coptis, V., &amp; Farris, S. M. (2008). Metamorphosis and adult development of the mushroom bodies of the red flour beetle, Tribolium castaneum. Developmental Neurobiology, 68(13), 1487-1502. https://doi.org/10.1002/dneu.20669</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
