<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35535687</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>11</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>15</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2060</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>54</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Dec</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Annals of medicine</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Ann Med</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Tumour budding is a novel marker in breast cancer: the clinical application and future prospects.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>1303</StartPage>
          <EndPage>1312</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>1303-1312</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1080/07853890.2022.2070272</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Breast cancer (BC) is a group of markedly heterogeneous tumours. There are many subtypes with different biological behaviours and clinicopathological characteristics, leading to significantly different prognosis. Despite significant advances in the treatment of BC, early metastatic is a critical factor for poor prognosis in BC patients. Tumour budding (TB) is considered as the first step process of tumour metastasis and is related to the epithelial-mesenchymal transition (EMT). TB has been observed in a variety of cancers, such as colorectal and gastric cancer, and had been considered as a distinct clinicopathological characteristics for early metastasis. However, TB evaluation standards and clinical application are not uniform in BC, as well as its molecular mechanism is not fully understood. Here, we reviewed the interpretation criteria, mechanism, clinicopathological characteristics and clinical application prospects of TB in BC. Key messagesCurrently, tumour budding is a poor prognosis for various solid tumours, also in breast cancer.Tumour budding is based on epithelial-mesenchymal transition and tumour microenvironment factors and is presumed to be an early step in the metastatic process.Breast cancer tumour budding still needs multi-centre experiments. We summarize the current research on breast cancer tumour budding, analyse the method of discriminating breast cancer tumour budding and explore the prognostic role and mechanism in breast cancer.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Huang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ting</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Clinical Pathology, the First Affiliated Hospital of Jinan University, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bao</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hui</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Plastic Surgery, the First Affiliated Hospital of Jinan University, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Meng</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yu-Hua</ForeName>
            <Initials>YH</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Clinical Pathology, the First People's Hospital of Shunde, Foshan, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jian-Lin</ForeName>
            <Initials>JL</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of General Surgery, the First Affiliated Hospital of Jinan University, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xiao-Dong</ForeName>
            <Initials>XD</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of General Surgery, the First Affiliated Hospital of Jinan University, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xiao-Li</ForeName>
            <Initials>XL</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>State Key Laboratory of Dampness Syndrome of Chinese Medicine, The Second Affiliated Hospital of Guangzhou University of Chinese Medicine, Guangdong, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Guangdong Provincial Key laboratory of Chinese Medicine for Prevention and Treatment of Refractory Chronic Diseases, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Pan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jing-Hua</ForeName>
            <Initials>JH</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of General Surgery, the First Affiliated Hospital of Jinan University, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Ann Med</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8906388</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0785-3890</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D014408">Biomarkers, Tumor</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014408" MajorTopicYN="N">Biomarkers, Tumor</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001943" MajorTopicYN="Y">Breast Neoplasms</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D058750" MajorTopicYN="N">Epithelial-Mesenchymal Transition</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011379" MajorTopicYN="N">Prognosis</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D059016" MajorTopicYN="N">Tumor Microenvironment</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Breast cancer</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">epithelial–mesenchymal transition</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tumour budding</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors report no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>3</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35535687</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9103277</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07853890.2022.2070272</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Siegel RL, Miller KD, Fuchs HE, et al. . 
Cancer statistics, 2022. CA A Cancer J Clin. 2022;72(1):1303–33.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roizen MF.
Hallmarks of cancer: the next generation. Yearbook Anesthesiol Pain Manage. 2012;2012:13.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lugli A, Kirsch R, Ajioka Y, et al. . 
Recommendations for reporting tumor budding in colorectal cancer based on the international tumor budding consensus conference (ITBCC) 2016. Mod Pathol. 2017;30(9):1299–1311.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28548122</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grigore AD, Jolly MK, Jia D, et al. . 
Tumor budding: the name is EMT. Partial EMT. JCM. 2016;5(5):51.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Almangush A, Bello IO, Keski-Säntti H, et al. . 
Depth of invasion, tumor budding, and worst pattern of invasion: prognostic indicators in early-stage oral tongue cancer. Head Neck. 2014;36(6):811–818.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4229066</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23696499</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim S, Huh JW, Lee WY, et al. . 
Lymphovascular invasion, perineural invasion, and tumor budding are prognostic factors for stage I Colon cancer recurrence. Int J Colorectal Dis. 2020;35(5):881–885.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32112198</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dawson H, Lugli A.. 
Molecular and pathogenetic aspects of tumor budding in colorectal cancer. Front Med (Lausanne). 2015;2:11.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4354406</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25806371</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jiménez-Salazar JE, Posadas-Rodríguez P, Lazzarini-Lechuga RC, et al. . 
Membrane-Initiated estradiol signaling of epithelial-mesenchymal transition-associated mechanisms through regulation of tight junctions in human breast cancer cells. Horm Cancer. 2014;5(3):161–173.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24771004</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Silva L, Lopes M, Sa MC, et al. . 
Histopathologic grading and its relationship with outcome in oral tongue squamous cell carcinoma. J Oral Pathol Med. 2021;50(2):183–190.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33151566</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kocsmar E, Lotz G, Kiss A, et al. . 
Prognostic impact of tumor budding and EMT in periampullary adenocarcinoma: a quantitative approach. J. Cancer. 2020;11(22):6474–6483.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7545681</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33046968</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jun SY, Chung JY, Yoon N, et al. . 
Tumor budding and poorly differentiated clusters in small intestinal adenocarcinoma. Cancers. 2020;12(8):2199..</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jypa B, Ji DG, Dcc Y, et al. . 
Tumor budding in cervical cancer as a prognostic factor and its possible role as an additional intermediate-risk factor. Gynecol Oncol. 2020;159(1):157–163.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32741542</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Renuka IV, Madhavi K, Premalatha P, et al. . 
Tumor budding in invasive carcinoma of breast of no special type (NST): value as a prognostic factor. J Diagnos Pathol Oncol. 2019;4(2):125–129.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gabal SM, Bassam AM, Sedqi ME, et al. . 
Tumour budding and MMP-2 expression in breast invasive ductal carcinoma. J Clin Diagnos Res. 2018;12(5):EC25–EC9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salhia B, Trippel M, Pfaltz K, et al. . 
High tumor budding stratifies breast cancer with metastatic properties. Breast Cancer Res Treat. 2015;150(2):363–371.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4368849</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25779101</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Masilamani DS, P DK.. 
Evaluation of clinicopathologic significance of tumor budding in breast carcinoma. Int J Clin Diagn Pathol. 2019;2(1):171–173.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liang F, Cao W, Wang Y, et al. . 
The prognostic value of tumor budding in invasive breast cancer. Pathol Res Pract. 2013;209(5):269–275.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23561623</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gujam FJ, McMillan DC, Mohammed ZM, et al. . 
The relationship between tumour budding, the tumour microenvironment and survival in patients with invasive ductal breast cancer. Br J Cancer. 2015;113(7):1066–1074.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4651125</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26263482</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Agarwal R, Khurana N, Singh T, et al. . 
Tumor budding in infiltrating breast carcinoma: correlation with known clinicopathological parameters and hormone receptor status. Indian J Pathol Microbiol. 2019;62(2):222–225.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30971544</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lugli A, Zlobec I, Berger MD, et al. . 
Tumour budding in solid cancers. Nat Rev Clin Oncol. 2021;18(2):101–115.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32901132</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bronsert P, Enderle-Ammour K, Bader M, et al. . 
Cancer cell invasion and EMT marker expression: a three-dimensional study of the human cancer-host interface. J Pathol. 2014;234(3):410–422.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25081610</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vilchez Mercedes SA, Bocci F, Levine H, et al. . 
Decoding leader cells in collective cancer invasion. Nat Rev Cancer. 2021;21(9):592–604.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34239104</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brabletz T, Kalluri R, Nieto MA, et al. . 
EMT in cancer. Nat Rev Cancer. 2018;18(2):128–134.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29326430</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yifan WB, P, Zhou. Epithelial-Mesenchymal transition—a hallmark of breast cancer metastasis. Cancer Hallm. 2013;1(1):38–49.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3944831</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24611128</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang Y, Weinberg RA.. 
Epithelial-to-mesenchymal transition in cancer: complexity and opportunities. Front Med. 2018;12(4):361–373.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6186394</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30043221</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goossens S, Vandamme N, Vlierberghe PV, et al. . 
EMT transcription factors in cancer development re-evaluated: beyond EMT and MET. Biochim Biophys Acta. 2017;1868(2):584–591.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu X, Zhang M, Xu F, et al. . 
Wnt signaling in breast cancer: biological mechanisms, challenges and opportunities. Mol Cancer. 2020;19(1):165.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7686704</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33234169</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yeh HW, Lee SS, Chang CY, et al. . 
A new switch for TGFβ in cancer. Cancer Res. 2019;79(15):3797–3805.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31300476</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>David CJ, Massague Joan. Publisher correction: contextual determinants of TGFβ action in development, immunity and cancer. Nat Rev Mol Cell Biol. 2018;19(7):479.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Suriyamurthy S, Baker D, Ten Dijke P, et al. . 
Epigenetic reprogramming of TGF-beta signaling in breast cancer. Cancers. 2019;11(5):726.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Taylor MA, Parvani JG, Schiemann WP.. 
The pathophysiology of epithelial-mesenchymal transition induced by transforming growth factor-beta in normal and malignant mammary epithelial cells. J Mammary Gland Biol Neoplasia. 2010;15(2):169–190.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3721368</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20467795</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Polyak K, Weinberg R.. 
Transitions between epithelial and mesenchymal states: acquisition of malignant and stem cell traits. Nat Rev Cancer. 2009;9(4):265–273.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19262571</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li L, Fenglong Z, Juan L, et al. . 
Notch-1 signaling promotes the malignant features of human breast cancer through NF-κB activation. PLoS One. 2014;9(4):e95912.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3997497</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24760075</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oyanagi H, Shimada Y, Nagahashi M, et al. . 
SMAD4 alteration associates with invasive-front pathological markers and poor prognosis in colorectal cancer. Histopathology. 2019;74(6):873–882.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6849740</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30636020</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shao S, Zhao X, Zhang X, et al. . 
Notch1 signaling regulates the epithelial-mesenchymal transition and invasion of breast cancer in a slug-dependent manner. Mol Cancer. 2015;14(1):28.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4322803</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25645291</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Calaf GM, Balajee AS, Montalvo-Villagra MT, et al. . 
Vimentin and notch as biomarkers for breast cancer progression. Oncol Lett. 2014;7(3):721–727.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3919898</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24527079</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li L, Zhang J, Xiong N, et al. . 
Notch-1 signaling activates NF-κB in human breast carcinoma MDA-MB-231 cells via PP2A-dependent AKT pathway. Med Oncol. 2016;33(4):33.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26945854</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kohler I, Bronsert P, Timme S, et al. . 
Detailed analysis of epithelial-mesenchymal transition and tumor budding identifies predictors of long-term survival in pancreatic ductal adenocarcinoma. J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2015;30:78–84.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25827809</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jensen D, Dabelsteen E, Specht L, et al. . 
Molecular profiling of tumour budding implicates TGFβ-mediated epithelial-mesenchymal transition as a therapeutic target in oral squamous cell carcinoma. J Pathol. 2015;236(4):505–516.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25925492</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Galván JA, Zlobec I, Wartenberg M, et al. . 
Expression of E-cadherin repressors SNAIL, ZEB1 and ZEB2 by tumour and stromal cells influences tumour-budding phenotype and suggests heterogeneity of stromal cells in pancreatic cancer. Br J Cancer. 2015;112(12):1944–1950.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4580384</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25989272</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abdulla T, Luna-Zurita L, de la Pompa J, et al. . 
Epithelial to mesenchymal transition-the roles of cell morphology, labile adhesion and junctional coupling. Comput Methods Programs Biomed. 2013;111(2):435–446.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23787029</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhan HX, Zhou B, Cheng YG, et al. . 
Crosstalk between stromal cells and cancer cells in pancreatic cancer: new insights into stromal biology. Cancer Lett. 2017;392:83–93.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28189533</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Najafi M, Goradel NH, Farhood B, et al. . 
Tumor microenvironment: interactions and therapy. J Cell Physiol. 2019;234(5):5700–5721.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30378106</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hui L, Chen Y.. 
Tumor microenvironment: sanctuary of the devil. Cancer Lett. 2015;368(1):7–13.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26276713</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lou Y, Diao L, Cuentas E, et al. . 
Epithelial-Mesenchymal transition is associated with a distinct tumor microenvironment including elevation of inflammatory signals and multiple immune checkpoints in lung adenocarcinoma. Clin Cancer Res. 2016;22(14):3630–3642.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4947453</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26851185</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mak MP, Tong P, Diao L, et al. . 
A patient-derived, pan-cancer EMT signature identifies global molecular alterations and immune target enrichment following epithelial-to-mesenchymal transition. Clin Cancer Res. 2016;22(3):609–620.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4737991</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26420858</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhaoji L, Gregg L.. 
Hua-feng Z. Hypoxia-inducible factor 1 and breast cancer metastasis. Biomed Biotechnol. 2015;16:32–43.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rhodes LV, Martin EC, Segar HC, et al. . 
Dual regulation by microRNA-200b-3p and microRNA-200b-5p in the inhibition of epithelial-to-mesenchymal transition in triple-negative breast cancer. Oncotarget. 2015;6(18):16638–16652.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4599295</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26062653</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chad C, Don G, Jonathan Kurie.. 
The role of epithelial-mesenchymal transition programming in invasion and metastasis: a clinical perspective. Cancer Manag Res. 2013;5:187–195.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3754282</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23986650</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boxberg M, Götz C, Haidari S, et al. . 
Immunohistochemical expression of CD44 in oral squamous cell carcinoma in relation to histomorphological parameters and clinicopathological factors. Histopathology. 2018;73(4):559–572.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29468726</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zheng Z, Yu H, Huang Q, et al. . 
Heterogeneous expression of Lgr5 as a risk factor for focal invasion and distant metastasis of colorectal carcinoma. Oncotarget. 2018;9(53):30025–30033.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6059015</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30046385</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhou Y, Xia L, Wang H, et al. . 
Cancer stem cells in progression of colorectal cancer. Oncotarget. 2018;9(70):33403–33415.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6161799</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30279970</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>IZ A, HED A, AB A, et al. . 
Are tumour grade and tumour budding equivalent in colorectal cancer? A retrospective analysis of 771 patients. Eur J Cancer. 2020;130:139–145.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32200222</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lloyd A, Ryan É, Boland M, et al. . 
The histopathological and molecular features of breast carcinoma with tumour budding – a systematic review and meta-analysis. Breast Cancer Res Treat. 2020;183(3):503–514.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32710280</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Irene C, Sohns AP, Miriam F, et al. . 
DNA profiling of tumor buds in colorectal cancer indicates that they have the same mutation profile as the tumor from which they derive. Virchows Arch. 2017;470(3):341–346.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28130698</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Laedrach C, Salhia B, Cihoric N, et al. . 
Immunophenotypic profile of tumor buds in breast cancer. Pathol Res Pract. 2018;214(1):25–29.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7474545</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29254793</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ferrari-Amorotti G, Chiodoni C, Shen F, et al. . 
Suppression of invasion and metastasis of triple-negative breast cancer lines by pharmacological or genetic inhibition of slug activity. Neoplasia. 2014;16(12):1047–1058.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4557365</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25499218</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jente VS, David B, Peter TD, et al. . 
Epithelial–mesenchymal-transition-inducing transcription factors: new targets for tackling chemoresistance in cancer? Oncogene. 2018;37(48):6195–6211.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30002444</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Papadaki MA, Stoupis G, Theodoropoulos PA, et al. . 
Circulating tumor cells with stemness and epithelial-to-mesenchymal transition features are chemoresistant and predictive of poor outcome in metastatic breast cancer. Mol Cancer Ther. 2019;18(2):437–447.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30401696</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
