<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35534858</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>17</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2051-5960</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>10</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>09</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Acta neuropathologica communications</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Acta Neuropathol Commun</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Changes in glial cell phenotypes precede overt neurofibrillary tangle formation, correlate with markers of cortical cell damage, and predict cognitive status of individuals at Braak III-IV stages.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>72</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>72</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">72</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s40478-022-01370-3</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Clinico-pathological correlation studies show that some otherwise healthy elderly individuals who never developed cognitive impairment harbor a burden of Alzheimer's disease lesions (plaques and tangles) that would be expected to result in dementia. In the absence of comorbidities explaining such discrepancies, there is a need to identify other brain changes that meaningfully contribute to the cognitive status of an individual in the face of such burdens of plaques and tangles. Glial inflammatory responses, a universal phenomenon in symptomatic AD, show robust association with degree of cognitive impairment, but their significance in early tau pathology stages and contribution to the trajectory of cognitive decline at an individual level remain widely unexplored. We studied 55 brains from individuals at intermediate stages of tau tangle pathology (Braak III-IV) with diverging antemortem cognition (demented vs. non-demented, here termed `resilient'), and age-matched cognitively normal controls (Braak 0-II). We conducted quantitative assessments of amyloid and tau lesions, cellular vulnerability markers, and glial phenotypes in temporal pole (Braak III-IV region) and visual cortex (Braak V-VI region) using artificial-intelligence based semiautomated quantifications. We found distinct glial responses with increased proinflammatory and decreased homeostatic markers, both in regions with tau tangles (temporal pole) and without overt tau deposits (visual cortex) in demented but not in resilient. These changes were significantly associated with markers of cortical cell damage. Similar phenotypic glial changes were detected in the white matter of demented but not resilient and were associated with higher burden of overlying cortical cellular damage in regions with and without tangles. Our data suggest that changes in glial phenotypes in cortical and subcortical regions represent an early phenomenon that precedes overt tau deposition and likely contributes to cell damage and loss of brain function predicting the cognitive status of individuals at intermediate stages of tau aggregate burden (Braak III-IV).</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Taddei</LastName>
            <ForeName>Raquel N</ForeName>
            <Initials>RN</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Massachusetts General Hospital, 15th Parkman St, Boston, MA, 02114, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Massachusetts Alzheimer's Disease Research Center, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Dementia Research Institute, University College London, London, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sanchez-Mico</LastName>
            <ForeName>Maria V</ForeName>
            <Initials>MV</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Massachusetts General Hospital, 15th Parkman St, Boston, MA, 02114, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bonnar</LastName>
            <ForeName>Orla</ForeName>
            <Initials>O</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Massachusetts General Hospital, 15th Parkman St, Boston, MA, 02114, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Connors</LastName>
            <ForeName>Theresa</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Massachusetts Alzheimer's Disease Research Center, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>C.S. Kubik Laboratory for Neuropathology, Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gaona</LastName>
            <ForeName>Angelica</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Massachusetts Alzheimer's Disease Research Center, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>C.S. Kubik Laboratory for Neuropathology, Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Denbow</LastName>
            <ForeName>Dominique</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Massachusetts General Hospital, 15th Parkman St, Boston, MA, 02114, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Frosch</LastName>
            <ForeName>Matthew P</ForeName>
            <Initials>MP</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Massachusetts Alzheimer's Disease Research Center, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>C.S. Kubik Laboratory for Neuropathology, Massachusetts General Hospital, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gómez-Isla</LastName>
            <ForeName>Teresa</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7977-2075</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Massachusetts General Hospital, 15th Parkman St, Boston, MA, 02114, USA. tgomezisla@mgh.harvard.edu.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Massachusetts Alzheimer's Disease Research Center, Boston, MA, USA. tgomezisla@mgh.harvard.edu.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <GrantList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>P30AG06242</GrantID>
            <Acronym>NH</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>R56AG069192</GrantID>
            <Acronym>NH</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
        </GrantList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D052061">Research Support, N.I.H., Extramural</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>09</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Acta Neuropathol Commun</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101610673</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2051-5960</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D015415">Biomarkers</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D016875">tau Proteins</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000544" MajorTopicYN="Y">Alzheimer Disease</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015415" MajorTopicYN="N">Biomarkers</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001921" MajorTopicYN="N">Brain</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003071" MajorTopicYN="N">Cognition</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016874" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neurofibrillary Tangles</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009457" MajorTopicYN="N">Neuroglia</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D010641" MajorTopicYN="N">Phenotype</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D058225" MajorTopicYN="N">Plaque, Amyloid</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016875" MajorTopicYN="N">tau Proteins</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">AD</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Cognition</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Cortical cell vulnerability</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Glial phenotypes</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Neurofibrillary tangles</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">White matter changes</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
          <Hour>23</Hour>
          <Minute>36</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35534858</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9082857</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40478-022-01370-3</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s40478-022-01370-3</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aizenstein HJ, Nebes RD, Saxton JA, Price JC, Mathis CA, Tsopelas ND, Ziolko SK, James JA, Snitz BE, Houck PR, Bi W, Cohen AD, Lopresti BJ, DeKosky ST, Halligan EM, Klunk WE. Frequent amyloid deposition without significant cognitive impairment among the elderly. Arch Neurol. 2008;65:1509–1517. doi: 10.1001/archneur.65.11.1509.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archneur.65.11.1509</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2636844</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19001171</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Araque Caballero MÁ, Suárez-Calvet M, Duering M, Franzmeier N, Benzinger T, Fagan AM, Bateman RJ, Jack CR, Levin J, Dichgans M, Jucker M, Karch C, Masters CL, Morris JC, Weiner M, Rossor M, Fox NC, Lee J-H, Salloway S, Danek A, Goate A, Yakushev I, Hassenstab J, Schofield PR, Haass C, Ewers M. White matter diffusion alterations precede symptom onset in autosomal dominant Alzheimer’s disease. Brain. 2018;141:3065–3080. doi: 10.1093/brain/awy229.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awy229</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6158739</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30239611</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arriagada PV, Marzloff K, Hyman BT. Distribution of Alzheimer-type pathologic changes in nondemented elderly individuals matches the pattern in Alzheimer’s disease. Neurology. 1992;42:1681. doi: 10.1212/WNL.42.9.1681.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.42.9.1681</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1307688</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bachstetter AD, Van Eldik LJ, Schmitt FA, Neltner JH, Ighodaro ET, Webster SJ, Patel E, Abner EL, Kryscio RJ, Nelson PT. Disease-related microglia heterogeneity in the hippocampus of Alzheimer’s disease, dementia with Lewy bodies, and hippocampal sclerosis of aging. Acta Neuropathol Commun. 2015;3:32–32. doi: 10.1186/s40478-015-0209-z.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40478-015-0209-z</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4489160</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26001591</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barroeta-Espar I, Weinstock LD, Perez-Nievas BG, Meltzer AC, Siao Tick Chong M, Amaral AC, Murray ME, Moulder KL, Morris JC, Cairns NJ, Parisi JE, Lowe VJ, Petersen RC, Kofler J, Ikonomovic MD, López O, Klunk WE, Mayeux RP, Frosch MP, Wood LB, Gomez-Isla T. Distinct cytokine profiles in human brains resilient to Alzheimer’s pathology. Neurobiol Dis. 2019;121:327–337. doi: 10.1016/j.nbd.2018.10.009.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nbd.2018.10.009</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6437670</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30336198</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beach TG, Malek-Ahmadi M. Alzheimer’s disease neuropathological comorbidities are common in the younger-old. J Alzheimers Dis JAD. 2021;79:389–400. doi: 10.3233/JAD-201213.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/JAD-201213</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8034496</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33285640</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bellenguez C, Küçükali F, Jansen I, Andrade V, Moreno-Grau S, Amin N, Naj AC, Grenier-Boley B, Campos-Martin R, Holmans PA, Boland A, Kleineidam L, Damotte V, van der Lee SJ, Kuulasmaa T, Yang Q, de Rojas I, Bis JC, Yaqub A, Prokic I, Costa MR, Chapuis J, Ahmad S, Giedraitis V, Boada M, Aarsland D, García-González P, Abdelnour C, Alarcón-Martín E, Alegret M, Alvarez I, Álvarez V, Armstrong NJ, Tsolaki A, Antúnez C, Appollonio I, Arcaro M, Archetti S, Pastor AA, Arosio B, Athanasiu L, Bailly H, Banaj N, Baquero M, Belén Pastor A, Benussi L, Berr C, Besse C, Bessi V, Binetti G, Bizzarro A, Alcolea D, Blesa R, Borroni B, Boschi S, Bossù P, Bråthen G, Bresner C, Brookes KJ, Brusco LI, Bûrger K, Bullido MJ, Burholt V, Bush WS, Calero M, Dufouil C, Carracedo Á, Cecchetti R, Cervera-Carles L, Charbonnier C, Chillotti C, Brodaty H, Ciccone S, Claassen JAHR, Clark C, Conti E, Corma-Gómez A, Costantini E, Custodero C, Daian D, Dalmasso MC, Daniele A, Dardiotis E, Dartigues J-F, de Deyn PP, de Paiva Lopes K, de Witte LD, Debette S, Deckert J, del Ser T, Denning N, DeStefano A, Dichgans M, Diehl-Schmid J, Diez-Fairen M, Rossi PD, Djurovic S, Duron E, Düzel E, Engelborghs S, Escott-Price V, Espinosa A, Buiza-Rueda D, Ewers M, Tagliavini F, Nielsen SF, Farotti L, Fenoglio C, Fernández-Fuertes M, Hardy J, Ferrari R, Ferreira CB, Ferri E, Fin B, Fischer P, Fladby T, Fließbach K, Fortea J, Fostinelli S, Fox NC, Franco-Macías E, Frank-García A, Froelich L, Galimberti D, García-Alberca JM, Garcia-Madrona S, García-Ribas G, Chene G, Ghidoni R, Giegling I, Giaccone G, Goldhardt O, González-Pérez A, Graff C, Grande G, Green E, Grimmer T, Grünblatt E, Guetta-Baranes T, Haapasalo A, Hadjigeorgiou G, Haines JL, Hamilton-Nelson KL, EADB, Gra@ce, ADGC, Charge, DemGen, FinnGen, EADI, GERAD, Hampel H, Hanon O, Hartmann AM, Hausner L, Harwood J, Heilmann-Heimbach S, Helisalmi S, Heneka MT, Hernández I, Herrmann MJ, Hoffmann P, Holmes C, Holstege H, Vilas RH, Hulsman M, Humphrey J, Biessels GJ, Johansson C, Kehoe PG, Kilander L, Ståhlbom AK, Kivipelto M, Koivisto A, Kornhuber J, Kosmidis MH, Kuksa PP, Kunkle BW, Lage C, Laukka EJ, Lauria A, Lee C-Y, Lehtisalo J, Satizabal CL, Lerch O, Lleó A, Lopez R, Lopez O, de Munain AL, Love S, Löwemark M, Luckcuck L, Macías J, MacLeod CA, Maier W, Mangialasche F, Spallazzi M, Marquié M, Marshall R, Martin ER, Martín Montes A, Rodríguez CM, Masullo C, Mayeux R, Mead S, Mecocci P, Medina M, Meggy A, Mendoza S, Menéndez-González M, Mir P, Periñán MT, Mol M, Molina-Porcel L, Montrreal L, Morelli L, Moreno F, Morgan K, Nöthen MM, Muchnik C, Nacmias B, Ngandu T, Nicolas G, Nordestgaard BG, Olaso R, Orellana A, Orsini M, Ortega G, Padovani A, Caffarra P, Papenberg G, Parnetti L, Pasquier F, Pastor P, Pérez-Cordón A, Pérez-Tur J, Pericard P, Peters O, Pijnenburg YAL, Pineda JA, Piñol-Ripoll G, Pisanu C, Polak T, Popp J, Posthuma D, Priller J, Puerta R, Quenez O, Quintela I, Thomassen JQ, Rábano A, Rainero I, Ramakers I, Real LM, Reinders MJT, Riedel-Heller S, Riederer P, Rodriguez-Rodriguez E, Rongve A, Allende IR, Rosende-Roca M, Royo JL, Rubino E, Rujescu D, Sáez ME, Sakka P, Saltvedt I, Sanabria Á, Sánchez-Arjona MB, Sanchez-Garcia F, Mehrabian S, Sánchez-Juan P, Sánchez-Valle R, Sando SB, Scamosci M, Scarmeas N, Scarpini E, Scheltens P, Scherbaum N, Scherer M, Schmid M, Schneider A, Schott JM, Selbæk G, Sha J, Shadrin AA, Skrobot O, Snijders GJL, Soininen H, Solfrizzi V, Solomon A, Sorbi S, Sotolongo-Grau O, Spalletta G, Spottke A, Squassina A, Tartari JP, Tárraga L, Tesí N, Thalamuthu A, Tegos T, Traykov L, Tremolizzo L, Tybjærg-Hansen A, Uitterlinden A, Ullgren A, Ulstein I, Valero S, Van Broeckhoven C, van der Lugt A, Van Dongen J, van Rooij J, van Swieten J, Vandenberghe R, Verhey F, Vidal J-S, Vogelgsang J, Vyhnalek M, Wagner M, Wallon D, Wang L-S, Wang R, Weinhold L, Wiltfang J, Windle G, Woods B, Yannakoulia M, Zhao Y, Zulaica M, Serrano-Rios M, Seripa D, Stordal E, Farrer LA, Psaty BM, Ghanbari M, Raj T, Sachdev P, Mather K, Jessen F, Ikram MA, de Mendonça A, Hort J, Tsolaki M, Pericak-Vance MA, Amouyel P, Williams J, Frikke-Schmidt R, Clarimon J, Deleuze J-F, Rossi G, Seshadri S, Andreassen OA, Ingelsson M, Hiltunen M, Sleegers K, Schellenberg GD, van Duijn CM, Sims R, van der Flier WM, Ruiz A, Ramirez A, Lambert J-C (2020) New insights on the genetic etiology of Alzheimer’s and related dementia. medRxiv 2020.10.01.20200659.10.1101/2020.10.01.20200659</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bennett DA, Wilson RS, Schneider JA, Evans DA, Mendes de Leon CF, Arnold SE, Barnes LL, Bienias JL. Education modifies the relation of AD pathology to level of cognitive function in older persons. Neurology. 2003;60:1909–1915. doi: 10.1212/01.WNL.0000069923.64550.9F.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/01.WNL.0000069923.64550.9F</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12821732</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Biel D, Brendel M, Rubinski A, Buerger K, Janowitz D, Dichgans M, Franzmeier N, for the Alzheimer’s Disease Neuroimaging Initiative (ADNI) (2021) Tau-PET and in vivo Braak-staging as prognostic markers of future cognitive decline in cognitively normal to demented individuals. Alzheim Res Ther, 13:137. 10.1186/s13195-021-00880-x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bishop NA, Lu T, Yankner BA. Neural mechanisms of ageing and cognitive decline. Nature. 2010;464:529–535. doi: 10.1038/nature08983.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nature08983</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2927852</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20336135</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bondareff W, Mountjoy CQ, Roth M, Hauser DL. Neurofibrillary degeneration and neuronal loss in alzheimer’s disease. Neurobiol Aging. 1989;10:709–715. doi: 10.1016/0197-4580(89)90007-9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0197-4580(89)90007-9</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2628782</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boyle PA, Yu L, Leurgans SE, Wilson RS, Brookmeyer R, Schneider JA, Bennett DA. Attributable risk of Alzheimer’s dementia attributed to age-related neuropathologies. Ann Neurol. 2019;85:114–124. doi: 10.1002/ana.25380.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.25380</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30421454</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Braak H, Braak E. Neuropathological stageing of Alzheimer-related changes. Acta Neuropathol (Berl) 1991;82:239–259. doi: 10.1007/BF00308809.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF00308809</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1759558</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Braak H, Thal DR, Ghebremedhin E, Del Tredici K. Stages of the pathologic process in alzheimer disease: age categories from 1 to 100 Years. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol. 2011;70:960–969. doi: 10.1097/NEN.0b013e318232a379.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/NEN.0b013e318232a379</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22002422</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chatterjee P, Pedrini S, Stoops E, Goozee K, Villemagne VL, Asih PR, Verberk IMW, Dave P, Taddei K, Sohrabi HR, Zetterberg H, Blennow K, Teunissen CE, Vanderstichele HM, Martins RN. Plasma glial fibrillary acidic protein is elevated in cognitively normal older adults at risk of Alzheimer’s disease. Transl Psychiatry. 2021;11:27. doi: 10.1038/s41398-020-01137-1.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41398-020-01137-1</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7801513</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33431793</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen F, Tillberg PW, Boyden ES. Expansion microscopy. Science. 2015;347:543–548. doi: 10.1126/science.1260088.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.1260088</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4312537</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25592419</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coelho A, Fernandes HM, Magalhães R, Moreira PS, Marques P, Soares JM, Amorim L, Portugal-Nunes C, Castanho T, Santos NC, Sousa N. Signatures of white-matter microstructure degradation during aging and its association with cognitive status. Sci Rep. 2021;11:4517. doi: 10.1038/s41598-021-83983-7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-021-83983-7</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7907273</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33633204</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Corrada MM, Berlau DJ, Kawas CH. A population-based clinicopathological study in the oldest-old: the 90+ study. Curr Alzheimer Res. 2012;9:709–717. doi: 10.2174/156720512801322537.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/156720512801322537</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3409303</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22471863</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Crary JF, Trojanowski JQ, Schneider JA, Abisambra JF, Abner EL, Alafuzoff I, Arnold SE, Attems J, Beach TG, Bigio EH, Cairns NJ, Dickson DW, Gearing M, Grinberg LT, Hof PR, Hyman BT, Jellinger K, Jicha GA, Kovacs GG, Knopman DS, Kofler J, Kukull WA, Mackenzie IR, Masliah E, McKee A, Montine TJ, Murray ME, Neltner JH, Santa-Maria I, Seeley WW, Serrano-Pozo A, Shelanski ML, Stein T, Takao M, Thal DR, Toledo JB, Troncoso JC, Vonsattel JP, White CL, 3rd, Wisniewski T, Woltjer RL, Yamada M, Nelson PT. Primary age-related tauopathy (PART): a common pathology associated with human aging. Acta Neuropathol (Berl) 2014;128:755–766. doi: 10.1007/s00401-014-1349-0.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00401-014-1349-0</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4257842</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25348064</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>DeKosky ST, Scheff SW. Synapse loss in frontal cortex biopsies in alzheimer’s disease: correlation with cognitive severity. Ann Neurol. 1990;27:457–464. doi: 10.1002/ana.410270502.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.410270502</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2360787</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>DeVos SL, Corjuc BT, Oakley DH, Nobuhara CK, Bannon RN, Chase A, Commins C, Gonzalez JA, Dooley PM, Frosch MP, Hyman BT. Synaptic tau seeding precedes tau pathology in human alzheimer’s disease brain. Front Neurosci. 2018;12:267. doi: 10.3389/fnins.2018.00267.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnins.2018.00267</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5928393</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29740275</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dujardin S, Commins C, Lathuiliere A, Beerepoot P, Fernandes AR, Kamath TV, De Los Santos MB, Klickstein N, Corjuc DL, Corjuc BT, Dooley PM, Viode A, Oakley DH, Moore BD, Mullin K, Jean-Gilles D, Clark R, Atchison K, Moore R, Chibnik LB, Tanzi RE, Frosch MP, Serrano-Pozo A, Elwood F, Steen JA, Kennedy ME, Hyman BT. Tau molecular diversity contributes to clinical heterogeneity in Alzheimer’s disease. Nat Med. 2020;26:1256–1263. doi: 10.1038/s41591-020-0938-9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41591-020-0938-9</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7603860</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32572268</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Duncan GJ, Simkins TJ, Emery B. Neuron-oligodendrocyte interactions in the structure and integrity of axons. Front Cell Dev Biol. 2021;9:460. doi: 10.3389/fcell.2021.653101.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fcell.2021.653101</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Edison P, Donat CK, Sastre M. In vivo imaging of glial activation in Alzheimer’s Disease. Front Neurol. 2018;9:625. doi: 10.3389/fneur.2018.00625.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fneur.2018.00625</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6090997</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30131755</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Farfel JM, Yu L, Boyle PA, Leurgans S, Shah RC, Schneider JA, Bennett DA. Alzheimer’s disease frequency peaks in the tenth decade and is lower afterwards. Acta Neuropathol Commun. 2019;7:104. doi: 10.1186/s40478-019-0752-0.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40478-019-0752-0</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6609405</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31269985</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van der Flier WM, Scheltens P. Epidemiology and risk factors of dementia. J Neurol Neurosurg Amp Psychiatry. 2005;76:v2. doi: 10.1136/jnnp.2005.082867.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp.2005.082867</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gallagher B, Zhao Y. Nanoscale imaging of synaptic connections with expansion microscopy. Discov Craiova Rom. 2019;7:e101–e101. doi: 10.15190/d.2019.14.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15190/d.2019.14</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gómez-Isla T, Hollister R, West H, Mui S, Growdon JH, Petersen RC, Parisi JE, Hyman BT. Neuronal loss correlates with but exceeds neurofibrillary tangles in Alzheimer’s disease. Ann Neurol. 1997;41:17–24. doi: 10.1002/ana.410410106.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.410410106</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9005861</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gómez-Isla T, Price JL, McKeel DW, Jr, Morris JC, Growdon JH, Hyman BT. Profound loss of layer II entorhinal cortex neurons occurs in very mild alzheimer’s disease. J Neurosci. 1996;16:4491. doi: 10.1523/JNEUROSCI.16-14-04491.1996.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.16-14-04491.1996</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6578866</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8699259</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guerreiro R, Wojtas A, Bras J, Carrasquillo M, Rogaeva E, Majounie E, Cruchaga C, Sassi C, Kauwe JSK, Younkin S, Hazrati L, Collinge J, Pocock J, Lashley T, Williams J, Lambert J-C, Amouyel P, Goate A, Rademakers R, Morgan K, Powell J, St. George-Hyslop P, Singleton A, Hardy J. TREM2 variants in alzheimer’s disease. N Engl J Med. 2013;368:117–127. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1211851.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1211851</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3631573</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23150934</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harold D, Abraham R, Hollingworth P, Sims R, Gerrish A, Hamshere ML, Pahwa JS, Moskvina V, Dowzell K, Williams A, Jones N, Thomas C, Stretton A, Morgan AR, Lovestone S, Powell J, Proitsi P, Lupton MK, Brayne C, Rubinsztein DC, Gill M, Lawlor B, Lynch A, Morgan K, Brown KS, Passmore PA, Craig D, McGuinness B, Todd S, Holmes C, Mann D, Smith AD, Love S, Kehoe PG, Hardy J, Mead S, Fox N, Rossor M, Collinge J, Maier W, Jessen F, Schürmann B, Heun R, van den Bussche H, Heuser I, Kornhuber J, Wiltfang J, Dichgans M, Frölich L, Hampel H, Hüll M, Rujescu D, Goate AM, Kauwe JSK, Cruchaga C, Nowotny P, Morris JC, Mayo K, Sleegers K, Bettens K, Engelborghs S, De Deyn PP, Van Broeckhoven C, Livingston G, Bass NJ, Gurling H, McQuillin A, Gwilliam R, Deloukas P, Al-Chalabi A, Shaw CE, Tsolaki M, Singleton AB, Guerreiro R, Mühleisen TW, Nöthen MM, Moebus S, Jöckel K-H, Klopp N, Wichmann H-E, Carrasquillo MM, Pankratz VS, Younkin SG, Holmans PA, O’Donovan M, Owen MJ, Williams J. Genome-wide association study identifies variants at CLU and PICALM associated with Alzheimer’s disease. Nat Genet. 2009;41:1088–1093. doi: 10.1038/ng.440.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ng.440</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2845877</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19734902</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harrison TM, La Joie R, Maass A, Baker SL, Swinnerton K, Fenton L, Mellinger TJ, Edwards L, Pham J, Miller BL, Rabinovici GD, Jagust WJ. Longitudinal tau accumulation and atrophy in aging and alzheimer disease. Ann Neurol. 2019;85:229–240. doi: 10.1002/ana.25406.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.25406</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6579738</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30597624</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Henstridge CM, Tzioras M, Paolicelli RC. Glial contribution to excitatory and inhibitory synapse loss in neurodegeneration. Front Cell Neurosci. 2019;13:63. doi: 10.3389/fncel.2019.00063.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fncel.2019.00063</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6399113</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30863284</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hollingworth P, Harold D, Sims R, Gerrish A, Lambert J-C, Carrasquillo MM, Abraham R, Hamshere ML, Pahwa JS, Moskvina V, Dowzell K, Jones N, Stretton A, Thomas C, Richards A, Ivanov D, Widdowson C, Chapman J, Lovestone S, Powell J, Proitsi P, Lupton MK, Brayne C, Rubinsztein DC, Gill M, Lawlor B, Lynch A, Brown KS, Passmore PA, Craig D, McGuinness B, Todd S, Holmes C, Mann D, Smith AD, Beaumont H, Warden D, Wilcock G, Love S, Kehoe PG, Hooper NM, Vardy ERLC, Hardy J, Mead S, Fox NC, Rossor M, Collinge J, Maier W, Jessen F, Rüther E, Schürmann B, Heun R, Kölsch H, van den Bussche H, Heuser I, Kornhuber J, Wiltfang J, Dichgans M, Frölich L, Hampel H, Gallacher J, Hüll M, Rujescu D, Giegling I, Goate AM, Kauwe JSK, Cruchaga C, Nowotny P, Morris JC, Mayo K, Sleegers K, Bettens K, Engelborghs S, De Deyn PP, Van Broeckhoven C, Livingston G, Bass NJ, Gurling H, McQuillin A, Gwilliam R, Deloukas P, Al-Chalabi A, Shaw CE, Tsolaki M, Singleton AB, Guerreiro R, Mühleisen TW, Nöthen MM, Moebus S, Jöckel K-H, Klopp N, Wichmann H-E, Pankratz VS, Sando SB, Aasly JO, Barcikowska M, Wszolek ZK, Dickson DW, Graff-Radford NR, Petersen RC, Alzheimer’s Disease Neuroimaging Initiative, van Duijn CM, Breteler MMB, Ikram MA, DeStefano AL, Fitzpatrick AL, Lopez O, Launer LJ, Seshadri S, CHARGE consortium, Berr C, Campion D, Epelbaum J, Dartigues J-F, Tzourio C, Alpérovitch A, Lathrop M, EADI1 consortium, Feulner TM, Friedrich P, Riehle C, Krawczak M, Schreiber S, Mayhaus M, Nicolhaus S, Wagenpfeil S, Steinberg S, Stefansson H, Stefansson K, Snaedal J, Björnsson S, Jonsson PV, Chouraki V, Genier-Boley B, Hiltunen M, Soininen H, Combarros O, Zelenika D, Delepine M, Bullido MJ, Pasquier F, Mateo I, Frank-Garcia A, Porcellini E, Hanon O, Coto E, Alvarez V, Bosco P, Siciliano G, Mancuso M, Panza F, Solfrizzi V, Nacmias B, Sorbi S, Bossù P, Piccardi P, Arosio B, Annoni G, Seripa D, Pilotto A, Scarpini E, Galimberti D, Brice A, Hannequin D, Licastro F, Jones L, Holmans PA, Jonsson T, Riemenschneider M, Morgan K, Younkin SG, Owen MJ, O’Donovan M, Amouyel P, Williams J (2011) Common variants at ABCA7, MS4A6A/MS4A4E, EPHA1, CD33 and CD2AP are associated with Alzheimer’s disease. Nat Genet 43:429–435. 10.1038/ng.803</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hong S, Beja-Glasser VF, Nfonoyim BM, Frouin A, Li S, Ramakrishnan S, Merry KM, Shi Q, Rosenthal A, Barres BA, Lemere CA, Selkoe DJ, Stevens B. Complement and microglia mediate early synapse loss in Alzheimer mouse models. Science. 2016;352:712–716. doi: 10.1126/science.aad8373.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.aad8373</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5094372</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27033548</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hopperton KE, Mohammad D, Trépanier MO, Giuliano V, Bazinet RP. Markers of microglia in post-mortem brain samples from patients with Alzheimer’s disease: a systematic review. Mol Psychiatry. 2018;23:177–198. doi: 10.1038/mp.2017.246.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/mp.2017.246</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5794890</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29230021</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hu WT, Ozturk T, Kollhoff A, Wharton W, Christina Howell J, Weiner M, Aisen P, Petersen R, Jack CR, Jagust W, Trojanowki JQ, Toga AW, Beckett L, Green RC, Saykin AJ, Morris J, Perrin RJ, Shaw LM, Kachaturian Z, Carrillo M, Potter W, Barnes L, Bernard M, González H, Ho C, Hsiao JK, Masliah E, Masterman D, Okonkwo O, Ryan L, Silverberg N, Fleisher A, Montine T, Kaye JA, Silbert LC, Schneider LS, Pawluczyk S, Becerra M, Brewer J, Heidebrink JL, Knopman D, Villanueva-Meyer J, Doody RS, Kass JS, Stern Y, Honig LS, Mintz A, Ances B, Mintun MA, Geldmacher D, Love MN, Grossman H, Goldstein MA, Shah RC, Lamar M, Duara R, Greig-Custo MT, Albert M, Onyike C, Smith A, Sadowski M, Wisniewski T, Shulman M, Doraiswamy PM, Petrella JR, James O, Karlawish JH, Wolk DA, Smith CD, Jicha GA, El Khouli R, Lopez OL, Porsteinsson AP, Thai G, Pierce A, Kelley B, Nguyen T, Womack K, Levey AI, Lah JJ, Burns JM, Swerdlow RH, Brooks WM, Silverman DHS, Kremen S, Graff-Radford NR, Farlow MR, van Dyck CH, Mecca AP, Chertkow H, Vaitekunis S, Black S, Stefanovic B, Heyn C, Hsiung G-YR, Sossi V, Finger E, Pasternak S, Rachinsky I, Grant I, Rogalski E, Mesulam M-M, Pomara N, Hernando R, Sarrael A, Rosen HJ, Miller BL, Perry D, Turner RS, Sperling RA, Johnson KA, Marshall GA, Yesavage J, Taylor JL, Chao S, Belden CM, Atri A, Spann BM, Killiany R, Stern R, Mez J, Obisesan TO, Ntekim OE, Lerner A, Ogrocki P, Tatsuoka C, Fletcher E, Maillard P, Olichney J, DeCarli C, Bates V, Capote H, Borrie M, Lee T-Y, Bartha R, Johnson S, Asthana S, Carlsson CM, Perrin A, Scharre DW, Kataki M, Tarawneh R, Hart D, Zimmerman EA, Celmins D, Miller DD, Koleva H, Shim H, Williamson JD, Craft S, Cleveland J, Ott BR, Drake J, Tremont G, Sabbagh M, Ritter A, Mintzer J, Masdeu J, Shi J, Newhouse P, Potkin S, Salloway S, Malloy P, Correia S, Kittur S, Pearlson GD, Blank K, Flashman LA, Seltzer M, Lee A, Relkin N, Chiang G, Alzheimer’s Disease Neuroimaging Initiative (2021) Higher CSF sTNFR1-related proteins associate with better prognosis in very early Alzheimer’s disease. Nat Commun 12:4001. 10.1038/s41467-021-24220-7</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hyman BT, Phelps CH, Beach TG, Bigio EH, Cairns NJ, Carrillo MC, Dickson DW, Duyckaerts C, Frosch MP, Masliah E, Mirra SS, Nelson PT, Schneider JA, Thal DR, Thies B, Trojanowski JQ, Vinters HV, Montine TJ. National institute on aging-alzheimer’s association guidelines for the neuropathologic assessment of Alzheimer’s disease. Alzheimers Dement J Alzheimers Assoc. 2012;8:1–13. doi: 10.1016/j.jalz.2011.10.007.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jalz.2011.10.007</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hyman BT, Trojanowski JQ. Editorial on consensus recommendations for the postmortem diagnosis of alzheimer disease from the national institute on aging and the reagan institute working group on diagnostic criteria for the neuropathological assessment of alzheimer disease. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol. 1997;56:1095–1097. doi: 10.1097/00005072-199710000-00002.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005072-199710000-00002</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9329452</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ishiki A, Okamura N, Furukawa K, Furumoto S, Harada R, Tomita N, Hiraoka K, Watanuki S, Ishikawa Y, Tago T, Funaki Y, Iwata R, Tashiro M, Yanai K, Kudo Y, Arai H. Longitudinal assessment of tau pathology in patients with alzheimer’s disease using [18F]THK-5117 positron emission tomography. PLoS ONE. 2015;10:e0140311–e0140311. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0140311.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0140311</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4604169</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26461913</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jack CR, Jr, Wiste HJ, Lesnick TG, Weigand SD, Knopman DS, Vemuri P, Pankratz VS, Senjem ML, Gunter JL, Mielke MM, Lowe VJ, Boeve BF, Petersen RC. Brain β-amyloid load approaches a plateau. Neurology. 2013;80:890–896. doi: 10.1212/WNL.0b013e3182840bbe.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0b013e3182840bbe</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3653215</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23446680</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jack CR, Jr, Wiste HJ, Weigand SD, Therneau TM, Lowe VJ, Knopman DS, Botha H, Graff-Radford J, Jones DT, Ferman TJ, Boeve BF, Kantarci K, Vemuri P, Mielke MM, Whitwell J, Josephs K, Schwarz CG, Senjem ML, Gunter JL, Petersen RC. Predicting future rates of tau accumulation on PET. Brain. 2020;143:3136–3150. doi: 10.1093/brain/awaa248.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awaa248</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7586089</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33094327</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jurga AM, Paleczna M, Kuter KZ. Overview of general and discriminating markers of differential microglia phenotypes. Front Cell Neurosci. 2020;14:198. doi: 10.3389/fncel.2020.00198.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fncel.2020.00198</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7424058</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32848611</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kamphuis W, Middeldorp J, Kooijman L, Sluijs JA, Kooi E-J, Moeton M, Freriks M, Mizee MR, Hol EM. Glial fibrillary acidic protein isoform expression in plaque related astrogliosis in Alzheimer’s disease. Neurobiol Aging. 2014;35:492–510. doi: 10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2013.09.035.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2013.09.035</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24269023</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kapasi A, DeCarli C, Schneider JA. Impact of multiple pathologies on the threshold for clinically overt dementia. Acta Neuropathol (Berl) 2017;134:171–186. doi: 10.1007/s00401-017-1717-7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00401-017-1717-7</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5663642</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28488154</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kawas CH, Kim RC, Sonnen JA, Bullain SS, Trieu T, Corrada MM. Multiple pathologies are common and related to dementia in the oldest-old: the 90+ Study. Neurology. 2015;85:535–542. doi: 10.1212/WNL.0000000000001831.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000001831</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4540246</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26180144</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kempthorne L, Yoon H, Madore C, Smith S, Wszolek ZK, Rademakers R, Kim J, Butovsky O, Dickson DW. Loss of homeostatic microglial phenotype in CSF1R-related Leukoencephalopathy. Acta Neuropathol Commun. 2020;8:72–72. doi: 10.1186/s40478-020-00947-0.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40478-020-00947-0</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7236286</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32430064</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim G-W, Park S-E, Park K, Jeong G-W. White matter connectivity and gray matter volume changes following donepezil treatment in patients with mild cognitive impairment: a preliminary study using probabilistic tractography. Front Aging Neurosci. 2021;12:506. doi: 10.3389/fnagi.2020.604940.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnagi.2020.604940</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kneynsberg A, Combs B, Christensen K, Morfini G, Kanaan NM. Axonal degeneration in tauopathies: disease relevance and underlying mechanisms. Front Neurosci. 2017;11:572–572. doi: 10.3389/fnins.2017.00572.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnins.2017.00572</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5651019</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29089864</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kopeikina KJ, Hyman BT, Spires-Jones TL. Soluble forms of tau are toxic in Alzheimer’s disease. Transl Neurosci. 2012;3:223–233. doi: 10.2478/s13380-012-0032-y.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/s13380-012-0032-y</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3460520</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23029602</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lambert J-C, Heath S, Even G, Campion D, Sleegers K, Hiltunen M, Combarros O, Zelenika D, Bullido MJ, Tavernier B, Letenneur L, Bettens K, Berr C, Pasquier F, Fiévet N, Barberger-Gateau P, Engelborghs S, De Deyn P, Mateo I, Franck A, Helisalmi S, Porcellini E, Hanon O, de Pancorbo MM, Lendon C, Dufouil C, Jaillard C, Leveillard T, Alvarez V, Bosco P, Mancuso M, Panza F, Nacmias B, Bossù P, Piccardi P, Annoni G, Seripa D, Galimberti D, Hannequin D, Licastro F, Soininen H, Ritchie K, Blanché H, Dartigues J-F, Tzourio C, Gut I, Van Broeckhoven C, Alpérovitch A, Lathrop M, Amouyel P, the European Alzheimer’s Disease Initiative Investigators (2009) Genome-wide association study identifies variants at CLU and CR1 associated with Alzheimer’s disease. Nat Genet, 41:1094–1099. 10.1038/ng.439</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Latimer CS, Burke BT, Liachko NF, Currey HN, Kilgore MD, Gibbons LE, Henriksen J, Darvas M, Domoto-Reilly K, Jayadev S, Grabowski TJ, Crane PK, Larson EB, Kraemer BC, Bird TD, Keene CD. Resistance and resilience to Alzheimer’s disease pathology are associated with reduced cortical pTau and absence of limbic-predominant age-related TDP-43 encephalopathy in a community-based cohort. Acta Neuropathol Commun. 2019;7:91. doi: 10.1186/s40478-019-0743-1.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40478-019-0743-1</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6556006</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31174609</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Latimer CS, Keene CD, Flanagan ME, Hemmy LS, Lim KO, White LR, Montine KS, Montine TJ. Resistance to alzheimer disease neuropathologic changes and apparent cognitive resilience in the nun and honolulu-asia aging studies. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol. 2017;76:458–466. doi: 10.1093/jnen/nlx030.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jnen/nlx030</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6334750</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28499012</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lopresti BJ, Klunk WE, Mathis CA, Hoge JA, Ziolko SK, Lu X, Meltzer CC, Schimmel K, Tsopelas ND, DeKosky ST, Price JC. Simplified quantification of pittsburgh compound B amyloid Imaging PET studies: a comparative analysis. J Nucl Med. 2005;46:1959.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16330558</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Low A, Mak E, Malpetti M, Passamonti L, Nicastro N, Stefaniak JD, Savulich G, Chouliaras L, Su L, Rowe JB, Markus HS, O’Brien JT. In vivo neuroinflammation and cerebral small vessel disease in mild cognitive impairment and Alzheimer’s disease. J Neurol Neurosurg Amp Psychiatry. 2021;92:45. doi: 10.1136/jnnp-2020-323894.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jnnp-2020-323894</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lue L-F, Brachova L, Civin WH, Rogers J. Inflammation, Aβ deposition, and neurofibrillary tangle formation as correlates of alzheimer’s disease neurodegeneration. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol. 1996;55:1083–1088. doi: 10.1097/00005072-199655100-00008.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00005072-199655100-00008</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8858005</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Malpetti M, Kievit RA, Passamonti L, Jones PS, Tsvetanov KA, Rittman T, Mak E, Nicastro N, Bevan-Jones WR, Su L, Hong YT, Fryer TD, Aigbirhio FI, O’Brien JT, Rowe JB. Microglial activation and tau burden predict cognitive decline in Alzheimer’s disease. Brain. 2020;143:1588–1602. doi: 10.1093/brain/awaa088.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awaa088</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7241955</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32380523</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McAleese KE, Miah M, Graham S, Hadfield GM, Walker L, Johnson M, Colloby SJ, Thomas AJ, DeCarli C, Koss D, Attems J. Frontal white matter lesions in Alzheimer’s disease are associated with both small vessel disease and AD-associated cortical pathology. Acta Neuropathol (Berl) 2021 doi: 10.1007/s00401-021-02376-2.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00401-021-02376-2</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mintun MA, LaRossa GN, Sheline YI, Dence CS, Lee SY, Mach RH, Klunk WE, Mathis CA, DeKosky ST, Morris JC. [11C]PIB in a nondemented population. Neurology. 2006;67:446. doi: 10.1212/01.wnl.0000228230.26044.a4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/01.wnl.0000228230.26044.a4</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16894106</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mirra SS, Heyman A, McKeel D, Sumi SM, Crain BJ, Brownlee LM, Vogel FS, Hughes JP, Belle G van, Berg L, participating CERAD neuropathologists (1991) The Consortium to Establish a Registry for Alzheimer’s Disease (CERAD). Neurology, 41:479. 10.1212/WNL.41.4.479</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Naj AC, Schellenberg GD, Alzheimer’s Disease Genetics Consortium (ADGC) 2017 Genomic variants, genes, and pathways of Alzheimer’s disease: an overview. Am J Med Genet Part B Neuropsychiatr Genet Off Publ Int Soc Psychiatr Genet, 174:5-26. 10.1002/ajmg.b.32499</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nasrabady SE, Rizvi B, Goldman JE, Brickman AM. White matter changes in Alzheimer’s disease: a focus on myelin and oligodendrocytes. Acta Neuropathol Commun. 2018;6:22. doi: 10.1186/s40478-018-0515-3.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40478-018-0515-3</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5834839</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29499767</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nelson PT, Alafuzoff I, Bigio EH, Bouras C, Braak H, Cairns NJ, Castellani RJ, Crain BJ, Davies P, Tredici KD, Duyckaerts C, Frosch MP, Haroutunian V, Hof PR, Hulette CM, Hyman BT, Iwatsubo T, Jellinger KA, Jicha GA, Kövari E, Kukull WA, Leverenz JB, Love S, Mackenzie IR, Mann DM, Masliah E, McKee AC, Montine TJ, Morris JC, Schneider JA, Sonnen JA, Thal DR, Trojanowski JQ, Troncoso JC, Wisniewski T, Woltjer RL, Beach TG. Correlation of alzheimer disease neuropathologic changes with cognitive status: a review of the literature. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol. 2012;71:362–381. doi: 10.1097/NEN.0b013e31825018f7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/NEN.0b013e31825018f7</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3560290</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22487856</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nelson PT, Braak H, Markesbery WR. Neuropathology and cognitive impairment in alzheimer disease: a complex but coherent relationship. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol. 2009;68:1–14. doi: 10.1097/NEN.0b013e3181919a48.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/NEN.0b013e3181919a48</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2692822</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19104448</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nordengen K, Kirsebom B-E, Henjum K, Selnes P, Gísladóttir B, Wettergreen M, Torsetnes SB, Grøntvedt GR, Waterloo KK, Aarsland D, Nilsson LNG, Fladby T. Glial activation and inflammation along the Alzheimer’s disease continuum. J Neuroinflamm. 2019;16:46. doi: 10.1186/s12974-019-1399-2.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12974-019-1399-2</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oeckl P, Halbgebauer S, Anderl-Straub S, Steinacker P, Huss AM, Neugebauer H, von Arnim CAF, Diehl-Schmid J, Grimmer T, Kornhuber J, Lewczuk P, Danek A, Consortium for Frontotemporal Lobar Degeneration German, Ludolph AC, Otto M (2019) Glial fibrillary acidic protein in serum is increased in alzheimer’s disease and correlates with cognitive impairment. J Alzheimers Dis, 67:481–488. 10.3233/JAD-180325</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pantoni L, Garcia JH. Cognitive impairment and cellular/vascular changes in the cerebral white mattera. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 1997;826:92–102. doi: 10.1111/j.1749-6632.1997.tb48463.x.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1749-6632.1997.tb48463.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9329683</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Perez-Nievas BG, Stein TD, Tai H-C, Dols-Icardo O, Scotton TC, Barroeta-Espar I, Fernandez-Carballo L, de Munain EL, Perez J, Marquie M, Serrano-Pozo A, Frosch MP, Lowe V, Parisi JE, Petersen RC, Ikonomovic MD, López OL, Klunk W, Hyman BT, Gómez-Isla T. Dissecting phenotypic traits linked to human resilience to Alzheimer’s pathology. Brain J Neurol. 2013;136:2510–2526. doi: 10.1093/brain/awt171.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awt171</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Prins ND, Scheltens P. White matter hyperintensities, cognitive impairment and dementia: an update. Nat Rev Neurol. 2015;11:157–165. doi: 10.1038/nrneurol.2015.10.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrneurol.2015.10</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25686760</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raj D, Yin Z, Breur M, Doorduin J, Holtman IR, Olah M, Mantingh-Otter IJ, Van Dam D, De Deyn PP, den Dunnen W, Eggen BJL, Amor S, Boddeke E. Increased white matter inflammation in aging- and alzheimer’s disease brain. Front Mol Neurosci. 2017;10:206. doi: 10.3389/fnmol.2017.00206.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnmol.2017.00206</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5492660</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28713239</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raz N, Yang Y, Dahle CL, Land S. Volume of white matter hyperintensities in healthy adults: contribution of age, vascular risk factors, and inflammation-related genetic variants. Biochim Biophys Acta. 2012;1822:361–369. doi: 10.1016/j.bbadis.2011.08.007.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbadis.2011.08.007</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3245802</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21889590</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reas ET. Amyloid and tau pathology in normal cognitive aging. J Neurosci Off J Soc Neurosci. 2017;37:7561–7563. doi: 10.1523/JNEUROSCI.1388-17.2017.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.1388-17.2017</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Riley KP, Snowdon DA, Desrosiers MF, Markesbery WR. Early life linguistic ability, late life cognitive function, and neuropathology: findings from the Nun Study. Dev Orig Aging Brain Blood Vessels. 2005;26:341–347. doi: 10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2004.06.019.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2004.06.019</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Robinson JL, Corrada MM, Kovacs GG, Dominique M, Caswell C, Xie SX, Lee VM-Y, Kawas CH, Trojanowski JQ. Non-Alzheimer’s contributions to dementia and cognitive resilience in The 90+ Study. Acta Neuropathol (Berl) 2018;136:377–388. doi: 10.1007/s00401-018-1872-5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00401-018-1872-5</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6534149</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29916037</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rowe CC, Ng S, Ackermann U, Gong SJ, Pike K, Savage G, Cowie TF, Dickinson KL, Maruff P, Darby D, Smith C, Woodward M, Merory J, Tochon-Danguy H, O’Keefe G, Klunk WE, Mathis CA, Price JC, Masters CL, Villemagne VL. Imaging β-amyloid burden in aging and dementia. Neurology. 2007;68:1718. doi: 10.1212/01.wnl.0000261919.22630.ea.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/01.wnl.0000261919.22630.ea</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17502554</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Santacruz K, Lewis J, Spires T, Paulson J, Kotilinek L, Ingelsson M, Guimaraes A, DeTure M, Ramsden M, McGowan E, Forster C, Yue M, Orne J, Janus C, Mariash A, Kuskowski M, Hyman B, Hutton M, Ashe KH. Tau suppression in a neurodegenerative mouse model improves memory function. Science. 2005;309:476–481. doi: 10.1126/science.1113694.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1126/science.1113694</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1574647</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16020737</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schneider JA, Aggarwal NT, Barnes L, Boyle P, Bennett DA. The neuropathology of older persons with and without dementia from community versus clinic cohorts. J Alzheimers Dis JAD. 2009;18:691–701. doi: 10.3233/JAD-2009-1227.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/JAD-2009-1227</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2853869</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19749406</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sekar S, McDonald J, Cuyugan L, Aldrich J, Kurdoglu A, Adkins J, Serrano G, Beach TG, Craig DW, Valla J, Reiman EM, Liang WS. Alzheimer’s disease is associated with altered expression of genes involved in immune response and mitochondrial processes in astrocytes. Neurobiol Aging. 2015;36:583–591. doi: 10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2014.09.027.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2014.09.027</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4315763</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25448601</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Serrano-Pozo A, Frosch MP, Masliah E, Hyman BT. Neuropathological alterations in Alzheimer disease. Cold Spring Harb Perspect Med. 2011;1:a006189–a006189. doi: 10.1101/cshperspect.a006189.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/cshperspect.a006189</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3234452</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22229116</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Serrano-Pozo A, Mielke ML, Gómez-Isla T, Betensky RA, Growdon JH, Frosch MP, Hyman BT. Reactive glia not only associates with plaques but also parallels tangles in Alzheimer’s disease. Am J Pathol. 2011;179:1373–1384. doi: 10.1016/j.ajpath.2011.05.047.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajpath.2011.05.047</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3157187</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21777559</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shanbhag NM, Evans MD, Mao W, Nana AL, Seeley WW, Adame A, Rissman RA, Masliah E, Mucke L. Early neuronal accumulation of DNA double strand breaks in Alzheimer’s disease. Acta Neuropathol Commun. 2019;7:77. doi: 10.1186/s40478-019-0723-5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40478-019-0723-5</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6524256</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31101070</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Simpson JE, Ince PG, Lace G, Forster G, Shaw PJ, Matthews F, Savva G, Brayne C, Wharton SB. Astrocyte phenotype in relation to Alzheimer-type pathology in the ageing brain. Neurobiol Aging. 2010;31:578–590. doi: 10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2008.05.015.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2008.05.015</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18586353</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Simpson JE, Ince PG, Shaw PJ, Heath PR, Raman R, Garwood CJ, Gelsthorpe C, Baxter L, Forster G, Matthews FE, Brayne C, Wharton SB. Microarray analysis of the astrocyte transcriptome in the aging brain: relationship to Alzheimer’s pathology and APOE genotype. Neurobiol Aging. 2011;32:1795–1807. doi: 10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2011.04.013.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neurobiolaging.2011.04.013</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21705112</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singh A, Allen D, Fracassi A, Tumurbaatar B, Natarajan C, Scaduto P, Woltjer R, Kayed R, Limon A, Krishnan B, Taglialatela G. Functional integrity of synapses in the central nervous system of cognitively intact individuals with high alzheimer’s disease neuropathology is associated with absence of synaptic tau oligomers. J Alzheimers Dis. 2020;78:1661–1678. doi: 10.3233/JAD-200716.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3233/JAD-200716</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7836055</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33185603</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sobue A, Komine O, Hara Y, Endo F, Mizoguchi H, Watanabe S, Murayama S, Saito T, Saido TC, Sahara N, Higuchi M, Ogi T, Yamanaka K. Microglial gene signature reveals loss of homeostatic microglia associated with neurodegeneration of Alzheimer’s disease. Acta Neuropathol Commun. 2021;9:1. doi: 10.1186/s40478-020-01099-x.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40478-020-01099-x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7786928</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33402227</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stevens B, Allen NJ, Vazquez LE, Howell GR, Christopherson KS, Nouri N, Micheva KD, Mehalow AK, Huberman AD, Stafford B, Sher A, Litke AM, Lambris JD, Smith SJ, John SWM, Barres BA. The classical complement cascade mediates CNS synapse elimination. Cell. 2007;131:1164–1178. doi: 10.1016/j.cell.2007.10.036.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2007.10.036</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18083105</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Terry RD. Cell death or synaptic loss in alzheimer disease. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol. 2000;59:1118–1119. doi: 10.1093/jnen/59.12.1118.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jnen/59.12.1118</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11138931</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thal D, Rüb U, Schultz C, Sassin I, Ghebremedhin E, Tredici K, Braak E, Braak H. Sequence of A b-protein deposition in the human medial temporal lobe. J Neuropathol Exp Neurol. 2000 doi: 10.1093/jnen/59.8.733.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/jnen/59.8.733</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10952063</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tzioras M, Daniels MJD, King D, Popovic K, Holloway RK, Stevenson AJ, Tulloch J, Kandasamy J, Sokol D, Latta C, Rose J, Smith C, Miron VE, Henstridge C, McColl BW, Spires-Jones TL (2019) Altered synaptic ingestion by human microglia in Alzheimer’s disease. bioRxiv 795930. 10.1101/795930</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Uematsu M, Nakamura A, Ebashi M, Hirokawa K, Takahashi R, Uchihara T. Brainstem tau pathology in Alzheimer’s disease is characterized by increase of three repeat tau and independent of amyloid β. Acta Neuropathol Commun. 2018;6:1. doi: 10.1186/s40478-017-0501-1.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s40478-017-0501-1</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5753447</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29298724</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verkhratsky A, Lazareva N, Semyanov A. Glial decline and loss of homeostatic support rather than inflammation defines cognitive aging. Neural Regen Res. 2022;17:565–566. doi: 10.4103/1673-5374.320979.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/1673-5374.320979</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8504371</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34380892</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vogt L, et al.  Laminar distribution of neuron degeneration in posterior cingulate cortex in Alzheimer’s disease. Acta Neuropathol. 1990;80(6):581–589. doi: 10.1007/BF00307624.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF00307624</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1703381</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vonsattel JPG, Del Amaya MP, Keller CE. Twenty-first century brain banking. Processing brains for research: the Columbia University methods. Acta Neuropathol (Berl) 2008;115:509–532. doi: 10.1007/s00401-007-0311-9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00401-007-0311-9</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2292479</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17985145</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vonsattel JPG, Myers RH, Tessa Hedley-Whyte E, Ropper AH, Bird ED, Richardson EP., Jr Cerebral amyloid angiopathy without and with cerebral hemorrhages: a comparative histological study. Ann Neurol. 1991;30:637–649. doi: 10.1002/ana.410300503.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.410300503</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1763890</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Walker DG. Defining activation states of microglia in human brain tissue: an unresolved issue for Alzheimer’s disease. Neuroimmunol Neuroinflamm. 2020;7:194–214. doi: 10.20517/2347-8659.2020.09.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.20517/2347-8659.2020.09</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weinhard L, di Bartolomei G, Bolasco G, Machado P, Schieber NL, Neniskyte U, Exiga M, Vadisiute A, Raggioli A, Schertel A, Schwab Y, Gross CT. Microglia remodel synapses by presynaptic trogocytosis and spine head filopodia induction. Nat Commun. 2018;9:1228. doi: 10.1038/s41467-018-03566-5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-018-03566-5</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5964317</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29581545</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weintraub S, Salmon D, Mercaldo N, Ferris S, Graff-Radford NR, Chui H, Cummings J, DeCarli C, Foster NL, Galasko D, Peskind E, Dietrich W, Beekly DL, Kukull WA, Morris JC. The alzheimer’s disease centers’ uniform data set (UDS): the neuropsychologic test battery. Alzheimer Dis Assoc Disord. 2009;23:91–101. doi: 10.1097/WAD.0b013e318191c7dd.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/WAD.0b013e318191c7dd</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2743984</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19474567</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wightman DP, Jansen IE, Savage JE, Shadrin AA, Bahrami S, Holland D, Rongve A, Børte S, Winsvold BS, Drange OK, Martinsen AE, Skogholt AH, Willer C, Bråthen G, Bosnes I, Nielsen JB, Fritsche LG, Thomas LF, Pedersen LM, Gabrielsen ME, Johnsen MB, Meisingset TW, Zhou W, Proitsi P, Hodges A, Dobson R, Velayudhan L, Heilbron K, Auton A, Agee M, Aslibekyan S, Babalola E, Bell RK, Bielenberg J, Bryc K, Bullis E, Cameron B, Coker D, Partida GC, Dhamija D, Das S, Elson SL, Filshtein T, Fletez-Brant K, Fontanillas P, Freyman W, Gandhi PM, Hicks B, Hinds DA, Huber KE, Jewett EM, Jiang Y, Kleinman A, Kukar K, Lane V, Lin K-H, Lowe M, Luff MK, McCreight JC, McIntyre MH, McManus KF, Micheletti SJ, Moreno ME, Mountain JL, Mozaffari SV, Nandakumar P, Noblin ES, O’Connell J, Petrakovitz AA, Poznik GD, Schumacher M, Shastri AJ, Shelton JF, Shi J, Shringarpure S, Tian C, Tran V, Tung JY, Wang X, Wang W, Weldon CH, Wilton P, Sealock JM, Davis LK, Pedersen NL, Reynolds CA, Karlsson IK, Magnusson S, Stefansson H, Thordardottir S, Jonsson PV, Snaedal J, Zettergren A, Skoog I, Kern S, Waern M, Zetterberg H, Blennow K, Stordal E, Hveem K, Zwart J-A, Athanasiu L, Selnes P, Saltvedt I, Sando SB, Ulstein I, Djurovic S, Fladby T, Aarsland D, Selbæk G, Ripke S, Stefansson K, Andreassen OA, Posthuma D, 23andMe Research Team 2021 A genome-wide association study with 1,126,563 individuals identifies new risk loci for Alzheimer’s disease. Nat Genet, 53:1276–1282, 10.1038/s41588-021-00921-z</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wilson RS, Boyle PA, Yu L, Barnes LL, Schneider JA, Bennett DA. Life-span cognitive activity, neuropathologic burden, and cognitive aging. Neurology. 2013;81:314–321. doi: 10.1212/WNL.0b013e31829c5e8a.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0b013e31829c5e8a</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3772831</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23825173</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zrzavy T, Hametner S, Wimmer I, Butovsky O, Weiner HL, Lassmann H. Loss of ‘homeostatic’ microglia and patterns of their activation in active multiple sclerosis. Brain. 2017;140:1900–1913. doi: 10.1093/brain/awx113.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awx113</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6057548</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28541408</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
