<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35535898</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>22</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">1673-5374</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>17</Volume>
            <Issue>11</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Nov</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Neural regeneration research</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Neural Regen Res</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Effects of progesterone on T-type-Ca<sup>2+</sup>-channel expression in Purkinje cells.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>2465</StartPage>
          <EndPage>2471</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>2465-2471</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/1673-5374.339008</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Plasticity of cerebellar Purkinje cells (PC) is influenced by progesterone via the classical progesterone receptors PR-A and PR-B by stimulating dendritogenesis, spinogenesis, and synaptogenesis in these cells. Dissociated PC cultures were used to analyze progesterone effects at a molecular level on the voltage-gated T-type-Ca<sup>2+</sup>-channels Ca<sub>v</sub>3.1, Ca<sub>v</sub>3.2, and Ca<sub>v</sub>3.3 as they helped determine neuronal plasticity by regulating Ca<sup>2+</sup>-influx in neuronal cells. The results showed direct effects of progesterone on the mRNA expression of T-type-Ca<sup>2+</sup>-channels, as well as on the protein kinases A and C being involved in downstream signaling pathways that play an important role in neuronal plasticity. For the mRNA expression studies of T-type-Ca<sup>2+</sup>-channels and protein kinases of the signaling cascade, laser microdissection and purified PC cultures of different maturation stages were used. Immunohistochemical staining was also performed to characterize the localization of T-type-Ca<sup>2+</sup>-channels in PC. Experimental progesterone treatment was performed on the purified PC culture for 24 and 48 hours. Our results show that progesterone increases the expression of Ca<sub>v</sub>3.1 and Ca<sub>v</sub>3.3 and associated protein kinases A and C in PC at the mRNA level within 48 hours after treatment at latest. These effects extend the current knowledge of the function of progesterone in the central nervous system and provide an explanatory approach for its influence on neuronal plasticity.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Eickhoff</LastName>
            <ForeName>Annika</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cytology, Institute of Anatomy, Ruhr-University Bochum, Bochum, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tjaden</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jonas</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cytology, Institute of Anatomy, Ruhr-University Bochum, Bochum, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Stahlke</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sarah</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cytology, Institute of Anatomy, Ruhr-University Bochum, Bochum, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Vorgerd</LastName>
            <ForeName>Matthias</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Neuromuscular Center Ruhrgebiet, University Hospital Bergmannsheil, Ruhr-Universität Bochum, Bochum, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Theis</LastName>
            <ForeName>Verena</ForeName>
            <Initials>V</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cytology, Institute of Anatomy, Ruhr-University Bochum, Bochum, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Matschke</LastName>
            <ForeName>Veronika</ForeName>
            <Initials>V</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cytology, Institute of Anatomy, Ruhr-University Bochum, Bochum, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Theiss</LastName>
            <ForeName>Carsten</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cytology, Institute of Anatomy, Ruhr-University Bochum, Bochum, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Neural Regen Res</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101316351</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1673-5374</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cav3.1</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cav3.2</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cav3.3</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Purkinje cells</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">T-type-Ca2+-channels</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuronal plasticity</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">progesterone</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">protein kinase A</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">protein kinase C</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rat cerebellum</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>None</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>7</Hour>
          <Minute>58</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35535898</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9120685</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/1673-5374.339008</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">NeuralRegenRes_2022_17_11_2465_339008</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aguado C, García-Madrona S, Gil-Minguez M, Luján R. Ontogenic changes and differential localization of T-type Ca(2+) channel subunits Cav3.1 and Cav3.2 in mouse hippocampus and cerebellum. Front Neuroanat. 2016;10:83.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4999439</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27616982</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arcos-Montoya D, Wegman-Ostrosky T, Mejía-Pérez S, De la Fuente-Granada M, Camacho-Arroyo I, García-Carrancá A, Velasco-Velázquez MA, Manjarrez-Marmolejo J, González-Arenas A. Progesterone receptor together with PKCαexpression as prognostic factors for astrocytomas malignancy. Onco Targets Ther. 2021;14:3757–3768.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8217595</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34168461</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Asmara H, Micu I, Rizwan AP, Sahu G, Simms BA, Zhang FX, Engbers JDT, Stys PK, Zamponi GW, Turner RW. A T-type channel-calmodulin complex triggers αCaMKII activation. Mol Brain. 2017;10:37.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5553682</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28800734</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bannister RA, Beam KG. Ca(V)1.1: The atypical prototypical voltage-gated Ca²+channel. Biochim Biophys Acta. 2013;1828:1587–1597.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3615030</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22982493</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baulieu EE. Neurosteroids: of the nervous system, by the nervous system for the nervous system. Recent Prog Horm Res. 1997;52:1–32.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baulieu EE, Robel P. Neurosteroids: a new brain function?J Steroid Biochem Mol Biol. 1990;37:395–403.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Belardetti F, Zamponi GW. Linking calcium-channel isoforms to potential therapies. Curr Opin Investig Drugs. 2008;9:707–715.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bennison SA, Blazejewski SM, Smith TH, Toyo-oka K. Protein kinases: master regulators of neuritogenesis and therapeutic targets for axon regeneration. Cell Mol Life Sci. 2020;77:1511–1530.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7166181</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31659414</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Borodinova AA, Zuzina AB, Balaban PM. Role of atypical protein kinases in maintenance of long-term memory and synaptic plasticity. Biochemistry (Mosc) 2017;82:243–256.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28320265</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Catterall WA. Structure and regulation of voltage-gated Ca2+channels. Annu Rev Cell Dev Biol. 2000;16:521–555.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11031246</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Catterall WA, Leal K, Nanou E. Calcium channels and short-term synaptic plasticity. J Biol Chem. 2013;288:10742–10749.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3624454</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23400776</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chemin J, Mezghrani A, Bidaud I, Dupasquier S, Marger F, Barrère C, Nargeot J, Lory P. Temperature-dependent modulation of CaV3 T-type calcium channels by protein kinases C and A in mammalian cells. J Biol Chem. 2007;282:32710–32718.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17855364</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chemin J, Monteil A, Perez-Reyes E, Bourinet E, Nargeot J, Lory P. Specific contribution of human T-type calcium channel isotypes (alpha(1G), alpha(1H) and alpha(1I)) to neuronal excitability. J Physiol 540. 2002;(Pt 1):3–14.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Nicola AF, Garay LI, Meyer M, Guennoun R, Sitruk-Ware R, Schumacher M, Gonzalez Deniselle MC. Neurosteroidogenesis and progesterone anti-inflammatory/neuroprotective effects. J Neuroendocrinol. 2018;30:e12502.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Nicola AF, Gonzalez SL, Labombarda F, González Deniselle MC, Garay L, Guennoun R, Schumacher M. Progesterone treatment of spinal cord injury: Effects on receptors, neurotrophins and myelination. J Mol Neurosci. 2006;28:3–15.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16632872</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Engbers JD, Anderson D, Zamponi GW, Turner RW. Signal processing by T-type calcium channel interactions in the cerebellum. Front Cell Neurosci. 2013;7:230.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3841819</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24348329</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghoumari AM, Abi Ghanem C, Asbelaoui N, Schumacher M, Hussain R. Roles of progesterone, testosterone and their nuclear receptors in central nervous system myelination and remyelination. Int J Mol Sci. 2020;3163;21</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guennoun R. Progesterone in the brain: hormone, neurosteroid and neuroprotectant. Int J Mol Sci. 2020;21:5271.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Han VZ, Zhang Y, Bell CC, Hansel C. Synaptic plasticity and calcium signaling in Purkinje cells of the central cerebellar lobes of mormyrid fish. J Neurosci. 2007;27:13499–13512.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6673090</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18057208</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heron SE, Khosravani H, Varela D, Bladen C, Williams TC, Newman MR, Scheffer IE, Berkovic SF, Mulley JC, Zamponi GW. Extended spectrum of idiopathic generalized epilepsies associated with CACNA1H functional variants. Ann Neurol. 2007;62:560–568.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17696120</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Higgins D, Graupner M, Brunel N. Memory maintenance in synapses with calcium-based plasticity in the presence of background activity. PLoS Comput Biol. 2014;10:e1003834.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4183374</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25275319</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hildebrand ME, Isope P, Miyazaki T, Nakaya T, Garcia E, Feltz A, Schneider T, Hescheler J, Kano M, Sakimura K, Watanabe M, Dieudonné S, Snutch TP. Functional coupling between mGluR1 and Cav3.1 T-type calcium channels contributes to parallel fiber-induced fast calcium signaling within Purkinje cell dendritic spines. J Neurosci. 2009;29:9668–82.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6666586</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19657020</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hu C, Depuy SD, Yao J, McIntire WE, Barrett PQ. Protein kinase A activity controls the regulation of T-type CaV3.2 channels by Gbetagamma dimers. J Biol Chem. 2009;284:7465–7473.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2658042</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19131331</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jagodic MM, Pathirathna S, Nelson MT, Mancuso S, Joksovic PM, Rosenberg ER, Bayliss DA, Jevtovic-Todorovic V, Todorovic SM. Cell-specific alterations of T-type calcium current in painful diabetic neuropathy enhance excitability of sensory neurons. J Neurosci. 2007;27:3305–3316.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6672477</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17376991</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kapfhammer JP. Cellular and molecular control of dendritic growth and development of cerebellar Purkinje cells. Prog Histochem Cytochem. 2004;39:131–182.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15580762</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kapur J, Joshi S. Progesterone modulates neuronal excitability bidirectionally. Neurosci Lett. 2021;744:135619.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7821816</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33421486</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim JA, Park JY, Kang HW, Huh SU, Jeong SW, Lee JH. Augmentation of Cav3.2 T-type calcium channel activity by cAMP-dependent protein kinase A. J Pharmacol Exp Ther. 2006;318:230–237.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16569752</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim MJ, Shin HJ, Won KA, Yang KY, Ju JS, Park YY, Park JS, Bae YC, Ahn DK. Progesterone produces antinociceptive and neuroprotective effects in rats with microinjected lysophosphatidic acid in the trigeminal nerve root. Mol Pain. 2012;8:16.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3315401</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22429647</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kipp M, Amor S, Krauth R, Beyer C. Multiple sclerosis: neuroprotective alliance of estrogen-progesterone and gender. Front Neuroendocrinol. 2012;33:1–16.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22289667</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kitamura K, Kano M. Dendritic calcium signaling in cerebellar Purkinje cell. Neural Netw. 2013;47:11–17.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22985934</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Klöckner U, Lee JH, Cribbs LL, Daud A, Hescheler J, Pereverzev A, Perez-Reyes E, Schneider T. Comparison of the Ca2+currents induced by expression of three cloned alpha1 subunits, alpha1G alpha1H and alpha1I of low-voltage-activated T-type Ca2 +channels. Eur J Neurosci. 1999;11:4171–4178.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10594642</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leonelli E, Bianchi R, Cavaletti G, Caruso D, Crippa D, Garcia-Segura LM, Lauria G, Magnaghi V, Roglio I, Melcangi RC. Progesterone and its derivatives are neuroprotective agents in experimental diabetic neuropathy: A multimodal analysis. Neuroscience. 2007;144:1293–1304.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17187935</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leresche N, Lambert RC. T-type calcium channels in synaptic plasticity. Channels. 2017;11:121–139.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5398590</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27653665</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lin H, Magrane J, Clark EM, Halawani SM, Warren N, Rattelle A, Lynch DR. Early VGLUT1-specific parallel fiber synaptic deficits and dysregulated cerebellar circuit in the KIKO mouse model of Friedreich ataxia. Dis Model Mech. 2017;10:1529–1538.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5769605</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29259026</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lory P, Nicole S, Monteil A. Neuronal Cav3 channelopathies: recent progress and perspectives. Pflugers Arch. 2020;472:831–844.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7351805</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32638069</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maggio N, Vlachos A. Synaptic plasticity at the interface of health and disease: New insights on the role of endoplasmic reticulum intracellular calcium stores. Neuroscience. 2014;281:135–146.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25264032</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marquina-Sánchez B, González-Jorge J, Hansberg-Pastor V, Wegman-Ostrosky T, Baranda-Ávila N, Mejía-Pérez S, Camacho-Arroyo I, González-Arenas A. The interplay between intracellular progesterone receptor and PKC plays a key role in migration and invasion of human glioblastoma cells. J Steroid Biochem Mol Biol. 2017;172:198–206.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27717886</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mateos-Aparicio P, Rodríguez-Moreno A. Calcium dynamics and synaptic plasticity. Adv Exp Med Biol. 2020;1131:965–984.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31646541</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McRory JE, Santi CM, Hamming KS, Mezeyova J, Sutton KG, Baillie DL, Stea A, Snutch TP. Molecular and functional characterization of a family of rat brain T-type calcium channels. J Biol Chem. 2001;276:3999–4011.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11073957</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Metzger F, Kapfhammer JP. Protein kinase C: its role in activity-dependent Purkinje cell dendritic development and plasticity. Cerebellum. 2003;2:206–214.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14509570</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Molineux ML, McRory JE, McKay BE, Hamid J, Mehaffey WH, Rehak R, Snutch TP, Zamponi GW, Turner RW. Specific T-type calcium channel isoforms are associated with distinct burst phenotypes in deep cerebellar nuclear neurons. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2006;103:5555–5560.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1459392</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16567615</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mullen RJ, Buck CR, Smith AM. NeuN, a neuronal specific nuclear protein in vertebrates. Development. 1992;116:201–211.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1483388</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Napper RMA, Harvey RJ. Number of parallel fiber synapses on an individual Purkinje cell in the cerebellum of the rat. J Comp Neurol. 1988;274:168–177.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3209740</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nelson MT, Todorovic SM, Perez-Reyes E. The role of T-type calcium channels in epilepsy and pain. Curr Pharm Des. 2006;12:2189–2197.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16787249</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nemer A, Azab AN, Rimon G, Lamprecht S, Ben-Menahem D. Different roles of cAMP/PKA and PKC signaling in regulating progesterone and PGE2 levels in immortalized rat granulosa cell cultures. Gen Comp Endocrinol. 2018;269:88–95.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30144443</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Neveu D, Zucker RS. Postsynaptic levels of [Ca2+]i needed to trigger LTD and LTP. Neuron. 1996;16:619–629.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8785059</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Newton AC. Protein kinase C: poised to signal. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2010;298:E395-402.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2838521</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19934406</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Newton AC. Protein kinase C: perfectly balanced. Crit Rev Biochem Mol Biol. 2018;53:208–230.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5901981</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29513138</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Park JY, Kang HW, Moon HJ, Huh SU, Jeong SW, Soldatov NM, Lee JH. Activation of protein kinase C augments T-type Ca2+channel activity without changing channel surface density. J Physiol. 2006;577(Pt 2):513–523.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1890444</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17008378</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pemberton KE, Hill-Eubanks LJ, Jones SV. Modulation of low-threshold T-type calcium channels by the five muscarinic receptor subtypes in NIH 3T3 cells. Pflugers Arch. 2000;440:452–461.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10954332</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Perez-Reyes E. Molecular physiology of low-voltage-activated t-type calcium channels. Physiol Rev. 2003;83:117–161.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12506128</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pieczora L, Stracke L, Vorgerd M, Hahn S, Theiss C, Theis V. Unveiling of miRNA expression patterns in purkinje cells during development. Cerebellum. 2017;16:376–387.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27387430</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roglio I, Bianchi R, Gotti S, Scurati S, Giatti S, Pesaresi M, Caruso D, Panzica GC, Melcangi RC. Neuroprotective effects of dihydroprogesterone and progesterone in an experimental model of nerve crush injury. Neuroscience. 2008;155:673–685.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18625290</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sakamoto H, Ukena K, Tsutsui K. Effects of progesterone synthesized de novo in the developing purkinje cell on its dendritic growth and synaptogenesis. J Neurosci. 2001;21:6221–6232.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6763166</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11487645</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schroeder J, Fischbach P, McCleskey E. T-type calcium channels: heterogeneous expression in rat sensory neurons and selective modulation by phorbol esters. J Neurosci. 1990;10:947–951.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6570135</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2156966</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schumacher M, Guennoun R, Stein DG, De Nicola AF. Progesterone: therapeutic opportunities for neuroprotection and myelin repair. Pharmacol Ther. 2007;116:77–106.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17659348</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schumacher M, Hussain R, Gago N, Oudinet JP, Mattern C, Ghoumari AM. Progesterone synthesis in the nervous system: implications for myelination and myelin repair. Front Neurosci. 2012;6:10.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3274763</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22347156</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Seil FJ. Interactions between cerebellar Purkinje cells and their associated astrocytes. Histol Histopathol. 2001;16:955–968.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11510987</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shea TB, Cressman CM, Spencer MJ, Beermann ML, Nixon RA. Enhancement of neurite outgrowth following calpain inhibition is mediated by protein kinase C. J Neurochem. 1995;65:517–527.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7616205</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shobe J. The role of PKA, CaMKII and PKC in avoidance conditioning: permissive or instructive? Neurobiol Learn Mem. 2002;77:291–312.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11991759</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singh M, Su C. Progesterone and neuroprotection. Horm Behav. 2013;63:284–290.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3467329</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22732134</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Snyder EM, Colledge M, Crozier RA, Chen WS, Scott JD, Bear MF. Role for A kinase-anchoring proteins (AKAPS) in glutamate receptor trafficking and long term synaptic depression. J Biol Chem. 2005;280:16962–16968.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3923403</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15718245</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stein DG, Wright DW, Kellermann AL. Does progesterone have neuroprotective properties? Ann Emerg Med. 2008;51:164–172.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17588708</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Strünker T, Goodwin N, Brenker C, Kashikar ND, Weyand I, Seifert R, Kaupp UB. The CatSper channel mediates progesterone-induced Ca2+influx in human sperm. Nature. 2011;471:382–386.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21412338</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sun J, Moenter SM. Progesterone treatment inhibits and dihydrotestosterone (DHT) treatment potentiates voltage-gated calcium currents in gonadotropin-releasing hormone (GnRH) neurons. Endocrinology. 2010;151:5349–5358.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2954728</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20739401</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Talavera K, Nilius B. Biophysics and structure–function relationship of T-type Ca2+channels. Cell Calcium. 2006;40:97–114.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16777221</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Taylor SS, Ilouz R, Zhang P, Kornev AP. Assembly of allosteric macromolecular switches: lessons from PKA. Nat Rev Mol Cell Biol. 2012;13:646–658.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3985763</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22992589</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Theis V, Theiss C. Progesterone effects in the nervous system. Anat Rec. 2019;302:1276–1286.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tjaden J, Pieczora L, Wach F, Theiss C, Theis V. Cultivation of purified primary purkinje cells from rat cerebella. Cell Mol Neurobiol. 2018;38:1399–1412.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30066224</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tseng GN, Boyden PA. Different effects of intracellular Ca and protein kinase C on cardiac T and L Ca currents. Am J Physiol 261. 1991;(2 Pt 2):H364–379.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tsutsui K, Haraguchi S. Neuroprotective actions of cerebellar and pineal allopregnanolone on Purkinje cells. FASEB Bioadv. 2020;2:149–159.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7059624</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32161904</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Turnham RE, Scott JD. Protein kinase A catalytic subunit isoform PRKACA;History, function and physiology. Gene. 2016;577:101–108.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4713328</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26687711</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Valdés-Rives SA, Arcos-Montoya D, de la Fuente-Granada M, Zamora-Sánchez CJ, Arias-Romero LE, Villamar-Cruz O, Camacho-Arroyo I, Pérez-Tapia SM, González-Arenas A. LPA1 receptor promotes progesterone receptor phosphorylation through PKCαin human glioblastoma cells. Cells. 2021;10:807.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8066126</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33916643</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Viero C, Dayanithi G. Neurosteroids are excitatory in supraoptic neurons but inhibitory in the peripheral nervous system: it is all about oxytocin and progesterone receptors. Prog Brain Res. 2008;170:177–192.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18655882</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Welsby PJ, Wang H, Wolfe JT, Colbran RJ, Johnson ML, Barrett PQ. A mechanism for the direct regulation of T-type calcium channels by Ca 2+/calmodulin-dependent kinase II. J Neurosci. 2003;23:10116–10121.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6740846</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14602827</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wessel L, Balakrishnan-Renuka A, Henkel C, Meyer HE, Meller K, Brand-Saberi B, Theiss C. Long-term incubation with mifepristone (MLTI) increases the spine density in developing Purkinje cells: new insights into progesterone receptor mechanisms. Cell Mol Life Sci. 2014;71:1723–1740.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23982753</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wheeler DG, Groth RD, Ma H, Barrett CF, Owen SF, Safa P, Tsien RW. CaV1 and CaV2 channels engage distinct modes of Ca2+signaling to control CREB-dependent gene expression. Cell. 2012;149:1112–1124.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3654514</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22632974</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Willett RT, Bayin NS, Lee AS, Krishnamurthy A, Wojcinski A, Lao Z, Stephen D, Rosello-Diez A, Dauber-Decker KL, Orvis GD, Wu Z, Tessier-Lavigne M, Joyner AL. Cerebellar nuclei excitatory neurons regulate developmental scaling of presynaptic Purkinje cell number and organ growth. eLife. 2019;8:e50617.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6890462</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31742552</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wisden W. Structure and distribution of multiple GABAA receptor subunits with special reference to the cerebellum. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 1995;757:506–515.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7611708</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wolfe JT, Wang H, Howard J, Garrison JC, Barrett PQ. T-type calcium channel regulation by specific G-protein βγsubunits. Nature. 2003;424:209–213.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12853961</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wolfe JT, Wang H, Perez-Reyes E, Barrett PQ. Stimulation of recombinant Ca(v)3.2, T-type Ca(2+) channel currents by CaMKIIgamma(C) J Physiol. 2002;538(Pt 2):343–355.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2290082</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11790804</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu N, Engbers J, Khaja S, Xu L, Clark JJ, Hansen MR. Influence of cAMP and protein kinase A on neurite length from spiral ganglion neurons. Hear Res. 2012;283(1-2):33–44.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3277666</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22154930</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yamada K, Watanabe M. Cytodifferentiation of Bergmann glia and its relationship with Purkinje cells. Anat Sci Int. 2002;77:94–108.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12418089</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang Y, Lisberger SG. Purkinje-cell plasticity and cerebellar motor learning are graded by complex-spike duration. Nature. 2014;510:529–532.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4132823</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24814344</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yilmaz C, Karali K, Fodelianaki G, Gravanis A, Chavakis T, Charalampopoulos I, Alexaki VI. Neurosteroids as regulators of neuroinflammation. Front Neuroendocrinol. 2019;55:100788.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31513776</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zamponi GW, Striessnig J, Koschak A, Dolphin AC. The physiology, pathology and pharmacology of voltage-gated calcium channels and their future therapeutic potential. Pharmacol Rev. 2015;67:821–870.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4630564</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26362469</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang JD, Biczok R, Ruschhaupt M. ddCt: the ddCt algorithm for the analysis of quantitative real-time PCR (qRT-PCR) R package version 1.32.0. 2015.  
https://doi.org/doi: 10.18129/B9.bioc.ddCt. 
</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35535898</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>22</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">1673-5374</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>17</Volume>
            <Issue>11</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Nov</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Neural regeneration research</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Neural Regen Res</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Effects of progesterone on T-type-Ca<sup>2+</sup>-channel expression in Purkinje cells.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>2465</StartPage>
          <EndPage>2471</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>2465-2471</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/1673-5374.339008</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Plasticity of cerebellar Purkinje cells (PC) is influenced by progesterone via the classical progesterone receptors PR-A and PR-B by stimulating dendritogenesis, spinogenesis, and synaptogenesis in these cells. Dissociated PC cultures were used to analyze progesterone effects at a molecular level on the voltage-gated T-type-Ca<sup>2+</sup>-channels Ca<sub>v</sub>3.1, Ca<sub>v</sub>3.2, and Ca<sub>v</sub>3.3 as they helped determine neuronal plasticity by regulating Ca<sup>2+</sup>-influx in neuronal cells. The results showed direct effects of progesterone on the mRNA expression of T-type-Ca<sup>2+</sup>-channels, as well as on the protein kinases A and C being involved in downstream signaling pathways that play an important role in neuronal plasticity. For the mRNA expression studies of T-type-Ca<sup>2+</sup>-channels and protein kinases of the signaling cascade, laser microdissection and purified PC cultures of different maturation stages were used. Immunohistochemical staining was also performed to characterize the localization of T-type-Ca<sup>2+</sup>-channels in PC. Experimental progesterone treatment was performed on the purified PC culture for 24 and 48 hours. Our results show that progesterone increases the expression of Ca<sub>v</sub>3.1 and Ca<sub>v</sub>3.3 and associated protein kinases A and C in PC at the mRNA level within 48 hours after treatment at latest. These effects extend the current knowledge of the function of progesterone in the central nervous system and provide an explanatory approach for its influence on neuronal plasticity.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Eickhoff</LastName>
            <ForeName>Annika</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cytology, Institute of Anatomy, Ruhr-University Bochum, Bochum, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tjaden</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jonas</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cytology, Institute of Anatomy, Ruhr-University Bochum, Bochum, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Stahlke</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sarah</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cytology, Institute of Anatomy, Ruhr-University Bochum, Bochum, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Vorgerd</LastName>
            <ForeName>Matthias</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology, Neuromuscular Center Ruhrgebiet, University Hospital Bergmannsheil, Ruhr-Universität Bochum, Bochum, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Theis</LastName>
            <ForeName>Verena</ForeName>
            <Initials>V</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cytology, Institute of Anatomy, Ruhr-University Bochum, Bochum, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Matschke</LastName>
            <ForeName>Veronika</ForeName>
            <Initials>V</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cytology, Institute of Anatomy, Ruhr-University Bochum, Bochum, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Theiss</LastName>
            <ForeName>Carsten</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cytology, Institute of Anatomy, Ruhr-University Bochum, Bochum, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Neural Regen Res</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101316351</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1673-5374</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cav3.1</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cav3.2</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cav3.3</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Purkinje cells</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">T-type-Ca2+-channels</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuronal plasticity</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">progesterone</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">protein kinase A</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">protein kinase C</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">rat cerebellum</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>None</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>7</Hour>
          <Minute>58</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35535898</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9120685</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/1673-5374.339008</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">NeuralRegenRes_2022_17_11_2465_339008</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aguado C, García-Madrona S, Gil-Minguez M, Luján R. Ontogenic changes and differential localization of T-type Ca(2+) channel subunits Cav3.1 and Cav3.2 in mouse hippocampus and cerebellum. Front Neuroanat. 2016;10:83.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4999439</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27616982</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arcos-Montoya D, Wegman-Ostrosky T, Mejía-Pérez S, De la Fuente-Granada M, Camacho-Arroyo I, García-Carrancá A, Velasco-Velázquez MA, Manjarrez-Marmolejo J, González-Arenas A. Progesterone receptor together with PKCαexpression as prognostic factors for astrocytomas malignancy. Onco Targets Ther. 2021;14:3757–3768.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8217595</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34168461</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Asmara H, Micu I, Rizwan AP, Sahu G, Simms BA, Zhang FX, Engbers JDT, Stys PK, Zamponi GW, Turner RW. A T-type channel-calmodulin complex triggers αCaMKII activation. Mol Brain. 2017;10:37.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5553682</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28800734</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bannister RA, Beam KG. Ca(V)1.1: The atypical prototypical voltage-gated Ca²+channel. Biochim Biophys Acta. 2013;1828:1587–1597.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3615030</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22982493</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baulieu EE. Neurosteroids: of the nervous system, by the nervous system for the nervous system. Recent Prog Horm Res. 1997;52:1–32.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baulieu EE, Robel P. Neurosteroids: a new brain function?J Steroid Biochem Mol Biol. 1990;37:395–403.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Belardetti F, Zamponi GW. Linking calcium-channel isoforms to potential therapies. Curr Opin Investig Drugs. 2008;9:707–715.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bennison SA, Blazejewski SM, Smith TH, Toyo-oka K. Protein kinases: master regulators of neuritogenesis and therapeutic targets for axon regeneration. Cell Mol Life Sci. 2020;77:1511–1530.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7166181</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31659414</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Borodinova AA, Zuzina AB, Balaban PM. Role of atypical protein kinases in maintenance of long-term memory and synaptic plasticity. Biochemistry (Mosc) 2017;82:243–256.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28320265</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Catterall WA. Structure and regulation of voltage-gated Ca2+channels. Annu Rev Cell Dev Biol. 2000;16:521–555.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11031246</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Catterall WA, Leal K, Nanou E. Calcium channels and short-term synaptic plasticity. J Biol Chem. 2013;288:10742–10749.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3624454</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23400776</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chemin J, Mezghrani A, Bidaud I, Dupasquier S, Marger F, Barrère C, Nargeot J, Lory P. Temperature-dependent modulation of CaV3 T-type calcium channels by protein kinases C and A in mammalian cells. J Biol Chem. 2007;282:32710–32718.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17855364</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chemin J, Monteil A, Perez-Reyes E, Bourinet E, Nargeot J, Lory P. Specific contribution of human T-type calcium channel isotypes (alpha(1G), alpha(1H) and alpha(1I)) to neuronal excitability. J Physiol 540. 2002;(Pt 1):3–14.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Nicola AF, Garay LI, Meyer M, Guennoun R, Sitruk-Ware R, Schumacher M, Gonzalez Deniselle MC. Neurosteroidogenesis and progesterone anti-inflammatory/neuroprotective effects. J Neuroendocrinol. 2018;30:e12502.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Nicola AF, Gonzalez SL, Labombarda F, González Deniselle MC, Garay L, Guennoun R, Schumacher M. Progesterone treatment of spinal cord injury: Effects on receptors, neurotrophins and myelination. J Mol Neurosci. 2006;28:3–15.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16632872</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Engbers JD, Anderson D, Zamponi GW, Turner RW. Signal processing by T-type calcium channel interactions in the cerebellum. Front Cell Neurosci. 2013;7:230.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3841819</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24348329</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghoumari AM, Abi Ghanem C, Asbelaoui N, Schumacher M, Hussain R. Roles of progesterone, testosterone and their nuclear receptors in central nervous system myelination and remyelination. Int J Mol Sci. 2020;3163;21</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guennoun R. Progesterone in the brain: hormone, neurosteroid and neuroprotectant. Int J Mol Sci. 2020;21:5271.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Han VZ, Zhang Y, Bell CC, Hansel C. Synaptic plasticity and calcium signaling in Purkinje cells of the central cerebellar lobes of mormyrid fish. J Neurosci. 2007;27:13499–13512.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6673090</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18057208</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heron SE, Khosravani H, Varela D, Bladen C, Williams TC, Newman MR, Scheffer IE, Berkovic SF, Mulley JC, Zamponi GW. Extended spectrum of idiopathic generalized epilepsies associated with CACNA1H functional variants. Ann Neurol. 2007;62:560–568.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17696120</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Higgins D, Graupner M, Brunel N. Memory maintenance in synapses with calcium-based plasticity in the presence of background activity. PLoS Comput Biol. 2014;10:e1003834.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4183374</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25275319</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hildebrand ME, Isope P, Miyazaki T, Nakaya T, Garcia E, Feltz A, Schneider T, Hescheler J, Kano M, Sakimura K, Watanabe M, Dieudonné S, Snutch TP. Functional coupling between mGluR1 and Cav3.1 T-type calcium channels contributes to parallel fiber-induced fast calcium signaling within Purkinje cell dendritic spines. J Neurosci. 2009;29:9668–82.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6666586</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19657020</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hu C, Depuy SD, Yao J, McIntire WE, Barrett PQ. Protein kinase A activity controls the regulation of T-type CaV3.2 channels by Gbetagamma dimers. J Biol Chem. 2009;284:7465–7473.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2658042</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19131331</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jagodic MM, Pathirathna S, Nelson MT, Mancuso S, Joksovic PM, Rosenberg ER, Bayliss DA, Jevtovic-Todorovic V, Todorovic SM. Cell-specific alterations of T-type calcium current in painful diabetic neuropathy enhance excitability of sensory neurons. J Neurosci. 2007;27:3305–3316.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6672477</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17376991</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kapfhammer JP. Cellular and molecular control of dendritic growth and development of cerebellar Purkinje cells. Prog Histochem Cytochem. 2004;39:131–182.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15580762</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kapur J, Joshi S. Progesterone modulates neuronal excitability bidirectionally. Neurosci Lett. 2021;744:135619.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7821816</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33421486</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim JA, Park JY, Kang HW, Huh SU, Jeong SW, Lee JH. Augmentation of Cav3.2 T-type calcium channel activity by cAMP-dependent protein kinase A. J Pharmacol Exp Ther. 2006;318:230–237.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16569752</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim MJ, Shin HJ, Won KA, Yang KY, Ju JS, Park YY, Park JS, Bae YC, Ahn DK. Progesterone produces antinociceptive and neuroprotective effects in rats with microinjected lysophosphatidic acid in the trigeminal nerve root. Mol Pain. 2012;8:16.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3315401</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22429647</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kipp M, Amor S, Krauth R, Beyer C. Multiple sclerosis: neuroprotective alliance of estrogen-progesterone and gender. Front Neuroendocrinol. 2012;33:1–16.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22289667</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kitamura K, Kano M. Dendritic calcium signaling in cerebellar Purkinje cell. Neural Netw. 2013;47:11–17.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22985934</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Klöckner U, Lee JH, Cribbs LL, Daud A, Hescheler J, Pereverzev A, Perez-Reyes E, Schneider T. Comparison of the Ca2+currents induced by expression of three cloned alpha1 subunits, alpha1G alpha1H and alpha1I of low-voltage-activated T-type Ca2 +channels. Eur J Neurosci. 1999;11:4171–4178.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10594642</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leonelli E, Bianchi R, Cavaletti G, Caruso D, Crippa D, Garcia-Segura LM, Lauria G, Magnaghi V, Roglio I, Melcangi RC. Progesterone and its derivatives are neuroprotective agents in experimental diabetic neuropathy: A multimodal analysis. Neuroscience. 2007;144:1293–1304.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17187935</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leresche N, Lambert RC. T-type calcium channels in synaptic plasticity. Channels. 2017;11:121–139.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5398590</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27653665</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lin H, Magrane J, Clark EM, Halawani SM, Warren N, Rattelle A, Lynch DR. Early VGLUT1-specific parallel fiber synaptic deficits and dysregulated cerebellar circuit in the KIKO mouse model of Friedreich ataxia. Dis Model Mech. 2017;10:1529–1538.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5769605</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29259026</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lory P, Nicole S, Monteil A. Neuronal Cav3 channelopathies: recent progress and perspectives. Pflugers Arch. 2020;472:831–844.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7351805</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32638069</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maggio N, Vlachos A. Synaptic plasticity at the interface of health and disease: New insights on the role of endoplasmic reticulum intracellular calcium stores. Neuroscience. 2014;281:135–146.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25264032</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marquina-Sánchez B, González-Jorge J, Hansberg-Pastor V, Wegman-Ostrosky T, Baranda-Ávila N, Mejía-Pérez S, Camacho-Arroyo I, González-Arenas A. The interplay between intracellular progesterone receptor and PKC plays a key role in migration and invasion of human glioblastoma cells. J Steroid Biochem Mol Biol. 2017;172:198–206.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27717886</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mateos-Aparicio P, Rodríguez-Moreno A. Calcium dynamics and synaptic plasticity. Adv Exp Med Biol. 2020;1131:965–984.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31646541</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McRory JE, Santi CM, Hamming KS, Mezeyova J, Sutton KG, Baillie DL, Stea A, Snutch TP. Molecular and functional characterization of a family of rat brain T-type calcium channels. J Biol Chem. 2001;276:3999–4011.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11073957</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Metzger F, Kapfhammer JP. Protein kinase C: its role in activity-dependent Purkinje cell dendritic development and plasticity. Cerebellum. 2003;2:206–214.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14509570</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Molineux ML, McRory JE, McKay BE, Hamid J, Mehaffey WH, Rehak R, Snutch TP, Zamponi GW, Turner RW. Specific T-type calcium channel isoforms are associated with distinct burst phenotypes in deep cerebellar nuclear neurons. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2006;103:5555–5560.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1459392</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16567615</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mullen RJ, Buck CR, Smith AM. NeuN, a neuronal specific nuclear protein in vertebrates. Development. 1992;116:201–211.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1483388</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Napper RMA, Harvey RJ. Number of parallel fiber synapses on an individual Purkinje cell in the cerebellum of the rat. J Comp Neurol. 1988;274:168–177.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3209740</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nelson MT, Todorovic SM, Perez-Reyes E. The role of T-type calcium channels in epilepsy and pain. Curr Pharm Des. 2006;12:2189–2197.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16787249</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nemer A, Azab AN, Rimon G, Lamprecht S, Ben-Menahem D. Different roles of cAMP/PKA and PKC signaling in regulating progesterone and PGE2 levels in immortalized rat granulosa cell cultures. Gen Comp Endocrinol. 2018;269:88–95.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30144443</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Neveu D, Zucker RS. Postsynaptic levels of [Ca2+]i needed to trigger LTD and LTP. Neuron. 1996;16:619–629.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8785059</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Newton AC. Protein kinase C: poised to signal. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2010;298:E395-402.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2838521</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19934406</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Newton AC. Protein kinase C: perfectly balanced. Crit Rev Biochem Mol Biol. 2018;53:208–230.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5901981</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29513138</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Park JY, Kang HW, Moon HJ, Huh SU, Jeong SW, Soldatov NM, Lee JH. Activation of protein kinase C augments T-type Ca2+channel activity without changing channel surface density. J Physiol. 2006;577(Pt 2):513–523.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1890444</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17008378</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pemberton KE, Hill-Eubanks LJ, Jones SV. Modulation of low-threshold T-type calcium channels by the five muscarinic receptor subtypes in NIH 3T3 cells. Pflugers Arch. 2000;440:452–461.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10954332</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Perez-Reyes E. Molecular physiology of low-voltage-activated t-type calcium channels. Physiol Rev. 2003;83:117–161.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12506128</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pieczora L, Stracke L, Vorgerd M, Hahn S, Theiss C, Theis V. Unveiling of miRNA expression patterns in purkinje cells during development. Cerebellum. 2017;16:376–387.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27387430</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roglio I, Bianchi R, Gotti S, Scurati S, Giatti S, Pesaresi M, Caruso D, Panzica GC, Melcangi RC. Neuroprotective effects of dihydroprogesterone and progesterone in an experimental model of nerve crush injury. Neuroscience. 2008;155:673–685.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18625290</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sakamoto H, Ukena K, Tsutsui K. Effects of progesterone synthesized de novo in the developing purkinje cell on its dendritic growth and synaptogenesis. J Neurosci. 2001;21:6221–6232.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6763166</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11487645</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schroeder J, Fischbach P, McCleskey E. T-type calcium channels: heterogeneous expression in rat sensory neurons and selective modulation by phorbol esters. J Neurosci. 1990;10:947–951.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6570135</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2156966</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schumacher M, Guennoun R, Stein DG, De Nicola AF. Progesterone: therapeutic opportunities for neuroprotection and myelin repair. Pharmacol Ther. 2007;116:77–106.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17659348</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schumacher M, Hussain R, Gago N, Oudinet JP, Mattern C, Ghoumari AM. Progesterone synthesis in the nervous system: implications for myelination and myelin repair. Front Neurosci. 2012;6:10.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3274763</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22347156</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Seil FJ. Interactions between cerebellar Purkinje cells and their associated astrocytes. Histol Histopathol. 2001;16:955–968.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11510987</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shea TB, Cressman CM, Spencer MJ, Beermann ML, Nixon RA. Enhancement of neurite outgrowth following calpain inhibition is mediated by protein kinase C. J Neurochem. 1995;65:517–527.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7616205</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shobe J. The role of PKA, CaMKII and PKC in avoidance conditioning: permissive or instructive? Neurobiol Learn Mem. 2002;77:291–312.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11991759</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singh M, Su C. Progesterone and neuroprotection. Horm Behav. 2013;63:284–290.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3467329</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22732134</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Snyder EM, Colledge M, Crozier RA, Chen WS, Scott JD, Bear MF. Role for A kinase-anchoring proteins (AKAPS) in glutamate receptor trafficking and long term synaptic depression. J Biol Chem. 2005;280:16962–16968.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3923403</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15718245</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stein DG, Wright DW, Kellermann AL. Does progesterone have neuroprotective properties? Ann Emerg Med. 2008;51:164–172.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17588708</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Strünker T, Goodwin N, Brenker C, Kashikar ND, Weyand I, Seifert R, Kaupp UB. The CatSper channel mediates progesterone-induced Ca2+influx in human sperm. Nature. 2011;471:382–386.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21412338</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sun J, Moenter SM. Progesterone treatment inhibits and dihydrotestosterone (DHT) treatment potentiates voltage-gated calcium currents in gonadotropin-releasing hormone (GnRH) neurons. Endocrinology. 2010;151:5349–5358.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2954728</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20739401</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Talavera K, Nilius B. Biophysics and structure–function relationship of T-type Ca2+channels. Cell Calcium. 2006;40:97–114.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16777221</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Taylor SS, Ilouz R, Zhang P, Kornev AP. Assembly of allosteric macromolecular switches: lessons from PKA. Nat Rev Mol Cell Biol. 2012;13:646–658.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3985763</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22992589</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Theis V, Theiss C. Progesterone effects in the nervous system. Anat Rec. 2019;302:1276–1286.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tjaden J, Pieczora L, Wach F, Theiss C, Theis V. Cultivation of purified primary purkinje cells from rat cerebella. Cell Mol Neurobiol. 2018;38:1399–1412.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30066224</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tseng GN, Boyden PA. Different effects of intracellular Ca and protein kinase C on cardiac T and L Ca currents. Am J Physiol 261. 1991;(2 Pt 2):H364–379.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tsutsui K, Haraguchi S. Neuroprotective actions of cerebellar and pineal allopregnanolone on Purkinje cells. FASEB Bioadv. 2020;2:149–159.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7059624</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32161904</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Turnham RE, Scott JD. Protein kinase A catalytic subunit isoform PRKACA;History, function and physiology. Gene. 2016;577:101–108.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4713328</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26687711</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Valdés-Rives SA, Arcos-Montoya D, de la Fuente-Granada M, Zamora-Sánchez CJ, Arias-Romero LE, Villamar-Cruz O, Camacho-Arroyo I, Pérez-Tapia SM, González-Arenas A. LPA1 receptor promotes progesterone receptor phosphorylation through PKCαin human glioblastoma cells. Cells. 2021;10:807.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8066126</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33916643</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Viero C, Dayanithi G. Neurosteroids are excitatory in supraoptic neurons but inhibitory in the peripheral nervous system: it is all about oxytocin and progesterone receptors. Prog Brain Res. 2008;170:177–192.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18655882</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Welsby PJ, Wang H, Wolfe JT, Colbran RJ, Johnson ML, Barrett PQ. A mechanism for the direct regulation of T-type calcium channels by Ca 2+/calmodulin-dependent kinase II. J Neurosci. 2003;23:10116–10121.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6740846</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14602827</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wessel L, Balakrishnan-Renuka A, Henkel C, Meyer HE, Meller K, Brand-Saberi B, Theiss C. Long-term incubation with mifepristone (MLTI) increases the spine density in developing Purkinje cells: new insights into progesterone receptor mechanisms. Cell Mol Life Sci. 2014;71:1723–1740.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23982753</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wheeler DG, Groth RD, Ma H, Barrett CF, Owen SF, Safa P, Tsien RW. CaV1 and CaV2 channels engage distinct modes of Ca2+signaling to control CREB-dependent gene expression. Cell. 2012;149:1112–1124.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3654514</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22632974</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Willett RT, Bayin NS, Lee AS, Krishnamurthy A, Wojcinski A, Lao Z, Stephen D, Rosello-Diez A, Dauber-Decker KL, Orvis GD, Wu Z, Tessier-Lavigne M, Joyner AL. Cerebellar nuclei excitatory neurons regulate developmental scaling of presynaptic Purkinje cell number and organ growth. eLife. 2019;8:e50617.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6890462</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31742552</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wisden W. Structure and distribution of multiple GABAA receptor subunits with special reference to the cerebellum. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 1995;757:506–515.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7611708</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wolfe JT, Wang H, Howard J, Garrison JC, Barrett PQ. T-type calcium channel regulation by specific G-protein βγsubunits. Nature. 2003;424:209–213.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12853961</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wolfe JT, Wang H, Perez-Reyes E, Barrett PQ. Stimulation of recombinant Ca(v)3.2, T-type Ca(2+) channel currents by CaMKIIgamma(C) J Physiol. 2002;538(Pt 2):343–355.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2290082</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11790804</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu N, Engbers J, Khaja S, Xu L, Clark JJ, Hansen MR. Influence of cAMP and protein kinase A on neurite length from spiral ganglion neurons. Hear Res. 2012;283(1-2):33–44.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3277666</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22154930</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yamada K, Watanabe M. Cytodifferentiation of Bergmann glia and its relationship with Purkinje cells. Anat Sci Int. 2002;77:94–108.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12418089</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang Y, Lisberger SG. Purkinje-cell plasticity and cerebellar motor learning are graded by complex-spike duration. Nature. 2014;510:529–532.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4132823</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24814344</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yilmaz C, Karali K, Fodelianaki G, Gravanis A, Chavakis T, Charalampopoulos I, Alexaki VI. Neurosteroids as regulators of neuroinflammation. Front Neuroendocrinol. 2019;55:100788.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31513776</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zamponi GW, Striessnig J, Koschak A, Dolphin AC. The physiology, pathology and pharmacology of voltage-gated calcium channels and their future therapeutic potential. Pharmacol Rev. 2015;67:821–870.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4630564</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26362469</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang JD, Biczok R, Ruschhaupt M. ddCt: the ddCt algorithm for the analysis of quantitative real-time PCR (qRT-PCR) R package version 1.32.0. 2015.  
https://doi.org/doi: 10.18129/B9.bioc.ddCt. 
</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
