<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35535908</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>22</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">1673-5374</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>17</Volume>
            <Issue>11</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Nov</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Neural regeneration research</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Neural Regen Res</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Obstructive sleep apnea aggravates neuroinflammation and pyroptosis in early brain injury following subarachnoid hemorrhage via ASC/HIF-1α pathway.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>2537</StartPage>
          <EndPage>2543</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>2537-2543</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/1673-5374.339000</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Obstructive sleep apnea can worsen the prognosis of subarachnoid hemorrhage. However, the underlying mechanism remains unclear. In this study, we established a mouse model of subarachnoid hemorrhage using the endovascular perforation method and exposed the mice to intermittent hypoxia for 8 hours daily for 2 consecutive days to simulate sleep apnea. We found that sleep apnea aggravated brain edema, increased hippocampal neuron apoptosis, and worsened neurological function in this mouse model of subarachnoid hemorrhage. Then, we established an in vitro HT-22 cell model of hemin-induced subarachnoid hemorrhage/intermittent hypoxia and found that the cells died, and lactate dehydrogenase release increased, after 48 hours. We further investigated the underlying mechanism and found that sleep apnea increased the expression of hippocampal neuroinflammatory factors interleukin-1β, interleukin-18, interleukin-6, nuclear factor κB, pyroptosis-related protein caspase-1, pro-caspase-1, and NLRP3, promoted the proliferation of astrocytes, and increased the expression of hypoxia-inducible factor 1α and apoptosis-associated speck-like protein containing a CARD, which are the key proteins in the hypoxia-inducible factor 1α/apoptosis-associated speck-like protein containing a CARD signaling pathway. We also found that knockdown of hypoxia-inducible factor 1α expression in vitro greatly reduced the damage to HY22 cells. These findings suggest that sleep apnea aggravates early brain injury after subarachnoid hemorrhage by aggravating neuroinflammation and pyroptosis, at least in part through the hypoxia-inducible factor 1α/apoptosis-associated speck-like protein containing a CARD signaling pathway.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Xu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jun</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Respiration, Nanjing First Hospital, Nanjing Medical University, Nanjing, Jiangsu Province, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Li</LastName>
            <ForeName>Qian</ForeName>
            <Initials>Q</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Respiration, Nanjing First Hospital, Nanjing Medical University, Nanjing, Jiangsu Province, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Xu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Chen-Yu</ForeName>
            <Initials>CY</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Respiration, Nanjing First Hospital, Nanjing Medical University, Nanjing, Jiangsu Province, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mao</LastName>
            <ForeName>Shan</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Respiration, Nanjing First Hospital, Nanjing Medical University, Nanjing, Jiangsu Province, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Jin</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jia-Jia</ForeName>
            <Initials>JJ</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Respiration, Nanjing First Hospital, Nanjing Medical University, Nanjing, Jiangsu Province, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Wei</ForeName>
            <Initials>W</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Respiration, Nanjing First Hospital, Nanjing Medical University, Nanjing, Jiangsu Province, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Shi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ying</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Respiration, Nanjing First Hospital, Nanjing Medical University, Nanjing, Jiangsu Province, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zou</LastName>
            <ForeName>Chun-Fang</ForeName>
            <Initials>CF</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Respiration, Nanjing First Hospital, Nanjing Medical University; Department of Respiration, Nanjing Yuhua Hospital, Yuhua Branch of Nanjing First Hospital, Nanjing, Jiangsu Province, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ye</LastName>
            <ForeName>Liang</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Respiration, Nanjing First Hospital, Nanjing Medical University, Nanjing, Jiangsu Province, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Neural Regen Res</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101316351</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1673-5374</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">apoptosis associated speck like protein containing a CARD</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">early brain injury</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hypoxia-inducible factor 1α</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuroinflammation</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nucleotide-binding domain and leucine-rich repeat protein 3</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">obstructive sleep apnea</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pyroptosis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">subarachnoid hemorrhage</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement><b>Conflicts of interest:</b>
<i>The authors declare that they have no competing interests</i>.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>7</Hour>
          <Minute>58</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35535908</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9120669</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/1673-5374.339000</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">NeuralRegenRes_2022_17_11_2537_339000</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alim I, Caulfield JT, Chen Y, Swarup V, Geschwind DH, Ivanova E, Seravalli J, Ai Y, Sansing LH, Ste Marie EJ, Hondal RJ, Mukherjee S, Cave JW, Sagdullaev BT, Karuppagounder SS, Ratan RR. Selenium drives a transcriptional adaptive program to block ferroptosis and treat stroke. Cell. 2019;177:1262–1279. e25.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31056284</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barteczek P, Li L, Ernst AS, Böhler LI, Marti HH, Kunze R. Neuronal HIF-1αand HIF-2αdeficiency improves neuronal survival and sensorimotor function in the early acute phase after ischemic stroke. J Cereb Blood Flow Metab. 2017;37:291–306.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5363746</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26746864</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bir SC, Nanda A, Cuellar H, Sun H, Guthikonda B, Liendo C, Minagar A, Chernyshev OY. Coexistence of obstructive sleep apnea worsens the overall outcome of intracranial aneurysm: a pioneer study. J Neurosurg. 2018;128:735–746.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28338434</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen JH, Yang LK, Chen L, Wang YH, Wu Y, Jiang BJ, Zhu J, Li PP. Atorvastatin ameliorates early brain injury after subarachnoid hemorrhage via inhibition of AQP4 expression in rabbits. Int J Mol Med. 2016a;37:1059–1066.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26935263</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen JH, Wu T, Yang LK, Chen L, Zhu J, Li PP, Hu X, Wang YH. Protective effects of atorvastatin on cerebral vessel autoregulation in an experimental rabbit model of subarachnoid hemorrhage. Mol Med Rep. 2018;17:1651–1659.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5780106</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29257200</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen J, Zhu J, He J, Wang Y, Chen L, Zhang C, Zhou J, Yang L. Ultra-early microsurgical treatment within 24 h of SAH improves prognosis of poor-grade aneurysm combined with intracerebral hematoma. Oncol Lett. 2016b;11:3173–3178.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4841047</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27123084</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen J, Zhang C, Yan T, Yang L, Wang Y, Shi Z, Li M, Chen Q. Atorvastatin ameliorates early brain injury after subarachnoid hemorrhage via inhibition of pyroptosis and neuroinflammation. J Cell Physiol. 2021;236:6920–6931.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33792028</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen J, Xuan Y, Chen Y, Wu T, Chen L, Guan H, Yang S, He J, Shi D, Wang Y. Netrin-1 alleviates subarachnoid haemorrhage-induced brain injury via the PPARγ/NF-KB signalling pathway. J Cell Mol Med. 2019;23:2256–2262.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6378208</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30614619</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen JH, Wu T, Xia WY, Shi ZH, Zhang CL, Chen L, Chen QX, Wang YH. An early neuroprotective effect of atorvastatin against subarachnoid hemorrhage. Neural Regen Res. 2020a;15:1947–1954.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7513987</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32246644</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen T, Zhu J, Wang YH, Hang CH. Arc silence aggravates traumatic neuronal injury via mGluR1-mediated ER stress and necroptosis. Cell Death Dis. 2020b;11:4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6952410</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31919348</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chernyshev OY, Bir SC, Maiti TK, Patra DP, Sun H, Guthikonda B, Kelley RE, Cuellar H, Minagar A, Nanda A. The relationship between obstructive sleep apnea and ruptured intracranial aneurysms. J Clin Sleep Med. 2019;15:1839–1848.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7099178</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31839111</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Almeida L, Khare S, Misharin AV, Patel R, Ratsimandresy RA, Wallin MC, Perlman H, Greaves DR, Hoffman HM, Dorfleutner A, Stehlik C. The PYRIN domain-only protein POP1 inhibits inflammasome assembly and ameliorates inflammatory disease. Immunity. 2015;43:264–276.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4666005</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26275995</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Rooij NK, Linn FH, van der Plas JA, Algra A, Rinkel GJ. Incidence of subarachnoid haemorrhage: a systematic review with emphasis on region, age gender and time trends. J Neurol Neurosurg Psychiatry. 2007;78:1365–1372.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2095631</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17470467</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fang Y, Gao S, Wang X, Cao Y, Lu J, Chen S, Lenahan C, Zhang JH, Shao A, Zhang J. Programmed cell deaths and potential crosstalk with blood-brain barrier dysfunction after hemorrhagic stroke. Front Cell Neurosci. 2020;14:68.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7146617</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32317935</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fricker M, Tolkovsky AM, Borutaite V, Coleman M, Brown GC. Neuronal cell death. Physiol Rev. 2018;98:813–880.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5966715</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29488822</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gabryelska A, Sochal M, Turkiewicz S, Białasiewicz P. Relationship between HIF-1 and circadian clock proteins in obstructive sleep apnea patients-preliminary study. J Clin Med. 2020;9:1599.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gao C, Yan Y, Chen G, Wang T, Luo C, Zhang M, Chen X, Tao L. Autophagy activation represses pyroptosis through the IL-13 and JAK1/STAT1 pathways in a mouse model of moderate traumatic brain injury. ACS Chem Neurosci. 2020;11:4231–4239.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33170612</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Geer JH, Falcone GJ, Vanent KN, Leasure AC, Woo D, Molano JR, Sansing LH, Langefeld CD, Pisani MA, Yaggi HK, Sheth KN. Obstructive sleep apnea as a risk factor for intracerebral hemorrhage. Stroke. 2021;52:1835–1838.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8085039</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33827242</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gong LJ, Wang XY, Gu WY, Wu X. Pinocembrin ameliorates intermittent hypoxia-induced neuroinflammation through BNIP3-dependent mitophagy in a murine model of sleep apnea. J Neuroinflammation. 2020;17:337.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7656728</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33176803</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hu X, Yan J, Huang L, Araujo C, Peng J, Gao L, Liu S, Tang J, Zuo G, Zhang JH. INT-777 attenuates NLRP3-ASC inflammasome-mediated neuroinflammation via TGR5/cAMP/PKA signaling pathway after subarachnoid hemorrhage in rats. Brain Behav Immun. 2021;91:587–600.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7749833</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32961266</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hung MW, Tipoe GL, Poon AM, Reiter RJ, Fung ML. Protective effect of melatonin against hippocampal injury of rats with intermittent hypoxia. J Pineal Res. 2008;44:214–221.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18289174</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ingall T, Asplund K, Mähönen M, Bonita R. A multinational comparison of subarachnoid hemorrhage epidemiology in the WHO MONICA stroke study. Stroke. 2000;31:1054–1061.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10797165</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kao CH, Chang CZ, Su YF, Tsai YJ, Chang KP, Lin TK, Hwang SL, Lin CL. 17β-Estradiol attenuates secondary injury through activation of Akt signaling via estrogen receptor alpha in rat brain following subarachnoid hemorrhage. J Surg Res. 2013;183:e23–30.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23465388</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Komotar RJ, Schmidt JM, Starke RM, Claassen J, Wartenberg KE, Lee K, Badjatia N, Connolly ES, Jr, Mayer SA. Resuscitation and critical care of poor-grade subarachnoid hemorrhage. Neurosurgery. 2009;64:397–410. discussion 410-411.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19240601</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li J, McEvoy RD, Zheng D, Loffler KA, Wang X, Redline S, Woodman RJ, Anderson CS. Self-reported snoring patterns predict stroke events in high-risk patients with OSA: post hoc analyses of the SAVE study. Chest. 2020;158:2146–2154.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32679238</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li WD, Sun Q, Zhang XS, Wang CX, Li S, Li W, Hang CH. Expression and cell distribution of neuroglobin in the brain tissue after experimental subarachnoid hemorrhage in rats: a pilot study. Cell Mol Neurobiol. 2014;34:247–255.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24281943</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liang Y, Song P, Chen W, Xie X, Luo R, Su J, Zhu Y, Xu J, Liu R, Zhu P, Zhang Y, Huang M. Inhibition of caspase-1 ameliorates ischemia-associated blood-brain barrier dysfunction and integrity by suppressing pyroptosis activation. Front Cell Neurosci. 2020;14:540669.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7874210</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33584203</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lien TS, Sun DS, Wu CY, Chang HH. Exposure to dengue envelope protein domain III induces Nlrp3 inflammasome-dependent endothelial dysfunction and hemorrhage in mice. Front Immunol. 2021;12:617251.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7947687</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33717109</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lin X, Ye H, Siaw-Debrah F, Pan S, He Z, Ni H, Xu Z, Jin K, Zhuge Q, Huang L. AC-YVAD-CMK inhibits pyroptosis and improves functional outcome after intracerebral hemorrhage. Biomed Res Int. 2018;2018:3706047.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6206581</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30410928</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Livak KJ, Schmittgen TD. Analysis of relative gene expression data using real-time quantitative PCR and the 2(-Delta Delta C(T)) Method. Methods. 2001;25:402–408.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11846609</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Macdonald RL, Schweizer TA. Spontaneous subarachnoid haemorrhage. Lancet. 2017;389:655–666.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27637674</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mason RH, Ruegg G, Perkins J, Hardinge M, Amann-Vesti B, Senn O, Stradling JR, Kohler M. Obstructive sleep apnea in patients with abdominal aortic aneurysms: highly prevalent and associated with aneurysm expansion. Am J Respir Crit Care Med. 2011;183:668–674.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20622036</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Min JW, Hu JJ, He M, Sanchez RM, Huang WX, Liu YQ, Bsoul NB, Han S, Yin J, Liu WH, He XH, Peng BW. Vitexin reduces hypoxia-ischemia neonatal brain injury by the inhibition of HIF-1alpha in a rat pup model. Neuropharmacology. 2015;99:38–50.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26187393</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nieuwkamp DJ, Setz LE, Algra A, Linn FH, de Rooij NK, Rinkel GJ. Changes in case fatality of aneurysmal subarachnoid haemorrhage over time, according to age sex and region: a meta-analysis. Lancet Neurol. 2009;8:635–642.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19501022</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Orrù G, Storari M, Scano A, Piras V, Taibi R, Viscuso D. Obstructive Sleep Apnea, oxidative stress inflammation and endothelial dysfunction-An overview of predictive laboratory biomarkers. Eur Rev Med Pharmacol Sci. 2020;24:6939–6948.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32633387</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ostrowski RP, Colohan AR, Zhang JH. Mechanisms of hyperbaric oxygen-induced neuroprotection in a rat model of subarachnoid hemorrhage. J Cereb Blood Flow Metab. 2005;25:554–571.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15703702</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pontes-Neto OM, Fernandes RM, Sander HH, da Silva LA, Mariano DC, Nobre F, Simão G, de Araujo DB, dos Santos AC, Leite JP. Obstructive sleep apnea is frequent in patients with hypertensive intracerebral hemorrhage and is related to perihematoma edema. Cerebrovasc Dis. 2010;29:36–42.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19893310</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Prabhakar NR, Peng YJ, Nanduri J. Hypoxia-inducible factors and obstructive sleep apnea. J Clin Invest. 2020;130:5042–5051.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7524484</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32730232</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schaible EV, Windschügl J, Bobkiewicz W, Kaburov Y, Dangel L, Krämer T, Huang C, Sebastiani A, Luh C, Werner C, Engelhard K, Thal SC, Schäfer MK. 2-Methoxyestradiol confers neuroprotection and inhibits a maladaptive HIF-1αresponse after traumatic brain injury in mice. J Neurochem. 2014;129:940–954.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24606183</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schneider CA, Rasband WS, Eliceiri KW. NIH Image to ImageJ: 25 years of image analysis. Nat Methods. 2012;9:671–675.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5554542</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22930834</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schuiling WJ, Rinkel GJ, Walchenbach R, de Weerd AW. Disorders of sleep and wake in patients after subarachnoid hemorrhage. Stroke. 2005;36:578–582.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15677579</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shi Y, Guo X, Zhang J, Zhou H, Sun B, Feng J. DNA binding protein HMGB1 secreted by activated microglia promotes the apoptosis of hippocampal neurons in diabetes complicated with OSA. Brain Behav Immun. 2018;73:482–492.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29920330</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Strausz S, Ruotsalainen S, Ollila HM, Karjalainen J, Kiiskinen T, Reeve M, Kurki M, Mars N, Havulinna AS, Luonsi E, Mansour Aly D, Ahlqvist E, Teder-Laving M, Palta P, Groop L, Mägi R, Mäkitie A, Salomaa V, Bachour A, Tuomi T, et al.  Genetic analysis of obstructive sleep apnoea discovers a strong association with cardiometabolic health. Eur Respir J. 2021;57:2003091.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33243845</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sugawara T, Ayer R, Jadhav V, Zhang JH. A new grading system evaluating bleeding scale in filament perforation subarachnoid hemorrhage rat model. J Neurosci Methods. 2008;167:327–334.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2259391</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17870179</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tan J, Xing H, Sha S, Li J, Miao Y, Zhang Q. Analysis of circulating microvesicles levels and effects of associated factors in elderly patients with obstructive sleep apnea. Front Aging Neurosci. 2021;13:609282.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7943723</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33716708</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tan MS, Tan L, Jiang T, Zhu XC, Wang HF, Jia CD, Yu JT. Amyloid-βinduces NLRP1-dependent neuronal pyroptosis in models of Alzheimer's disease. Cell Death Dis. 2014;5:e1382.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4454321</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25144717</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Trollmann R, Richter M, Jung S, Walkinshaw G, Brackmann F. Pharmacologic stabilization of hypoxia-inducible transcription factors protects developing mouse brain from hypoxia-induced apoptotic cell death. Neuroscience. 2014;278:327–342.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25162122</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wei C, Guo S, Liu W, Jin F, Wei B, Fan H, Su H, Liu J, Zhang N, Fang D, Li G, Shu S, Li X, He X, Zhang X, Duan C. Resolvin D1 ameliorates inflammation-mediated blood-brain barrier disruption after subarachnoid hemorrhage in rats by modulating A20 and NLRP3 inflammasome. Front Pharmacol. 2020;11:610734.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7957930</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33732145</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu CS, Chang IY, Hung JL, Liao WC, Lai YR, Chang KP, Li HP, Chang YS. ASC modulates HIF-1αstability and induces cell mobility in OSCC. Cell Death Dis. 2020;11:721.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7471912</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32883954</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu X, Gong L, Xie L, Gu W, Wang X, Liu Z, Li S. NLRP3 deficiency protects against intermittent hypoxia-induced neuroinflammation and mitochondrial ROS by promoting the PINK1-Parkin pathway of mitophagy in a murine model of sleep apnea. Front Immunol. 2021;12:628168.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7943742</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33717152</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xiong M, Zhao Y, Mo H, Yang H, Yue F, Hu K. Intermittent hypoxia increases ROS/HIF-1α'related oxidative stress and inflammation and worsens bleomycin-induced pulmonary fibrosis in adult male C57BL/6J mice. Int Immunopharmacol. 2021;100:108165.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34560512</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu P, Hong Y, Xie Y, Yuan K, Li J, Sun R, Zhang X, Shi X, Li R, Wu J, Liu X, Hu W, Sun W. TREM-1 exacerbates neuroinflammatory injury via NLRP3 inflammasome-mediated pyroptosis in experimental subarachnoid hemorrhage. Transl Stroke Res. 2021a;12:643–659.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32862402</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu W, Xu R, Li X, Zhang H, Wang X, Zhu J. Downregulating hypoxia-inducible factor-1αexpression with perfluorooctyl-bromide nanoparticles reduces early brain injury following experimental subarachnoid hemorrhage in rats. Am J Transl Res. 2016;8:2114–2126.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4891424</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27347319</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu W, Song C, Wang X, Li Y, Bai X, Liang X, Wu J, Liu J. Downregulation of miR-155-5p enhances the anti-tumor effect of cetuximab on triple-negative breast cancer cells via inducing cell apoptosis and pyroptosis. Aging (Albany NY) 2021b;13:228–240.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7835015</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33472170</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ystgaard MB, Scheffler K, Suganthan R, Bjørås M, Ranheim T, Sagen EL, Halvorsen B, Saugstad OD, Yndestad A. Neuromodulatory effect of NLRP3 and ASC in neonatal hypoxic ischemic encephalopathy. Neonatology. 2019;115:355–362.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30909283</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yu LM, Zhang WH, Han XX, Li YY, Lu Y, Pan J, Mao JQ, Zhu LY, Deng JJ, Huang W, Liu YH. Hypoxia-induced ROS contribute to myoblast pyroptosis during obstructive sleep apnea via the NF-κB/HIF-1αsignaling pathway. Oxid Med Cell Longev. 2019;2019:4596368.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6927050</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31885794</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yuan B, Zhou XM, You ZQ, Xu WD, Fan JM, Chen SJ, Han YL, Wu Q, Zhang X. Inhibition of AIM2 inflammasome activation alleviates GSDMD-induced pyroptosis in early brain injury after subarachnoid haemorrhage. Cell Death Dis. 2020;11:76.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6992766</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32001670</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zaremba S, Albus L, Schuss P, Vatter H, Klockgether T, Güresir E. Increased risk for subarachnoid hemorrhage in patients with sleep apnea. J Neurol. 2019;266:1351–1357.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30834980</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhaba WD, Deji QZ, Deng HJ, Han YL, Gao SQ, Liu XL, Zhou ML. Retinal hypoxia after experimental subarachnoid hemorrhage. Neurosci Lett. 2021;742:135554.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33352284</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhou Y, Tao T, Liu G, Gao X, Gao Y, Zhuang Z, Lu Y, Wang H, Li W, Wu L, Zhang D, Hang C. TRAF3 mediates neuronal apoptosis in early brain injury following subarachnoid hemorrhage via targeting TAK1-dependent MAPKs and NF-κB pathways. Cell Death Dis. 2021;12:10.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7790824</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33414375</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zille M, Karuppagounder SS, Chen Y, Gough PJ, Bertin J, Finger J, Milner TA, Jonas EA, Ratan RR. Neuronal death after hemorrhagic stroke in vitro and in vivo shares features of ferroptosis and necroptosis. Stroke. 2017;48:1033–1043.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5613764</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28250197</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
