<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35535878</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>22</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">1673-5374</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>17</Volume>
            <Issue>11</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Nov</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Neural regeneration research</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Neural Regen Res</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>The uPA/uPAR system in astrocytic wound healing.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>2404</StartPage>
          <EndPage>2406</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>2404-2406</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/1673-5374.338991</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The repair of injured tissue is a highly complex process that involves cell proliferation, differentiation, and migration. Cell migration requires the dismantling of intercellular contacts in the injured zone and their subsequent reconstitution in the wounded area. Urokinase-type plasminogen activator (uPA) is a serine proteinase found in multiple cell types including endothelial cells, smooth muscle cells, monocytes, and macrophages. A substantial body of experimental evidence with different cell types outside the central nervous system indicates that the binding of uPA to its receptor (uPAR) on the cell surface prompts cell migration by inducing plasmin-mediated degradation of the extracellular matrix. In contrast, although uPA and uPAR are abundantly found in astrocytes and uPA binding to uPAR triggers astrocytic activation, it is unknown if uPA also plays a role in astrocytic migration. Neuronal cadherin is a member of cell adhesion proteins pivotal for the formation of cell-cell contacts between astrocytes. More specifically, while the extracellular domain of neuronal cadherin interacts with the extracellular domain of neuronal cadherin in neighboring cells, its intracellular domain binds to β-catenin, which in turn links the complex to the actin cytoskeleton. Glycogen synthase kinase 3β is a serine-threonine kinase that prevents the cytoplasmic accumulation of β-catenin by inducing its phosphorylation at Ser33, Ser37, and Ser41, thus activating a sequence of events that lead to its proteasomal degradation. The data discussed in this perspective indicate that astrocytes release uPA following a mechanical injury, and that binding of this uPA to uPAR on the cell membrane induces the detachment of β-catenin from the intracellular domain of neuronal cadherin by triggering its extracellular signal-regulated kinase 1/2-mediated phosphorylation at Tyr650. Remarkably, this is followed by the cytoplasmic accumulation of β-catenin because uPA-induced extracellular signal-regulated kinase 1/2 activation also phosphorylates lipoprotein receptor-related protein 6 at Ser1490, which in turn, by recruiting glycogen synthase kinase 3β to its intracellular domain abrogates its effect on β-catenin. The cytoplasmic accumulation of β-catenin is followed by its nuclear translocation, where it induces the expression of uPAR, which is required for the migration of astrocytes from the injured edge into the wounded area.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yepes</LastName>
            <ForeName>Manuel</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Neuropharmacology and Neurologic Diseases, Yerkes National Primate Research Center; Department of Neurology, Emory University School of Medicine; Department of Neurology, Veterans Affairs Medical Center, Atlanta, GA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <GrantList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>I01 BX003441</GrantID>
            <Acronym>BX</Acronym>
            <Agency>BLRD VA</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>R01 NS091201</GrantID>
            <Acronym>NS</Acronym>
            <Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
        </GrantList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Neural Regen Res</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101316351</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1673-5374</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Wnt-β-catenin pathway</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">astrocytes</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lipoprotein receptor-related protein 6</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">plasmin</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">urokinase receptor</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">urokinase-type plasminogen activator</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">wound healing</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">β-catenin</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement><b>Conflicts of interest:</b>
<i>The author declares no conflicts of interest</i>.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>7</Hour>
          <Minute>58</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35535878</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9120704</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/1673-5374.338991</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">NeuralRegenRes_2022_17_11_2404_338991</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Andreasen PA, Kjøller L, Christensen L, Duffy MJ. The urokinase-type plasminogen activator system in cancer metastasis: a review. Int J Cancer. 1997;72:1–22.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9212216</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bastakoty D, Young PP. Wnt/beta-catenin pathway in tissue injury: roles in pathology and therapeutic opportunities for regeneration. FASEB J. 2016;30:3271–3284.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5024694</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27335371</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beschorner R, Schluesener HJ, Nguyen TD, Magdolen V, Luther T, Pedal I, Mattern R, Meyermann R, Schwab JM. Lesion-associated accumulation of uPAR/CD87- expressing infiltrating granulocytes, activated microglial cells/macrophages and upregulation by endothelial cells following TBI and FCI in humans. Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol. 2000;26:522–527.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11123718</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Buck RC. Cell migration in repair of mouse corneal epithelium. Invest Ophthalmol Vis Sci. 1979;18:767–784.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">457355</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carmeliet P, Moons L, Herbert JM, Crawley J, Lupu F, Lijnen R, Collen D. Urokinase but not tissue plasminogen activator mediates arterial neointima formation in mice. Circ Res. 1997;81:829–839.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9351457</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cheon SS, Wei Q, Gurung A, Youn A, Bright T, Poon R, Whetstone H, Guha A, Alman BA. Beta-catenin regulates wound size and mediates the effect of TGF-beta in cutaneous healing. FASEB J. 2006;20:692–701.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16581977</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dent MA, Sumi Y, Morris RJ, Seeley PJ. Urokinase-type plasminogen activator expression by neurons and oligodendrocytes during process outgrowth in developing rat brain. Eur J Neurosci. 1993;5:633–647.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8261137</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Diaz A, Yepes M. Urokinase-type plasminogen activator promotes synaptic repair in the ischemic brain. Neural Regen Res. 2018;13:232–233.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5879890</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29557368</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Diaz A, Merino P, Manrique LG, Cheng L, Yepes M. Urokinase-type plasminogen activator (uPA) protects the tripartite synapse in the ischemic brain via ezrin-mediated formation of peripheral astrocytic processes. J Cereb Blood Flow Metab. 2018;39:2157–2171.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6827113</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29890880</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Diaz A, Martin-Jimenez C, Xu Y, Merino P, Woo Y, Torre E, Yepes M. Urokinase-type plasminogen activator-mediated crosstalk between N-cadherin and beta-catenin promotes wound healing. J Cell Sci. 2021;134:jcs255919.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8214757</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34085693</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Diaz A, Merino P, Manrique LG, Ospina JP, Cheng L, Wu F, Jeanneret V, Yepes M. A cross-talk between neuronal urokinase-type plasminogen activator (uPA) and astrocytic uPA receptor (uPAR) promotes astrocytic activation and synaptic recovery in the ischemic brain. J Neurosci. 2017;37:10310–10322.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5656992</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28931568</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Diaz A, Merino P, Guo JD, Yepes MA, McCann P, Katta T, Tong EM, Torre E, Rangaraju S, Yepes M. Urokinase-type plasminogen activator protects cerebral cortical neurons from soluble abeta-induced synaptic damage. J Neurosci. 2020;40:4251–4263.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7244203</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32332118</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dupin I, Camand E, Etienne-Manneville S. Classical cadherins control nucleus and centrosome position and cell polarity. J Cell Biol. 2009;185:779–786.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2711586</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19487453</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Floridon C, Nielsen O, Holund B, Sunde L, Westergaard JG, Thomsen SG, Teisner B. Localization and significance of urokinase plasminogen activator and its receptor in placental tissue from intrauterine, ectopic and molar pregnancies. Placenta. 1999;20:711–721.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10527826</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Geiger B, Bershadsky A, Pankov R, Yamada KM. Transmembrane crosstalk between the extracellular matrix--cytoskeleton crosstalk. Nat Rev Mol Cell Biol. 2001;2:793–805.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11715046</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gurtner GC, Werner S, Barrandon Y, Longaker MT. Wound repair and regeneration. Nature. 2008;453:314–321.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18480812</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kikuchi A, Kishida S, Yamamoto H. Regulation of Wnt signaling by protein-protein interaction and post-translational modifications. Exp Mol Med. 2006;38:1–10.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16520547</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kjoller L. The urokinase plasminogen activator receptor in the regulation of the actin cytoskeleton and cell motility. Biol Chem. 2002;383:5–19.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11928822</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krishnamachary B, Berg-Dixon S, Kelly B, Agani F, Feldser D, Ferreira G, Iyer N, LaRusch J, Pak B, Taghavi P, Semenza GL. Regulation of colon carcinoma cell invasion by hypoxia-inducible factor 1. Cancer Res. 2003;63:1138–1143.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12615733</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lawrence D, Strandberg L, Grundstrom T, Ny T. Purification of active human plasminogen activator inhibitor 1 from Escherichia coli. Comparison with natural and recombinant forms purified from eucaryotic cells. Eur J Biochem. 1989;186:523–533.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Masos T, Miskin R. Localization of urokinase-type plasminogen activator mRNA in the adult mouse brain. Brain Res Mol Brain Res. 1996;35:139–148.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8717349</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mendez P, De Roo M, Poglia L, Klauser P, Muller D. N-cadherin mediates plasticity-induced long-term spine stabilization. J Cell Biol. 2010;189:589–600.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2867305</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20440002</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Merino P, Diaz A, Jeanneret V, Wu F, Torre E, Cheng L, Yepes M. Urokinase-type plasminogen activator (uPA) binding to the uPA receptor (uPAR) promotes axonal regeneration in the central nervous system. J Biol Chem. 2016;292:2741–2753.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5314171</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27986809</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ozawa M, Baribault H, Kemler R. The cytoplasmic domain of the cell adhesion molecule uvomorulin associates with three independent proteins structurally related in different species. EMBO J. 1989;8:1711–1717.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC401013</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2788574</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Piedra J, Martinez D, Castano J, Miravet S, Dunach M, de Herreros AG. Regulation of beta-catenin structure and activity by tyrosine phosphorylation. J Biol Chem. 2001;276:20436–20443.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11279024</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Poujade M, Grasland-Mongrain E, Hertzog A, Jouanneau J, Chavrier P, Ladoux B, Buguin A, Silberzan P. Collective migration of an epithelial monolayer in response to a model wound. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2007;104:15988–15993.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2042149</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17905871</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Romer J, Lund LR, Eriksen J, Pyke C, Kristensen P, Dano K. The receptor for urokinase-type plasminogen activator is expressed by keratinocytes at the leading edge during re-epithelialization of mouse skin wounds. J Invest Dermatol. 1994;102:519–522.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8151132</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shen Y, Guo Y, Du C, Wilczynska M, Hellstrom S, Ny T. Mice deficient in urokinase-type plasminogen activator have delayed healing of tympanic membrane perforations. PLoS One. 2012;7:e51303.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3517469</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23236466</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shih W, Yamada S. N-cadherin-mediated cell-cell adhesion promotes cell migration in a three-dimensional matrix. J Cell Sci. 2012;125:3661–3670.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3445327</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22467866</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singer AJ, Clark RA. Cutaneous wound healing. N Engl J Med. 1999;341:738–746.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10471461</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith HW, Marshall CJ. Regulation of cell signalling by uPAR. Nat Rev Mol Cell Biol. 2010;11:23–36.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20027185</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sofroniew MV. Molecular dissection of reactive astrogliosis and glial scar formation. Trends Neurosci. 2009;32:638–647.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2787735</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19782411</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tamai K, Zeng X, Liu C, Zhang X, Harada Y, Chang Z, He X. A mechanism for Wnt coreceptor activation. Mol Cell. 2004;13:149–156.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14731402</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tamai K, Semenov M, Kato Y, Spokony R, Liu C, Katsuyama Y, Hess F, Saint-Jeannet JP, He X. LDL-receptor-related proteins in Wnt signal transduction. Nature. 2000;407:530–535.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11029007</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tanner K, Ferris DR, Lanzano L, Mandefro B, Mantulin WW, Gardiner DM, Rugg EL, Gratton E. Coherent movement of cell layers during wound healing by image correlation spectroscopy. Biophys J. 2009;97:2098–2106.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2756390</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19804742</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vial E, Sahai E, Marshall CJ. ERK-MAPK signaling coordinately regulates activity of Rac1 and RhoA for tumor cell motility. Cancer Cell. 2003;4:67–79.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12892714</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vitorino P, Hammer M, Kim J, Meyer T. A steering model of endothelial sheet migration recapitulates monolayer integrity and directed collective migration. Mol Cell Biol. 2011;31:342–350.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3019974</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20974808</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang Y, Dang J, Wang H, Allgayer H, Murrell GA, Boyd D. Identification of a novel nuclear factor-kappaB sequence involved in expression of urokinase-type plasminogen activator receptor. Eur J Biochem. 2000;267:3248–3254.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10824110</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wysocki AB, Kusakabe AO, Chang S, Tuan TL. Temporal expression of urokinase plasminogen activator, plasminogen activator inhibitor and gelatinase-B in chronic wound fluid switches from a chronic to acute wound profile with progression to healing. Wound Repair Regen. 1999;7:154–165.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10417751</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yamada S, Pokutta S, Drees F, Weis WI, Nelson WJ. Deconstructing the cadherin-catenin-actin complex. Cell. 2005;123:889–901.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3368712</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16325582</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang H, Nie X, Shi X, Zhao J, Chen Y, Yao Q, Sun C, Yang J. Regulatory mechanisms of the Wnt/beta-catenin pathway in diabetic cutaneous ulcers. Front Pharmacol. 2018;9:1114.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6199358</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30386236</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhao M, Song B, Pu J, Forrester JV, McCaig CD. Direct visualization of a stratified epithelium reveals that wounds heal by unified sliding of cell sheets. FASEB J. 2003;17:397–406.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1459285</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12631579</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
