<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35533255</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>09</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4652</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>09</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of cellular physiology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Cell Physiol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Specific ablation of Hippo signalling component Yap1 in retinal progenitors and Müller cells results in late onset retinal degeneration.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/jcp.30757</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Yes-associated protein (YAP) is a major component of the Hippo pathway involved in development, growth, repair and homeostasis. Nonsense YAP1 mutations in humans result in autosomal dominant coloboma. Here, we generated a conditional knockout mouse model in which Yap1 was specifically deleted in embryonic retinal progenitor cells (RPCs) and in mature Müller cells using a Chx10-Cre driver. Our data demonstrated that the conditional ablation of Yap1 in embryonic RPCs does not prevent normal retinal development and caused no gross changes in retinal structure during embryonic and early postnatal life. Nevertheless, Yap1 deficient in retinal Müller cells in adult mice leads to impaired visual responses and extensive late-onset retinal degeneration, characterized by reduced cell number in all retinal layers. Immunofluorescence data further revealed the degeneration and death of rod and cone photoreceptors, bipolar cells, horizontal cells, amacrine cells and ganglion cells to varying degrees in aged knockout mice. Moreover, alteration of glial homeostasis and reactive gliosis were also observed. Finally, cell proliferation and TUNEL assay revealed that the broad retinal degeneration is mainly caused by enhanced apoptosis in late period. Together, this work uncovers that YAP is essential for the normal vision and retinal maintenance, highlighting the crucial role of YAP in retinal function and homeostasis.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yeming</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Sichuan Provincial Key Laboratory for Human Disease Gene Study, Center for Medical Genetics, Sichuan Provincial People's Hospital, University of Electronic Science and Technology of China, Chengdu, Sichuan, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Psychosomatic Medicine, Sichuan Academy of Medical Sciences &amp; Sichuan Provincial People's Hospital, Chengdu, Sichuan, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Tibetan Medicine Research, Chinese Academy of Sciences and Qinghai Provincial Key Laboratory of Tibetan Medicine Research, Northwest Institute of Plateau Biology, Xining, Qinghai, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Jiang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xiaoyan</ForeName>
            <Initials>X</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Sichuan Provincial Key Laboratory for Human Disease Gene Study, Center for Medical Genetics, Sichuan Provincial People's Hospital, University of Electronic Science and Technology of China, Chengdu, Sichuan, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Li</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xiao</ForeName>
            <Initials>X</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Sichuan Provincial Key Laboratory for Human Disease Gene Study, Center for Medical Genetics, Sichuan Provincial People's Hospital, University of Electronic Science and Technology of China, Chengdu, Sichuan, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sun</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kuanxiang</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Sichuan Provincial Key Laboratory for Human Disease Gene Study, Center for Medical Genetics, Sichuan Provincial People's Hospital, University of Electronic Science and Technology of China, Chengdu, Sichuan, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xianjun</ForeName>
            <Initials>X</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2531-7552</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Sichuan Provincial Key Laboratory for Human Disease Gene Study, Center for Medical Genetics, Sichuan Provincial People's Hospital, University of Electronic Science and Technology of China, Chengdu, Sichuan, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Key Laboratory of Tibetan Medicine Research, Chinese Academy of Sciences and Qinghai Provincial Key Laboratory of Tibetan Medicine Research, Northwest Institute of Plateau Biology, Xining, Qinghai, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Research Unit for Blindness Prevention of Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences (2019RU026), Sichuan Academy of Medical Sciences &amp; Sichuan Provincial People's Hospital, Chengdu, Sichuan, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Departemnt of Ophthalmology, First People's Hospital of Shangqiu, Shangqiu, Henan, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhou</LastName>
            <ForeName>Bo</ForeName>
            <Initials>B</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Psychosomatic Medicine, Sichuan Academy of Medical Sciences &amp; Sichuan Provincial People's Hospital, Chengdu, Sichuan, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>09</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Cell Physiol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0050222</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0021-9541</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hippo signalling</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Yap1</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">knockout model</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">retinal degeneration</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
          <Hour>14</Hour>
          <Minute>42</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35533255</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcp.30757</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Asaoka, Y., Hata, S., Namae, M., Furutani-Seiki, M., &amp; Nishina, H. (2014). The Hippo pathway controls a switch between retinal progenitor cell proliferation and photoreceptor cell differentiation in zebrafish. PLoS One, 9(5), e97365.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bachleda, A. R., Pevny, L. H., &amp; Weiss, E. R. (2016). Sox2-deficient müller glia disrupt the structural and functional maturation of the mammalian retina. Investigative Ophthalmology &amp; Visual Science, 57(3), 1488-1499.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bringmann, A., Pannicke, T., Biedermann, B., Francke, M., Iandiev, I., Grosche, J., Wiedemann, P., Albrecht, J., &amp; Reichenbach, A. (2009). Role of retinal glial cells in neurotransmitter uptake and metabolism. Neurochemistry International, 54(3-4), 143-160.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bringmann, A., Pannicke, T., Grosche, J., Francke, M., Wiedemann, P., Skatchkov, S. N., Osborne, N. N., &amp; Reichenbach, A. (2006). Müller cells in the healthy and diseased retina. Progress in Retinal and Eye Research, 25(4), 397-424.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bringmann, A., &amp; Wiedemann, P. (2012). Müller glial cells in retinal disease. Ophthalmologica, 227(1), 1-19.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Byrne, L. C., Khalid, F., Lee, T., Zin, E. A., Greenberg, K. P., Visel, M., Schaffer, D. V., &amp; Flannery, J. G. (2013). AAV-mediated, optogenetic ablation of Müller glia leads to structural and functional changes in the mouse retina. PLoS One, 8(9), e76075.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cabochette, P., Vega-Lopez, G., Bitard, J., Parain, K., Chemouny, R., Masson, C., Borday, C., Hedderich, M., Henningfeld, K. A., Locker, M., Bronchain, O., &amp; Perron, M. (2015). YAP controls retinal stem cell DNA replication timing and genomic stability. eLife, 4, e08488.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Di Cara, F., Maile, T., Parsons, B., Magico, A., Basu, S., Tapon, N., &amp; King-Jones, K. (2015). The Hippo pathway promotes cell survival in response to chemical stress. Cell Death &amp; Differentiation, 22(9), 1526-1539.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cepko, C. L., Austin, C. P., Yang, X., Alexiades, M., &amp; Ezzeddine, D. (1996). Cell fate determination in the vertebrate retina. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, 93(2), 589-595.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dong, J., Feldmann, G., Huang, J., Wu, S., Zhang, N., Comerford, S. A., Gayyed, M. F., Anders, R. A., Maitra, A., &amp; Pan, D. (2007). Elucidation of a universal size-control mechanism in Drosophila and mammals. Cell, 130(6), 1120-1133.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dyer, M. A., &amp; Cepko, C. L. (2000). Control of Müller glial cell proliferation and activation following retinal injury. Nature Neuroscience, 3(9), 873-880.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fernández-Sánchez, L., Lax, P., Campello, L., Pinilla, I., &amp; Cuenca, N. (2015). Astrocytes and Müller cell alterations during retinal degeneration in a transgenic rat model of retinitis pigmentosa. Frontiers in Cellular Neuroscience, 9, 484.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fossdal, R. (2004). A novel TEAD1 mutation is the causative allele in Sveinsson's chorioretinal atrophy (helicoid peripapillary chorioretinal degeneration). Human Molecular Genetics, 13(9), 975-981.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hamon, A., Masson, C., Bitard, J., Gieser, L., Roger, J. E., &amp; Perron, M. (2017). Retinal degeneration triggers the activation of YAP/TEAD in reactive Müller cells. Investigative Ophthalmology &amp; Visual Science, 58(4), 1941-1953.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hauri, S., Wepf, A., van Drogen, A., Varjosalo, M., Tapon, N., Aebersold, R., &amp; Gstaiger, M. (2013). Interaction proteome of human H ippo signaling: Modular control of the co-activator YAP 1. Molecular Systems Biology, 9(1), 713.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>He, J., Bao, Q., Zhang, Y., Liu, M., Lv, H., Liu, Y., Yao, L., Li, B., Zhang, C., He, S., Zhai, G., Zhu, Y., Liu, X., Zhang, K., Wang, X. J., Zou, M. H., Zhu, Y., &amp; Ai, D. (2018). Yes-associated protein promotes angiogenesis via signal transducer and activator of transcription 3 in endothelial cells. Circulation Research, 122(4), 591-605.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>He, Q., Gao, Y., Wang, T., Zhou, L., Zhou, W., &amp; Yuan, Z. (2019). Deficiency of Yes-associated protein induces cataract in mice. Aging and Disease, 10(2), 293.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heynen, H., Wachtmeister, L., &amp; van Norren, D. (1985). Origin of the oscillatory potentials in the primate retina. Vision Research, 25(10), 1365-1373.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hinds, J. W. (1968). Autoradiographic study of histogenesis in the mouse olfactory bulb I. Time of origin of neurons and neuroglia. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 134(3), 287-304.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Holt, R., Ceroni, F., Bax, D. A., Broadgate, S., Diaz, D. G., Santos, C., Gerrelli, D., &amp; Ragge, N. K. (2017). New variant and expression studies provide further insight into the genotype-phenotype correlation in YAP1-related developmental eye disorders. Scientific Reports, 7(1), 1-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jeon, C.-J., Strettoi, E., &amp; Masland, R. H. (1998). The major cell populations of the mouse retina. Journal of Neuroscience, 18(21), 8936-8946.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jiang, Q., Liu, D., Gong, Y., Wang, Y., Sun, S., Gui, Y., &amp; Song, H. (2009). Yap is required for the development of brain, eyes, and neural crest in zebrafish. Biochemical and Biophysical Research Communications, 384(1), 114-119.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jones, B. W., Watt, C. B., Frederick, J. M., Baehr, W., Chen, C. K., Levine, E. M., Milam, A. H., Lavail, M. M., &amp; Marc, R. E. (2003). Retinal remodeling triggered by photoreceptor degenerations. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 464(1), 1-16.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim, J. Y., Park, R., Lee, J. H. J., Shin, J., Nickas, J., Kim, S., &amp; Cho, S.-H. (2016). Yap is essential for retinal progenitor cell cycle progression and RPE cell fate acquisition in the developing mouse eye. Developmental Biology, 419(2), 336-347.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kowalchuk, A. M., Maurer, K. A., Shoja-Taheri, F., &amp; Brown, N. L. (2018). Requirements for Neurogenin2 during mouse postnatal retinal neurogenesis. Developmental Biology, 442(2), 220-235.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee, M., Goraya, N., Kim, S., &amp; Cho, S. H. (2018). Hippo-yap signaling in ocular development and disease. Developmental Dynamics, 247(6), 794-806.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lu, Q., Ivanova, E., Ganjawala, T. H., &amp; Pan, Z.-H. (2013). Cre-mediated recombination efficiency and transgene expression patterns of three retinal bipolar cell-expressing Cre transgenic mouse lines. Molecular Vision, 19, 1310-1320.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>MacDonald, R. B., Randlett, O., Oswald, J., Yoshimatsu, T., Franze, K., &amp; Harris, W. A. (2015). Müller glia provide essential tensile strength to the developing retina. Journal of Cell Biology, 210(7), 1075-1083.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Masson, C., García-García, D., Bitard, J., Grellier, É. -K., Roger, J. E., &amp; Perron, M. (2020). Yap haploinsufficiency leads to Müller cell dysfunction and late-onset cone dystrophy. Cell Death &amp; Disease, 11(8), 1-15.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meng, Z., Moroishi, T., &amp; Guan, K.-L. (2016). Mechanisms of Hippo pathway regulation. Genes &amp; Development, 30(1), 1-17.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miesfeld, J. B., Gestri, G., Clark, B. S., Flinn, M. A., Poole, R. J., Bader, J. R., Besharse, J. C., Wilson, S. W., Link, B. A., Miesfeld, J. B., Gestri, G., Clark, B. S., Flinn, M. A., Poole, R. J., Bader, J. R., Besharse, J. C., Wilson, S. W., &amp; Link, B. A. (2015). Yap and Taz regulate retinal pigment epithelial cell fate. Development, 142(17), 3021-3032.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mizutani, M., Gerhardinger, C., &amp; Lorenzi, M. (1998). Müller cell changes in human diabetic retinopathy. Diabetes, 47(3), 445-449.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moon, K. H., &amp; Kim, J. W. (2018). Hippo signaling circuit and divergent tissue growth in mammalian eye. Molecules and Cells, 41(4), 257-263.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Newman, E., &amp; Reichenbach, A. (1996). The Müller cell: a functional element of the retina. Trends in Neurosciences, 19(8), 307-312.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oatts, J. T., Hull, S., Michaelides, M., Arno, G., Webster, A. R., &amp; Moore, A. T. (2017). Novel heterozygous mutation in YAP1 in a family with isolated ocular colobomas. Ophthalmic Genetics, 38(3), 281-283.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Powner, M. B., Gillies, M. C., Tretiach, M., Scott, A., Guymer, R. H., Hageman, G. S., &amp; Fruttiger, M. (2010). Perifoveal Müller cell depletion in a case of macular telangiectasia type 2. Ophthalmology, 117(12), 2407-2416.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Powner, M. B., Gillies, M. C., Zhu, M., Vevis, K., Hunyor, A. P., &amp; Fruttiger, M. (2013). Loss of Müller's cells and photoreceptors in macular telangiectasia type 2. Ophthalmology, 120(11), 2344-2352.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raeisossadati, R., Ferrari, M. F., Kihara, A. H., AlDiri, I., &amp; Gross, J. M. (2021). Epigenetic regulation of retinal development. Epigenetics &amp; Chromatin, 14(1), 1-15.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raghunathan, V. K., Dreier, B., Morgan, J. T., Tuyen, B. C., Rose, B. W., Reilly, C. M., Russell, P., &amp; Murphy, C. J. (2014). Involvement of YAP, TAZ and HSP90 in contact guidance and intercellular junction formation in corneal epithelial cells. PLoS One, 9(10), e109811.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reichenbach, A., &amp; Bringmann, A. (2013). New functions of Müller cells. GLIA, 61(5), 651-678.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rowan, S., &amp; Cepko, C. L. (2004). Genetic analysis of the homeodomain transcription factor Chx10 in the retina using a novel multifunctional BAC transgenic mouse reporter. Developmental Biology, 271(2), 388-402.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ruzafa, N., Pereiro, X., Lepper, M. F., Hauck, S. M., &amp; Vecino, E. (2018). A proteomics approach to identify candidate proteins secreted by Müller glia that protect ganglion cells in the retina. Proteomics, 18(11), 1700321.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sakabe, M., Fan, J., Odaka, Y., Liu, N., Hassan, A., Duan, X., Stump, P., Byerly, L., Donaldson, M., Hao, J., Fruttiger, M., Lu, Q. R., Zheng, Y., Lang, R. A., &amp; Xin, M. (2017). YAP/TAZ-CDC42 signaling regulates vascular tip cell migration. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, 114(41), 10918-10923.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sidman, R. L. (1960). Histogenesis of mouse retina studied with Thymidine-H-3. Paper presented at the anatomical record.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Soto, F., Watkins, K. L., Johnson, R. E., Schottler, F., &amp; Kerschensteiner, D. (2013). NGL-2 regulates pathway-specific neurite growth and lamination, synapse formation, and signal transmission in the retina. Journal of Neuroscience, 33(29), 11949-11959.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tan, J., Zhang, X., Li, D., Liu, G., Wang, Y., Zhang, D., Wang, X., Tian, W., Dong, X., Zhou, L., Zhu, X., Liu, X., &amp; Fan, N. (2020). scAAV2-mediated C3 transferase gene therapy in a rat model with retinal ischemia/reperfusion injuries. Molecular Therapy-Methods &amp; Clinical Development, 17, 894-903.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ueki, Y., Le, Y.-Z., Chollangi, S., Muller, W., &amp; Ash, J. D. (2009). Preconditioning-induced protection of photoreceptors requires activation of the signal-transducing receptor gp130 in photoreceptors. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, 106(50), 21389-21394.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang, Y. P., Dakubo, G., Howley, P., Campsall, K. D., Mazarolle, C. J., Shiga, S. A., Lewis, P. M., McMahon, A. P., &amp; Wallace, V. A. (2002). Development of normal retinal organization depends on Sonic hedgehog signaling from ganglion cells. Nature Neuroscience, 5(9), 831-832.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Williamson, K. A., Rainger, J., Floyd, J. A., Ansari, M., Meynert, A., Aldridge, K. V., Rainger, J. K., Anderson, C. A., Moore, A. T., Hurles, M. E., Clarke, A., van Heyningen, V., Verloes, A., Taylor, M. S., Wilkie, A. O., &amp; Fitzpatrick, D. R., UK10K Consortium. (2014). Heterozygous loss-of-function mutations in YAP1 cause both isolated and syndromic optic fissure closure defects. The American Journal of Human Genetics, 94(2), 295-302.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang, Y., Liu, W., Sun, K., Jiang, L., &amp; Zhu, X. (2019). Tmem30a deficiency leads to retinal rod bipolar cell degeneration. Journal of Neurochemistry, 148(3), 400-412.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yu, F.-X., Zhao, B., &amp; Guan, K.-L. (2015). Hippo pathway in organ size control, tissue homeostasis, and cancer. Cell, 163(4), 811-828.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang, H., Deo, M., Thompson, R. C., Uhler, M. D., &amp; Turner, D. L. (2012). Negative regulation of Yap during neuronal differentiation. Developmental Biology, 361(1), 103-115.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang, N., Bai, H., David, K. K., Dong, J., Zheng, Y., Cai, J., Giovannini, M., Liu, P., Anders, R. A., &amp; Pan, D. (2010). The Merlin/NF2 tumor suppressor functions through the YAP oncoprotein to regulate tissue homeostasis in mammals. Developmental Cell, 19(1), 27-38.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhao, B., Li, L., Lei, Q., &amp; Guan, K.-L. (2010). The Hippo-YAP pathway in organ size control and tumorigenesis: an updated version. Genes &amp; Development, 24(9), 862-874.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
