<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35535869</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>22</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">1673-5374</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>17</Volume>
            <Issue>11</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Nov</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Neural regeneration research</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Neural Regen Res</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>An atypical ubiquitin ligase at the heart of neural development and programmed axon degeneration.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>2347</StartPage>
          <EndPage>2350</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>2347-2350</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.4103/1673-5374.338992</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The degeneration of nerve fibres following injury was first described by Augustus Waller over 170 years ago. Initially assumed to be a passive process, it is now evident that axons respond to insult via regulated cellular signaling events resulting in their programmed degeneration. Pro-survival and pro-degenerative factors have been identified and their regulatory mechanisms are beginning to emerge. The ubiquitin system has been implicated in the pro-degenerative process and a key component is the ubiquitin E3 ligase MYCBP2 (also known as PHR1). Ubiquitin E3 ligases are tasked with the transfer of the small protein modifier ubiquitin to substrates and consist of hundreds of members. They can be classified as single subunit systems or as multi-subunit complexes. Their catalytic domains can also be assigned to three general architectures. Hints that MYCBP2 might not conform to these established formats came to light and it is now clear from biochemical and structural studies that MYCBP2 is indeed an outlier in terms of its modus operandi. Furthermore, the unconventional way in which MYCBP2 transfers ubiquitin to substrates has been linked to neurodevelopmental and pro-degenerative function. Herein, we will summarize these research developments relating to the unusual features of MYCBP2 and postulate therapeutic strategies that prevent Wallerian degeneration. These have exciting potential for providing relief from pathological neuropathies and neurodegenerative diseases.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Virdee</LastName>
            <ForeName>Satpal</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>MRC Protein Phosphorylation and Ubiquitylation Unit, University of Dundee, Scotland, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Neural Regen Res</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101316351</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1673-5374</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">E3 ligase</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MYCBP2</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chemical biology</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neurodegeneration</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">progammed axon death</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">structural biology</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ubiqultin</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">wallerian degeneration</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>None</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>7</Hour>
          <Minute>58</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35535869</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9120709</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/1673-5374.338992</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">NeuralRegenRes_2022_17_11_2347_338992</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abrams B, Grill B, Huang X, Jin Y. Cellular and molecular determinants targeting the Caenorhabditis elegans PHR protein RPM-1 to perisynaptic regions. Dev Dyn. 2008;237:630–639.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2657606</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18224716</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Adalbert R, Coleman MP. Review: Axon pathology in age-related neurodegenerative disorders. Neuropathol Appl Neurobiol. 2013;39:90–108.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23046254</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ali YO, Allen HM, Yu L, Li-Kroeger D, Bakhshizadehmahmoudi D, Hatcher A, McCabe C, Xu J, Bjorklund N, Taglialatela G, Bennett DA, De Jager PL, Shulman JM, Bellen HJ, Lu HC. NMNAT2: HSP90 complex mediates proteostasis in proteinopathies. PLoS Biol. 2016;14:e1002472.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4890852</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27254664</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Babetto E, Beirowski B, Russler EV, Milbrandt J, DiAntonio A. The Phr1 ubiquitin ligase promotes injury-induced axon self-destruction. Cell Rep. 2013;3:1422–1429.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3671584</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23665224</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baek K, Scott DC, Schulman BA. NEDD8 and ubiquitin ligation by cullin-RING E3 ligases. Curr Opin Struct Biol. 2020;67:101–109.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8096640</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33160249</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bloom AJ, Miller BR, Sanes JR, DiAntonio A. The requirement for Phr1 in CNS axon tract formation reveals the corticostriatal boundary as a choice point for cortical axons. Genes Dev. 2007;21:2593–2606.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2000324</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17901218</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Burgess RW, Peterson KA, Johnson MJ, Roix JJ, Welsh IC, O'Brien TP. Evidence for a conserved function in synapse formation reveals Phr1 as a candidate gene for respiratory failure in newborn mice. Mol Cell Biol. 2004;24:1096–1105.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC321423</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14729956</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coleman MP, Hoke A. Programmed axon degeneration: from mouse to mechanism to medicine. Nat Rev Neurosci. 2020;21:183–196.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8926152</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32152523</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Crawley O, Opperman KJ, Desbois M, Adrados I, Borgen MA, Giles AC, Duckett DR, Grill B. Autophagy is inhibited by ubiquitin ligase activity in the nervous system. Nat Commun. 2019;10:5017.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6825199</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31676756</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>D'Souza J, Hendricks M, Le Guyader S, Subburaju S, Grunewald B, Scholich K, Jesuthasan S. Formation of the retinotectal projection requires Esrom, an ortholog of PAM (protein associated with Myc) Development. 2005;132:247–256.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15590740</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dadon-Nachum M, Melamed E, Offen D. The “dying-back” phenomenon of motor neurons in ALS. J Mol Neurosci. 2011;43:470–477.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21057983</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Desbois M, Crawley O, Evans PR, Baker ST, Masuho I, Yasuda R, Grill B. PAM forms an atypical SCF ubiquitin ligase complex that ubiquitinates and degrades NMNAT2. J Biol Chem. 2018;293:13897–13909.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6130950</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29997255</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Di Stefano M, Nascimento-Ferreira I, Orsomando G, Mori V, Gilley J, Brown R, Janeckova L, Vargas ME, Worrell LA, Loreto A, Tickle J, Patrick J, Webster JR, Marangoni M, Carpi FM, Pucciarelli S, Rossi F, Meng W, Sagasti A, Ribchester RR, et al.  A rise in NAD precursor nicotinamide mononucleotide (NMN) after injury promotes axon degeneration. Cell Death Differ. 2015;22:731–742.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4392071</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25323584</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dorr A, Pierre S, Zhang DD, Henke M, Holland S, Scholich K. MYCBP2 Is a guanosine exchange factor for ran protein and determines its localization in neurons of dorsal root ganglia. J Biol Chem. 2015;290:25620–25635.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4646206</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26304119</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Essuman K, Summers DW, Sasaki Y, Mao X, DiAntonio A, Milbrandt J. The SARM1 Toll/Interleukin-1 receptor domain possesses intrinsic NAD(+) cleavage activity that promotes pathological axonal degeneration. Neuron. 2017;93:1334–1343.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6284238</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28334607</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Figley MD, Gu W, Nanson JD, Shi Y, Sasaki Y, Cunnea K, Malde AK, Jia X, Luo Z, Saikot FK, Mosaiab T, Masic V, Holt S, Hartley-Tassell L, McGuinness HY, Manik MK, Bosanac T, Landsberg MJ, Kerry PS, Mobli M, et al.  SARM1 is a metabolic sensor activated by an increased NMN/NAD(+) ratio to trigger axon degeneration. Neuron. 2021;109:1118–1136.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8174188</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33657413</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Geisler S. Vincristine- and bortezomib-induced neuropathies - from bedside to bench and back. Exp Neurol. 2020:113519.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33129841</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Geisler S, Doan RA, Cheng GC, Cetinkaya-Fisgin A, Huang SX, Hoke A, Milbrandt J, DiAntonio A. Vincristine and bortezomib use distinct upstream mechanisms to activate a common SARM1-dependent axon degeneration program. JCI Insight. 2019;4:e129920.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gerdts J, Summers DW, Sasaki Y, DiAntonio A, Milbrandt J. Sarm1-mediated axon degeneration requires both SAM and TIR interactions. J Neurosci. 2013;33:13569–13580.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3742939</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23946415</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gilley J, Coleman MP. Endogenous Nmnat2 is an essential survival factor for maintenance of healthy axons. PLoS Biol. 2010;8:e1000300.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2811159</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20126265</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grill B, Murphey RK, Borgen MA. The PHR proteins: intracellular signaling hubs in neuronal development and axon degeneration. Neural Dev. 2016;11:8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4806438</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27008623</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grill B, Bienvenut WV, Brown HM, Ackley BD, Quadroni M, Jin Y. C. elegans RPM-1 regulates axon termination and synaptogenesis through the Rab GEF GLO-4 and the Rab GTPase GLO-1. Neuron. 2007;55:587–601.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17698012</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guo Q, Xie J, Dang CV, Liu ET, Bishop JM. Identification of a large Myc-binding protein that contains RCC1-like repeats. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1998;95:9172–9177.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC21311</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9689053</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Han S, Witt RM, Santos TM, Polizzano C, Sabatini BL, Ramesh V. Pam (Protein associated with Myc) functions as an E3 ubiquitin ligase and regulates TSC/mTOR signaling. Cell Signal. 2008;20:1084–1091.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2435383</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18308511</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Han S, Kim S, Bahl S, Li L, Burande CF, Smith N, James M, Beauchamp RL, Bhide P, DiAntonio A, Ramesh V. The E3 ubiquitin ligase protein associated with Myc (Pam) regulates mammalian/mechanistic target of rapamycin complex 1 (mTORC1) signaling in vivo through N- and C-terminal domains. J Biol Chem. 2012;287:30063–30072.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3436263</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22798074</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hershko A, Ciechanover A. The ubiquitin system. Annu Rev Biochem. 1998;67:425–479.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9759494</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hill CS, Sreedharan J, Loreto A, Menon DK, Coleman MP. Loss of highwire protects against the deleterious effects of traumatic brain injury in Drosophila melanogaster. Front Neurol. 2020;11:401.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7235382</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32477254</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huppke P, Wegener E, Gilley J, Angeletti C, Kurth I, Drenth JPH, Stadelmann C, Barrantes-Freer A, Bruck W, Thiele H, Nurnberg P, Gartner J, Orsomando G, Coleman MP. Homozygous NMNAT2 mutation in sisters with polyneuropathy and erythromelalgia. Exp Neurol. 2019;320:112958.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31132363</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krauss R, Bosanac T, Devraj R, Engber T, Hughes RO. Axons matter: the promise of treating neurodegenerative disorders by targeting SARM1-mediated axonal degeneration. Trends Pharmacol Sci. 2020;41:281–293.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32107050</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liao EH, Hung W, Abrams B, Zhen M. An SCF-like ubiquitin ligase complex that controls presynaptic differentiation. Nature. 2004;430:345–350.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15208641</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lukacs M, Gilley J, Zhu Y, Orsomando G, Angeletti C, Liu J, Yang X, Park J, Hopkin RJ, Coleman MP, Zhai RG, Stottmann RW. Severe biallelic loss-of-function mutations in nicotinamide mononucleotide adenylyltransferase 2 (NMNAT2) in two fetuses with fetal akinesia deformation sequence. Exp Neurol. 2019;320:112961.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6708453</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31136762</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lunn ER, Perry VH, Brown MC, Rosen H, Gordon S. Absence of Wallerian degeneration does not hinder regeneration in peripheral nerve. Eur J Neurosci. 1989;1:27–33.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12106171</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mabbitt PD, Loreto A, Dery MA, Fletcher AJ, Stanley M, Pao KC, Wood NT, Coleman MP, Virdee S. Structural basis for RING-Cys-Relay E3 ligase activity and its role in axon integrity. Nat Chem Biol. 2020;16:1227–1236.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7610530</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32747811</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mack TG, Reiner M, Beirowski B, Mi W, Emanuelli M, Wagner D, Thomson D, Gillingwater T, Court F, Conforti L, Fernando FS, Tarlton A, Andressen C, Addicks K, Magni G, Ribchester RR, Perry VH, Coleman MP. Wallerian degeneration of injured axons and synapses is delayed by a Ube4b/Nmnat chimeric gene. Nat Neurosci. 2001;4:1199–1206.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mulder MPC, Witting KF, Ovaa H. Cracking the ubiquitin code: the ubiquitin toolbox. Curr Issues Mol Biol. 2020;37:1–20.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31674341</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Murthy V, Han S, Beauchamp RL, Smith N, Haddad LA, Ito N, Ramesh V. Pam and its ortholog highwire interact with and may negatively regulate the TSC1.TSC2 complex. J Biol Chem. 2004;279:1351–1358.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14559897</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Neukomm LJ, Burdett TC, Seeds AM, Hampel S, Coutinho-Budd JC, Farley JE, Wong J, Karadeniz YB, Osterloh JM, Sheehan AE, Freeman MR. Axon death pathways converge on axundead to promote functional and structural axon disassembly. Neuron. 2017;95:78–91.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28683272</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Osterloh JM, Yang J, Rooney TM, Fox AN, Adalbert R, Powell EH, Sheehan AE, Avery MA, Hackett R, Logan MA, MacDonald JM, Ziegenfuss JS, Milde S, Hou YJ, Nathan C, Ding A, Brown RH, Jr, Conforti L, Coleman M, Tessier-Lavigne M, et al.  dSarm/Sarm1 is required for activation of an injury-induced axon death pathway. Science. 2012;337:481–484.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5225956</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22678360</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Otten EG, Werner E, Crespillo-Casado A, Boyle KB, Dharamdasani V, Pathe C, Santhanam B, Randow F. Ubiquitylation of lipopolysaccharide by RNF213 during bacterial infection. Nature. 2021;594:111–116.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7610904</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34012115</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pao KC, Wood NT, Knebel A, Rafie K, Stanley M, Mabbitt PD, Sundaramoorthy R, Hofmann K, van Aalten DMF, Virdee S. Activity-based E3 ligase profiling uncovers an E3 ligase with esterification activity. Nature. 2018;556:381–385.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29643511</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pao KC, Stanley M, Han C, Lai YC, Murphy P, Balk K, Wood NT, Corti O, Corvol JC, Muqit MM, Virdee S. Probes of ubiquitin E3 ligases enable systematic dissection of parkin activation. Nat Chem Biol. 2016;12:324–331.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4909137</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26928937</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pohl C, Dikic I. Cellular quality control by the ubiquitin-proteasome system and autophagy. Science. 2019;366:818–822.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31727826</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Richter KT, Kschonsak YT, Vodicska B, Hoffmann I. FBXO45-MYCBP2 regulates mitotic cell fate by targeting FBXW7 for degradation. Cell Death Differ. 2020;27:758–772.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7206008</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31285543</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saiga T, Fukuda T, Matsumoto M, Tada H, Okano HJ, Okano H, Nakayama KI. Fbxo45 forms a novel ubiquitin ligase complex and is required for neuronal development. Mol Cell Biol. 2009;29:3529–3543.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2698766</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19398581</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schaefer AM, Hadwiger GD, Nonet ML. rpm-1 a conserved neuronal gene that regulates targeting and synaptogenesis in C. elegans. Neuron. 2000;26:345–356.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10839354</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sharma J, Baker ST, Turgeon SM, Gurney AM, Opperman KJ, Grill B. Identification of a peptide inhibitor of the RPM-1. FSN-1 ubiquitin ligase complex. J Biol Chem. 2014;289:34654–34666.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shi X, Xiang S, Cao J, Zhu H, Yang B, He Q, Ying M. Kelch-like proteins: physiological functions and relationships with diseases. Pharmacol Res. 2019;148:104404.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31442578</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tagliaferro P, Burke RE. Retrograde axonal degeneration in Parkinson disease. J Parkinsons Dis. 2016;6:1–15.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Waller A. Experiments on the section of the glossopharyngeal and hypoglossal nerves of the frog, and observations of the alterations produced thereby in the structure of their primitive fibres. Edinb Med Surg J. 1851;76:369–376.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wan HI, DiAntonio A, Fetter RD, Bergstrom K, Strauss R, Goodman CS. Highwire regulates synaptic growth in Drosophila. Neuron. 2000;26:313–329.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10839352</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang J, Zhai Q, Chen Y, Lin E, Gu W, McBurney MW, He Z. A local mechanism mediates NAD-dependent protection of axon degeneration. J Cell Biol. 2005;170:349–355.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2171458</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16043516</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang K, Deshaies RJ, Liu X. Assembly and regulation of CRL ubiquitin ligases. Adv Exp Med Biol. 2020;1217:33–46.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31898220</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>White MA, Lin Z, Kim E, Henstridge CM, Pena Altamira E, Hunt CK, Burchill E, Callaghan I, Loreto A, Brown-Wright H, Mead R, Simmons C, Cash D, Coleman MP, Sreedharan J. Sarm1 deletion suppresses TDP-43-linked motor neuron degeneration and cortical spine loss. Acta Neuropathol Commun. 2019;7:166.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6819591</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31661035</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu C, Daniels RW, DiAntonio A. DFsn collaborates with Highwire to down-regulate the Wallenda/DLK kinase and restrain synaptic terminal growth. Neural Dev. 2007;2:16.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2031890</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17697379</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xiong X, Hao Y, Sun K, Li J, Li X, Mishra B, Soppina P, Wu C, Hume RI, Collins CA. The Highwire ubiquitin ligase promotes axonal degeneration by tuning levels of Nmnat protein. PLoS Biol. 2012;10:e1001440.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3514318</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23226106</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yamagishi Y, Tessier-Lavigne M. An atypical SCF-like ubiquitin ligase complex promotes Wallerian degeneration through regulation of axonal Nmnat2. Cell Rep. 2016;17:774–782.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5075525</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27732853</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhen M, Huang X, Bamber B, Jin Y. Regulation of presynaptic terminal organization by C. elegans RPM-1, a putative guanine nucleotide exchanger with a RING-H2 finger domain. Neuron. 2000;26:331–343.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10839353</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zheng N, Shabek N. Ubiquitin ligases: structure, function, and regulation. Annu Rev Biochem. 2017;86:129–157.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28375744</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
