<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35537706</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>10</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2710</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>10</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of clinical pharmacy and therapeutics</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Pharm Ther</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Successful treatment of severe quetiapine intoxication with CytoSorb hemoadsorption.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jcpt.13668</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="WHAT IS KNOWN AND OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">While many drug poisonings are successfully treated with specific antidotes, intoxications with tricyclic antidepressants and/or atypical neuroleptics still represent a major challenge. Besides conventional approaches, a new hemoadsorption device might represent an opportunity for therapeutic detoxification.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CASE SUMMARY" NlmCategory="METHODS">We report a 64-year-old female patient who attempted suicide by ingesting an unknown dose of quetiapine. Following application of all available standard diagnostic and therapeutic measures, she was admitted to the intensive care in a deeply somnolent state. Gastroscopy was performed necessitating analgo-sedation, intubation, and mechanical ventilation. Since quetiapine is in principle not dialysable, CytoSorb hemoadsorption was commenced resulting in a clear and rapid decrease in plasma levels of quetiapine and its metabolite norquetiapine over the next few hours. The next day, analgesia was stopped, the patient became alert, and cooperative so that she could be extubated without issues. CytoSorb blood purification therapy was discontinued after 2 days. One day later, the patient was transferred to a psychiatric clinic.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="WHAT IS NEW AND CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">We were able to quickly and efficiently reduce quetiapine and norquetiapine to non-toxic serum levels and to stabilize a critical situation using CytoSorb. Therefore, in the absence of a proven beneficial treatment regimen, the use of CytoSorb might represent an alternative for life-threatening complications of quetiapine intoxication. In particular, intoxications caused by lipophilic agents should be further evaluated.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Authors. Journal of Clinical Pharmacy and Therapeutics published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Reuchsel</LastName>
            <ForeName>Caterina</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1882-1080</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology and Intensive Care Medicine, SRH Klinikum Gera, Gera, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gonnert</LastName>
            <ForeName>Falk A</ForeName>
            <Initials>FA</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology and Intensive Care Medicine, SRH Klinikum Gera, Gera, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Clin Pharm Ther</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8704308</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0269-4727</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CytoSorb</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Intoxication</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hemoadsorption</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">quetiapine</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>31</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>19</Hour>
          <Minute>52</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35537706</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jcpt.13668</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goren JL, Levin GM. Quetiapine, an atypical antipsychotic. Pharmacotherapy. 1998;18(6):1183-1194.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Green B. Focus on quetiapine. Curr Med Res Opin. 1999;15(3):145-151.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fabre LF Jr, Arvanitis L, Pultz J, Jones VM, Malick JB, Slotnick VB. ICI 204, 636, a novel, atypical antipsychotic: early indication of safety and efficacy in patients with chronic and subchronic schizophrenia. Clin Ther. 1995;17(3):366-378.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Müller C, Reuter H, Dohmen C. Intoxication after extreme oral overdose of quetiapine to attempt suicide: pharmacological concerns of side effects. Case Rep Med. 2009;2009:371698.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cole JB, Stellpflug SJ, Ellsworth H, Harris CR. Reversal of quetiapine-induced altered mental status with physostigmine: a case series. Am J Emerg Med. 2012 Jul;30(6):950-953.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reiter K, Bordoni V, Dall'Olio G, et al. In vitro removal of therapeutic drugs with a novel adsorbent system. Blood Purif. 2002;20(4):380-388.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giuntoli L, Dalmastri V, Cilloni N, et al. Severe quetiapine voluntary overdose successfully treated with a new hemoperfusion sorbent. Int J Artif Organs. 2019;42(9):516-520.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zoller M, Döbbeler G, Maier B, Vogeser M, Frey L, Zander J. Can cytokine adsorber treatment affect antibiotic concentrations? A case report. J Antimicrob Chemother. 2015;70(7):2169-2171.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cytosorbents Inc. Instructions for use, Document Number 17-0071-14.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zickler D, Nee J, Arnold T, et al. Use of hemoadsorption in patients with severe intoxication requiring extracorporeal cardiopulmonary support-a case series. ASAIO J. 2021;67(11):e186-e190.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paland M. Use of Cyto Sorb in cases of acute amitriptyline intoxication. J Clin Pharm Ther. 2021;46(5):1476-1479.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
