<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35535208</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>12</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2210-6715</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>83</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Aug</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Sustainable cities and society</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Sustain Cities Soc</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Riding the wave: Predicting the use of the bike-sharing system in Barcelona before and during COVID-19.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>103929</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>103929</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.scs.2022.103929</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>To simultaneously promote health, economic, and environmental sustainability, a number of cities worldwide have established bike-sharing systems (BSS) that complement the conventional public transport systems. As the rapid spread of COVID-19 becoming a global pandemic disrupted urban mobility due to government-imposed lockdowns and the heightened fear of infection in crowded spaces, populations were increasingly less likely to use public transportation and instead shifted toward alternative transport systems, including BSS. In this study, we use probabilistic machine learning in a quasi-experimental research design to identify how the relevance of a comprehensive set of factors to predict the use of Bicing (the BSS in Barcelona) may have changed as COVID-19 unfolded. We unpack the key factors in predicting the use of Bicing, uncovering evidence of increasing bike-related built infrastructure (e.g., tactical urbanism), trip distance, and the income levels of neighborhoods as the most relevant predictors. Moreover, we find that the relevance of the factors in predicting Bicing usage has generally decreased during the global pandemic, suggesting altered societal behavior. Our study enhances the understanding of BSS and societal behavior, which can have important implications for developing resilient programs for cities to adopt sustainable practices through transport policy, infrastructure planning, and urban development.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bustamante</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xavier</ForeName>
            <Initials>X</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Universitat Politècnica De Catalunya, Carrer Jordi Girona 31, 08034 Barcelona, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Federo</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ryan</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Universitat de les Illes Balears, Campus Cra. Valldemossa. Km 7, 07122, Palma de Mallorca, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Fernández-I-Marin</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xavier</ForeName>
            <Initials>X</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Universitat de Barcelona, Gran Via de les Corts Catalanes, 585, 08007, Barcelona, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>04</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Sustain Cities Soc</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101735304</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2210-6707</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bicing Barcelona</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bike-sharing system</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Probabilistic machine learning</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Quasi-experimental research</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sustainability</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Tactical urbanism</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>1</Hour>
          <Minute>47</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35535208</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9066899</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.scs.2022.103929</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">S2210-6707(22)00251-7</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ajuntament de Barcelona. (2020). Pla de Mobilitat Urbana 2024. https://www.barcelona.cat/mobilitat/en/news-and-documents/initial-approval-2024-urban-mobility-plan.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Albuquerque V., Andrade F., Ferreira J.C., Dias M.S., Bacao F. Bike-sharing mobility patterns: A data-driven analysis for the city of Lisbon. EAI Endorsed Transactions on Smart Cities. 2021:e7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alfano V., Ercolano S. The efficacy of lockdown against COVID-19: A cross-country panel analysis. Applied health economics and health policy. 2020;18(4):509–517.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7268966</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32495067</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Amer F., Hammoud S., Farran B., Boncz I., Endrei D. Assessment of countries’ preparedness and lockdown effectiveness in fighting COVID-19. Disaster Medicine and Public Health Preparedness. 2021;15(2):e15–e22.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7385315</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32576335</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bach, X. (2021). Los servicios de bicicleta compartida en Barcelona y su área metropolitana: Proceso de implementación y tendencias de futuro.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Basu R., Ferreira J. Sustainable mobility in auto-dominated Metro Boston: Challenges and opportunities post-COVID-19. Transport Policy. 2021;103:197–210.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bauman A., Crane M., Drayton B.A., Titze S. The unrealised potential of bike share schemes to influence population physical activity levels–A narrative review. Preventive Medicine. 2017;103:S7–S14.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bergantino A.S., Intini M., Tangari L. Influencing factors for potential bike-sharing users: An empirical analysis during the COVID-19 pandemic. Research in Transportation Economics. 2021;86</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bian Z., Zuo F., Gao J., Chen Y., Venkata S.S.C.P., Bernardes S.D., et al.  Time lag effects of COVID-19 policies on transportation systems: A comparative study of New York City and Seattle. Transportation Research Part A: Policy and Practice. 2021;145:269–283.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bordagaray M., dell'Olio L., Fonzone A., Ibeas Á. Capturing the conditions that introduce systematic variation in bike-sharing travel behavior using data mining techniques. Transportation Research Part C: Emerging Technologies. 2016;71:231–248.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Braun L.M. Disparities in bicycle commuting: could bike lane investment widen the gap? Journal of Planning Education and Research. 2021 0739456×21993905.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Braun L.M., Rodriguez D.A., Cole-Hunter T., Ambros A., Donaire-Gonzalez D., Jerrett M., et al.  Short-term planning and policy interventions to promote cycling in urban centers: Findings from a commute mode choice analysis in Barcelona, Spain. Transportation Research Part A: Policy and Practice. 2016;89:164–183.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Braun L.M., Rodriguez D.A., Gordon-Larsen P. Social (in) equity in access to cycling infrastructure: Cross-sectional associations between bike lanes and area-level sociodemographic characteristics in 22 large US cities. Journal of transport geography. 2019;80</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bucsky P. Modal share changes due to COVID-19: The case of Budapest. Transportation Research Interdisciplinary Perspectives. 2020;8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Buehler R., Pucher J. COVID-19 impacts on cycling, 2019–2020. Transport Reviews. 2021;41(4):393–400.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bullock C., Brereton F., Bailey S. The economic contribution of public bike-share to the sustainability and efficient functioning of cities. Sustainable Cities and Society. 2017;28:76–87.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cariello A., Ferorelli R., Rotondo F. Tactical urbanism in Italy: From grassroots to institutional tool—assessing value of public space experiments. Sustainability. 2021;13(20):11482.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cerutti P.S., Martins R.D., Macke J., Sarate J.A.R. Green, but not as green as that”: An analysis of a Brazilian bike-sharing system. Journal of cleaner production. 2019;217:185–193.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chai X., Guo X., Xiao J., Jiang J. Analysis of spatiotemporal mobility of shared-bike usage during COVID-19 pandemic in Beijing. Transactions in GIS. 2021;25(6):2866–2887.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen Z., Li X. Unobserved heterogeneity in transportation equity analysis: Evidence from a bike-sharing system in southern Tampa. Journal of Transport Geography. 2021;91</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chibwe J., Heydari S., Imani A.F., Scurtu A. An exploratory analysis of the trend in the demand for the London bike-sharing system: From London Olympics to Covid-19 pandemic. Sustainable Cities and Society. 2021;69</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Corcoran J., Li T., Rohde D., Charles-Edwards E., Mateo-Babiano D. Spatio-temporal patterns of a public bicycle sharing program: The effect of weather and calendar events. Journal of Transport Geography. 2014;41:292–305.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Currie G., Jain T., Aston L. Evidence of a post-COVID change in travel behaviour–Self-reported expectations of commuting in Melbourne. Transportation Research Part A: Policy and Practice. 2021;153:218–234.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Desjardins E., Higgins C.D., Páez A. Examining equity in accessibility to bike share: A balanced floating catchment area approach. Transportation Research Part D: Transport and Environment. 2022;102</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dingil A.E., Esztergár-Kiss D. The Influence of the Covid-19 Pandemic on Mobility Patterns: The First Wave's Results. Transportation Letters. 2021;13(5–6):434–446.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>El-Assi W., Mahmoud M.S., Habib K.N. Effects of built environment and weather on bike sharing demand: A station level analysis of commercial bike sharing in Toronto. Transportation. 2017;44(3):589–613.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elias W., Albert G., Shiftan Y. Travel behavior in the face of surface transportation terror threats. Transport policy. 2013;28:114–122.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eren E., Uz V.E. A review on bike-sharing: The factors affecting bike-sharing demand. Sustainable Cities and Society. 2020;54</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Etminani-Ghasrodashti R., Paydar M., Ardeshiri A. Recreational cycling in a coastal city: Investigating lifestyle, attitudes and built environment in cycling behavior. Sustainable Cities and Society. 2018;39:241–251.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Faghih-Imani A., Eluru N., El-Geneidy A.M., Rabbat M., Haq U. How land-use and urban form impact bicycle flows: Evidence from the bicycle-sharing system (BIXI) in Montreal. Journal of Transport Geography. 2014;41:306–314.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Faghih-Imani A., Hampshire R., Marla L., Eluru N. An empirical analysis of bike sharing usage and rebalancing: Evidence from Barcelona and Seville. Transportation Research Part A: Policy and Practice. 2017;97:177–191.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Feng P., Li W. Willingness to use a public bicycle system: An example in Nanjing City. Journal of Public Transportation. 2016;19(1):6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Firth C.L., Hosford K., Winters M. Who were these bike lanes built for? Social-spatial inequities in Vancouver's bikeways, 2001–2016. Journal of transport geography. 2021;94</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fishman E. Bikeshare: A review of recent literature. Transport Reviews. 2016;36(1):92–113.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fishman E., Washington S., Haworth N. Bike share: A synthesis of the literature. Transport Reviews. 2013;33(2):148–165.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fishman E., Washington S., Haworth N. Bike share's impact on car use: Evidence from the United States, Great Britain, and Australia. Transportation Research Part D: Transport and Environment. 2014;31:13–20.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fishman E., Washington S., Haworth N., Watson A. Factors influencing bike share membership: An analysis of Melbourne and Brisbane. Transportation Research Part A: Policy and Practice. 2015;71:17–30.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gebhart K., Noland R.B. The impact of weather conditions on bikeshare trips in Washington, DC. Transportation. 2014;41(6):1205–1225.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Graells-Garrido E., Serra-Burriel F., Rowe F., Cucchietti F.M., Reyes P. A city of cities: Measuring how 15-minutes urban accessibility shapes human mobility in Barcelona. PloS one. 2021;16(5)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Graziano T. Smart Technologies, Back-to-the-village rhetoric, and tactical urbanism: Post-COVID planning scenarios in Italy. International Journal of E-Planning Research (IJEPR) 2021;10(2):80–93.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Habib K.N., Mann J., Mahmoud M., Weiss A. Synopsis of bicycle demand in the City of Toronto: Investigating the effects of perception, consciousness and comfortability on the purpose of biking and bike ownership. Transportation Research Part A: Policy and Practice. 2014;70:67–80.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hamidi S., Pollackporter K. How cities are taking action on COVID-19. Planning. 2020;86(7):25–29.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heydari S., Konstantinoudis G., Behsoodi A.W. Effect of the COVID-19 pandemic on bike-sharing demand and hire time: Evidence from Santander Cycles in London. PloS one. 2021;16(12)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hirsch J.A., Green G.F., Peterson M., Rodriguez D.A., Gordon-Larsen P. Neighborhood sociodemographics and change in built infrastructure. Journal of Urbanism: International Research on Placemaking and Urban Sustainability. 2017;10(2):181–197.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hong J., McArthur D.P., Sim J., Kim C. Did air pollution continue to affect bike share usage in Seoul during the COVID-19 pandemic? Journal of Transport &amp; Health. 2022</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hood J., Sall E., Charlton B. A GPS-based bicycle route choice model for San Francisco, California. Transportation Letters the International Journal of Transportation Research. 2011;3(1):63–75.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hu S.R., Liu C.T. An optimal location model for the bicycle sharing system: A case study of the KaoSiung City-bike system. Transportation Planning Journal. 2014;43(4):367–392.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hu S., Chen P. Who left riding transit? Examining socioeconomic disparities in the impact of COVID-19 on ridership. Transportation Research Part D: Transport and Environment. 2021;90</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hu S., Xiong C., Liu Z., Zhang L. Examining spatiotemporal changing patterns of bike-sharing usage during COVID-19 pandemic. Journal of Transport Geography. 2021;91</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hu Yujie, Zhang Yongping, Lamb David, Zhang Mingming, Jia Peng. Examining and optimizing the BCycle bike-sharing system–A pilot study in Colorado, US. Applied Energy. 2019;247:1–12.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hua M., Chen X., Cheng L., Chen J. Should bike-sharing continue operating during the COVID-19 pandemic? Empirical findings from Nanjing, China. Journal of Transport &amp; Health. 2021;23</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ibarra-Vega D. Lockdown, one, two, none, or smart. Modeling containing covid-19 infection. A conceptual model. Science of the Total Environment. 2020;730</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jobe J., Griffin G.P. Bike share responses to COVID-19. Transportation Research Interdisciplinary Perspectives. 2021;10</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kabak M., Erbaş M., Çetinkaya C., Özceylan E. A GIS-based MCDM approach for the evaluation of bike-share stations. Journal of Cleaner Production. 2018;201:49–60.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaltenbrunner A., Meza R., Grivolla J., Codina J., Banchs R. Urban cycles and mobility patterns: Exploring and predicting trends in a bicycle-based public transport system. Pervasive and Mobile Computing. 2010;6(4):455–466.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kharroubi S., Saleh F. Are lockdown measures effective against COVID-19? Frontiers in public health. 2020:610.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim K. Investigation on the effects of weather and calendar events on bike-sharing according to the trip patterns of bike rentals of stations. Journal of Transport Geography. 2018;66:309–320.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim K. Impact of COVID-19 on usage patterns of a bike-sharing system: Case study of seoul. Journal of transportation engineering, Part A: Systems. 2021;147(10)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kraus S., Koch N. Provisional COVID-19 infrastructure induces large, rapid increases in cycling. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences. 2021;118(15)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kubalák S., Kalašová A., Hájnik A. The bike-sharing system in Slovakia and the impact of COVID-19 on this shared mobility service in a selected city. Sustainability. 2021;13(12):6544.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lau H., Khosrawipour V., Kocbach P., Mikolajczyk A., Schubert J., Bania J., et al.  The positive impact of lockdown in Wuhan on containing the COVID-19 outbreak in China. Journal of Travel Medicine. 2020</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee R.J., Sener I.N., Jones S.N. Understanding the role of equity in active transportation planning in the United States. Transport reviews. 2017;37(2):211–226.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leister E.H., Vairo N., Sims D., Bopp M. Understanding bike share reach, use, access and function: An exploratory study. Sustainable Cities and Society. 2018;43:191–196.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li A., Zhao P., Haitao H., Mansourian A., Axhausen K.W. How did micro-mobility change in response to COVID-19 pandemic? A case study based on spatial-temporal-semantic analytics. Computers, Environment and Urban Systems, 2021;90</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li H., Zhang Y., Zhu M., Ren G. Impacts of COVID-19 on the usage of public bicycle share in London. Transportation Research Part A: Policy and Practice. 2021;150:140–155.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lu M., Hsu S.C., Chen P.C., Lee W.Y. Improving the sustainability of integrated transportation system with bike-sharing: A spatial agent-based approach. Sustainable Cities and Society. 2018;41:44–51.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lu W., Scott D.M., Dalumpines R. Understanding bike share cyclist route choice using GPS data: Comparing dominant routes and shortest paths. Journal of Transport Geography. 2018;71:172–181.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lydon, M., Bartman, D., Garcia, A., Preston, R., &amp; Woudstra, R. (2012). Tactical Urbanism 2: Short term action, long-term change.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lydon M., Garcia A.  Tactical urbanism. Island Press; Washington, DC: 2015. A tactical urbanism how-to; pp. 171–208.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ma X., Ji Y., Yuan Y., Van Oort N., Jin Y., Hoogendoorn S. A comparison in travel patterns and determinants of user demand between docked and dockless bike-sharing systems using multi-sourced data. Transportation Research Part A: Policy and Practice. 2020;139:148–173.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mattson J., Godavarthy R. Bike share in Fargo, North Dakota: Keys to success and factors affecting ridership. Sustainable Cities and Society. 2017;34:174–182.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Melnick E.R., Ioannidis J.P. Should governments continue lockdown to slow the spread of covid-19? BMJ (Clinical research ed.) 2020:369.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miketa, D., &amp; Sun, P. (2020). As mobility patterns change, cities shift gears. Planning, June.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mora R., Truffello R., Oyarzún G. Equity and accessibility of cycling infrastructure: An analysis of Santiago de Chile. Journal of Transport Geography. 2021;91</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moudon A.V., Lee C., Cheadle A.D., Collier C.W., Johnson D., Schmid T.L., et al.  Cycling and the built environment, a US perspective. Transportation Research Part D: Transport and Environment. 2005;10(3):245–261.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nguyen M.H., Pojani D. The emergence of recreational cycling in Hanoi during the Covid-19 pandemic. Journal of Transport &amp; Health. 2022</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nikiforiadis A., Ayfantopoulou G., Stamelou A. Assessing the impact of COVID-19 on bike-sharing usage: The case of Thessaloniki. Greece. Sustainability. 2020;12(19):8215.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nikitas A., Tsigdinos S., Karolemeas C., Kourmpa E., Bakogiannis E. Cycling in the era of COVID-19: Lessons learnt and best practice policy recommendations for a more bike-centric future. Sustainability. 2021;13(9):4620.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Padmanabhan V., Penmetsa P., Li X., Dhondia F., Dhondia S., Parrish A. COVID-19 effects on shared-biking in New York, Boston, and Chicago. Transportation research interdisciplinary perspectives. 2021;9</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pase F., Chiariotti F., Zanella A., Zorzi M. Bike sharing and urban mobility in a post-pandemic world. IEEE access : practical innovations, open solutions. 2020;8:187291–187306.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pedroso F.E., Angriman F., Bellows A.L., Taylor K. Bicycle use and cyclist safety following Boston's bicycle infrastructure expansion, 2009–2012. American Journal of Public Health. 2016;106(12):2171–2177.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5105001</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27736203</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ricci M. Bike sharing: A review of evidence on impacts and processes of implementation and operation. Research in Transportation Business &amp; Management. 2015;15:28–38.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rixey R.A. Station-level forecasting of bikesharing ridership: Station network effects in three US systems. Transportation Research Record. 2013;2387(1):46–55.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saberi M., Ghamami M., Gu Y., Shojaei M.H.S., Fishman E. Understanding the impacts of a public transit disruption on bicycle sharing mobility patterns: A case of Tube strike in London. Journal of Transport Geography. 2018;66:154–166.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salvatier J., Wiecki T.V., Fonnesbeck C. Probabilistic programming in Python using PyMC3. PeerJ Computer Science. 2016;2:e55.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schoner J.E., Levinson D.M. The missing link: Bicycle infrastructure networks and ridership in 74 US cities. Transportation. 2014;41(6):1187–1204.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sears J., Flynn B., Aultman-Hall L., Dana G. To bike or not to bike: Seasonal factors for bicycle commuting. Transportation Research Record: Journal of the Transportation Research Board. 2012;(2314):105–111.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shaer A., Rezaei M., Moghani Rahimi B. Assessing the COVID-19 outbreak effects on active mobility of men in comparison with women. Journal of Urbanism: International Research on Placemaking and Urban Sustainability. 2021:1–18.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shaheen S.A., Guzman S., Zhang H. Bikesharing in Europe, the Americas, and Asia: Past, present, and future. Transportation Research Record. 2010;2143(1):159–167.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shaheen S., Chan N. Mobility and the sharing economy: Potential to facilitate the first-and last-mile public transit connections. Built Environment. 2016;42(4):573–588.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shamshiripour A., Rahimi E., Shabanpour R., Mohammadian A.K. How is COVID-19 reshaping activity-travel behavior? Evidence from a comprehensive survey in Chicago. Transportation Research Interdisciplinary Perspectives. 2020;7</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shang W.L., Chen J., Bi H., Sui Y., Chen Y., Yu H. Impacts of COVID-19 pandemic on user behaviors and environmental benefits of bike sharing: A big-data analysis. Applied Energy. 2021;285</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sharifi A., Khavarian-Garmsir A. The COVID-19 pandemic: Impacts on cities and major lessons for urban planning, design, and management. Science of the Total Environment. 2020;749</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Si H., Shi J.G., Wu G., Chen J., Zhao X. Mapping the bike sharing research published from 2010 to 2018: A scientometric review. Journal of Cleaner Production. 2019;213:415–427.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Silva P. Tactical urbanism: Towards an evolutionary cities’ approach? Environment and Planning B: Planning and design. 2016;43(6):1040–1051.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Simons D., Clarys P., De Bourdeaudhuij I., de Geus B., Vandelanotte C., Deforche B. Factors influencing mode of transport in older adolescents: A qualitative study. BMC public health. 2013;13(1):323.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3626670</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23574974</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Simsekoglu Ö., Klöckner C.A. The role of psychological and socio-demographical factors for electric bike use in Norway. International Journal of Sustainable Transportation. 2019;13(5):315–323.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Song J., Zhang L., Qin Z., Ramli M.A. Spatiotemporal evolving patterns of bike-share mobility networks and their associations with land-use conditions before and after the COVID-19 outbreak. Physica A: Statistical Mechanics and its Applications. 2022;592</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stevens Q., Awepuga F., Dovey K. Temporary and Tactical Urbanism in Australia: Perspectives from Practice. Urban Policy and Research. 2021;39(3):262–275.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Teixeira J.F., Lopes M. The link between bike sharing and subway use during the COVID-19 pandemic: The case-study of New York's Citi Bike. Transportation Research Interdisciplinary Perspectives. 2020;6</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Teixeira J.F., Silva C., Moura e Sá F. Empirical evidence on the impacts of bikesharing: A literature review. Transport Reviews. 2021;41(3):329–351.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Torrisi V., Ignaccolo M., Inturri G., Tesoriere G., Campisi T. Exploring the factors affecting bike-sharing demand: Evidence from student perceptions, usage patterns and adoption barriers. Transportation Research Procedia. 2021;52:573–580.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Venter Z.S., Barton D.N., Gundersen V., Figari H., Nowell M. Urban nature in a time of crisis: Recreational use of green space increases during the COVID-19 outbreak in Oslo. Norway. Environmental research letters. 2020;15(10)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang H., Noland R.B. Bikeshare and subway ridership changes during the COVID-19 pandemic in New York City. Transport Policy. 2021;106:262–270.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8711868</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34975237</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang J., Lindsey G. Do new bike share stations increase member use: A quasi-experimental study. Transportation Research Part A: Policy and Practice. 2019;121:1–11.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang K., Akar G., Chen Y.-.J. Bike sharing differences among millennials, GenXers, and baby boomers: Lessons learnt from New York City's bike share. Transportation Research Part A: Policy and Practice. 2018;116:1–14.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Willberg E., Salonen M., Toivonen T. What do trip data reveal about bike-sharing system users? Journal of Transport Geography. 2021;91</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xing Y., Wang K., Lu J.J. Exploring travel patterns and trip purposes of dockless bike-sharing by analyzing massive bike-sharing data in Shanghai. China. Journal of transport geography. 2020;87</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu S.J., Chow J.Y. A longitudinal study of bike infrastructure impact on bikesharing system performance in New York City. International journal of sustainable transportation. 2020;14(11):886–902.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang Y., Wu X., Zhou P., Gou Z., Lu Y. Towards a cycling-friendly city: An updated review of the associations between built environment and cycling behaviors (2007–2017) Journal of Transport &amp; Health. 2019;14</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yao L., Wu C. Traffic safety for electric bike riders in China: Attitudes, risk perception, and aberrant riding behaviors. Transportation Research Record. 2012;2314(1):49–56.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang Y., Thomas T., Brussel M., Van Maarseveen M. Exploring the impact of built environment factors on the use of public bikes at bike stations: Case study in Zhongshan. China. Journal of Transport Geography. 2017;58:59–70.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang Z., Qian C., Bian Y. Bicycle–metro integration for the ‘last mile’: Visualizing cycling in Shanghai. Environment and Planning A: Economy and Space. 2019;51(7):1420–1423.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
