<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35535809</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>10</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-4632</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>10</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>International journal of dermatology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Int J Dermatol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Utility of polymerase chain reaction for assessment of onychomycosis during topical therapy.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ijd.16241</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Increased detection of fungi including non-dermatophyte molds (NDMs) using polymerase chain reaction (PCR) methods is well-established. However, the use of PCR to evaluate ongoing onychomycosis treatment outcome has not been investigated.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Nail samples from 28 patients receiving topical efinaconazole were evaluated by both KOH/culture and PCR methods across the study period. Detection of microorganisms by PCR was compared to the culture at baseline and end of study at month 24 (M24). Fungal detection by both methods was evaluated with respect to clinical cure observed as 100% visual clearance of the target toenail.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">By culture, all 28 subjects were dermatophyte-positive at pre-treatment; only 4/28 also exhibited an NDM microorganism. According to PCR, 24/28 subjects were dermatophyte-positive pre-treatment, with 25/28 also exhibiting NDMs. At M24, 18/28 (64.3%) participants had negative KOH/culture results, in contrast to 4/28 (14.3%) negative PCR results. PCR showed higher rates of NDM detection than the culture at baseline as well as M24. Calculations to compare the diagnostic utility of KOH/culture versus PCR found that positive tests with both methods reliably indicate the presence of onychomycosis, but negative PCR correlated better with onychomycosis cure than did KOH/culture.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">PCR confirmed a high presence of NDMs pre-treatment, and continued presence of NDMs to M24, with unknown significance requiring further investigation. Though both KOH/culture and PCR have diagnostic limitations, PCR showed better overall utility than culture in predicting onychomycosis topical treatment outcome and should be more strongly considered for evaluation of topical therapies.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 the International Society of Dermatology.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gupta</LastName>
            <ForeName>Aditya K</ForeName>
            <Initials>AK</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8664-7723</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Dermatology, Faculty of Medicine, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Mediprobe Research Inc., London, ON, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Cooper</LastName>
            <ForeName>Elizabeth A</ForeName>
            <Initials>EA</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1121-5619</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Mediprobe Research Inc., London, ON, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Summerbell</LastName>
            <ForeName>Richard C</ForeName>
            <Initials>RC</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3395-6514</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Sporometrics, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Dalla Lana School of Public Health, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nakrieko</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kerry-Ann</ForeName>
            <Initials>KA</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-9317-7141</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Mediprobe Research Inc., London, ON, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Int J Dermatol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0243704</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0011-9059</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
          <Hour>7</Hour>
          <Minute>42</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35535809</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ijd.16241</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Nakrieko K-A. Onychomycosis infections: do polymerase chain reaction and culture reports agree? J Am Podiatr Med Assoc 2017; 107(4): 280-286.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Uchida T, Makimura K, Ishihara K, et al. Comparative study of direct polymerase chain reaction, microscopic examination and culture-based morphological methods for detection and identification of dermatophytes in nail and skin samples. J Dermatol 2009; 36(4): 202-208.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kondori N, Abrahamsson AL, Ataollahy N, et al. Comparison of a new commercial test, dermatophyte-PCR kit, with conventional methods for rapid detection and identification of trichophyton rubrum in nail specimens. Med Mycol 2010; 48(7): 1005-1008.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chandran NS, Pan J-Y, Pramono ZA, et al. Complementary role of a polymerase chain reaction test in the diagnosis of onychomycosis. Australas J Dermatol 2013; 54(2): 105-108.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bausch Health, Canada Inc. PrJublia™ Efinaconazole Topical Solution, 10% w/w Topical Antifungal Agent. Prescribing Information Revision: 20 January 2020. Accessed 2022 Feb 01. https://bauschhealth.ca/wp-content/uploads/pdf/Jublia%20PM-E-2020-01-20.pdf</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghannoum M, Isham N, Catalano V. A second look at efficacy criteria for onychomycosis: Clinical and mycological cure. Br J Dermatol 2014; 170(1): 182-187.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Cooper EA. Long-term efficacy and safety of once-daily topical efinaconazole 10% topical solution (Jublia) for dermatophyte toenail onychomycosis: An interim analysis. Skin Ther Lett 2021; 26(1): 5-10.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Drummond-Main C, Cooper EA, et al. Systematic review of nondermatophyte mold onychomycosis: Diagnosis, clinical types, epidemiology, and treatment. J Am Acad Dermatol 2012; 66(3): 494-502.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Cooper EA, MacDonald P, et al. Utility of inoculum counting (Walshe and English criteria) in clinical diagnosis of onychomycosis caused by nondermatophytic filamentous fungi. J Clin Microbiol 2001; 39(6): 2115-2121.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shemer A, Davidovici B, Grunwald MH, et al. New criteria for the laboratory diagnosis of nondermatophyte moulds in onychomycosis. Br J Dermatol 2009; 160(1): 37-39.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jackson CJ, Barton RC, Evans EG. Species identification and strain differentiation of dermatophyte fungi by analysis of ribosomal-DNA intergenic spacer regions. J Clin Microbiol 1999; 37(4): 931-936.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bontems O, Hauser PM, Monod M. Evaluation of a polymerase chain reaction-restriction fragment length polymorphism assay for dermatophyte and nondermatophyte identification in onychomycosis. Br J Dermatol 2009; 161(4): 791-796.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Machouart-Dubach M, Lacroix C, et al. Rapid discrimination among dermatophytes, Scytalidium spp., and other fungi with a PCR-restriction fragment length polymorphism ribotyping method. J Clin Microbiol 2001; 39(2): 685-690.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ebihara M, Makimura K, Sato K, et al. Molecular detection of dermatophytes and nondermatophytes in onychomycosis by nested polymerase chain reaction based on 28S ribosomal RNA gene sequences. Br J Dermatol 2009; 161(5): 1038-1044.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gupta AK, Taborda VBA, Taborda PRO, et al. High prevalence of mixed infections in global onychomycosis. PLoS One 2020; 15(9): e0239648.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Trevethan R. Sensitivity, specificity, and predictive values: foundations, pliabilities, and pitfalls in research and practice. Front Public Health 2017; 5: Article 307.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Foley K, Gupta AK, Versteeg S, et al. Topical and device-based treatments for fungal infections of the toenails. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 2020; 1: CD012093.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
