<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35546485</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>13</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1742-481X</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>12</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>International wound journal</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Int Wound J</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Effectiveness of moist dressings in wound healing after surgical suturing: A Bayesian network meta-analysis of randomised controlled trials.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/iwj.13839</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The moist healing theory proves that a moderately moist and airtight environment is conducive to wound healing. However, different moist dressings have different functions. We aim to evaluate the effects of moist dressings on wound healing after surgical suturing and identify superior moist dressings. Randomised controlled trials investigating the application of moist dressings were retrieved from electronic databases, including PubMed, EMBASE, Web of Science, and the Cochrane Library. Wound healing, surgical site infection (SSI), and times of dressing change were assessed. The values of the surface under the cumulative ranking (SUCRA) curve were calculated based on the Bayesian network meta-analysis. Inconsistency tests and funnel plots were applied to analyse the consistency and publication bias. All the analysis complies with the PRISMA (Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analyses) 2020 Checklist and AMSTAR (Assessing the Methodological Quality of Systematic Reviews) Guidelines. Sixteen randomised controlled trials involving 4444 patients were pooled in the network meta-analysis. The ionic silver dressing (SUCRA, 93%) ranked first in wound healing, the metallic silver dressing (SUCRA, 75.9%) ranked first in SSI, and the hydrocolloid dressing (SUCRA, 73.9%) ranked first in times of dressing change. Inconsistency was only observed in wound healing, and no publication bias was observed in this study. The effects of moist dressings are better than gauze dressings in the process of wound healing. The ionic silver dressing is effective in wound healing, whereas the metallic silver dressing is effective in SSI prevention. The hydrocolloid dressing requires the fewest times of dressing change. More high-quality RCTs are required to support the network meta-analysis.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Authors. International Wound Journal published by Medicalhelplines.com Inc (3M) and John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sun</LastName>
            <ForeName>Wenjing</ForeName>
            <Initials>W</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1865-0098</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Maojun</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Duan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Dan</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Liu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Wenjie</ForeName>
            <Initials>W</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Cui</LastName>
            <ForeName>Wenyao</ForeName>
            <Initials>W</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Li</LastName>
            <ForeName>Li</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurosurgery, West China Hospital, Sichuan University, Chengdu, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Int Wound J</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101230907</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1742-4801</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">network meta-analysis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">occlusive dressings</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">surgical wound infection</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">sutures</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">wound healing</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
          <Hour>1</Hour>
          <Minute>49</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35546485</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/iwj.13839</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Regula CG, Yag-Howard C. Suture products and techniques: what to use, where, and why. Dermatol Surg Off Publ Am Soc Dermatol Surg Al. 2015;41(Suppl. 10):S187-S200. doi:10.1097/DSS.0000000000000492</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Azmat CE, Council M. Wound Closure Techniques. StatPearls. Treasure Island (FL): StatPearls Publishing; 2021. http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK470598/</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sganga G. Surgical site infections. Urologia. 2014;81(4):191-195. doi:10.5301/uro.5000102</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sandy-Hodgetts K, Carville K, Leslie GD. Surgical wound dehiscence: a conceptual framework for patient assessment. J Wound Care. 2018;27(3):119-126. doi:10.12968/jowc.2018.27.3.119</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bryan J. Moist wound healing: a concept that changed our practice. J Wound Care. 2004;13(6):227-228. doi:10.12968/jowc.2004.13.6.26625</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mirhaj M, Labbaf S, Tavakoli M, Seifalian AM. Emerging treatment strategies in wound care. Int Wound J. Published online March 17, 2022. doi:10.1111/iwj.13786</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rutter L. Obtaining the optimum moist wound healing environment. Br J Community Nurs. 2017;22(Suppl. 12):S36-S40. doi:10.12968/bjcn.2017.22</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>China trauma rescue and treatment association, National Center for trauma medicine, trauma treatment Center of Peking University People's hospital. Chinese expert consensus on emergency open wound debridement and suture. Nat Med J China. 2020;100(21):1605-1610. doi:10.3760/cma.j.cn112137-20191125-02560</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Page MJ, McKenzie JE, Bossuyt PM, et al. The PRISMA 2020 statement: an updated guideline for reporting systematic reviews. Int J Surg Lond Engl. 2021;88:105906. doi:10.1016/j.ijsu.2021.105906</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shea BJ, Reeves BC, Wells G, et al. AMSTAR 2: a critical appraisal tool for systematic reviews that include randomised or non-randomised studies of healthcare interventions, or both. BMJ. 2017;358:j4008. doi:10.1136/bmj.j4008</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arroyo AA, Casanova PL, Soriano JV, Torra IBJE. Open-label clinical trial comparing the clinical and economic effectiveness of using a polyurethane film surgical dressing with gauze surgical dressings in the care of post-operative surgical wounds. Int Wound J. 2015;12(3):285-292. doi:10.1111/iwj.12099</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beele H, Van Overschelde P, Olivecrona C, Smet S. A prospective randomized controlled clinical investigation comparing two post-operative wound dressings used after elective hip and knee replacement; Mepilex(R) border post-Op vs Aquacel(R) surgical. Int J Orthop Trauma Nurs. 2020;38:100772. doi:10.1016/j.ijotn.2020.100772</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Biffi R, Fattori L, Bertani E, et al. Surgical site infections following colorectal cancer surgery: a randomized prospective trial comparing common and advanced antimicrobial dressing containing ionic silver. World J Surg Oncol. 2012;10:94. doi:10.1186/1477-7819-10-94</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blazeby J. Bluebelle pilot randomised controlled trial of three wound dressing strategies to reduce surgical site infection in primary surgical wounds. BMJ Open. 2020;10(1):e030615. doi:10.1136/bmjopen-2019-030615</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Connery SA, Yankowitz J, Odibo L, Raitano O, Nikolic-Dorschel D, Louis JM. Effect of using silver nylon dressings to prevent superficial surgical site infection after cesarean delivery: a randomized clinical trial. Am J Obstet Gynecol. 2019;221(1):57.e1-57.e7. doi:10.1016/j.ajog.2019.02.053</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dickinson Jennings C, Culver Clark R, Baker JW. A prospective, randomized controlled trial comparing 3 dressing types following sternotomy. Ostomy Wound Manage. 2015;61(5):42-49. https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/25965091</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Holm C, Petersen JS, Gronboek F, Gottrup F. Effects of occlusive and conventional gauze dressings on incisional healing after abdominal operations. Eur J Surg. 1998;164(3):179-183. doi:10.1080/110241598750004616</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Michie DD, Hugill JV. Influence of occlusive and impregnated gauze dressings on incisional healing: a prospective, randomized, controlled study. Ann Plast Surg. 1994;32(1):57-64. doi:10.1097/00000637-199401000-00011</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ozaki CK, Hamdan AD, Barshes NR, et al. Prospective, randomized, multi-institutional clinical trial of a silver alginate dressing to reduce lower extremity vascular surgery wound complications. J Vasc Surg. 2015;61(2):419-427.e1. doi:10.1016/j.jvs.2014.07.034</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ruiz-Tovar J, Llavero C, Perez-Lopez M, Garcia-Marin A. Effects of the application of vitamin E and silicone dressings vs conventional dressings on incisional surgical site infection in elective laparoscopic colorectal surgery: a prospective randomized clinical trial. J Hosp Infect. 2019;102(3):262-266. doi:10.1016/j.jhin.2018.10.021</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shinohara T, Yamashita Y, Satoh K, et al. Prospective evaluation of occlusive hydrocolloid dressing vs conventional gauze dressing regarding the healing effect after abdominal operations: randomized controlled trial. Asian J Surg. 2008;31(1):1-5. doi:10.1016/S1015-9584(08)60046-9</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stanirowski PJ, Bizoń M, Cendrowski K, Sawicki W. Randomized controlled trial evaluating Dialkylcarbamoyl chloride impregnated dressings for the prevention of surgical site infections in adult women undergoing cesarean section. Surg Infect. 2016;17(4):427-435. doi:10.1089/sur.2015.223</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Teshima H, Kawano H, Kashikie H, et al. A new hydrocolloid dressing prevents surgical site infection of median sternotomy wounds. Surg Today. 2009;39(10):848-854. doi:10.1007/s00595-008-3974-5</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vogt KC, Uhlyarik M, Schroeder TV. Moist wound healing compared with standard care of treatment of primary closed vascular surgical wounds: a prospective randomized controlled study. Wound Repair Regen. 2007;15(5):624-627. doi:10.1111/j.1524-475X.2007.00294.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wynne R, Botti M, Stedman H, et al. Effect of three wound dressings on infection, healing comfort, and cost in patients with sternotomy wounds - a randomized trial. Chest. 2004;125(1):43-49. doi:10.1378/chest.125.1.43</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xue SL, Yang J, Lv X. The evaluation of calcium alginate dressing helping wound healing of nail surgery. Sichuan Da Xue Xue Bao Yi Xue Ban. 2018;49(4):652-655. doi:10.13464/j.scuxbyxb.2018.04.033</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Phillips SJ. Physiology of wound healing and surgical wound care. Asaio J. 2000;46(6):S2-5. doi:10.1097/00002480-200011000-00029</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maillard JY, Hartemann P. Silver as an antimicrobial: facts and gaps in knowledge. Crit Rev Microbiol. 2013;39(4):373-383. doi:10.3109/1040841X.2012.713323</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oliverius M, Drozd J, Bratka P, Whitley A, Mohlenikova Duchonova B, Gürlich R. A new silver dressing, StopBac, used in the prevention of surgical site infections. Int Wound J. 2022;19(1):29-35. doi:10.1111/iwj.13593</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sørensen LT. Wound healing and infection in surgery: the pathophysiological impact of smoking, smoking cessation, and nicotine replacement therapy: a systematic review. Ann Surg. 2012;255(6):1069-1079. doi:10.1097/SLA.0b013e31824f632d</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brogliato AR, Borges PA, Barros JF, et al. The effect and safety of dressing composed by nylon threads covered with metallic silver in wound treatment. Int Wound J. 2012;11(2):190-197. doi:10.1111/j.1742-481X.2012.01065.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Böttrich JG, Braunwarth H, Dissemond J, Münter KC, Schümmelfeder F, Wilken P. Best practice recommendations for silver wound dressings: results of an expert survey aiming to reach a consensus. Wound Med. 2019;27(1):100167. doi:10.1016/j.wndm.2019.100167</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lindholm C, Searle R. Wound management for the 21st century: combining effectiveness and efficiency. Int Wound J. 2016;13(Suppl 2):5-15. doi:10.1111/iwj.12623</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chengyu S, Chengyu W, He L, et al. Selection of appropriate wound dressing for various wounds. Front Bioeng Biotechnol. 2020;8(1):182. doi:10.3389/fbioe.2020.00182</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barnes HR. Wound care: fact and fiction about hydrocolloid dressings. J Gerontol Nurs. 1993;19(6):23-26. doi:10.3928/0098-9134-19930601-08</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Joy H, Bielby A, Searle R. A collaborative project to enhance efficiency through dressing change practice. J Wound Care. 2015;24(7):312-317. doi:10.12968/jowc.2015.24.7.312</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tickle J. Quality dressings and assessment. Br J Nurs Mark Allen Publ. 2014;23(12):S30-S31. doi:10.12968/bjon.2014.23</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
