<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35545848</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>12</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1863-2378</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>11</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Zoonoses and public health</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Zoonoses Public Health</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Occurrence and bacterial loads of Bartonella and haemotropic Mycoplasma species in privately owned cats and dogs and their fleas from East and Southeast Asia.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/zph.12959</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Bartonella spp. and haemoplasmas are pathogens of veterinary and medical interest with ectoparasites mainly involved in their transmission. This study aimed at molecular detection of Bartonella spp. and haemoplasmas in cats (n = 93) and dogs (n = 96), and their related fleas (n = 189) from countries in East and Southeast Asia. Ctenocephalides felis was the dominant flea species infesting both cats (97.85%) and dogs (75%) followed by Ctenocephalides orientis in dogs (18.75%) and rarely in cats (5.2%). Bartonella spp. DNA was only detected in blood samples of flea-infested cats (21.51%) (p &lt; .0001, OR = 27.70) with Bartonella henselae more frequently detected than Bartonella clarridgeiae in cat hosts (15.05%, 6.45%) and their associated fleas (17.24%, 13.79%). Out of three Bartonella-positive fleas from dogs, two Ct. orientis fleas carried Bartonella vinsonii subsp. berkhoffii and Bartonella clarridgeiae, while the 3rd flea (Ct. felis) carried Candidatus Bartonella merieuxii. Felines represented a risk factor for Bartonella spp. infections, where fleas collected from cats (32.25%) presented an increased likelihood for Bartonella spp. occurrence (p &lt; .0001, OR = 14.76) than those from dogs (3.13%). Moreover, when analysing infectious status, higher Bartonella spp. DNA loads were detected in fleas from bacteraemic cats compared to those from non-bacteraemic ones (p &lt; .05). The haemoplasma occurrence was 16.13% (15/93) and 4.17% (4/96) in cat and dog blood samples from different countries (i.e. Indonesia, Malaysia, the Philippines, Taiwan and Thailand), with cats more at risk of infection (p &lt; .01, OR = 5.96) than dogs. Unlike Bartonella spp., there was no evidence for flea involvement in the hemoplasmas' transmission cycle, thus supporting the hypothesis of non-vectorial transmission for these pathogens. In conclusion, client-owned cats and dogs living in East and Southeast Asia countries are exposed to vector-borne pathogens with fleas from cats playing a key role in Bartonella spp. transmission, thus posing a high risk of infection for humans sharing the same environment.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Authors. Zoonoses and Public Health published by Wiley-VCH GmbH.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zarea</LastName>
            <ForeName>Aya Attia Koraney</ForeName>
            <Initials>AAK</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2290-1988</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Veterinary Medicine, University of Bari "Aldo Moro", Bari, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Microbiology and Immunology, Veterinary Research Institute, National Research Centre (NRC), Cairo, Egypt.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bezerra-Santos</LastName>
            <ForeName>Marcos Antonio</ForeName>
            <Initials>MA</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0575-6758</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Veterinary Medicine, University of Bari "Aldo Moro", Bari, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nguyen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Viet-Linh</ForeName>
            <Initials>VL</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Oxford University Clinical Research Unit (OUCRU), Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Colella</LastName>
            <ForeName>Vito</ForeName>
            <Initials>V</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Faculty of Veterinary and Agricultural Sciences, University of Melbourne, Melbourne, Victoria, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Dantas-Torres</LastName>
            <ForeName>Filipe</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Immunology, Aggeu Magalhães Institute, Recife, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Halos</LastName>
            <ForeName>Lenaig</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Boehringer Ingelheim Animal Health, Lyon, France.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Bill &amp; Melinda Gates Foundation, Seattle, Washington, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Beugnet</LastName>
            <ForeName>Frederic</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Boehringer Ingelheim Animal Health, Lyon, France.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tempesta</LastName>
            <ForeName>Maria</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Veterinary Medicine, University of Bari "Aldo Moro", Bari, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Otranto</LastName>
            <ForeName>Domenico</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7518-476X</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Veterinary Medicine, University of Bari "Aldo Moro", Bari, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Faculty of Veterinary Sciences, Bu-Ali Sina University, Hamedan, Iran.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Greco</LastName>
            <ForeName>Grazia</ForeName>
            <Initials>G</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4338-6746</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Veterinary Medicine, University of Bari "Aldo Moro", Bari, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>Germany</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Zoonoses Public Health</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101300786</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1863-1959</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bartonella spp.</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Candidatus Bartonella merieuxii</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">East and Southeast Asia</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">flea</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">haemoplasmas</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>1</Hour>
          <Minute>52</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35545848</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/zph.12959</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abdel-Rahman, S. M., El-Saadani, M. A., Ashry, K. M., &amp; Haggag, A. S. (2009). Detection of adulteration and identification of cat's, dog's, donkey's and horse's meat using species-specific PCR and PCR-RFLP techniques. Australian Journal of Basic and Applied Sciences, 3(3), 1716-1719.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Álvarez-Fernández, A., Breitschwerdt, E. B., &amp; Solano-Gallego, L. (2018). Bartonella infections in cats and dogs including zoonotic aspects. Parasites &amp; Vectors, 11(1), 1-21. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13071-018-3152-6</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arvand, M., Klose, A. J., Schwartz-Porsche, D., Hahn, H., &amp; Wendt, C. (2001). Genetic variability and prevalence of Bartonella henselae in cats in Berlin, Germany, and analysis of its genetic relatedness to a strain from Berlin that is pathogenic for humans. Journal of Clinical Microbiology, 39(2), 743-746. https://doi.org/10.1128/JCM.39.2.743-746.2001</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Assarasakorn, S., Veir, J. K., Hawley, J. R., Brewer, M. M., Morris, A. K., Hill, A. E., &amp; Lappin, M. R. (2012). Prevalence of Bartonella species, hemoplasmas, and Rickettsia felis DNA in blood and fleas of cats in Bangkok, Thailand. Research in Veterinary Science, 93(3), 1213-1216. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rvsc.2012.03.015</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barrs, V. R., Beatty, J. A., Wilson, B. J., Evans, N., Gowan, R., Baral, R. M., Lingard, A. E., Perkovic, G., Hawley, J. R., &amp; Lappin, M. R. (2010). Prevalence of Bartonella species, Rickettsia felis, haemoplasmas and the Ehrlichia group in the blood of cats and fleas in eastern Australia. Australian Veterinary Journal, 88(5), 160-165. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1751-0813.2010.00569.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bergmann, M., Englert, T., Stuetzer, B., Hawley, J. R., Lappin, M. R., &amp; Hartmann, K. (2017). Risk factors of different hemoplasma species infections in cats. BMC Veterinary Research, 13(1), 16. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12917-017-0953-3</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bergmans, A. M., Schellekens, J. F., van Embden, J. D., &amp; Schouls, L. M. (1996). Predominance of two Bartonella henselae variants among cat-scratch disease patients in the Netherlands. Journal of Clinical Microbiology, 34(2), 254-260. https://doi.org/10.1128/jcm.34.2.254-260.1996</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bezerra-Santos, M. A., Ramos, R. A. N., Campos, A. K., Dantas-Torres, F., &amp; Otranto, D. (2021). Didelphis spp. opossums and their parasites in the Americas: A One Health perspective. Parasitology Research, 120(12), 4091-4111. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00436-021-07072-4</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Billeter, S. A., Sangmaneedet, S., Kosakewich, R. C., &amp; Kosoy, M. Y. (2012). Bartonella species in dogs and their ectoparasites from Khon Kaen Province, Thailand. The Southeast Asian Journal of Tropical Medicine and Public Health, 43(5), 1186-1192.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Biondo, A. W., Dos Santos, A. P., Guimarães, A. M., Vieira, R. F., Vidotto, O., Macieira, D., Almosny, N. R., Molento, M. B., Timenetsky, J., de Morais, H. A., González, F. H., &amp; Messick, J. B. (2009). A review of the occurrence of hemoplasmas (hemotrophic mycoplasmas) in Brazil. Revista brasileira de parasitologia veterinaria = Brazilian journal of veterinary parasitology: Orgao Oficial do Colegio Brasileiro de Parasitologia Veterinaria, 18(3), 1-7. https://doi.org/10.4322/rbpv.01803001</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bouhsira, E., Ferrandez, Y., Liu, M., Franc, M., Boulouis, H. J., &amp; Biville, F. (2013). Ctenocephalides felis an in vitro potential vector for five Bartonella species. Comparative Immunology, Microbiology and Infectious Diseases, 36(2), 105-111. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cimid.2012.10.004</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Breitschwerdt, E. B., &amp; Kordick, D. L. (2000). Bartonella infection in animals: carriership, reservoir potential, pathogenicity, and zoonotic potential for human infection. Clinical Microbiology Reviews, 13(3), 428-438. https://doi.org/10.1128/CMR.13.3.428</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Breitschwerdt, E. B., Maggi, R. G., Chomel, B. B., &amp; Lappin, M. R. (2010). Bartonellosis: An emerging infectious disease of zoonotic importance to animals and human beings. Journal of Veterinary Emergency and Critical Care, 20(1), 8-30. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1476-4431.2009.00496.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brenner, E. C., Chomel, B. B., Singhasivanon, O. U., Namekata, D. Y., Kasten, R. W., Kass, P. H., Cortés-Vecino, J. A., Gennari, S. M., Rajapakse, R. P., Huong, L. T., &amp; Dubey, J. P. (2013). Bartonella infection in urban and rural dogs from the tropics: Brazil, Colombia, Sri Lanka and Vietnam. Epidemiology and Infection, 141(1), 54-61. https://doi.org/10.1017/S0950268812000519</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Calvani, N. E. D., Bell, L., Carney, A., De La Fuente, C., Stragliotto, T., Tunstall, M., &amp; Šlapeta, J. (2020). The molecular identity of fleas (Siphonaptera) carrying Rickettsia felis, Bartonella clarridgeiae and Bartonella rochalimae from dogs and cats in Northern Laos. Heliyon, 6(7), 4-7. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.heliyon.2020.e04385</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chandra, S., Forsyth, M., Lawrence, A. L., Emery, D., &amp; Šlapeta, J. (2017). Cat fleas (Ctenocephalides felis) from cats and dogs in New Zealand: Molecular characterisation, presence of Rickettsia felis and Bartonella clarridgeiae and comparison with Australia. Veterinary Parasitology, 234, 25-30. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vetpar.2016.12.017</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chang, C. C., Lee, C. C., Maruyama, S., Lin, J. W., &amp; Pan, M. J. (2006). Cat-scratch disease in veterinary-associated populations and in its cat reservoir in Taiwan. Veterinary Research, 37(4), 565-577. https://doi.org/10.1051/vetres:2006019</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Changbunjong, T., Buddhirongawatr, R., Suwanpakdee, S., Siengsanan, J., Yongyuttawichai, P., Cheewajorn, K., Jangjaras, J., Sangloung, C., &amp; Ratanakorn, P. (2009). A survey of ectoparasitic arthropods on domestic animals in Tak Province, Thailand. The Southeast Asian Journal of Tropical Medicine and Public Health, 40(3), 435-442.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chomel, B. B., Abbot, R. C., Kasten, R. W., Floyd-Hawkins, K. A., Kass, P. H., Glaser, C. A., Pedersen, N. C., &amp; Koehler, J. E. (1995). Bartonella henselae prevalence in domestic cats in California: Risk factors and association between bacteremia and antibody titers. Journal of Clinical Microbiology, 33(9), 2445-2450. https://doi.org/10.1128/jcm.33.9.2445-2450.1995</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chomel, B. B., Boulouis, H. J., Breitschwerdt, E. B., Kasten, R. W., Vayssier-Taussat, M., Birtles, R. J., Koehler, J. E., &amp; Dehio, C. (2009). Ecological fitness and strategies of adaptation of Bartonella species to their hosts and vectors. Veterinary Research, 40(2), 29. https://doi.org/10.1051/vetres/2009011</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chomel, B. B., Boulouis, H. J., Maruyama, S., &amp; Breitschwerdt, E. B. (2006). Bartonella spp. in pets and effect on human health. Emerging Infectious Diseases, 12(3), 389-394. https://doi.org/10.3201/eid1203.050931</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chomel, B. B., Boulouis, H. J., Petersen, H., Kasten, R. W., Yamamoto, K., Chang, C. C., Gandoin, C., Bouillin, C., &amp; Hew, C. M. (2002). Prevalence of Bartonella infection in domestic cats in Denmark. Veterinary Research, 33(2), 205-213. https://doi.org/10.1051/vetres:2002008</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chomel, B. B., Carlos, E. T., Kasten, R. W., Yamamoto, K., Chang, C. C., Carlos, R. S., Abenes, M. V., &amp; Pajares, C. M. (1999). Bartonella henselae and Bartonella clarridgeiae infection in domestic cats from the Philippines. American Journal of Tropical Medicine and Hygiene, 60(4), 593 597. https://doi.org/10.4269/ajtmh.1999.60.593</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chomel, B. B., Kasten, R. W., Floyd-Hawkins, K., Chi, B., Yamamoto, K., Roberts-Wilson, J., Gurfield, A. N., Abbott, R. C., Pedersen, N. C., &amp; Koehler, J. E. (1996). Experimental transmission of Bartonella henselae by the cat flea. Journal of Clinical Microbiology, 34(8), 1952. https://doi.org/10.1088/0022-3727/49/25/254001</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chomel, B. B., Kasten, R. W., Williams, C., Wey, A. C., Henn, J. B., Maggi, R., Carrasco, S., Mazet, J., Boulouis, H. J., Maillard, R., &amp; Breitschwerdt, E. B. (2009). Bartonella endocarditis: A pathology shared by animal reservoirs and patients. Annals of the New York Academy of Sciences, 1166, 120-126. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1749-6632.2009.04523.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chomel, B. B., McMillan-Cole, A. C., Kasten, R. W., Stuckey, M. J., Sato, S., Maruyama, S., Diniz, P. P., &amp; Breitschwerdt, E. B. (2012). Candidatus Bartonella merieuxii, a potential new zoonotic Bartonella species in canids from Iraq. PLoS Neglected Tropical Diseases, 6(9), e1843. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pntd.0001843</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chongsuvivatwong, V., Phua, K. H., Yap, M. T., Pocock, N. S., Hashim, J. H., Chhem, R., Wilopo, S. A., &amp; Lopez, A. D. (2011). Health and health-care systems in southeast Asia: Diversity and transitions. Lancet, 377(9763), 429-437. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0140-6736(10)61507-3</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Colella, V., Nguyen, V. L., Tan, D. Y., Lu, N., Fang, F., Zhijuan, Y., Wang, J., Liu, X., Chen, X., Dong, J., Nurcahyo, W., Hadi, U. K., Venturina, V., Tong, K., Tsai, Y. L., Taweethavonsawat, P., Tiwananthagorn, S., Le, T. Q., Bui, K. L., … Halos, L. (2020). Zoonotic vector borne pathogens and ectoparasites of dogs and cats in Eastern and Southeast Asia. Emerging Infectious Diseases, 26(6), 1221-1233. https://doi.org/10.3201/eid2606.191832</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Compton, S. M., Maggi, R. G., &amp; Breitschwerdt, E. B. (2012). Candidatus Mycoplasma haematoparvum and Mycoplasma haemocanis infections in dogs from the United States. Comparative Immunology, Microbiology and Infectious Diseases, 35(6), 557-562. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cimid.2012.06.004</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Criado-Fornelio, A., Martinez-Marcos, A., Buling-Saraña, A., &amp; Barba-Carretero, J. C. (2003). Presence of Mycoplasma haemofelis, Mycoplasma haemominutum and piroplasmids in cats from southern Europe: A molecular study. Veterinary Microbiology, 93(4), 307-317. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0378-1135(03)00044-0</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Diaz, M. H., Bai, Y., Malania, L., Winchell, J. M., &amp; Kosoy, M. Y. (2012). Development of a novel genus-specific real-time PCR assay for detection and differentiation of Bartonella species and genotypes. Journal of Clinical Microbiology, 50(5), 1645-1649. https://doi.org/10.1128/JCM.06621-11</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Díaz-Regañón, D., Villaescusa, A., Ayllón, T., Rodríguez-Franco, F., García-Sancho, M., Agulla, B., &amp; Sainz, Á. (2018). Epidemiological study of hemotropic Mycoplasmas (hemoplasmas) in cats from central Spain. Parasites &amp; Vectors, 11(1), 140. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13071-018-2740-9</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Diniz, P. P., Maggi, R. G., Schwartz, D. S., Cadenas, M. B., Bradley, J. M., Hegarty, B., &amp; Breitschwerdt, E. B. (2007). Canine bartonellosis: Serological and molecular prevalence in Brazil and evidence of co-infection with Bartonella henselae and Bartonella vinsonii subsp. berkhoffii. Veterinary Research, 38(5), 697-710. https://doi.org/10.1051/vetres:2007023</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Do, T., Kamyingkird, K., Bui, L. K., &amp; Inpankaew, T. (2020). Genetic characterization and risk factors for feline hemoplasma infection in semi-domesticated cats in Bangkok, Thailand. Veterinary World, 13(5), 975-980. https://doi.org/10.14202/vetworld.2020.975-980</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Do, T., Kamyingkird, K., Chimnoi, W., &amp; Inpankaew, T. (2021). Evaluation of hematological alteration of vector-borne pathogens in cats from Bangkok, Thailand. BMC Veterinary Research, 17(1), 1-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>dos Santos, A. P., dos Santos, R. P., Biondo, A. W., Dora, J. M., Goldani, L. Z., de Oliveira, S. T., de Sá Guimarães, A. M., Timenetsky, J., de Morais, H. A., González, F. H., &amp; Messick, J. B. (2008). Hemoplasma infection in HIV-positive patient, Brazil. Emerging Infectious Diseases, 14(12), 1922-1924. https://doi.org/10.3201/eid1412.080964</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Duong, V., Tarantola, A., Ong, S., Mey, C., Choeung, R., Ly, S., Bourhy, H., Dussart, P., &amp; Buchy, P. (2016). Laboratory diagnostics in dog-mediated rabies: An overview of performance and a proposed strategy for various settings. International Journal of Infectious Diseases, 46, 107-114. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijid.2016.03.016</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ebani, V. V., Bertelloni, F., Turchi, B., Filogari, D., &amp; Cerri, D. (2015). Molecular survey of tick-borne pathogens in Ixodid ticks collected from hunted wild animals in Tuscany, Italy. Asian Pacific Journal of Tropical Medicine, 8(9), 714-717. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apjtm.2015.07.033</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Greco, G., Brianti, E., Buonavoglia, C., Carelli, G., Pollmeier, M., Schunack, B., Dowgier, G., Capelli, G., Dantas-Torres, F., &amp; Otranto, D. (2019). Effectiveness of a 10% imidacloprid 4.5% flumethrin polymer matrix collar in reducing the risk of Bartonella spp. Infection in privately owned cats. Parasites &amp; Vectors, 12(1), 1-10. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13071-018-3257-y</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Greco, G., Sazmand, A., Goudarztalejerdi, A., Zolhavarieh, S. M., Decaro, N., Lapsley, W. D., Otranto, D., &amp; Chomel, B. B. (2019). High prevalence of Bartonella sp. In dogs from Hamadan, Iran. American Journal of Tropical Medicine and Hygiene, 101(4), 749-752. https://doi.org/10.4269/ajtmh.19-0345</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Greco, G., Zarea, A., Sgroi, G., Tempesta, M., D'Alessio, N., Lanave, G., Bezerra-Santos, M. A., Iatta, R., Veneziano, V., Otranto, D., &amp; Chomel, B. (2021). Zoonotic Bartonella species in Eurasian wolves and other free-ranging wild mammals from Italy. Zoonoses and Public Health, 68(4), 316-326. https://doi.org/10.1111/zph.12827</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guptill, L., Slater, L., Wu, C. C., Lin, T. L., Glickman, L. T., Welch, D. F., &amp; HogenEsch, H. (1997). Experimental infection of young specific pathogen-free cats with Bartonella henselae. The Journal of Infectious Diseases, 176(1), 206-216. https://doi.org/10.1086/514026</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gutiérrez, R., Nachum-Biala, Y., &amp; Harrus, S. (2015). Relationship between the presence of Bartonella species and bacterial loads in cats and cat fleas (Ctenocephalides felis) under natural conditions. Applied and Environmental Microbiology, 81(16), 5613-5621. https://doi.org/10.1128/AEM.01370-15</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Higgins, J. A., Radulovic, S., Jaworski, D. C., &amp; Azad, A. F. (1996). Acquisition of the cat scratch disease agent Bartonella henselae by cat fleas (Siphonaptera: Pulicidae). Journal of Medical Entomology, 33(3), 490-495. https://doi.org/10.1093/jmedent/33.3.490</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hodžić, A., Mrowietz, N., Cézanne, R., Bruckschwaiger, P., Punz, S., Habler, V. E., Tomsik, V., Lazar, J., Duscher, G. G., Glawischnig, W., &amp; Fuehrer, H. P. (2018). Occurrence and diversity of arthropod-transmitted pathogens in red foxes (Vulpes vulpes) in western Austria, and possible vertical (transplacental) transmission of Hepatozoon canis. Parasitology, 145(3), 335-344. https://doi.org/10.1017/S0031182017001536</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huggins, L. G., Colella, V., Koehler, A. V., Schunack, B., &amp; Traub, R. J. (2021). A multipronged next-generation sequencing metabarcoding approach unearths hyperdiverse and abundant dog pathogen communities in Cambodia. Transboundary and Emerging Diseases. https://doi.org/10.1111/tbed.14180</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huggins, L. G., Koehler, A. V., Ng-Nguyen, D., Wilcox, S., Schunack, B., Inpankaew, T., &amp; Traub, R. J. (2019). Assessment of a metabarcoding approach for the characterisation of vector-borne bacteria in canines from Bangkok, Thailand. Parasites &amp; Vectors, 12(1), 394. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13071-019-3651-0</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hwang, J., Gottdenker, N., Min, M. S., Lee, H., &amp; Chun, M. S. (2016). Evaluation of biochemical and haematological parameters and prevalence of selected pathogens in feral cats from urban and rural habitats in South Korea. Journal of Feline Medicine and Surgery, 18(6), 443-451. https://doi.org/10.1177/1098612X15587572</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Inoue, K., Maruyama, S., Kabeya, H., Kawanami, K., Yanai, K., Jitchum, S., &amp; Jittaparapong, S. (2009). Prevalence of Bartonella infection in cats and dogs in a metropolitan area, Thailand. Epidemiology and Infection, 137(11), 1568-1573. https://doi.org/10.1017/S095026880900257X</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Inpankaew, T., Hii, S. F., Chimnoi, W., &amp; Traub, R. J. (2016). Canine vector-borne pathogens in semi-domesticated dogs residing in northern Cambodia. Parasites &amp; Vectors, 9(1), 253. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13071-016-1552-z</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ishida, C., Tsuneoka, H., Iino, H., Murakami, K., Inokuma, H., Ohnishi, T., &amp; Tsukahara, M. (2001). Bartonella henselae infection in domestic cat and dog fleas. Kansenshōgaku Zasshi, 75(2), 133-136. doi:10.11150/kansenshogakuzasshi1970.75.133</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jensen, W. A., Fall, M. Z., Rooney, J., Kordick, D. L., &amp; Breitschwerdt, E. B. (2000). Rapid identification and differentiation of Bartonella species using a single-step PCR assay. Journal of Clinical Microbiology, 38(5), 1717-1722. https://doi.org/10.1128/jcm.38.5.1717-1722.2000</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaewmongkol, S., Lakhana, N., Sirinarumitr, T., Fenwick, S. G., &amp; Kaewmongkol, G. (2020). Investigation of hemotropic Mycoplasma spp. genotypes in client-owned cats in Thailand. Veterinary Microbiology, 247, 108765. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vetmic.2020.108765</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaewmongkol, G., Lukkana, N., Yangtara, S., Kaewmongkol, S., Thengchaisri, N., Sirinarumitr, T., Jittapalapong, S., &amp; Fenwick, S. G. (2017). Association of Ehrlichia canis, Hemotropic Mycoplasma spp. and Anaplasma platys and severe anemia in dogs in Thailand. Veterinary Microbiology, 201, 195-200. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vetmic.2017.01.022</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaiser, P. O., Riess, T., O'Rourke, F., Linke, D., &amp; Kempf, V. A. J. (2011). Bartonella spp: Throwing light on uncommon human infections. International Journal of Medical Microbiology, 301(1), 7-15. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijmm.2010.06.004</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kamrani, A., Parreira, V. R., Greenwood, J., &amp; Prescott, J. F. (2008). The prevalence of Bartonella, hemoplasma, and Rickettsia felis infections in domestic cats and in cat fleas in Ontario. Canadian Journal of Veterinary Research, 72(5), 411-419.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kernif, T., Socolovschi, C., Wells, K., Lakim, M. B., Inthalad, S., Slesak, G., Boudebouch, N., Beaucournu, J. C., Newton, P. N., Raoult, D., &amp; Parola, P. (2012). Bartonella and Rickettsia in arthropods from the Lao PDR and from Borneo, Malaysia. Comparative Immunology, Microbiology and Infectious Diseases, 35(1), 51-57. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cimid.2011.10.003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim, Y. S., Seo, K. W., Lee, J. H., Choi, E. W., Lee, H. W., Hwang, C. Y., Shin, N. S., Youn, H. J., &amp; Youn, H. Y. (2009). Prevalence of Bartonella henselae and Bartonella clarridgeiae in cats and dogs in Korea. Journal of Veterinary Science, 10(1), 85-87. https://doi.org/10.4142/jvs.2009.10.1.85</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kirchhoff, H., Rosengarten, R., Lotz, W., Fischer, M., &amp; Lopatta, D. (1984). Flask-shaped mycoplasmas: properties and pathogenicity for man and animals. Israel Journal of Medical Sciences, 20(9), 848-853.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kosoy, M., &amp; Goodrich, I. (2019). Comparative ecology of Bartonella and Brucella infections in wild carnivores. Frontiers in Veterinary Science, 5, 322. https://doi.org/10.3389/fvets.2018.00322</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>La Scola, B., Davoust, B., Boni, M., &amp; Raoult, D. (2002). Lack of correlation between Bartonella DNA detection within fleas, serological results, and results of blood culture in a Bartonella-infected stray cat population. Clinical Microbiology and Infection, 8(6), 345-351. https://doi.org/10.1046/j.1469-0691.2002.00434.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lappin, M. R., Griffin, B., Brunt, J., Riley, A., Burney, D., Hawley, J., Brewer, M. M., &amp; Jensen, W. A. (2006). Prevalence of Bartonella species, haemoplasma species, Ehrlichia species, Anaplasma phagocytophilum, and Neorickettsia risticii DNA in the blood of cats and their fleas in the United States. Journal of Feline Medicine and Surgery, 8(2), 85-90. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jfms.2005.08.003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lappin, M. R., &amp; Hawley, J. (2009). Presence of Bartonella species and Rickettsia species DNA in the blood, oral cavity, skin and claw beds of cats in the United States. Veterinary dermatology, 20(5-6), 509-514. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-3164.2009.00800.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Latrofa, M. S., Iatta, R., Toniolo, F., Furlanello, T., Ravagnan, S., Capelli, G., Schunack, B., Chomel, B., Zatelli, A., Mendoza-Roldan, J., Dantas-Torres, F., &amp; Otranto, D. (2020). A molecular survey of vector-borne pathogens and haemoplasmas in owned cats across Italy. Parasites &amp; Vectors, 13(1), 116. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13071-020-3990-x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu, M., Ruttayaporn, N., Saechan, V., Jirapattharasate, C., Vudriko, P., Moumouni, P. F. A., Cao, S., Inpankaew, T., Ybañez, A. P., Suzuki, H., &amp; Xuan, X. (2016). Molecular survey of canine vector-borne diseases in stray dogs in Thailand. Parasitology International, 65(4), 357-361. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.parint.2016.04.011</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maggi, R. G., Mascarelli, P. E., Havenga, L. N., Naidoo, V., &amp; Breitschwerdt, E. B. (2013). Co-infection with Anaplasma platys, Bartonella henselae and Candidatus Mycoplasma haematoparvum in a veterinarian. Parasites &amp; Vectors, 6, 103. https://doi.org/10.1186/1756-3305-6-103</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maruyama, S., Nakamura, Y., Kabeya, H., Tanaka, S., Sakai, T., &amp; Katsube, Y. (2000). Prevalence of Bartonella henselae, Bartonella clarridgeiae and the 16S rRNA gene types of Bartonella henselae among pet cats in Japan. Journal of Veterinary Medical Science, 62(3), 273-279. https://doi.org/10.1292/jvms.62.273</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maruyama, S., Sakai, T., Morita, Y., Tanaka, S., Kabeya, H., Boonmar, S., Poapolathep, A., Chalarmchaikit, T., Chang, C. C., Kasten, R. W., Chomel, B. B., &amp; Katsube, Y. (2001). Prevalence of Bartonella species and 16s rRNA gene types of Bartonella henselae from domestic cats in Thailand. American Journal of Tropical Medicine and Hygiene, 65(6), 783-787. https://doi.org/10.4269/ajtmh.2001.65.783</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Messick, J. B. (2004). Hemotrophic mycoplasmas (hemoplasmas): A review and new insights into pathogenic potential. Veterinary Clinical Pathology, 33(1), 2-13. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1939-165X.2004.tb00342.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Messick, J. B., Walker, P. G., Raphael, W., Berent, L., &amp; Shi, X. (2002). “Candidatus Mycoplasma haemodidelphidis” sp. nov., “Candidatus Mycoplasma haemolamae” sp. nov. and Mycoplasma haemocanis comb. nov., haemotrophic parasites from a naturally infected opossum (Didelphis virginiana), alpaca (Lama pacos) and dog (Canis familiaris). International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology, 52(3), 693-698. https://doi.org/10.1099/ijs.0.01861-0</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Museux, K., Boretti, F. S., Willi, B., Riond, B., Hoelzle, K., Hoelzle, L. E., Wittenbrink, M. M., Tasker, S., Wengi, N., Reusch, C. E., Lutz, H., &amp; Hofmann-Lehmann, R. (2009). In vivo transmission studies of 'Candidatus Mycoplasma turicensis' in the domestic cat. Veterinary Research, 40(5), 45. https://doi.org/10.1051/vetres/2009028</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Neimark, H., Johansson, K. E., Rikihisa, Y., &amp; Tully, J. G. (2001). Proposal to transfer some members of the genera Haemobartonella and Eperythrozoon to the genus Mycoplasma with descriptions of 'Candidatus Mycoplasma haemofelis', 'Candidatus Mycoplasma haemomuris', 'Candidatus Mycoplasma haemosuis' and 'Candidatus Mycoplasma wenyonii'. International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology, 51(Pt 3), 891-899. https://doi.org/10.1099/00207713-51-3-891</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nguyen, V. L., Colella, V., Greco, G., Fang, F., Nurcahyo, W., Hadi, U. K., Venturina, V., Tong, K., Tsai, Y. L., Taweethavonsawat, P., Tiwananthagorn, S., Tangtrongsup, S., Le, T. Q., Bui, K. L., Do, T., Watanabe, M., Rani, P., Dantas-Torres, F., Halos, L., … Otranto, D. (2020). Molecular detection of pathogens in ticks and fleas collected from companion dogs and cats in East and Southeast Asia. Parasites &amp; Vectors, 13(1), 420. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13071-020-04288-8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Novacco, M., Meli, M. L., Gentilini, F., Marsilio, F., Ceci, C., Pennisi, M. G., Lombardo, G., Lloret, A., Santos, L., Carrapiço, T., Willi, B., Wolf, G., Lutz, H., &amp; Hofmann-Lehmann, R. (2010). Prevalence and geographical distribution of canine hemotropic Mycoplasma infections in Mediterranean countries and analysis of risk factors for infection. Veterinary Microbiology, 142(3-4), 276-284. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vetmic.2009.09.069</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Otranto, D., Napoli, E., Latrofa, M. S., Annoscia, G., Tarallo, V. D., Greco, G., Lorusso, E., Gulotta, L., Falsone, L., Basano, F. S., Pennisi, M. G., Deuster, K., Capelli, G., Dantas-Torres, F., &amp; Brianti, E. (2017). Feline and canine leishmaniosis and other vector-borne diseases in the Aeolian Islands: Pathogen and vector circulation in a confined environment. Veterinary Parasitology, 236, 144-151. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vetpar.2017.01.019</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peters, I. R., Helps, C. R., Willi, B., Hofmann-Lehmann, R., &amp; Tasker, S. (2008). The prevalence of three species of feline haemoplasmas in samples submitted to a diagnostics service as determined by three novel real-time duplex PCR assays. Veterinary Microbiology, 126(1-3), 142-150. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vetmic.2007.06.017</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pitassi, L. H., de Paiva Diniz, P. P., Scorpio, D. G., Drummond, M. R., Lania, B. G., Barjas-Castro, M. L., Gilioli, R., Colombo, S., Sowy, S., Breitschwerdt, E. B., Nicholson, W. L., &amp; Velho, P. E. (2015). Bartonella spp. bacteremia in blood donors from Campinas, Brazil. PLoS Neglected Tropical Diseases, 9(1), e0003467. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pntd.0003467</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raimundo, J. M., Guimarães, A., Amaro, G. M., Da Silva, A. T., Botelho, C. F. M., Massard, C. L., De Lemos, E. R. S., Favacho, A. R. M., &amp; Baldani, C. D. (2019). Molecular survey of Bartonella species in shelter cats in Rio de Janeiro: Clinical, hematological, and risk factors. American Journal of Tropical Medicine and Hygiene, 100(6), 1321-1327. https://doi.org/10.4269/ajtmh.18-0585</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ravagnan, S., Carli, E., Piseddu, E., Da Rold, G., Porcellato, E., Zanardello, C., Carminato, A., Vascellari, M., &amp; Capelli, G. (2017). Prevalence and molecular characterization of canine and feline hemotropic Mycoplasmas (hemoplasmas) in northern Italy. Parasites &amp; Vectors, 10(1), 132. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13071-017-2069-9</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rolain, J. M., Fournier, P. E., Raoult, D., &amp; Bonerandi, J. J. (2003). First isolation and detection by immunofluorescence assay of Bartonella koehlerae in erythrocytes from a French cat. Journal of Clinical Microbiology, 41(8), 4001-4002. https://doi.org/10.1128/JCM.41.8.4001-4002.2003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rolain, J. M., Franc, M., Davoust, B., &amp; Raoult, D. (2003). Molecular detection of Bartonella quintana, B. koehlerae, B. henselae, B. clarridgeiae, Rickettsia felis, and Wolbachia pipientis in cat fleas, France. Emerging Infectious Diseases, 9(3), 338-342. https://doi.org/10.3201/eid0903.020278</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roura, X., Peters, I. R., Altet, L., Tabar, M. D., Barker, E. N., Planellas, M., Helps, C. R., Francino, O., Shaw, S. E., &amp; Tasker, S. (2010). Prevalence of hemotropic Mycoplasmas in healthy and unhealthy cats and dogs in Spain. Journal of Veterinary Diagnostic Investigation, 22(2), 270-274. https://doi.org/10.1177/104063871002200219</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rust, M. K. (2005). Advances in the control of Ctenocephalides felis (cat flea) on cats and dogs. Trends in Parasitology, 21(5), 232-236. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pt.2005.03.010</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rust, M. K., &amp; Dryden, M. W. (1997). The biology, ecology, and management of the cat flea. Annual Review of Entomology, 42, 451-473. https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev.ento.42.1.451</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sander, A., Ruess, M., Bereswill, S., Schuppler, M., &amp; Steinbrueckner, B. (1998). Comparison of different DNA fingerprinting techniques for molecular typing of Bartonella henselae isolates. Journal of Clinical Microbiology, 36(10), 2973-2981. https://doi.org/10.1128/JCM.36.10.2973-2981.1998</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sasaki, M., Ohta, K., Matsuu, A., Hirata, H., Ikadai, H., &amp; Oyamada, T. (2008). A molecular survey of Mycoplasma haemocanis in dogs and foxes in Aomori Prefecture, Japan. The Journal of Protozoology Research, 18(2), 57-60.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Senevtratna, P., Weerasinghe, N., &amp; Ariyadasa, S. (1973). Transmission of Haemobartonella canis by the dog tick, Rhipiccphalus sanguineus. Research in Veterinary Science, 14(1), 112-114.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singer, G. A., Loya, F. P., Lapsley, W. D., Tobar, B. Z., Carlos, S., Carlos, R. S., Carlos, E. T., Adao, D. E. V., Rivera, W. L., Jaffe, D. A., Mazet, J. A. K., &amp; Chomel, B. B. (2020). Detection of Bartonella infection in pet dogs from Manila, the Philippines. Acta Tropica, 205, 105277. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actatropica.2019.105277</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Suh, G. H., Ahn, K. S., Ahn, J. H., Kim, H. J., Leutenegger, C., &amp; Shin, S. (2017). Serological and molecular prevalence of canine vector-borne diseases (CVBDs) in Korea. Parasites &amp; Vectors, 10(1), 146. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13071-017-2076-x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sykes, J. E. (2010). Feline hemotropic Mycoplasmas. Journal of Veterinary Emergency and Critical Care, 20(1), 62-69. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1476-4431.2009.00491.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sykes, J. E., Bailiff, N. L., Ball, L. M., Foreman, O., George, J. W., &amp; Fry, M. M. (2004). Identification of a novel hemotropic Mycoplasma in a splenectomized dog with hemic neoplasia. Journal of the American Veterinary Medical Association, 224(12), 1946-1951. https://doi.org/10.2460/javma.2004.224.1946</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sykes, J. E., Ball, L. M., Bailiff, N. L., &amp; Fry, M. M. (2005). “Candidatus Mycoplasma haematoparvum”, a novel small haemotropic Mycoplasma from a dog. International Journal of Systematic and Evolutionary Microbiology, 55(1), 27-30. https://doi.org/10.1099/ijs.0.02989-0</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tasker, S. (2010). Haemotropic mycoplasmas: What's their real significance in cats? Journal of Feline Medicine and Surgery, 12(5), 369-381. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jfms.2010.03.011</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tasker, S., Braddock, J. A., Baral, R., Helps, C. R., Day, M. J., Gruffydd-Jones, T. J., &amp; Malik, R. (2004). Diagnosis of feline haemoplasma infection in Australian cats using a real-time PCR assay. Journal of Feline Medicine and Surgery, 6(6), 345-354. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jfms.2003.12.003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tasker, S., Helps, C. R., Day, M. J., Gruffydd-Jones, T. J., &amp; Harbour, D. A. (2003). Use of real-time PCR to detect and quantify Mycoplasma haemofelis and "Candidatus Mycoplasma haemominutum" DNA. Journal of Clinical Microbiology, 41(1), 439-441. https://doi.org/10.1128/JCM.41.1.439-441.200</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tasker, S., Helps, C. R., Day, M. J., Harbour, D. A., Shaw, S. E., Harrus, S., Baneth, G., Lobetti, R. G., Malik, R., Beaufils, J. P., Belford, C. R., &amp; Gruffydd-Jones, T. J. (2003). Phylogenetic analysis of hemoplasma species: an international study. Journal of Clinical Microbiology, 41(8), 3877-3880. https://doi.org/10.1128/JCM.41.8.3877-3880.2003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tasker, S., Peters, I. R., Mumford, A. D., Day, M. J., Gruffydd-Jones, T. J., Day, S., Pretorius, A. M., Birtles, R. J., Helps, C. R., &amp; Neimark, H. (2010). Investigation of human haemotropic Mycoplasma infections using a novel generic haemoplasma qPCR assay on blood samples and blood smears. Journal of Medical Microbiology, 59(Pt 11), 1285-1292. https://doi.org/10.1099/jmm.0.021691-0</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tsai, Y. L., Chang, C. C., Chuang, S. T., &amp; Chomel, B. B. (2011). Bartonella species and their ectoparasites: selective host adaptation or strain selection between the vector and the mammalian host? Comparative Immunology, Microbiology and Infectious Diseases, 34(4), 299-314. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cimid.2011.04.005</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tsai, K. H., Huang, C. G., Fang, C. T., Shu, P. Y., Huang, J. H., &amp; Wu, W. J. (2011). Prevalence of Rickettsia felis and the first identification of Bartonella henselae Fizz/CAL-1 in cat fleas (Siphonaptera: Pulicidae) from Taiwan. Journal of Medical Entomology, 48(2), 445-452. https://doi.org/10.1603/ME10022</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vieira-Damiani, G., Diniz, P. P., Pitassi, L. H., Sowy, S., Scorpio, D. G., Lania, B. G., Drummond, M. R., Soares, T. C., Barjas-Castro, M., Breitschwerdt, E. B., Nicholson, W. L., &amp; Velho, P. E. (2015). Bartonella clarridgeiae bacteremia detected in an asymptomatic blooddonor. Journal of clinical microbiology, 53(1), 352-356.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Watanabe, M. (2012). Main pet Arthropod-borne diseases in Asia. 9th Merial Symposium on Parasitosis and Arthropod-Borne Diseases. Tokyo 6th, 18-21.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wells, K., Beaucournu, J. C., Durden, L. A., Petney, T. N., Lakim, M. B., &amp; O'Hara, R. B. (2012). Ectoparasite infestation patterns of domestic dogs in suburban and rural areas in Borneo. Parasitology Research, 111(2), 909-919. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00436-012-2917-7</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Willi, B., Boretti, F. S., Baumgartner, C., Tasker, S., Wenger, B., Cattori, V., Meli, M. L., Reusch, C. E., Lutz, H., &amp; Hofmann-Lehmann, R. (2006). Prevalence, risk factor analysis, and follow-up of infections caused by three feline hemoplasma species in cats in Switzerland. Journal of Clinical Microbiology, 44(3), 961-969. https://doi.org/10.1128/JCM.44.3.961-969.2006</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Willi, B., Boretti, F. S., Meli, M. L., Bernasconi, M. V., Casati, S., Hegglin, D., Puorger, M., Neimark, H., Cattori, V., Wengi, N., Reusch, C. E., Lutz, H., &amp; Hofmann-Lehmann, R. (2007). Real-time PCR investigation of potential vectors, reservoirs, and shedding patterns of feline hemotropic mycoplasmas. Applied and Environmental Microbiology, 73(12), 3798-3802. https://doi.org/10.1128/AEM.02977-06</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Woods, J. E., Brewer, M. M., Hawley, J. R., Wisnewski, N., &amp; Lappin, M. R. (2005). Evaluation of experimental transmission of Candidatus Mycoplasma haemominutum and Mycoplasma haemofelis by Ctenocephalides felis to cats. American Journal of Veterinary Research, 66(6), 1008-1012. https://doi.org/10.2460/ajvr.2005.66.1008</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yuan, C., Zhu, C., Wu, Y., Pan, X., &amp; Hua, X. (2011). Bacteriological and molecular identification of Bartonella species in cats from different regions of China. PLoS Neglected Tropical Diseases, 5(9), e1301. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pntd.0001301</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zangwill, K. M., Hamilton, D. H., Perkins, B. A., Regnery, R. L., Plikaytis, B. D., Hadler, J. L., Cartter, M. L., &amp; Wenger, J. D. (1993). Cat scratch disease in Connecticut. Epidemiology, risk factors, and evaluation of a new diagnostic test. The New England Journal of Medicine, 329(1), 8-13. https://doi.org/10.1056/NEJM199307013290102</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang, X. L., Li, X. W., Li, W. F., Huang, S. J., &amp; Shao, J. W. (2019). Molecular detection and characterization of Bartonella spp. in pet cats and dogs in Shenzhen, China. Acta Tropica, 197, 105056. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.actatropica.2019.105056</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang, Y., Zhang, Z., Lou, Y., &amp; Yu, Y. (2021). Prevalence of hemoplasmas and Bartonella species in client-owned cats in Beijing and Shanghai, China. Journal of Veterinary Medical Science, 83(5), 793-797. https://doi.org/10.1292/jvms.20-068</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
