<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35549993</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1750-1172</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>17</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>12</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Orphanet journal of rare diseases</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Orphanet J Rare Dis</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Genetic determinants of syndactyly: perspectives on pathogenesis and diagnosis.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>198</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>198</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">198</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s13023-022-02339-0</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The formation of the digits is a tightly regulated process. During embryogenesis, disturbance of genetic pathways in limb development could result in syndactyly; a common congenital malformation consisting of webbing in adjacent digits. Currently, there is a paucity of knowledge regarding the exact developmental mechanism leading to this condition. The best studied canonical interactions of Wingless-type-Bone Morphogenic Protein-Fibroblast Growth Factor (WNT-BMP-FGF8), plays a role in the interdigital cell death (ICD) which is thought to be repressed in human syndactyly. Animal studies have displayed other pathways such as the Notch signaling, metalloprotease and non-canonical WNT-Planar cell polarity (PCP), to also contribute to failure of ICD, although less prominence has been given. The current diagnosis is based on a clinical evaluation followed by radiography when indicated, and surgical release of digits at 6 months of age is recommended. This review discusses the interactions repressing ICD in syndactyly, and characterizes genes associated with non-syndromic and selected syndromes involving syndactyly, according to the best studied canonical WNT-BMP-FGF interactions in humans. Additionally, the controversies regarding the current syndactyly classification and the effect of non-coding elements are evaluated, which to our knowledge has not been previously highlighted. The aim of the review is to better understand the developmental process leading to this condition.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Cassim</LastName>
            <ForeName>Afraah</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5257-8056</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Human Genetics Unit, Faculty of Medicine, University of Colombo, 25, Kynsey Road, Colombo, Sri Lanka. c.afraah@gmail.com.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hettiarachchi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Dineshani</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Human Genetics Unit, Faculty of Medicine, University of Colombo, 25, Kynsey Road, Colombo, Sri Lanka.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Dissanayake</LastName>
            <ForeName>Vajira H W</ForeName>
            <Initials>VHW</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Human Genetics Unit, Faculty of Medicine, University of Colombo, 25, Kynsey Road, Colombo, Sri Lanka.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Orphanet J Rare Dis</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101266602</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1750-1172</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>62031-54-3</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D005346">Fibroblast Growth Factors</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005121" MajorTopicYN="N">Extremities</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005346" MajorTopicYN="N">Fibroblast Growth Factors</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015398" MajorTopicYN="N">Signal Transduction</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013576" MajorTopicYN="Y">Syndactyly</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Genetic screening</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Limb</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Syndactyly</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Syndactyly classification</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Synostosis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">WNT-BMP-FGF</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>18</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35549993</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9097448</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13023-022-02339-0</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s13023-022-02339-0</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Malik S. Syndactyly: phenotypes, genetics and current classification. Eur J Hum Genet. 2012;20:817–824.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3400728</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22333904</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hernández-Martínez R, Covarrubias L. Interdigital cell death function and regulation: new insights on an old programmed cell death model. Dev Growth Differ. 2011;53:245–258. doi: 10.1111/j.1440-169X.2010.01246.x.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1440-169X.2010.01246.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21338350</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jordan D, Hindocha S, Dhital M, Saleh M, Khan W. The epidemiology, genetics and future management of syndactyly. Open Orthop J. 2012;6:14–27.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3308320</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22448207</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ahmed H, Akbari H, Emami A, Akbari MR. Genetic overview of syndactyly and polydactyly. Plast Reconstr Surg. 2017;5:1–8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Umair M, Ahmad F, Bilal M, Abbas S. Syndactyly genes and classification: a mini review. J Biochem Clin Genet. 2018;1:10–10.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Montero JA, Hurle JM. Sculpturing digit shape by cell death. Apoptosis. 2010;15:365–375.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20041300</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Al-Qattan MM. A review of the genetics and pathogenesis of syndactyly in humans and experimental animals: a 3-step pathway of pathogenesis. Biomed Res Int. 2019;2019:9652649.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6766129</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31637260</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McCulloch DR, Nelson CM, Dixon LJ, Silver DL, Wylie JD, Lindner V, et al.  ADAMTS metalloproteases generate active versican fragments that regulate interdigital web regression. Dev Cell. 2009;17:687–698.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2780442</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19922873</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bocci F, Onuchic JN, Jolly MK. Understanding the principles of pattern formation driven by Notch signaling by integrating experiments and theoretical models. Front Physiol. 2020;11:929.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7411240</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32848867</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kuss P, Kraft K, Stumm J, Ibrahim D, Vallecillo-Garcia P, Mundlos S, et al.  Regulation of cell polarity in the cartilage growth plate and perichondrium of metacarpal elements by HOXD13 and WNT5A. Dev Biol. 2014;385:83–93.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24161848</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ermito S, Dinatale A, Carrara S, Cavaliere A, Imbruglia L, Recupero S. Prenatal diagnosis of limb abnormalities: role of fetal ultrasonography. J Prenat Med. 2009;3:18–22.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3279100</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22439035</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li Y, Ma D, Sun Y, Meng L, Wang Y, Jiang T. Apert syndrome with FGFR2 758 C &gt; G mutation: a Chinese case report. Front Genet. 2018;9:1–4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5776086</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29387083</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaltcheva MM, Anderson MJ, Harfe BD, Lewandoski M. BMPs are direct triggers of interdigital programmed cell death. Dev Biol. 2016;411:266–276.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7028150</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26826495</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pajni-Underwood S, Wilson CP, Elder C, Mishina Y, Lewandoski M. BMP signals control limb bud interdigital programmed cell death by regulating FGF signaling. Development. 2007;134:2359–2368.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17537800</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Macias D, Gañan Y, Ros MA, Hurle JM. In vivo inhibition of programmed cell death by local administration of FGF-2 and FGF-4 in the interdigital areas of the embryonic chick leg bud. Anat Embryol. 1996;193:533–541.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boulet AM, Moon AM, Arenkiel BR, Capecchi MR. The roles of Fgf4 and Fgf8 in limb bud initiation and outgrowth. Dev Biol. 2004;273:361–372.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15328019</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hernández-Martínez R, Castro-Obregón S, Covarrubias L. Progressive interdigital cell death: regulation by the antagonistic interaction between fibroblast growth factor 8 and retinoic acid. Development. 2009;136:3669–3678.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19820185</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Al-Qattan MM, Alkuraya FS. Cenani-Lenz syndrome and other related syndactyly disorders due to variants in LRP4, GREM1/FMN1, and APC: insight into the pathogenesis and the relationship to polyposis through the WNT and BMP antagonistic pathways. Am J Med Genet Part A. 2019;179:266–279.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30569497</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Murgai A, Altmeyer S, Wiegand S, Tylzanowski P, Stricker S. Cooperation of BMP and IHH signaling in interdigital cell fate determination. PLoS ONE. 2018;13:e0197535.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5957397</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29771958</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gros J, Hu JKH, Vinegoni C, Feruglio PF, Weissleder R, Tabin CJ. WNT5A/JNK and FGF/MAPK pathways regulate the cellular events shaping the vertebrate limb bud. Curr Biol. 2010;20:1993–2002.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2998074</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21055947</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Montero JA, Hurle JM, Lorda-diez CI, Sanchez-fernandez C. Cell death in the developing vertebrate limb: a locally regulated mechanism contributing to musculoskeletal tissue morphogenesis and differentiation. 2020;1–12.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhu X-J, Fang Y, Xiong Y, Wang M, Yang X, Li Y, et al.  Disruption of Wnt production in Shh lineage causes bone malformation in mice, mimicking human Malik–Percin-type syndactyly. FEBS Lett. 2018;592:356–368.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29292497</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gao B, Song H, Bishop K, Elliot G, Garrett L, English MA, et al.  Wnt signaling gradients establish planar cell polarity by inducing vangl2 phosphorylation through Ror2. Dev Cell. 2011;20:163–176.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3062198</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21316585</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tian J, Shao J, Liu C, Hou HY, Chou CW, Shboul M, et al.  Deficiency of lrp4 in zebrafish and human LRP4 mutation induce aberrant activation of Jagged–Notch signaling in fin and limb development. Cell Mol Life Sci. 2019;76:163–178.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30327840</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mehawej C, Chouery E, Maalouf D, Baujat G, Le Merrer M, Cormier-Daire V, et al.  Identification of a novel causative mutation in the ROR2 gene in a Lebanese family with a mild form of recessive Robinow syndrome. Eur J Med Genet. 2012;55:103–108.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22178368</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leupin O, Piters E, Halleux C, Hu S, Kramer I, Morvan F, et al.  Bone overgrowth-associated mutations in the LRP4 gene impair sclerostin facilitator function. J Biol Chem. 2011;286:19489–19500.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3103328</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21471202</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boudin E, Yorgan T, Fijalkowski I, Sonntag S, Steenackers E, Hendrickx G, et al.  The Lrp4 R1170Q homozygous knock-in mouse recapitulates the bone phenotype of Sclerosteosis in humans. J Bone Miner Res. 2017;32:1739–1749.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28477420</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alrayes N, Aziz A, Ullah F, Ishfaq M, Jelani M, Wali A. Novel missense alteration in LRP4 gene underlies Cenani–Lenz syndactyly syndrome in a consanguineous family. J Gene Med. 2020;22:e3143.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31750994</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sebastian A, Loots GG. Genetics of Sost/SOST in sclerosteosis and van Buchem disease animal models. Metabolism. 2018;80:38–47. doi: 10.1016/j.metabol.2017.10.005.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.metabol.2017.10.005</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29080811</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Démurger F, Ichkou A, Mougou-Zerelli S, Le Merrer M, Goudefroye G, Delezoide AL, et al.  New insights into genotype-phenotype correlation for GLI3 mutations. Eur J Hum Genet. 2015;23:92–102.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4266745</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24736735</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shi L, Huang H, Jiang Q, Huang R, Fu W, Mao L, et al.  Sub-exome target sequencing in a family with syndactyly type IV due to a novel partial duplication of the LMBR1 gene: first case report in Fujian Province of China. Front Genet. 2020;11:130.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7058806</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32184803</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu J, Wu J, Teng X, Cai L, Yuan H, Chen X, et al.  Large duplication in LMBR1 gene in a large Chinese pedigree with triphalangeal thumb polysyndactyly syndrome. Am J Med Genet Part A. 2020;182:2117–2123. doi: 10.1002/ajmg.a.61757.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ajmg.a.61757</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32662247</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koide T, Hayata T, Cho KWY. Negative regulation of Hedgehog signaling by the cholesterogenic enzyme 7-dehydrocholesterol reductase. Development. 2006;133:2395–2405.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16687448</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Azoury SC, Reddy S, Shukla V, Deng C-X. Fibroblast growth factor receptor 2 (FGFR2) mutation related syndromic craniosynostosis. Int J Biol Sci. 2017;13:1479–1488.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5723914</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29230096</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>O’Rourke MP, Soo K, Behringer RR, Hui CC, Tam PPL. Twist plays an essential role in FGF and SHH signal transduction during mouse limb development. Dev Biol. 2002;248:143–156.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12142027</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zuniga A, Quillet R, Perrin-Schmitt F, Zeller R. Mouse Twist is required for fibroblast growth factor-mediated epithelial-mesenchymal signalling and cell survival during limb morphogenesis. Mech Dev. 2002;114:51–59.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12175489</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhao X, Sun M, Zhao J, Leyva JA, Zhu H, Yang W, et al.  Mutations in HOXD13 underlie syndactyly type V and a novel brachydactyly-syndactyly syndrome. Am J Hum Genet. 2007;80:361–371.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1785357</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17236141</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Avitan-Hersh E, Indelman M, Bergman R, Sprecher E. ADULT syndrome caused by a mutation previously associated with EEC syndrome. Pediatr Dermatol. 2010;27:643–645.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21078104</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alessandri J-L, Dagoneau N, Laville J-M, Baruteau J, Hébert J-C, Cormier-Daire V. RAB23 mutation in a large family from Comoros Islands with Carpenter syndrome. Am J Med Genet Part A. 2010;152A:982–986. doi: 10.1002/ajmg.a.33327.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ajmg.a.33327</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20358613</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schwarzer W, Witte F, Rajab A, Mundlos S, Stricker S. A gradient of ROR2 protein stability and membrane localization confers brachydactyly type B or Robinow syndrome phenotypes. Hum Mol Genet. 2009;18:4013–4021.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19640924</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van Lierop AH, Appelman-Dijkstra NM, Papapoulos SE. Sclerostin deficiency in humans. Bone. 2017;96:51–62.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27742500</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boudin E, Yorgan ÃT, Fijalkowski ÃI, Sonntag S, Steenackers E, Hendrickx G, et al.  The Lrp4 R1170Q homozygous knock-in mouse humans. J Bone Miner Res. 2017;32:1739–1749.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28477420</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sethi SK, Goyal D, Khalil S, Yadav DK. Two Indian families with Greig cephalopolysyndactyly with non-syndromic phenotype. Eur J Pediatr. 2013;172:1131–1135.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23334564</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yousaf M, Azeem Z, Bilal M, Liaqat K, Hussain S, et al.  Variants in GLI3 cause Greig Cephalopolysyndactyly syndrome. Genet Test Mol Biomark. 2019;23:744–750.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Al-Qattan MM, Shamseldin HE, Al Mazyad M, Al Deghaither S, Alkuraya FS. Genetic heterogeneity in type III familial cutaneous syndactyly and linkage to chromosome 7q36. Am J Med Genet Part A. 2013;161:1579–1584. doi: 10.1002/ajmg.a.35956.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ajmg.a.35956</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ko JS, Choi BS, Seo JK, Shin JY, Chae JH, Kang GH, et al.  A novel DHCR7 mutation in a Smith–Lemli–Opitz syndrome infant presenting with neonatal cholestasis. J Korean Med Sci. 2010;25:159–162.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2799999</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20052364</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Twigg SRF, Lloyd D, Jenkins D, Elçioglu NE, Cooper CDO, Al-Sannaa N, et al.  Mutations in multidomain protein MEGF8 identify a carpenter syndrome subtype associated with defective lateralization. Am J Hum Genet. 2012;91:897–905.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3487118</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23063620</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haye D, Collet C, Sembely-Taveau C, Haddad G, Denis C, Soulé N, et al.  Prenatal findings in carpenter syndrome and a novel mutation in RAB23. Am J Med Genet Part A. 2014;164:2926–2930.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jenkins D, Seelow D, Jehee FS, Perlyn CA, Alonso LG, Bueno DF, et al.  RAB23 mutations in carpenter syndrome imply an unexpected role for Hedgehog signaling in cranial-suture development and obesity. Am J Hum Genet. 2007;80:1162–1170.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1867103</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17503333</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singh CB, Mishra B, Patel R, Kumar A, Ali A. Tripod-shaped syndactyly in Apert syndrome with FGFR2 p.P253R mutation. Indian J Plast Surg. 2021;54:370.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8515315</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34667527</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Suzuki H, Suda N, Shiga M, Kobayashi Y, Nakamura M, Iseki S, et al.  Apert syndrome mutant FGFR2 and its soluble form reciprocally alter osteogenesis of primary Calvarial osteoblasts. J Cell Physiol. 2012;227:3267–3277.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22105374</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hackett A, Rowe L. FGFR1 Pfeiffer syndrome without craniosynostosis: an additional case report. Clin Dysmorphol. 2006;15:207–210.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16957473</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chun K, Teebi AS, Jung JH, Kennedy S, Laframboise R, Meschino WS, et al.  Genetic analysis of patients with the Saethre–Chotzen phenotype. Am J Med Genet. 2002;110:136–143. doi: 10.1002/ajmg.10400.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ajmg.10400</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12116251</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tian J, Shao J, Liu C, Hou HY, Chou CW, Shboul M, et al.  Deficiency of lrp4 in zebrafish and human LRP4 mutation induce aberrant activation of Jagged–Notch signaling in fin and limb development. Cell Mol Life Sci. 2019;76:163–178. doi: 10.1007/s00018-018-2928-3.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00018-018-2928-3</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30327840</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lettice LA, Daniels S, Sweeney E, Venkataraman S, Devenney PS, Gautier P, et al.  Enhancer-adoption as a mechanism of human developmental disease. Hum Mutat. 2011;32:1492–1499.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21948517</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Charzewska A, Obersztyn E, Hoffman-Zacharska D, Lenart J, Poznański J, Bal J. Novel mutations in the IRF6 gene on the background of known polymorphisms in Polish patients with orofacial clefting. Cleft Palate-Craniofacial J. 2015;52:e161–e167.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rath M, Spiegler S, Strom TM, Trenkler J, Kroisel PM, Felbor U. Identification of pathogenic YY1AP1 splice variants in siblings with Grange syndrome by whole exome sequencing. Am J Med Genet Part A. 2019;179:295–299. doi: 10.1002/ajmg.a.60700.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ajmg.a.60700</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6590215</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30556293</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yigit G, Wieczorek D, Bögershausen N, Beleggia F, Möller-Hartmann C, Altmüller J, et al.  A syndrome of microcephaly, short stature, polysyndactyly, and dental anomalies caused by a homozygous KATNB1 mutation. Am J Med Genet Part A. 2016;170:728–733. doi: 10.1002/ajmg.a.37484.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ajmg.a.37484</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26640080</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Torres L, Hernández G, Barrera A, Ospina S, Prada R. Molecular analysis of exons 8, 9 and 10 of the fibroblast growth factor receptor 2 (FGFR2) gene in two families with index cases of apert syndrome. Colomb Med. 2015;46:155–158.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Waye JS, Nakamura LM, Eng B, Hunnisett L, Chitayat D, Costa T. Smith-Lemli-Opitz syndrome: carrier frequency and spectrum of DHCR7 mutations in Canada. J Med Genet. 2002;39:31.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Potuijt JWP, Baas M, Sukenik-Halevy R, Douben H, Nguyen P, Venter DJ, et al.  A point mutation in the pre-ZRS disrupts sonic hedgehog expression in the limb bud and results in triphalangeal thumb–polysyndactyly syndrome. Genet Med. 2018;20:1405–1413.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29543231</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Díaz-González F, Parrón-Pajares M, Barcia-Ramirez A, Heath KE. First case of compound heterozygous BHLHA9 variants in mesoaxial synostotic syndactyly with phalangeal reduction. Am J Med Genet Part A. 2020;182:628–631. doi: 10.1002/ajmg.a.61480.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ajmg.a.61480</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31912643</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Malik S. Mesoaxial synostotic syndactyly with phalangeal reduction (MSSD): syndactyly type IX. Skelet Radiol. 2018;47:149–149.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Malik S, Schott J, Ali SW, Oeffner F, Amin-Ud-Din M, Ahmad W, et al.  Evidence for clinical and genetic heterogeneity of syndactyly type I: the phenotype of second and third toe syndactyly maps to chromosome 3p21.31. Eur J Hum Genet. 2005;13:1268–1274.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16189548</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Malik S, Abbasi AA, Ansar M, Ahmad W, Koch MC, Grzeschik KH. Genetic heterogeneity of synpolydactyly: a novel locus SPD3 maps to chromosome 14q11.2–q12. Clin Genet. 2006;69:518–524.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16712704</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weinrich JM, Ajabnoor W, Bannas P. Case report of a novel nonsyndromic unilateral syndactyly of the hand. Skeletal Radiol. 2017;46:1741–1743.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28748361</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Özdemir M, Kavak P, Kaplanoğlu H. Case report an unusual association of ulnar Hemimelia with mesoaxial synostotic syndactyly. BJR Case Rep. 2020;6:20190073.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7068096</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32201614</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bosse K, Betz RC, Lee YA, Wienker TF, Reis A, Kleen H, et al.  Localization of a gene for syndactyly type 1 to chromosome 2q34-q36. Am J Hum Genet. 2000;67:492–497.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1287194</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10877983</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghadami M, Majidzadeh-A K, Haerian BS, Damavandi E, Yamada K, Pasallar P, et al.  Confirmation of genetic homogeneity of syndactyly type 1 in an Iranian family. Am J Med Genet. 2001;104:147–151.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11746046</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Montagu MFA. A pedigree of Syndactylism of the middle and ring fingers. Hum Genet. 1953;5:70–72.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Castilla EE, Paz JE, Orioli-Parreiras IM. Syndactyly: Frequency of specific types. Am J Med Genet. 1980;5:357–364.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6249121</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muragaki Y, Mundlos S, Upton J, Olsen BR. Altered growth and branching patterns in synpolydactyly caused by mutations in HOXD13. Science (80-). 1996;272:548–551.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Debeer P, Schoenmakers EFPM, Twal WO, Argraves WS, De Smet L, Fryns JP, et al.  The fibulin-1 gene (FBLN1)is disrupted in a t(12;22) associated with a complex type of synpolydactyly. J Med Genet. 2002;39:98–104.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1735038</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11836357</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ngoc NT, Duong NT, Quynh DH, Ton ND, Duc HH, Huong LTM, et al.  Identification of novel missense mutations associated with non-syndromic syndactyly in two vietnamese trios by whole exome sequencing. Clin Chim Acta. 2020;506:16–21.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32165123</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dobrowolski R, Sasse P, Schrickel JW, Watkins M, Kim JS, Rackauskas M, et al.  The conditional connexin43G138R mouse mutant represents a new model of hereditary oculodentodigital dysplasia in humans. Hum Mol Genet. 2008;17:539–554.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2847779</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18003637</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnston O, Kirby VV. Syndactyly of the ring and little finger. Am J Hum Genet. 1955;7:80–82.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1716555</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14361398</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haas SL. Bilateral complete syndactylism of all fingers. Am J Surg. 1940;50:363–366.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wieczorek D, Pawlik B, Li Y, Akarsu NA, Caliebe A, May KJW, et al.  A specific mutation in the distant sonic hedgehog (SHH) cis-regulator (ZRS) causes Werner Mesomelic Syndrome (WMS) while complete ZRS duplications underlie Haas type polysyndactyly and preaxial polydactyly (PPD) with or without triphalangeal thumb. Hum Mutat. 2010;31:81–89.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19847792</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu L, Liang D, Niikawa N, Ma F, Sun M, Pan Q, et al.  A ZRS duplication causes Syndactyly type IV with Tibial Hypoplasia. Am J Med Genet Part A. 2009;149:816–818.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cn D. Cleft hand: a report of a case successfully treated by the use of periosteal flaps. Ann Surg. 1896;24:211–216.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Temtamy SA, McKusick VA. The genetics of hand malformations. 1978.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li Y, Pawlik B, Elcioglu N, Aglan M, Kayserili H, Yigit G, et al.  LRP4 mutations Alter Wnt/β-catenin signaling and cause limb and kidney malformations in Cenani–Lenz syndrome. Am J Hum Genet. 2010;86:696–706.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2869043</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20381006</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dimitrov BI, Voet T, De Smet L, Vermeesch JR, Devriendt K, Fryns JP, et al.  Genomic rearrangements of the GREM1-FMN1 locus cause oligosyndactyly, radio-ulnar synostosis, hearing loss, renal defects syndrome and Cenanie–Lenz-like non-syndromic oligosyndactyly. J Med Genet. 2010;47:569–574.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20610440</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jamsheer A, Zemojtel T, Kolanczyk M, Stricker S, Hecht J, Krawitz P, et al.  Whole exome sequencing identifies FGF16 nonsense mutations as the cause of X-linked recessive metacarpal 4/5 fusion. J Med Genet. 2013;50:579–584.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23709756</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jones B, Byers H, Stewart Watson J, Newman WG. Identification of a novel familial FGF16 mutation in metacarpal 4–5 fusion. Clin Dysmorphol. 2014;23:95–97.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24878828</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kantaputra PN, Carlson BM. Genetic regulatory pathways of split-hand/foot malformation. Clin Genet. 2019;95:132–139. doi: 10.1111/cge.13434.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cge.13434</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30101460</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khan A, Wang R, Han S, Ahmad W, Zhang X. A novel homozygous missense mutation in BHLHA9 causes mesoaxial synostotic syndactyly with phalangeal reduction in a Pakistani family. Hum Genome Var. 2017;4:1–4.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Adkinson JM, Chung KC. Release of Finger Syndactyly Using Dorsal Rectangular Flap. Oper Tech Hand Wrist Surg. 2018. p. 811–8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boczek NJ, Miller EM, Ye D, Nesterenko VV, Tester DJ, Antzelevitch C, et al.  Novel Timothy syndrome mutation leading to increase in CACNA1C window current. Hear Rhythm. 2015;12:211–219.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim H-G, Rosenfeld JA, Scott DA, Bénédicte G, Labonne JD, Brown J, et al.  Disruption of PHF21A causes syndromic intellectual disability with craniofacial anomalies, epilepsy, hypotonia, and neurobehavioral problems including autism. Mol Autism. 2019;10:35. doi: 10.1186/s13229-019-0286-0.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13229-019-0286-0</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6805429</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31649809</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Orge FH, Dar SA, Blackburn CN, Grimes-Hodges SJ, Mitchell AL. Ocular manifestations of X-linked dominant FAM58A mutation in toe syndactyly, telecanthus, anogenital, and renal malformations (‘STAR’) syndrome. Ophthalmic Genet. 2016;37:323–327. doi: 10.3109/13816810.2015.1071407.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3109/13816810.2015.1071407</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26882209</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vladimir Socolov R, Ioana Andreescu N, Maria Haliciu A, Vlad Gorduza E, Dumitrache F, Anca Balan R, et al.  Intrapartum diagnostic of Roberts syndrome-case presentation. Rom J Morphol Embryol. 2015;56:585–588.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26193234</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Struck TJ, Mannakee BK, Gutenkunst RN. The impact of genome-wide association studies on biomedical research publications. Hum Genom. 2018;12:1–9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
