<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35545339</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>16</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>17</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">1672-7347</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>47</Volume>
            <Issue>4</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Apr</Month>
              <Day>28</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Zhong nan da xue xue bao. Yi xue ban = Journal of Central South University. Medical sciences</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Zhong Nan Da Xue Xue Bao Yi Xue Ban</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Probiotics improves abnormal behavior and hippocampal injury in pregnant-stressed offspring rats.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>443</StartPage>
          <EndPage>452</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>443-452</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.11817/j.issn.1672-7347.2022.210231</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">1672-7347(2022)04-0443-10</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">During pregnancy, pregnant women are prone to stress reactions due to external stimuli, affecting their own health and fetal development. At present, there is no good treatment for the stress reactions from pregnant women during pregnancy. This study aims to explore the effect of probiotics on abnormal behavior and hippocampal injury in pregnant stressed offspring.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">SD pregnant rats were divided into a control group, a stress group, and a probiotics group, with 6 rats in each group. The control group was untreated; the stress group was given restraint stress on the 15th-20th day of pregnancy; the probiotics group was given both bifidobacterium trisporus capsules and restraint stress on the 15th-20th day of pregnancy, and the offspring continued to be fed with probiotics until 60 days after birth (P60). The offspring rats completed behavioral tests such as the open field test, the elevated plus maze test, the new object recognition test, and the barnes maze test at 60-70 d postnatally. Nissl's staining was used to reflect the injury of hippocampal neurons; immunohistochemical staining was used to detect the expression of microglia marker ionized calcium binding adapter molecule 1 (IBA-1) which can reflect microglia activation; ELISA was used to detect the content of plasma TNF-α and IL-1β; Western blotting was used to detect the expression of Bax, Bcl-2, and caspase-3.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The retention time of offspring rats in the stress group in the central area of the open field was significantly less than that in the control group (<i>P</i>&lt;0.01), and the retention time of offspring rats in the probiotic group in the central area of the open field was significantly more than that in the stress group (<i>P</i>&lt;0.05). The offspring rats in the stress group stayed in the open arm for a shorter time than the control group (<i>P</i>&lt;0.05) and entered the open arm less often than the control group (<i>P</i>&lt;0.01); the offspring rats in the probiotic group stayed in the open arm for a longer time than the stress group and entered the open arm more often than the stress group (both <i>P</i>&lt;0.05). The discrimination ratio for new to old objects in the offspring rats of the stress group was significantly lower than that of the control group (<i>P</i>&lt;0.01), and the discrimination ratio for new to old objects in the offspring rats of the probiotic group was significantly higher than that of the stress group (<i>P</i>&lt;0.05). The offspring rats in the stress group made significantly more mistakes than the control group (<i>P</i>&lt;0.05), and the offspring rats in the probiotic group made significantly fewer mistakes than the stress group (<i>P</i>&lt;0.05). Compared with the control group, the numbers of Nissl bodies in CA1, CA3, and DG area were significantly reduced in the offspring rats of the stress group (all <i>P</i>&lt;0.001), the number of activated microglia in DG area of hippocampus was significantly increased (<i>P</i>&lt;0.01), the contents of TNF-α and IL-1β in peripheral blood were significantly increased (<i>P</i>&lt;0.05 or <i>P</i>&lt;0.01), the protein expression level of Bcl-2 was significantly down-regulated, and the protein expression levels of Bax and caspase-3 were significantly up-regulated (all <i>P</i>&lt;0.001). Compared with the stress group, the numbers of Nissl bodies in CA1, CA3, and DG area were significantly increased in the probiotic group offspring rats (<i>P</i>&lt;0.001, <i>P</i>&lt;0.01, <i>P</i>&lt;0.05), the number of activated microglia in the DG area of hippocampus was significantly reduced (<i>P</i>&lt;0.05), and the TNF-α and IL-1β levels in peripheral blood were significantly decreased (both <i>P</i>&lt;0.05), the protein expression level of Bcl-2 was significantly up-regulated, and the protein expression levels of Bax and caspase-3 were significantly down-regulated (all <i>P</i>&lt;0.001).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Probiotic intervention partially ameliorated anxiety and cognitive impairment in rats offspring of pregnancy stress, and the mechanism may be related to increasing the number of neurons, inhibiting the activation of hippocampal microglia, and reducing inflammation and apoptosis.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Huang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Zhongjun</ForeName>
            <Initials>Z</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Anatomy and Neurobiology, School of Basic Medical Science, Central South University, Changsha 410013. 1196728655@qq.com.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Bin</ForeName>
            <Initials>B</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Anatomy and Neurobiology, School of Basic Medical Science, Central South University, Changsha 410013.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Shanghai Pharmaceutical Clinical Research Center Co., Ltd., Shanghai 200032.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Liao</LastName>
            <ForeName>Libin</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Histology and Embryology, Basic Medical College of Xinjiang Medical University, Urumqi 830011, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jie</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Anatomy and Neurobiology, School of Basic Medical Science, Central South University, Changsha 410013.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zheng</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ruping</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Anatomy and Neurobiology, School of Basic Medical Science, Central South University, Changsha 410013.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Cai</LastName>
            <ForeName>Deyang</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Anatomy and Neurobiology, School of Basic Medical Science, Central South University, Changsha 410013.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Huang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jufang</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Anatomy and Neurobiology, School of Basic Medical Science, Central South University, Changsha 410013. huangjufang@csu.edu.cn.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <Language>chi</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <VernacularTitle>益生菌改善孕期应激子代大鼠异常行为和海马损伤.</VernacularTitle>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>China</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Zhong Nan Da Xue Xue Bao Yi Xue Ban</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101230586</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1672-7347</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D019253">Proto-Oncogene Proteins c-bcl-2</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D014409">Tumor Necrosis Factor-alpha</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D051028">bcl-2-Associated X Protein</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>EC 3.4.22.-</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D053148">Caspase 3</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D053148" MajorTopicYN="N">Caspase 3</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006624" MajorTopicYN="N">Hippocampus</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011247" MajorTopicYN="N">Pregnancy</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D019936" MajorTopicYN="Y">Probiotics</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D019253" MajorTopicYN="N">Proto-Oncogene Proteins c-bcl-2</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D051381" MajorTopicYN="N">Rats</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013315" MajorTopicYN="Y">Stress, Psychological</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014409" MajorTopicYN="N">Tumor Necrosis Factor-alpha</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D051028" MajorTopicYN="N">bcl-2-Associated X Protein</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="chi">
        <AbstractText><b>目的</b>: 在怀孕期间孕妇极易对外界刺激产生应激反应，影响自身健康和胎儿发育。目前针对孕妇在孕期的应激反应没有很好的治疗方式，本研究旨在探索益生菌对孕期应激子代异常行为和海马损伤的作用。<b>方法</b>: 将SD孕鼠分为对照组、应激组、益生菌组，每组6只。对照组不做任何处理；应激组在母鼠怀孕第15~20天进行束缚应激；益生菌组在母鼠怀孕第15~20天进行束缚应激的同时给予双歧杆菌三联活菌胶囊，子代继续给予益生菌饲喂直至生后60 d(P60)。子代大鼠在出生后60~70 d完成旷场实验、高架十字迷宫实验、新物体识别实验和Barnes迷宫实验等行为学检测。采用尼氏染色反映海马神经元受损的情况；免疫组织化学染色检测小胶质细胞标志物离子钙接头蛋白1(ionized calcium binding adapter molecule 1，IBA-1)的表达，以反映小胶质细胞活化情况；ELISA检测血浆TNF-α、IL-1β的含量；蛋白质印迹法检测Bax、Bcl-2及caspase-3的表达。<b>结果</b>: 应激组子代大鼠在旷场中央区滞留时间明显少于对照组(<i>P</i>&lt;0.01)，益生菌组在旷场中央区滞留时间明显长于应激组(<i>P</i>&lt;0.05)。应激组子代大鼠在开放臂停留的时间短于对照组(<i>P</i>&lt;0.05)，且进入开放臂的次数少于对照组(<i>P</i>&lt;0.01)；益生菌组子代大鼠在开放臂停留的时间长于应激组，且进入开放臂的次数多于应激组(均<i>P</i>&lt;0.05)。应激组子代大鼠的对新、旧物体的分辨比明显低于对照组(<i>P</i>&lt;0.01)，益生菌组子代大鼠对新、旧物体的分辨比明显高于应激组(<i>P</i>&lt;0.05)。应激组子代大鼠的犯错次数明显多于对照组(<i>P</i>&lt;0.05)，益生菌组子代大鼠的犯错次数明显少于应激组(<i>P</i>&lt;0.05)。与对照组比较，应激组子代大鼠CA1、CA3及DG区尼氏体数量均明显减少(均<i>P</i>&lt;0.001)，海马DG区小胶质细胞活化的数量明显增加(<i>P</i>&lt;0.01)，外周血TNF-α、IL-1β的含量显著增加(<i>P</i>&lt;0.05或<i>P</i>&lt;0.01)，Bcl-2的蛋白质表达水平明显下调，Bax及caspase-3的蛋白质表达水平明显上调(均<i>P</i>&lt;0.001)；与应激组相比，益生菌组子代大鼠CA1、CA3及DG区尼氏体数量均明显增加(<i>P</i>&lt;0.001，<i>P</i>&lt;0.01， <i>P</i>&lt;0.05)，海马DG区小胶质细胞活化的数量明显减少(<i>P</i>&lt;0.05)，外周血TNF-α、IL-1β的含量显著减少(<i>P</i>&lt;0.05)，Bcl-2的蛋白质表达水平明显上调，Bax及caspase-3的蛋白质表达水平明显下调(均<i>P</i>&lt;0.001)。<b>结论</b>: 益生菌干预可以部分改善孕期应激子代大鼠的焦虑及认知功能损伤，其机制可能与增加神经元的数量、抑制海马小胶质细胞的活化、减轻炎症和凋亡有关。.</AbstractText>
      </OtherAbstract>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">apoptosis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cognitive function</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">inflammation</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">microglia</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prenatal stress</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">probiotics</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>21</Hour>
          <Minute>12</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35545339</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.11817/j.issn.1672-7347.2022.210231</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">1672-7347(2022)04-0443-10</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Viswasam K, Eslick GD, Prevalence Starcevic V., onset and course of anxiety disorders during pregnancy: A systematic review and meta analysis[J]. J Affect Disord, 2019, 255: 27- 40. https://doi.org/ 10.1016/j.jad.2019.05.016.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>MacKinnon N, Kingsbury M, Mahedy L, et al. The association between prenatal stress and externalizing symptoms in childhood: Evidence from the Avon longitudinal study of parents and children[J]. Biol Psychiatry, 2018, 83(2): 100- 108. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biopsych.2017.07.010.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kingsbury M, Weeks M, MacKinnon N, et al. Stressful life events during pregnancy and offspring depression: evidence from a prospective cohort study[J]. J Am Acad Child Adolesc Psychiatry, 2016, 55(8): 709- 716. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jaac.2016.05.014.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abel KM, Heuvelman HP, Jörgensen L, et al. Severe bereavement stress during the prenatal and childhood periods and risk of psychosis in later life: population-based cohort study[J/OL]. BMJ, 2014, 348: f 7679 (2014-01-21)[ 2020-05-16]. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.f7679.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fitzgerald E, Parent C, Kee MZL, et al. Maternal distress and offspring neurodevelopment: challenges and opportunities for pre-clinical research models [J]. Front Hum Neurosci, 2021, 15: 635304. https://doi.org/ 10.3389/fnhum.2021.635304.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chunchai T, Thunapong W, Yasom S, et al. Decreased microglial activation through gut-brain axis by prebiotics, probiotics, or synbiotics effectively restored cognitive function in obese-insulin resistant rats[J]. J Neuroinflammation, 2018, 15(1): 11. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12974-018-1055-2.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sun J, Xu J, Yang B, et al. Effect of clostridium butyricum against microglia-mediated neuroinflammation in Alzheimer’s disease via regulating gut microbiota and metabolites butyrate[J/OL]. Mol Nutr Food Res, 2020, 64(2): e 1900636 (2019-12-13)[ 2021-01-01]. https://doi.org/10.1002/mnfr.201900636.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Romo-Araiza A, Ibarra A. Prebiotics and probiotics as potential therapy for cognitive impairment[J]. Med Hypotheses, 2020, 134: 109410. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mehy.2019.109410.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liao L, Wang X, Yao X, et al. Gestational stress induced differential expression of HDAC2 in male rat offspring hippocampus during development[J]. Neurosci Res, 2019, 147: 9- 16. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neures.2018.11.006.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Golubeva AV, Crampton S, Desbonnet L, et al. Prenatal stress-induced alterations in major physiological systems correlate with gut microbiota composition in adulthood[J]. Psychoneuroendocrinology, 2015, 60: 58- 74. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.psyneuen.2015.06.002.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hoban AE, Moloney RD, Golubeva AV, et al. Behavioural and neurochemical consequences of chronic gut microbiota depletion during adulthood in the rat[J]. Neuroscience, 2016, 339: 463- 477. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.neuroscience.2016. 10.003.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>O'Mahony SM, Clarke G, Borre YE, et al. Serotonin, tryptophan metabolismand the brain-gut-microbiome axis[J]. Behav Brain Res, 2015, 277: 32- 48. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bbr.2014.07.027.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gur TL, Bailey MT. Effects of stress on commensal microbes and immunesystem activity[J]. Adv Exp Med Biol, 2016, 874: 289- 300. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-20215-0_14.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zareie M, Johnson-Henry K, Jury J, et al. Probiotics prevent bacterial translocation and improve intestinal barrier function in rats following chronic psychological stress[J]. Gut, 2006, 55(11): 1553- 1560. https://doi.org/10.1136/gut.2005.080739.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang H, Braun C, Murphy EF, et al. Bifidobacterium longum 1714<sup>TM</sup> strain modulates brain activity of healthy volunteers during social stress[J]. Am J Gastroenterol, 2019, 114: 1152- 1162. https://doi.org/10.14309/ajg.0000000000000203.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gareau MG, Wine E, Rodrigues DM, et al. Bacterial infection causes stress-induced memory dysfunction in mice[J]. Gut, 2011, 60: 307- 317. https://doi.org/10.1136/gut.2009.202515.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>David SV. Cognition: neurons couple up to make decisions[J]. Nature, 2017, 548: 35- 36. https://doi.org/10.1038/nature23100.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>黄冲, 喻志源, 王伟, 等. 小胶质细胞对神经元调控作用的研究进展[J]. 神经损伤与功能重建, 2020, 15(7): 392- 394.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huo S, Ren J, Ma Y, et al. Upregulation of TRPC5 in hippocampal excitatory synapses improves memory impairment associated with neuroinflammation in microglia knockout IL-10 mice[J]. JNeuroinflammation, 2021, 18(1): 275. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12974-021-02321-w.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>邓佳丽, 丁维俊. 小胶质细胞活化抑制与中枢炎症反应关系的研究进展[J]. 临床与病理杂志, 2020, 40(5): 1286- 1290.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Campos AC, Rocha NP, Nicoli JR, et al. Absence of gut microbiota influences lipopolysaccharide-induced behavioral changes in mice[J]. Behav Brain Res, 2016, 312: 186- 194. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bbr.2016.06.027.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Galley JD, Parry NM, Ahmer BMM, et al. The commensal microbiota exacerbate infectious colitis in stressor-exposed mice[J]. Brain Behav Immun, 2017, 60: 44- 50. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bbi.2016.09.010.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fleshner M. Stress-evoked sterile inflammation, danger associated molecular patterns(DAMPs), microbial associated molecular patterns (MAMPs) and the inflammasome[J]. Brain Behav Immun, 2013, 27(1): 1- 7. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bbi. 2012.08.012.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Park HH, Lo YC, Lin SC, et al. The death domain superfamily in intracellular signaling of apoptosis and inflammation[J]. Annu Rev Immunol, 2007, 25: 561- 586. https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev.immunol.25.022106.141656.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
