<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35549651</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>17</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>20</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1933-6942</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>16</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Dec</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Fly</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Fly (Austin)</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Cutting edge technologies expose the temporal regulation of neurogenesis in the <i>Drosophila</i> nervous system.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>222</StartPage>
          <EndPage>232</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>222-232</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1080/19336934.2022.2073158</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>During the development of the central nervous system (CNS), extremely large numbers of neurons are produced in a regular fashion to form precise neural circuits. During this process, neural progenitor cells produce different neurons over time due to their intrinsic gene regulatory mechanisms as well as extrinsic mechanisms. The <i>Drosophila</i> CNS has played an important role in elucidating the temporal mechanisms that control neurogenesis over time. It has been shown that a series of temporal transcription factors are sequentially expressed in neural progenitor cells and regulate the temporal specification of neurons in the embryonic CNS. Additionally, similar mechanisms are found in the developing optic lobe and central brain in the larval CNS. However, it is difficult to elucidate the function of numerous molecules in many different cell types solely by molecular genetic approaches. Recently, omics analysis using single-cell RNA-seq and other methods has been used to study the <i>Drosophila</i> nervous system on a large scale and is making a significant contribution to the understanding of the temporal mechanisms of neurogenesis. In this article, recent findings on the temporal patterning of neurogenesis and the contributions of cutting-edge technologies will be reviewed.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sato</LastName>
            <ForeName>Makoto</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Mathematical Neuroscience Unit, Institute for Frontier Science Initiative,Laboratory of Developmental Neurobiology, Graduate School of Medical Sciences, Kanazawa University, Ishikawa, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Suzuki</LastName>
            <ForeName>Takumi</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>College of Science, Department of Science, Ibaraki University, Ibaraki, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Fly (Austin)</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101470897</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1933-6934</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D029721">Drosophila Proteins</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004330" MajorTopicYN="N">Drosophila</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D029721" MajorTopicYN="Y">Drosophila Proteins</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D018507" MajorTopicYN="N">Gene Expression Regulation, Developmental</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D058953" MajorTopicYN="Y">Neural Stem Cells</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D055495" MajorTopicYN="N">Neurogenesis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000235" MajorTopicYN="N">genetics</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009474" MajorTopicYN="N">Neurons</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Drosophila</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neural development</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">temporal patterning</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>No potential conflict of interest was reported by the author(s).</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
          <Hour>11</Hour>
          <Minute>59</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35549651</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9116403</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/19336934.2022.2073158</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guillemot F.
Spatial and temporal specification of neural fates by transcription factor codes. Development. 2007;134(21):3771–3780.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17898002</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miyares RL, Lee T. Temporal control of Drosophila central nervous system development. Curr Opin Neurobiol. 2019;56:24–32.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30500514</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Suzuki T, Sato M. Inter-progenitor pool wiring: an evolutionarily conserved strategy that expands neural circuit diversity. Dev Biol. 2017;431(2):101–110.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28958816</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sato M, Yasugi T, Trush O. Temporal patterning of neurogenesis and neural wiring in the fly visual system. Neurosci Res. 2018;138:49-58.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yasugi T, Nishimura T. Temporal regulation of the generation of neuronal diversity in Drosophila. Dev Growth Differ. 2016;58(1):73–87.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26690868</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Isshiki T, Pearson B, Holbrook S, et al. Drosophila neuroblasts sequentially express transcription factors which specify the temporal identity of their neuronal progeny. Cell. 2001;106(4):511–521.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11525736</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Britton JS, Edgar BA. Environmental control of the cell cycle in Drosophila: nutrition activates mitotic and endoreplicative cells by distinct mechanisms. Development. 1998;125(11):2149–2158.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9570778</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Otsuki L, Brand AH. Quiescent neural stem cells for brain repair and regeneration: lessons from model systems. Trends Neurosci. 2020;43(4):213–226.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32209453</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baek M, Mann RS. Lineage and birth date specify motor neuron targeting and dendritic architecture in adult Drosophila. J Neurosci. 2009;29(21):6904–6916.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6665603</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19474317</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yasugi T, Umetsu D, Murakami S, et al. Drosophila optic lobe neuroblasts triggered by a wave of proneural gene expression that is negatively regulated by JAK/STAT. Development. 2008;135(8):1471–1480.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18339672</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sato M, Suzuki T, Nakai Y. Waves of differentiation in the fly visual system. Dev Biol. 2013;380(1):1–11.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23603492</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Suzuki T, Sato M. Neurogenesis and neuronal circuit formation in the Drosophila visual center. Dev Growth Differ. 2014;56(7):491–498.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25200311</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sato M, Yasugi T, Minami Y, et al. Notch-mediated lateral inhibition regulates proneural wave propagation when combined with EGF-mediated reaction diffusion. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2016;113(35):E5153–62.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5024646</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27535937</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li X, Erclik T, Bertet C, et al. Temporal patterning of Drosophila medulla neuroblasts controls neural fates. Nature. 2013;498(7455):456–462.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3701960</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23783517</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Suzuki T, Kaido M, Takayama R, et al. A temporal mechanism that produces neuronal diversity in the Drosophila visual center. Dev Biol. 2013;380(1):12–24.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23665475</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hasegawa E, Kitada Y, Kaido M, et al. Concentric zones, cell migration and neuronal circuits in the Drosophila visual center. Development. 2011;138(5):983–993.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21303851</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hasegawa E, Kaido M, Takayama R, et al. Brain-specific-homeobox is required for the specification of neuronal types in the Drosophila optic lobe. Dev Biol. 2013;377(1):90–99.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23454478</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Apitz H, Salecker I. A region-specific neurogenesis mode requires migratory progenitors in the Drosophila visual system. Nat Neurosci. 2015;18(1):46–55.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4338547</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25501037</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bayraktar OA, Doe CQ. Combinatorial temporal patterning in progenitors expands neural diversity. Nature. 2013;498(7455):449–455.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3941985</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23783519</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang YC, Yang JS, Johnston R, et al. Drosophila intermediate neural progenitors produce lineage-dependent related series of diverse neurons. Development. 2014;141(2):253–258.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3879808</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24306106</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Menzel P, McCorkindale AL, Stefanov SR, et al. Transcriptional dynamics of microRNAs and their targets during Drosophila neurogenesis. RNA Biol. 2019;16(1):69–81.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6380339</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30582411</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hormann N, Schilling T, Ali AH, et al. A combinatorial code of transcription factors specifies subtypes of visual motion-sensing neurons in Drosophila. Development. 2020;147(9):dev186296.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Davis FP, Nern A, Picard S, et al. A genetic, genomic, and computational resource for exploring neural circuit function. eLife. 2020;9. DOI:10.7554/eLife.50901.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7554/eLife.50901</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ozel MN, Simon F, Jafari S, et al. Neuronal diversity and convergence in a visual system developmental atlas. Nature. 2021;589(7840):88–95.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7790857</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33149298</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kurmangaliyev YZ, Yoo J, Valdes-Aleman J, et al. Transcriptional programs of circuit assembly in the Drosophila visual system. Neuron. 2020;108(6):1045–57 e6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33125872</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Simon F, Konstantinides N. Single-cell transcriptomics in the Drosophila visual system: advances and perspectives on cell identity regulation, connectivity, and neuronal diversity evolution. Dev Biol. 2021;479:107–122.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34375653</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhu H, Zhao SD, Ray A, et al. A comprehensive temporal patterning gene network in Drosophila medulla neuroblasts revealed by single-cell RNA sequencing. Nat Commun. 2022;13(1):1247.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8913700</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35273186</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Michki NS, Li Y, Sanjasaz K, et al. The molecular landscape of neural differentiation in the developing Drosophila brain revealed by targeted scRNA-seq and multi-informatic analysis. Cell Rep. 2021;35(4):109039.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8139287</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33909998</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Konstantinides N, Holguera I, Rossi AM, et al. A complete temporal transcription factor series in the fly visual system. Nature. 2022;604(7905):316–322.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9074256</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35388222</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kambadur R, Koizumi K, Stivers C, et al. Regulation of POU genes by castor and hunchback establishes layered compartments in the Drosophila  CNS. Genes Dev. 1998;12(2):246–260.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC316437</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9436984</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Broadus J, Skeath JB, Spana EP, et al. New neuroblast markers and the origin of the aCC/pCC neurons in the Drosophila central nervous system. Mech Dev. 1995;53(3):393–402.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8645605</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hartenstein V, Younossi-Hartenstein A, Lekven A. Delamination and division in the Drosophila neurectoderm: spatiotemporal pattern, cytoskeletal dynamics, and common control by neurogenic and segment polarity genes. Dev Biol. 1994;165(2):480–499.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7958415</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brody T, Odenwald WF. Programmed transformations in neuroblast gene expression during Drosophila CNS lineage development. Dev Biol. 2000;226(1):34–44.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10993672</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Touma JJ, Weckerle FF, Cleary MD. Drosophila polycomb complexes restrict neuroblast competence to generate motoneurons. Development. 2012;139(4):657–666.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22219354</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grosskortenhaus R, Robinson KJ, Doe CQ. Pdm and castor specify late-born motor neuron identity in the NB7-1 lineage. Genes Dev. 2006;20(18):2618–2627.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1578683</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16980589</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baumgardt M, Karlsson D, Terriente J, et al. Neuronal subtype specification within a lineage by opposing temporal feed-forward loops. Cell. 2009;139(5):969–982.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19945380</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kohwi M, Doe CQ. Temporal fate specification and neural progenitor competence during development. Nat Rev Neurosci. 2013;14(12):823–838.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3951856</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24400340</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baumgardt M, Karlsson D, Salmani BY, et al. Global programmed switch in neural daughter cell proliferation mode triggered by a temporal gene cascade. Dev Cell. 2014;30(2):192–208.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25073156</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grosskortenhaus R, Pearson BJ, Marusich A, et al. Regulation of temporal identity transitions in Drosophila neuroblasts. Dev Cell. 2005;8(2):193–202.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15691761</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kanai MI, Okabe M, Hiromi Y. seven-up controls switching of transcription factors that specify temporal identities of Drosophila neuroblasts. Dev Cell. 2005;8(2):203–213.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15691762</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kohwi M, Lupton JR, Lai SL, et al. Developmentally regulated subnuclear genome reorganization restricts neural progenitor competence in Drosophila. Cell. 2013;152(1–2):97–108.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3670710</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23332748</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Averbukh I, Lai SL, Doe CQ, et al. A repressor-decay timer for robust temporal patterning in embryonic Drosophila neuroblast lineages. eLife. 2018;7. DOI:10.7554/eLife.38631</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7554/eLife.38631</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van Steensel B, Henikoff S. Identification of in vivo DNA targets of chromatin proteins using tethered dam methyltransferase. Nat Biotechnol. 2000;18(4):424–428.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10748524</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brand AH, Perrimon N. Targeted gene expression as a means of altering cell fates and generating dominant phenotypes. Development. 1993;118(2):401–415.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8223268</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Southall TD, Gold KS, Egger B, et al. Cell-type-specific profiling of gene expression and chromatin binding without cell isolation: assaying RNA Pol II occupancy in neural stem cells. Dev Cell. 2013;26(1):101–112.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3714590</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23792147</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Southall TD, Davidson CM, Miller C, et al. Dedifferentiation of neurons precedes tumor formation in lola mutants. Dev Cell. 2014;28(6):685–696.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3978655</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24631403</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Otsuki L, Brand AH. Cell cycle heterogeneity directs the timing of neural stem cell activation from quiescence. Science. 2018;360(6384):99–102.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6538531</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29622651</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carl SH, Russell S. Common binding by redundant group B sox proteins is evolutionarily conserved in Drosophila. BMC Genomics. 2015;16(1):292.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4419465</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25887553</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Otsuki L, Brand AH. Dorsal-Ventral differences in neural stem cell quiescence are induced by p57(KIP2)/Dacapo. Dev Cell. 2019;49(2):293–300 e3.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6486397</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30905769</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ray A, Li X, Shan F. A notch-dependent transcriptional mechanism controls expression of temporal patterning factors in Drosophila medulla. bioRxiv. 2021. 2021.10.29.466469. DOI: 10.1101/2021.02.10.430499.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1101/2021.02.10.430499</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sen SQ, Chanchani S, Southall TD, et al. Neuroblast-specific open chromatin allows the temporal transcription factor, hunchback, to bind neuroblast-specific loci. eLife. 2019;8:e44036.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hakes AE, Otsuki L, Brand AH. A newly discovered neural stem cell population is generated by the optic lobe neuroepithelium during embryogenesis in Drosophila melanogaster. Development. 2018;145(18). DOI:10.1242/dev.166207.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1242/dev.166207</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bertet C, Li X, Erclik T, et al. Temporal patterning of neuroblasts controls notch-mediated cell survival through regulation of hid or reaper. Cell. 2014;158(5):1173–1186.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4153738</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25171415</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Suzuki T, Takayama R, Sato M. eyeless/Pax6 controls the production of glial cells in the visual center of Drosophila melanogaster. Dev Biol. 2016;409(2):343–353.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26670857</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Naidu VG, Zhang Y, Lowe S, et al. Temporal progression of Drosophila medulla neuroblasts generates the transcription factor combination to control T1 neuron morphogenesis. Dev Biol. 2020;464(1):35–44.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7377279</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32442418</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu C, Trush O, Han X, et al. Dscam1 establishes the columnar units through lineage-dependent repulsion between sister neurons in the fly brain. Nat Commun. 2020;11(1):4067.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7426427</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32792493</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmucker D, Clemens JC, Shu H, et al. Drosophila Dscam is an axon guidance receptor exhibiting extraordinary molecular diversity. Cell. 2000;101(6):671–684.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10892653</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wojtowicz WM, Wu W, Andre I, et al. A vast repertoire of Dscam binding specificities arises from modular interactions of variable Ig domains. Cell. 2007;130(6):1134–1145.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2707357</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17889655</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miura SK, Martins A, Zhang KX, et al. Probabilistic splicing of Dscam1 establishes identity at the level of single neurons. Cell. 2013;155(5):1166–1177.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3950301</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24267895</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Trush O, Liu C, Han X, et al. N-cadherin orchestrates self-organization of neurons within a columnar unit in the Drosophila medulla. J Neurosci. 2019;39(30):5861–5880.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6650991</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31175213</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yasugi T, Sugie A, Umetsu D, et al. Coordinated sequential action of EGFR and notch signaling pathways regulates proneural wave progression in the Drosophila optic lobe. Development. 2010;137(19):3193–3203.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20724446</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang M, Han X, Liu C, et al. Intracellular trafficking of notch orchestrates temporal dynamics of notch activity in the fly brain. Nat Commun. 2021;12(1):2083.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8027629</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33828096</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Han X, Wang M, Liu C, et al. DWnt4 and DWnt10 regulate morphogenesis and arrangement of columnar units via Fz2/PCP signaling in the Drosophila brain. Cell Rep. 2020;33(4):108305.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33113378</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang CP, Fu CC, Sugino K, et al. Transcriptomes of lineage-specific Drosophila neuroblasts profiled by genetic targeting and robotic sorting. Development. 2016;143(3):411–421.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4760311</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26700685</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu Z, Yang CP, Sugino K, et al. Opposing intrinsic temporal gradients guide neural stem cell production of varied neuronal fates. Science. 2015;350(6258):317–320.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26472907</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Genovese S, Clement R, Gaultier C, et al. Coopted temporal patterning governs cellular hierarchy, heterogeneity and metabolism in Drosophila neuroblast tumors. eLife. 2019;8:e50375.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang CP, Samuels TJ, Huang Y, et al. Imp and Syp RNA-binding proteins govern decommissioning of Drosophila neural stem cells. Development. 2017;144(19):3454–3464.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5665480</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28851709</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pahl MC, Doyle SE, Siegrist SE. E93 integrates neuroblast intrinsic state with developmental time to terminate MB neurogenesis via autophagy. Curr Biol. 2019;29(5):750–62 e3.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6428584</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30773368</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Homem CCF, Steinmann V, Burkard TR, et al. Ecdysone and mediator change energy metabolism to terminate proliferation in Drosophila neural stem cells. Cell. 2014;158(4):874–888.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25126791</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Narbonne-Reveau K, Lanet E, Dillard C, et al. Neural stem cell-encoded temporal patterning delineates an early window of malignant susceptibility in Drosophila. eLife. 2016;5. DOI:10.7554/eLife.13463.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7554/eLife.13463</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Syed MH, Mark B, Doe CQ. Steroid hormone induction of temporal gene expression in Drosophila brain neuroblasts generates neuronal and glial diversity. eLife. 2017;6:e26287.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maurange C, Cheng L, Gould AP. Temporal transcription factors and their targets schedule the end of neural proliferation in Drosophila. Cell. 2008;133(5):891–902.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18510932</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kao CF, Yu HH, He Y, et al. Hierarchical deployment of factors regulating temporal fate in a diverse neuronal lineage of the Drosophila central brain. Neuron. 2012;73(4):677–684.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3566789</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22365543</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhu S, Lin S, Kao CF, et al. Gradients of the Drosophila Chinmo BTB-zinc finger protein govern neuronal temporal identity. Cell. 2006;127(2):409–422.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17055440</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu YC, Chen CH, Mercer A, et al. Let-7-complex microRNAs regulate the temporal identity of Drosophila mushroom body neurons via chinmo. Dev Cell. 2012;23(1):202–209.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3401410</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22814608</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kucherenko MM, Barth J, Fiala A, et al. Steroid-induced microRNA let-7 acts as a spatio-temporal code for neuronal cell fate in the developing Drosophila brain. EMBO J. 2012;31(24):4511–4523.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3545287</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23160410</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ren Q, Yang CP, Liu Z, et al. Stem cell-intrinsic, seven-up-triggered temporal factor gradients diversify intermediate neural progenitors. Curr Biol. 2017;27(9):1303–1313.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28434858</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chai PC, Liu Z, Chia W, et al. Hedgehog signaling acts with the temporal cascade to promote neuroblast cell cycle exit. PLoS Biol. 2013;11(2):e1001494.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3582610</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23468593</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Seuntjens E, Nityanandam A, Miquelajauregui A, et al. Sip1 regulates sequential fate decisions by feedback signaling from postmitotic neurons to progenitors. Nat Neurosci. 2009;12(11):1373–1380.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19838179</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marshall OJ, Brand AH. Chromatin state changes during neural development revealed by in vivo cell-type specific profiling. Nat Commun. 2017;8(1):2271.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5741632</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29273756</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van den Ameele J, Brand AH. Neural stem cell temporal patterning and brain tumour growth rely on oxidative phosphorylation. eLife. 2019;8:e47887.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bello BC, Izergina N, Caussinus E, et al. Amplification of neural stem cell proliferation by intermediate progenitor cells in Drosophila brain development. Neural Dev. 2008;3(1):5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2265709</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18284664</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boone JQ, Doe CQ. Identification of Drosophila type II neuroblast lineages containing transit amplifying ganglion mother cells. Dev Neurobiol. 2008;68(9):1185–1195.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2804867</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18548484</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bowman SK, Rolland V, Betschinger J, et al. The tumor suppressors brat and numb regulate transit-amplifying neuroblast lineages in Drosophila. Dev Cell. 2008;14(4):535–546.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2988195</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18342578</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sullivan LF, Warren TL, Doe CQ. Temporal identity establishes columnar neuron morphology, connectivity, and function in a Drosophila navigation circuit. eLife. 2019;8:e43482.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eroglu E, Burkard TR, Jiang Y, et al. SWI/SNF complex prevents lineage reversion and induces temporal patterning in neural stem cells. Cell. 2014;156(6):1259–1273.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24630726</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tang JLY, Hakes AE, Krautz R, et al. NanoDam identifies novel temporal transcription factors conserved between the Drosophila central brain and visual system. bioRxiv. 2021;2021.06.07.447332.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
