<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35545835</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>12</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2045-7634</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>11</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Cancer medicine</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Cancer Med</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Ursolic acid silences CYP19A1/aromatase to suppress gastric cancer growth.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/cam4.4536</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Gastric cancer (GCa) is a malignancy with few effective treatments. Ursolic acid (UA), a bioactive triterpenoid enriched in Hedyotis diffusa Willd, known to suppress GCa without identified target. CYP19A1 (cytochrome P450 family 19A1; also known as aromatase, Ar) was correlated to GCa prognosis. Relatedly, Ar silencers, which halt the expression of Ar exhibited anti-GCa effects in experimental models, are currently being investigated.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHOD" NlmCategory="METHODS">The docking simulation score of UA was compared with Ar inhibitors, e.g., letrozole, exemestane, in Ar protein crystallization. Hedyotis diffusa Willd ethanol extract, UA, or 5-fluracil were applied onto AGS, SC-M1, MKN45 GCa cells for cancer inhibition tests. Immunoblot for measuring gene expressions upon drug treatments, or gene knockdown/overexpression. Treatments were also applied in a MKN45 implantation tumor model. A web-based GCa cohort for Ar expression association with prognosis was performed.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULT" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The ethanol extracts of Hedyotis diffusa Willd, enrich with UA, exhibited cytotoxic activity against GCa cells. Molecular docking simulations with the 3D Ar structure revealed an excellent fitting score for UA. UA increase cytotoxic, and suppressed colony, in addition to its Ar silencing capacity. Moreover, UA synergistically facilitated 5-FU, (a standard GCa treatment) regimen in vitro. Consistent with those results, adding estradiol did not reverse the cancer-suppressing effects of UA, which confirmed UA acts as an Ar silencer. Furthermore, UA exhibited tumor-suppressing index (TSI) score of 90% over a 6-week treatment term when used for single dosing in xenograft tumor model. In the clinical setting, Ar expression was found to be higher in GCa tumors than normal parental tissue from the TCGA (The Cancer Genome Atlas) cohort, while high Ar expression associated with poor prognosis. Together, the results indicate UA could be used to treat GCa by silencing Ar expression in GCa. Hedyotis diffusa Willd ethanol extract could be an functional food supplements.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Authors. Cancer Medicine published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ma</LastName>
            <ForeName>Wen-Lung</ForeName>
            <Initials>WL</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5571-3302</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Graduate Institute of Biomedical Sciences, Center for Tumor Biology, Department of Pharmacology, Chinese Medicine Research Center, Drug Development Center, and Graduate Institute of Chinese Medicine, Graduate Institute of Integrated Medicine, School of Medicine, China Medical University, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medical Research, Chinese Medicine Research and Development Center, and Department of Obstetrics &amp; Gynecology, China Medical University Hospital, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Nursing, Department of Biotechnology, College of Medical and Health Science, Asia University, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ning</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medical Research, Chinese Medicine Research and Development Center, and Department of Obstetrics &amp; Gynecology, China Medical University Hospital, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yingchun</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medical Research, Chinese Medicine Research and Development Center, and Department of Obstetrics &amp; Gynecology, China Medical University Hospital, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Su</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yu-Ting</ForeName>
            <Initials>YT</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Graduate Institute of Biomedical Sciences, Center for Tumor Biology, Department of Pharmacology, Chinese Medicine Research Center, Drug Development Center, and Graduate Institute of Chinese Medicine, Graduate Institute of Integrated Medicine, School of Medicine, China Medical University, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medical Research, Chinese Medicine Research and Development Center, and Department of Obstetrics &amp; Gynecology, China Medical University Hospital, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Guan-Yu</ForeName>
            <Initials>GY</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2773-8748</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medical Research, Chinese Medicine Research and Development Center, and Department of Obstetrics &amp; Gynecology, China Medical University Hospital, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Cheng</LastName>
            <ForeName>Wei-Chung</ForeName>
            <Initials>WC</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medical Research, Chinese Medicine Research and Development Center, and Department of Obstetrics &amp; Gynecology, China Medical University Hospital, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yang-Chang</ForeName>
            <Initials>YC</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Graduate Institute of Biomedical Sciences, Center for Tumor Biology, Department of Pharmacology, Chinese Medicine Research Center, Drug Development Center, and Graduate Institute of Chinese Medicine, Graduate Institute of Integrated Medicine, School of Medicine, China Medical University, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medical Research, Chinese Medicine Research and Development Center, and Department of Obstetrics &amp; Gynecology, China Medical University Hospital, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Nursing, Department of Biotechnology, College of Medical and Health Science, Asia University, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Li</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ching-Chia</ForeName>
            <Initials>CC</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Graduate Institute of Clinical Medicine, College of Medicine, Kaohsiung Medical University, Kaohsiung, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Urology, Kaohsiung Medical University Hospital, Kaohsiung, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Urology, School of Medicine, College of Medicine, Kaohsiung Medical University, Kaohsiung, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Wei-Chun</ForeName>
            <Initials>WC</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medical Research, Chinese Medicine Research and Development Center, and Department of Obstetrics &amp; Gynecology, China Medical University Hospital, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Nursing, Department of Biotechnology, College of Medical and Health Science, Asia University, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology, Asia University Hospital, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Juan-Cheng</ForeName>
            <Initials>JC</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Graduate Institute of Biomedical Sciences, Center for Tumor Biology, Department of Pharmacology, Chinese Medicine Research Center, Drug Development Center, and Graduate Institute of Chinese Medicine, Graduate Institute of Integrated Medicine, School of Medicine, China Medical University, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Chinese Medicine, China Medical University, Taichung, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Cancer Med</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101595310</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2045-7634</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">
Hedyotis diffusa Willd
</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ar silencer</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CYP19A1/aromatase</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">gastric cancer</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ursolic acid</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>1</Hour>
          <Minute>12</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35545835</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cam4.4536</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gonzalez CA, Sala N, Rokkas T. Gastric cancer: epidemiologic aspects. Helicobacter. 2013;18(Suppl 1):34-38.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bray F, Ferlay J, Soerjomataram I, et al. GLOBOCAN estimates of incidence and mortality worldwide for 36 cancers in 185 countries. CA Cancer J Clin. 2018;68(2018):394-424.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ferlay J, Colombet M, Soerjomataram I, et al. GLOBOCAN sources and methods. Int J Cancer. 2018;144(2019):1941-1953.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Charalampakis N, Economopoulou P, Kotsantis I, et al. Medical management of gastric cancer: a 2017 update. Cancer Med. 2018;7:123-133.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Quadri HS, Smaglo BG, Morales SJ, et al. Gastric adenocarcinoma: a multimodal approach. Front Surg. 2017;4:42.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Orditura M, Galizia G, Sforza V, et al. Treatment of gastric cancer. World J Gastroenterol. 2014;20:1635-1649.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wagner AD, Syn NL, Moehler M, et al. Chemotherapy for advanced gastric cancer. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2017;8:CD004064.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coburn N, Cosby R, Klein L, et al. Staging and surgical approaches in gastric cancer: a systematic review. Cancer Treat Rev. 2018;63:104-115.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu ZY, Tang JN, Xie HX, et al. 5-Fluorouracil chemotherapy of gastric cancer generates residual cells with properties of cancer stem cells. Int J Biol Sci. 2015;11:284-294.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Charalampakis N, Economopoulou P, Kotsantis I. Medical management of gastric cancer: a 2017 update. Cancer Med. 2018;7(1):123-133.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roberto Persiani SR, Biondi A, et al. Combined modality treatment options for improving the outcome of locally advanced gastric cancer. Suppl Tumori. 2007;2:41-74.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cetin B, Ozet A. HER2/neu as target in gastric adenocarcinoma. Translational Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2016;1:59.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matsuoka T, Yashiro M. Recent advances in the HER2 targeted therapy of gastric cancer. World J Clinical Cases. 2015;3:42-51.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sartore-Bianchi A, Trusolino L, Martino C, et al. Dual-targeted therapy with trastuzumab and lapatinib in treatment-refractory, KRAS codon 12/13 wild-type, HER2-positive metastatic colorectal cancer (HERACLES): a proof-of-concept, multicentre, open-label, phase 2 trial. Lancet Oncol. 2016;17:738-746.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yan HHN, Siu HC, Law S, et al. A comprehensive human gastric cancer organoid biobank captures tumor subtype heterogeneity and enables therapeutic screening. Cell Stem Cell. 2018;23:882-897 e11.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kobayashi H, Yoshida S, Shirasawa N, Maeda K, Naito A. Expression and localization of aromatase in human gastric mucosa: immunohistochemical study using biopsy materials. Histochem Cell Biol. 2019;151:21-28.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Melby JC, Azar ST, Delaney M, Holbrook M, Griffing GT, Johnston JO. 19-Nor-corticosteroids in genetic hypertension. Effects of inhibitors of 11 beta, 18, 19-hydroxylase activity. J Steroid Biochem Mol Biol. 1993;45:13-18.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang Y, Li S, Zhu L, et al. Letrozole improves the sensitivity of breast cancer cells overexpressing aromatase to cisplatin via down-regulation of FEN1. Clin Transl Oncol. 2019;21:1026-1033.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chang WC, Huang SF, Lee YM, et al. Cholesterol import and steroidogenesis are biosignatures for gastric cancer patient survival. Oncotarget. 2017;8:692-704.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang JC, Chang N, Wu DC, et al. Preclinical evaluation of exemestane as a novel chemotherapy for gastric cancer. J Cell Mol Med. 2019;23:7417-7426.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morris GM, Huey R, Lindstrom W, et al. AutoDock4 and AutoDockTools4: automated docking with selective receptor flexibility. J Comput Chem. 2009;30:2785-2791.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghosh D, Lo J, Morton D, et al. Novel aromatase inhibitors by structure-guided design. J Med Chem. 2012;55:8464-8476.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sanner MF. Python: a programming language for software integration and development. J Mol Graph Model. 1999;17:57-61.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chung WM, Ho YP, Chang WC, et al. Increase paclitaxel sensitivity to better suppress serous epithelial ovarian cancer via ablating androgen receptor/aryl hydrocarbon receptor-ABCG2 axis. Cancers. 2019;11.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chou TC. Drug combination studies and their synergy quantification using the Chou-Talalay method. Cancer Res. 2010;70:440-446.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chou TC, Talalay P. Quantitative analysis of dose-effect relationships: the combined effects of multiple drugs or enzyme inhibitors. Adv Enzyme Regul. 1984;22:27-55.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chang WC, Wang HC, Cheng WC, et al. LDLR-mediated lipidome-transcriptome reprogramming in cisplatin insensitivity. Endocr Relat Cancer. 2020;27:81-95.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yadav SS, Li J, Stockert JA, et al. Combination effect of therapies targeting the PI3K- and AR-signaling pathways in prostate cancer. Oncotarget. 2016;7:76181-76196.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chung WM, Chang WC, Chen L, et al. MicroRNA-21 promotes the ovarian teratocarcinoma PA1 cell line by sustaining cancer stem/progenitor populations in vitro. Stem Cell Res Ther. 2013;4:88.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen L, Ma WL, Cheng WC, et al. Targeting lipid droplet lysophosphatidylcholine for cisplatin chemotherapy. J Cell Mol Med. 2020;24:7187-7200.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Seidlitz T, Chen YT, Uhlemann H, et al. Mouse models of human gastric cancer subtypes with stomach-specific CreERT2-mediated pathway alterations. Gastroenterology 157. 2019;1599-1614 e2.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen Z, Liu Q, Zhu Z, et al. Ursolic acid protects against proliferation and inflammatory response in LPS-treated gastric tumour model and cells by inhibiting NLRP3 in flammasome activation. Cancer Manag Res. 2020;12:8413-8424.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Damia G, D'Incalci M. Genetic instability influences drug response in cancer cells. Curr Drug Targets. 2010;11:1317-1324.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang YC, Wei MC, Chiu HF, Huang TC. Development and validation of a modified ultrasound-assisted extraction method and a HPLC method for the quantitative determination of two triterpenic acids in Hedyotis diffusa. Nat Prod Commun. 2013;8:1683-1686.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee HZ, Bau DT, Kuo CL, Tsai RY, Chen YC, Chang YH. Clarification of the phenotypic characteristics and anti-tumor activity of Hedyotis diffusa. Am J Chin Med. 2011;39:201-213.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li Q, Wang X, Shen A, et al. Hedyotis diffusa Willd overcomes 5-fluorouracil resistance in human colorectal cancer HCT-8/5-FU cells by downregulating the expression of P-glycoprotein and ATP-binding casette subfamily G member 2. Exp Ther Med. 2015;10:1845-1850.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gnoatto SC, Dassonville-Klimpt A, Da Nascimento S, et al. Evaluation of ursolic acid isolated from Ilex paraguariensis and derivatives on aromatase inhibition. Eur J Med Chem. 2008;43:1865-1877.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu PL, Zeng C, Zhou YF, Yin L, Yu XL, Xue Q. Farnesoid X receptor agonist GW4064 inhibits aromatase and ERbeta expression in human endometriotic stromal cells. Reprod Sci. 2019;26:1111-1120.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kelicen Ugur P, Lule S, Cincioglu M, Pekiner C, Gursoy-Ozdemir Y. Megestrol acetate inhibits the expression of cytoplasmic aromatase through nuclear C/EBPbeta in reperfusion injury-induced ischemic rat hippocampus. Eur J Pharmacol. 2011;654:217-225.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brueggemeier RW, Su B, Darby MV, Sugimoto Y. Selective regulation of aromatase expression for drug discovery. J Steroid Biochem Mol Biol. 2010;118:207-210.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gao R, Zhao L, Liu X, et al. Methylseleninic acid is a novel suppressor of aromatase expression. J Endocrinol. 2012;212:199-205.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen R, He J, Tong X, Tang L, Liu M. The Hedyotis diffusa Willd. (Rubiaceae): a review on phytochemistry, pharmacology, quality control and pharmacokinetics. Molecules. 2016;21.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hung KF, Hsu CP, Chiang JH, et al. Complementary Chinese herbal medicine therapy improves survival of patients with gastric cancer in Taiwan: a nationwide retrospective matched-cohort study. J Ethnopharmacol. 2017;199:168-174.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
