<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35545195</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>14</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1469-0691</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>08</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Clinical microbiology and infection : the official publication of the European Society of Clinical Microbiology and Infectious Diseases</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Clin Microbiol Infect</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>First-generation Oral Antivirals Against SARS-CoV-2.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1198-743X(22)00223-3</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.cmi.2022.04.015</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Oral drugs against SARS-COV-2 have received emergency use authorization for the treatment of mild-to-moderate COVID-19 in nonhospitalized patients who are at high risk for clinical progression.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To provide a clinical practice overview of first-generation oral antiviral agents against SARS-CoV-2.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="SOURCES" NlmCategory="METHODS">References for this review were identified through searches of PubMed, Google Scholar, bioRxiv, medRxiv, regulatory drug agencies, and pharmaceutical companies' websites up to 16 February 2022.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONTENT" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Molnupiravir and nirmatrelvir/ritonavir have been authorized for use in nonhospitalized individuals with mild-to-moderate COVID-19 who are at high risk for progression. In clinical trials, molnupiravir reduced the frequency of hospitalization or death by 3% (relative risk reduction 30%), and nirmatrelvir/ritonavir by 6% (relative risk reduction 89%). Their use in clinical practice requires early administration, review of drug-drug interactions (nirmatrelvir/ritonavir), considerations of embryo-fetal toxicity (molnupiravir), and compliance with ingestion of a high number of pills. Knowledge gaps include the efficacy of these agents in vaccinated, hospitalized, or immunosuppressed individuals with prolonged SARS-CoV-2 persistence.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="IMPLICATIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">First-generation oral antivirals represent progress in therapeutics against SARS-CoV-2, but also pose new challenges in clinical practice. Further advances in the development of new drugs are required.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022 European Society of Clinical Microbiology and Infectious Diseases. Published by Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sendi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Parham</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute for Infectious Diseases, University of Bern, Bern, Switzerland. Electronic address: parham.sendi@ifik.unibe.ch.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Razonable</LastName>
            <ForeName>Raymund R</ForeName>
            <Initials>RR</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Public Health, Infectious Diseases, and Occupational Medicine, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, MN, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nelson</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sandra B</ForeName>
            <Initials>SB</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Infectious Diseases, Massachusetts General Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Soriano</LastName>
            <ForeName>Alex</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Infectious Diseases, Hospital Clínic, IDIBAPS, Barcelona, University of Barcelona, Barcelona, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gandhi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Rajesh Tim</ForeName>
            <Initials>RT</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Infectious Diseases, Massachusetts General Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>08</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Clin Microbiol Infect</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9516420</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1198-743X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Antivirals</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">COVID-19</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Coronavirus</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Molnupiravir</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nirmatrelvir</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SARS-CoV-2</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>19</Hour>
          <Minute>24</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35545195</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9080050</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cmi.2022.04.015</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">S1198-743X(22)00223-3</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vegivinti C.T.R., Evanson K.W., Lyons H., Akosman I., Barrett A., Hardy N., Kane B., Keesari P.R., Pulakurthi Y.S., Sheffels E., Balasubramanian P., Chibbar R., Chittajallu S., Cowie K., Karon J., Siegel L., Tarchand R., Zinn C., Gupta N., Kallmes K.M., Saravu K., Touchette J. Efficacy of antiviral therapies for COVID-19: a systematic review of randomized controlled trials. BMC Infect Dis. 2022;22(1):107.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8802260</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35100985</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kreuzberger N., Hirsch C., Chai K.L., Tomlinson E., Khosravi Z., Popp M., Neidhardt M., Piechotta V., Salomon S., Valk S.J., Monsef I., Schmaderer C., Wood E.M., So-Osman C., Roberts D.J., McQuilten Z., Estcourt L.J., Skoetz N. SARS-CoV-2-neutralising monoclonal antibodies for treatment of COVID-19. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2021;9(9)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>V'Kovski P., Kratzel A., Steiner S., Stalder H., Thiel V. Coronavirus biology and replication: implications for SARS-CoV-2. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2021;19(3):155–170.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7592455</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33116300</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Owen D.R., Allerton C.M.N., Anderson A.S., Aschenbrenner L., Avery M., Berritt S., Boras B., Cardin R.D., Carlo A., Coffman K.J., Dantonio A., Di L., Eng H., Ferre R., Gajiwala K.S., Gibson S.A., Greasley S.E., Hurst B.L., Kadar E.P., Kalgutkar A.S., Lee J.C., Lee J., Liu W., Mason S.W., Noell S., Novak J.J., Obach R.S., Ogilvie K., Patel N.C., Pettersson M., Rai D.K., Reese M.R., Sammons M.F., Sathish J.G., Singh R.S.P., Steppan C.M., Stewart A.E., Tuttle J.B., Updyke L., Verhoest P.R., Wei L., Yang Q., Zhu Y. An oral SARS-CoV-2 M(pro) inhibitor clinical candidate for the treatment of COVID-19. Science. 2021;374(6575):1586–1593.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34726479</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Malone B., Campbell E.A. Molnupiravir: coding for catastrophe. Nat Struct Mol Biol. 2021;28(9):706–708.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34518697</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pillaiyar T., Manickam M., Namasivayam V., Hayashi Y., Jung S.H. An Overview of Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome-Coronavirus (SARS-CoV) 3CL Protease Inhibitors: Peptidomimetics and Small Molecule Chemotherapy. J Med Chem. 2016;59(14):6595–6628.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7075650</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26878082</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Toots M., Yoon J.J., Cox R.M., Hart M., Sticher Z.M., Makhsous N., Plesker R., Barrena A.H., Reddy P.G., Mitchell D.G., Shean R.C., Bluemling G.R., Kolykhalov A.A., Greninger A.L., Natchus M.G., Painter G.R., Plemper R.K. Characterization of orally efficacious influenza drug with high resistance barrier in ferrets and human airway epithelia. Sci Transl Med. 2019;11(515)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kabinger F., Stiller C., Schmitzová J., Dienemann C., Kokic G., Hillen H.S., Höbartner C., Cramer P. Mechanism of molnupiravir-induced SARS-CoV-2 mutagenesis. Nat Struct Mol Biol. 2021;28(9):740–746.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8437801</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34381216</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hammond J., Leister-Tebbe H., Gardner A., Abreu P., Bao W., Wisemandle W., Baniecki M., Hendrick V.M., Damle B., Simón-Campos A., Pypstra R., Rusnak J.M. Oral Nirmatrelvir for High-Risk, Nonhospitalized Adults with Covid-19. New England Journal of Medicine. 2022</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pfizer, Analyst and Investor Call to Discuss the First COVID-19 Comprehensive Approach: Pfizer-BioNTech Vaccine and Pfizer’s Novel Oral Antiviral Treatment Candidate - December 17, 2021. &lt;https://s28.q4cdn.com/781576035/files/doc_presentation/2021/12/17/COVID-Analyst-and-Investor-Call-deck_FINAL.pdf&gt;, 2021 (accessed March 28.2022).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fischer W.A., 2nd, Eron J.J., Jr., Holman W., Cohen M.S., Fang L., Szewczyk L.J., Sheahan T.P., Baric R., Mollan K.R., Wolfe C.R., Duke E.R., Azizad M.M., Borroto-Esoda K., Wohl D.A., Coombs R.W., James Loftis A., Alabanza P., Lipansky F., Painter W.P. A phase 2a clinical trial of molnupiravir in patients with COVID-19 shows accelerated SARS-CoV-2 RNA clearance and elimination of infectious virus. Sci Transl Med. 2022;14(628)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jayk Bernal A., Gomes da Silva M.M., Musungaie D.B., Kovalchuk E., Gonzalez A., Delos Reyes V., Martín-Quirós A., Caraco Y., Williams-Diaz A., Brown M.L., Du J., Pedley A., Assaid C., Strizki J., Grobler J.A., Shamsuddin H.H., Tipping R., Wan H., Paschke A., Butterton J.R., Johnson M.G., De Anda C. Molnupiravir for Oral Treatment of Covid-19 in Nonhospitalized Patients. N Engl J Med. 2021</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Modes M.E., Directo M.P., Melgar M., Johnson L.R., Yang H., Chaudhary P., Bartolini S., Kho N., Noble P.W., Isonaka S., Chen P. Clinical Characteristics and Outcomes Among Adults Hospitalized with Laboratory-Confirmed SARS-CoV-2 Infection During Periods of B.1.617.2 (Delta) and B.1.1.529 (Omicron) Variant Predominance - One Hospital, California, July 15-September 23, 2021, and December 21, 2021-January 27, 2022. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep. 2022;71(6):217–223.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8830624</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35143466</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morrison Ponce D., Kitchen L.K., Devlin J.J. Cost-Benefit Analysis of Novel Antiviral Ritonavir in the Active Duty U.S. Military Population. Mil Med. 2022</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dickerman B.A., Gerlovin H., Madenci A.L., Kurgansky K.E., Ferolito B.R., Figueroa Muñiz M.J., Gagnon D.R., Gaziano J.M., Cho K., Casas J.P., Hernán M.A. Comparative Effectiveness of BNT162b2 and mRNA-1273 Vaccines in U.S. Veterans. N Engl J Med. 2022;386(2):105–115.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8693691</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34942066</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grupper A., Rabinowich L., Schwartz D., Schwartz I.F., Ben-Yehoyada M., Shashar M., Katchman E., Halperin T., Turner D., Goykhman Y., Shibolet O., Levy S., Houri I., Baruch R., Katchman H. Reduced humoral response to mRNA SARS-CoV-2 BNT162b2 vaccine in kidney transplant recipients without prior exposure to the virus. Am J Transplant. 2021;21(8):2719–2726.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8250589</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33866672</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rabinowich L., Grupper A., Baruch R., Ben-Yehoyada M., Halperin T., Turner D., Katchman E., Levi S., Houri I., Lubezky N., Shibolet O., Katchman H. Low immunogenicity to SARS-CoV-2 vaccination among liver transplant recipients. J Hepatol. 2021;75(2):435–438.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8058047</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33892006</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Funakoshi Y., Yakushijin K., Ohji G., Hojo W., Sakai H., Watanabe M., Saeki M., Hirakawa Y., Sakai R., Matsumoto S., Mizutani Y., Kitao A., Miyata Y., Saito Y., Kawamoto S., Yamamoto K., Ito M., Nishimura M., Imamura Y., Kiyota N., Matsuoka H., Mori Y., Minami H. Limited increase in antibody titers following mRNA SARS-CoV-2 vaccination for more than 3 years after final dose of anti-CD20 antibody. Int J Hematol. 2022;115(1):7–10.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8723797</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34981433</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bierle D.M., Ganesh R., Tulledge-Scheitel S., Hanson S.N., Arndt L.L., Wilker C.G., Razonable R.R. Monoclonal Antibody Treatment of Breakthrough COVID-19 in Fully Vaccinated Individuals with High-Risk Comorbidities. J Infect Dis. 2022;225(4):598–602.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8767864</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34791298</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tepasse P.R., Hafezi W., Lutz M., Kühn J., Wilms C., Wiewrodt R., Sackarnd J., Keller M., Schmidt H.H., Vollenberg R. Persisting SARS-CoV-2 viraemia after rituximab therapy: two cases with fatal outcome and a review of the literature. Br J Haematol. 2020;190(2):185–188.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7300950</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32557623</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sepulcri C., Dentone C., Mikulska M., Bruzzone B., Lai A., Fenoglio D., Bozzano F., Bergna A., Parodi A., Altosole T., Delfino E., Bartalucci G., Orsi A., Di Biagio A., Zehender G., Ballerini F., Bonora S., Sette A., De Palma R., Silvestri G., De Maria A., Bassetti M. The Longest Persistence of Viable SARS-CoV-2 With Recurrence of Viremia and Relapsing Symptomatic COVID-19 in an Immunocompromised Patient-A Case Study. Open Forum Infect Dis. 2021;8(11):ofab217.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8135455</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34796242</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Choi B., Choudhary M.C., Regan J., Sparks J.A., Padera R.F., Qiu X., Solomon I.H., Kuo H.H., Boucau J., Bowman K., Adhikari U.D., Winkler M.L., Mueller A.A., Hsu T.Y., Desjardins M., Baden L.R., Chan B.T., Walker B.D., Lichterfeld M., Brigl M., Kwon D.S., Kanjilal S., Richardson E.T., Jonsson A.H., Alter G., Barczak A.K., Hanage W.P., Yu X.G., Gaiha G.D., Seaman M.S., Cernadas M., Li J.Z. Persistence and Evolution of SARS-CoV-2 in an Immunocompromised Host. N Engl J Med. 2020;383(23):2291–2293.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7673303</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33176080</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baang J.H., Smith C., Mirabelli C., Valesano A.L., Manthei D.M., Bachman M.A., Wobus C.E., Adams M., Washer L., Martin E.T., Lauring A.S. Prolonged Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome Coronavirus 2 Replication in an Immunocompromised Patient. J Infect Dis. 2021;223(1):23–27.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7797758</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33089317</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aydillo T., Gonzalez-Reiche A.S., Aslam S., van de Guchte A., Khan Z., Obla A., Dutta J., van Bakel H., Aberg J., García-Sastre A., Shah G., Hohl T., Papanicolaou G., Perales M.A., Sepkowitz K., Babady N.E., Kamboj M. Shedding of Viable SARS-CoV-2 after Immunosuppressive Therapy for Cancer. N Engl J Med. 2020;383(26):2586–2588.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7722690</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33259154</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Avanzato V.A., Matson M.J., Seifert S.N., Pryce R., Williamson B.N., Anzick S.L., Barbian K., Judson S.D., Fischer E.R., Martens C., Bowden T.A., de Wit E., Riedo F.X., Munster V.J. Case Study: Prolonged Infectious SARS-CoV-2 Shedding from an Asymptomatic Immunocompromised Individual with Cancer. Cell. 2020;183(7):1901–1912. e9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7640888</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33248470</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Waters M.D., Warren S., Hughes C., Lewis P., Zhang F. Human genetic risk of treatment with antiviral nucleoside analog drugs that induce lethal mutagenesis: The special case of molnupiravir. Environ Mol Mutagen. 2022;63(1):37–63.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35023215</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhou S., Hill C.S., Sarkar S., Tse L.V., Woodburn B.M.D., Schinazi R.F., Sheahan T.P., Baric R.S., Heise M.T., Swanstrom R. β-d-N4-hydroxycytidine Inhibits SARS-CoV-2 Through Lethal Mutagenesis But Is Also Mutagenic To Mammalian Cells. J Infect Dis. 2021;224(3):415–419.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8136050</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33961695</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Githaka J.M. Molnupiravir Does Not Induce Mutagenesis in Host Lung Cells during SARS-CoV-2 Treatment. Bioinform Biol Insights. 2022;16</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>EMA, European Medicines Agency: Assessment Report: Use of molnupiravir for COVID-19. &lt;https://www.ema.europa.eu/en/documents/referral/lagevrio-also-known-molnupiravir-mk-4482-covid-19-article-53-procedure-assessment-report_en.pdf&gt;, 2022 (accessed January, 27.2022).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marzolini C., Kuritzkes D., Marra F., Boyle A., Gibbons S., Flexner C., Pozniak A., Boffito M., Waters L., Burger D., Back D., Khoo S. Prescribing Nirmatrelvir–Ritonavir: How to Recognize and Manage Drug–Drug Interactions. Ann Intern Med. 2022 March 1;2022</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Andrews N., Stowe J., Kirsebom F., Toffa S., Rickeard T., Gallagher E., Gower C., Kall M., Groves N., O'Connell A.M., Simons D., Blomquist P.B., Zaidi A., Nash S., Iwani Binti Abdul Aziz N., Thelwall S., Dabrera G., Myers R., Amirthalingam G., Gharbia S., Barrett J.C., Elson R., Ladhani S.N., Ferguson N., Zambon M., Campbell C.N.J., Brown K., Hopkins S., Chand M., Ramsay M., Lopez Bernal J. Covid-19 Vaccine Effectiveness against the Omicron (B.1.1.529) Variant. N Engl J Med. 2022</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pulliam J.R.C., van Schalkwyk C., Govender N., von Gottberg A., Cohen C., Groome M.J., Dushoff J., Mlisana K., Moultrie H. Increased risk of SARS-CoV-2 reinfection associated with emergence of Omicron in South Africa. Science. 2022</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Merck, FACT SHEET FOR HEALTHCARE PROVIDERS: EMERGENCY USE AUTHORIZATION FOR MOLNUPIRAVIR. &lt;https://www.fda.gov/media/155054/download&gt;, 2021 (accessed January 28, 22.2022).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oakes M.C., Kernberg A.S., Carter E.B., Foeller M.E., Palanisamy A., Raghuraman N., Kelly J.C. Pregnancy as a risk factor for severe coronavirus disease 2019 using standardized clinical criteria. Am J Obstet Gynecol MFM. 2021;3(3):100319.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7826101</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33493707</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>The American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists COVID-19 FAQs for Obstetrician-Gynecologists. Obstetrics. 2022 https://www.acog.org/clinical-information/physician-faqs/covid-19-faqs-for-ob-gyns-obstetrics</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>IMPAACT, IMPAACT 2032: Pharmacokinetics and Safety of Remdesivir for Treatment of COVID-19 in Pregnant and Non-Pregnant Women in the United States. &lt;Pharmacokinetics and Safety of Remdesivir for Treatment of COVID-19 in Pregnant and Non-Pregnant Women in the United States&gt;, 2021 (accessed March 30.2022).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Agostini M.L., Pruijssers A.J., Chappell J.D., Gribble J., Lu X., Andres E.L., Bluemling G.R., Lockwood M.A., Sheahan T.P., Sims A.C., Natchus M.G., Saindane M., Kolykhalov A.A., Painter G.R., Baric R.S., Denison M.R. Small-Molecule Antiviral β-d-N (4)-Hydroxycytidine Inhibits a Proofreading-Intact Coronavirus with a High Genetic Barrier to Resistance. J Virol. 2019;93(24)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sheahan T.P., Sims A.C., Zhou S., Graham R.L., Pruijssers A.J., Agostini M.L., Leist S.R., Schäfer A., Dinnon K.H., 3rd, Stevens L.J., Chappell J.D., Lu X., Hughes T.M., George A.S., Hill C.S., Montgomery S.A., Brown A.J., Bluemling G.R., Natchus M.G., Saindane M., Kolykhalov A.A., Painter G., Harcourt J., Tamin A., Thornburg N.J., Swanstrom R., Denison M.R., Baric R.S. An orally bioavailable broad-spectrum antiviral inhibits SARS-CoV-2 in human airway epithelial cell cultures and multiple coronaviruses in mice. Sci Transl Med. 2020;12(541)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pfizer, FACT SHEET FOR HEALTHCARE PROVIDERS: EMERGENCY USE AUTHORIZATION FOR PAXLOVID. &lt;https://www.fda.gov/media/155050/download&gt;, 2021 (accessed January 28, 2022.).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li P., Wang Y., Lavrijsen M., Lamers M.M., de Vries A.C., Rottier R.J., Bruno M.J., Peppelenbosch M.P., Haagmans B.L., Pan Q. SARS-CoV-2 Omicron variant is highly sensitive to molnupiravir, nirmatrelvir, and the combination. Cell Res. 2022:1–3.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8666617</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34903854</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vangeel L., Chiu W., De Jonghe S., Maes P., Slechten B., Raymenants J., André E., Leyssen P., Neyts J., Jochmans D. Remdesivir, Molnupiravir and Nirmatrelvir remain active against SARS-CoV-2 Omicron and other variants of concern. Antiviral Res. 2022:105252.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8785409</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35085683</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kawaoka Y., Uraki R., Kiso M., Iida S., Imai M., Takashita E., Kuroda M., Halfmann P., Loeber S., Maemura T., Yamayoshi S., Fujisaki S., Wang Z., Ito M., Ujie M., Iwatsuki-Horimoto K., Furusawa Y., Wright R., Chong Z., Ozono S., Yasuhara A., Ueki H., Sakai Y., Li R., Liu Y., Larson D., Koga M., Tsutsumi T., Adachi E., Saito M., Yamamoto S., Matsubara S., Hagihara M., Mitamura K., Sato T., Hojo M., Hattori S.I., Maeda K., Okuda M., Murakami J., Duong C., Godbole S., Douek D., Watanabe S., Ohmagari N., Yotsuyanagi H., Diamond M., Hasegawa H., Mitsuya H., Suzuki T. Characterization and antiviral susceptibility of SARS-CoV-2 Omicron/BA.2. Res Sq. 2022</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tao K., Tzou P.L., Nouhin J., Gupta R.K., de Oliveira T., Kosakovsky Pond S.L., Fera D., Shafer R.W. The biological and clinical significance of emerging SARS-CoV-2 variants. Nat Rev Genet. 2021;22(12):757–773.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8447121</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34535792</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cully M. A tale of two antiviral targets - and the COVID-19 drugs that bind them. Nat Rev Drug Discov. 2022;21(1):3–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34857884</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gilead, Press Release: FDA Approves Veklury® (Remdesivir) for the Treatment of Non-Hospitalized Patients at High Risk for COVID-19 Disease Progression. &lt;https://www.gilead.com/news-and-press/press-room/press-releases/2022/1/fda-approves-veklury-remdesivir-for-the-treatment-of-nonhospitalized-patients-at-high-risk-for-covid19-disease-progression&gt;, 2022 (accessed January 28, 2022.2022).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lo M.K., Shrivastava-Ranjan P., Chatterjee P., Flint M., Beadle J.R., Valiaeva N., Murphy J., Schooley R.T., Hostetler K.Y., Montgomery J.M., Spiropoulou C.F. Broad-Spectrum In Vitro Antiviral Activity of ODBG-P-RVn: An Orally-Available, Lipid-Modified Monophosphate Prodrug of Remdesivir Parent Nucleoside (GS-441524) Microbiol Spectr. 2021;9(3)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cox R.M., Wolf J.D., Lieber C.M., Sourimant J., Lin M.J., Babusis D., DuPont V., Chan J., Barrett K.T., Lye D., Kalla R., Chun K., Mackman R.L., Ye C., Cihlar T., Martinez-Sobrido L., Greninger A.L., Bilello J.P., Plemper R.K. Oral prodrug of remdesivir parent GS-441524 is efficacious against SARS-CoV-2 in ferrets. Nat Commun. 2021;12(1):6415.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8571282</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34741049</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McKimm-Breschkin J.L., Hay A.J., Cao B., Cox R.J., Dunning J., Moen A.C., Olson D., Pizzorno A., Hayden F.G. COVID-19, Influenza and RSV: Surveillance-informed prevention and treatment - Meeting report from an isirv-WHO virtual conference. Antiviral Res. 2022;197:105227.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8684224</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34933044</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>SHIONOGI, Briefing Session on COVID-19 Therapeutic Drug S-217622, February 7, 2022, Transcription. &lt;https://www.shionogi.com/content/dam/shionogi/global/investors/ir-library/presentation/2021/e20220207_script.pdf&gt;, 2022 (accessed February 16.2022).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>SHIONOGI, Top-Line Results of the Phase 2a Part of the Phase 2/3 Trial of S-217622, the COVID-19 Therapeutic Drug, February 7, 2022, Presentation. &lt;https://www.shionogi.com/content/dam/shionogi/global/investors/ir-library/presentation/2021/e20220207_3.pdf&gt;, 2022 (accessed February 16.2022).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>P. Biosciences, INFORMATION ON PBI-0451: PBI-0451, an Investigational Coronaviral Protease Inhibitor. &lt;https://www.pardesbio.com/pipeline/&gt;, 2022 (accessed January 28, 2022.2022).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>L.-J. Jiang, EDP-235, A Potential Oral, Once-Daily Antiviral Treatment and Preventative for COVID-19, International Society for Influenza and Other Respiratory Virus Diseases (ISIRV), WHO, Virtual, 2019.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>E. PHARMACEUTICALS, Press Release: ENANTA PHARMACEUTICALS PRESENTS NEW DATA FOR EDP-235, ITS LEAD ORAL PROTEASE INHIBITOR DESIGNED FOR THE TREATMENT OF COVID-19, AT THE ISIRV–WHO VIRTUAL CONFERENCE 2021. &lt;https://www.enanta.com/investors/news-releases/press-release/2021/Enanta-Pharmaceuticals-Presents-New-Data-for-EDP-235-its-Lead-Oral-Protease-Inhibitor-Designed-for-the-Treatment-of-COVID-19-at-the-ISIRVWHO-Virtual-Conference-2021/default.aspx&gt;, 2021 (accessed January 28, 2022.2022).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sendi P., Battegay M. Orale Virostatika gegen SARS-CoV-2. Swiss Med Forum. 2022 doi: 10.4414/smf.2022.09108. (in press)</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4414/smf.2022.09108</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>NIH, The COVID-19 Treatment Guidelines Panel's Statement on Potential Drug-Drug Interactions Between Ritonavir-Boosted Nirmatrelvir (Paxlovid) and Concomitant Medications. &lt;https://www.covid19treatmentguidelines.nih.gov/therapies/statement-on-paxlovid-drug-drug-interactions/&gt;, 2022 (accessed February 16.2022).</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
