<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35543437</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>11</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-2761</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>11</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of fish diseases</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Fish Dis</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Transcriptome analysis of turbot (Scophthalmus maximus) head kidney and liver reveals immune mechanism in response to Vibrio anguillarum infection.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jfd.13628</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The diseases triggered by Vibrio anguillarum infection have created huge economic losses to the turbot (Scophthalmus maximus) farming industry. However, the immune mechanism of turbot to V. anguillarum infection has not been deeply investigated. To better understand the immune response of turbot to V. anguillarum infection, transcriptome analysis of the head kidney and liver of turbot was performed. A total of 15,948 and 11,494 differentially expressed genes (DEGs) were obtained from the turbot head kidney and liver, respectively. Transcriptome analysis revealed that the head kidney and liver of turbot have some differences in the gene ontology and Kyoto Encyclopedia of Genes and Genomes enrichment analysis of the DEGs for the different functions of these two organs. Although there are many uncertain factors in this immune process, such as the occurrence of alternative splicing (AS) events and the differences in the protein structure of the DEGs, the NFκB signalling pathway, MKK-dependent AP-1 activation, JAK-STAT signalling pathway, the signal transmission of MHC Ⅰ and a series of DEGs including HSP90 driving NLRP3 to produce inflammatory factors (IL-1β, IL-8, TNFα, etc.) were possible important immune response pathways for turbot to V. anguillarum infection. Overall, our research has conducted a preliminary exploration of the immune mechanism of turbot in response to V. anguillarum infection.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Song</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yuting</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>College of Marine Life Sciences, Ocean University of China, Qingdao, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Evolution &amp; Marine Biodiversity, Ocean University of China, Qingdao, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Dong</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xianzhi</ForeName>
            <Initials>X</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Biophysis, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Guobin</ForeName>
            <Initials>G</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4239-2503</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>College of Marine Life Sciences, Ocean University of China, Qingdao, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Evolution &amp; Marine Biodiversity, Ocean University of China, Qingdao, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Fish Dis</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9881188</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0140-7775</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">
Vibrio anguillarum
</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">immune mechanism</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">transcriptome analysis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">turbot</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
          <Hour>8</Hour>
          <Minute>13</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35543437</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jfd.13628</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Causey, D., Pohl, M., Stead, D., Martin, S., Secombes, C., &amp; Macqueen, D. (2018). High-throughput proteomic profiling of the fish liver following bacterial infection. BMC Genomics, 19, 719-735. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12864-018-5092-0</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cerna, D., Li, H. Y., Flaherty, S., Takebe, N., Coleman, N., &amp; Yoo, S. (2012). Inhibition of nicotinamide phosphoribosyltransferase (NAMPT) activity by small molecule GMX1778 regulates reactive oxygen species (ROS)-mediated cytotoxicity in a p53- and nicotinic acid phosphoribosyltransferase1 (NAPRT1)-dependent manner. Journal of Biological Chemistry, 287, 22408-22417. https://doi.org/10.1074/jbc.M112.357301</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chang, Y. H., Hsieh, S. H., Chen, M. C., &amp; Lin, W. W. (2002). Lymphotoxin beta receptor induces interleukin 8 gene expression via NF-kappaB and AP-1 activation. Experimental Cell Research, 278, 166-174.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Christoph, T., &amp; Robert, T. (2019). MHC I chaperone complexes shaping immunity. Current Opinion in Immunology, 58, 9-15. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coi.2019.01.001</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Gassart, A., &amp; Martinon, F. (2015). Pyroptosis: Caspase-11 unlocks the gates of death. Immunity, 43, 835-837.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Floen, M., Forred, B., Bloom, E., &amp; Vitiello, P. (2014). Thioredoxin-1 redox signaling regulates cell survival in response to hyperoxia. Free Radical Biology and Medicine, 75, 167-177. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.freeradbiomed.2014.07.023</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Frans, I., Michiels, C., Bossier, P., Willems, K., Lievens, B., &amp; Rediers, H. (2011). Vibrio anguillarum as a fish pathogen: Virulence factors, diagnosis and prevention. Journal of Fish Diseases, 34, 643-661. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2761.2011.01279.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>García, M., Gil, J., Ventoso, I., Guerra, S., Domingo, E., Rivas, C., &amp; Esteban, M. (2006). Impact of protein kinase PKR in cell biology: From antiviral to antiproliferative action. Microbiology and Molecular Biology Reviews, 70, 1032-1060. https://doi.org/10.1128/MMBR.00027-06</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>García, M., Meurs, E., &amp; Esteban, M. (2007). The dsRNA protein kinase PKR: Virus and cell control. Biochimie, 89, 799-811. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.biochi.2007.03.001</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Geven, E., &amp; Klaren, P. (2017). The teleost head kidney: Integrating thyroid and immune signaling. Developmental and Comparative Immunology, 66, 73-83.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grisez, L., Chair, M., Sorgeloos, P., &amp; Ollevier, F. (1996). Mode of infection and spread of Vibrio anguillarum in turbot Scophthalmus maximus larvae after oral challenge through live feed. Diseases of Aquatic Organisms, 26, 181-187. https://doi.org/10.3354/dao026181</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim, Y., Park, J., Kim, S., Kim, M., Kang, M. G., Kwak, C., Kang, M., Kim, B., Rhee, H. W., &amp; Kim, N. (2018). PKR senses nuclear and mitochondrial signals by interacting with endogenous double-stranded RNAs. Molecular Cell, 71, 1051-1063. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molcel.2018.07.029</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li, C. L., Chen, S. S., Song, J. Y., Liu, H. Y., Gu, W., Ai, H. X., Zhao, B., &amp; Zhang, S. Q. (2013). Molecular cloning and characterization of TNFSF14 (LIGHT) and its receptor TNFRSF14 (HVEM) in guinea pig (Cavia porcellus). Gene, 526, 374-384. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gene.2013.05.031</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li, L., Wataha, J. C., Cate, C., Zhang, H., DiJulio, D., &amp; Chung, W. (2012). Ni(II) alters the NFκB signaling pathway in monocytic cells. Journal of Biomedical Materials Research, 100B, 934-939. https://doi.org/10.1002/jbm.b.32655</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li, Y., Wu, J., Li, D., Huang, A., Bu, G., Meng, F., Kong, F., Cao, X., Han, X., Pan, X., Fan, W., Yang, S., Zeng, X., &amp; Du, X. (2019). Transcriptome analysis of spleen reveals the signal transduction of toll-like receptors after Aeromonas hydrophila infection in Schizothorax prenanti. Fish &amp; Shellfish Immunology, 84, 816-824. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fsi.2018.10.064</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Margulies, D. H., Jiang, J. S., &amp; Natarajan, K. (2020). Structural and dynamic studies of TAPBPR and Tapasin reveal the mechanism of peptide loading of MHC-I molecules. Current Opinion in Immunology, 64, 71-79. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coi.2020.04.004</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Medzhitov, R., &amp; Janeway, C. A. (1997). Innate immunity: Impact on the adaptive immune response. Current Opinion in Immunology, 9, 4-9. https://doi.org/10.1016/S0952-7915(97)80152-5</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muñoz-Flores, C., Astuya, A., Roa, F. J., Romero, A., Acosta, J., Sánchez, O., &amp; Toledo, J. R. (2018). Activation of membrane-bound and soluble Toll-like Receptors 5 in Salmo salar depends on the MyD88 signalling pathway. Biochimica Et Biophysica Acta (BBA) - General Subjects, 1862, 2215-2222. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bbagen.2018.07.008</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nemeth, E., Baird, A. W., &amp; O’Farrelly, C. (2009). Microanatomy of the liver immune system. Seminars in Immunopathology, 31, 333-343. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00281-009-0173-4</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oisson, J. C., Jöborn, A., Westerdahl, A., Blomberg, L., Kjelleberg, S., &amp; Conway, P. L. (1996). Is the turbot, Scophthalmus maximus (L.), intestine a portal of entry for the fish pathogen Vibrio anguillarum. Journal of Fish Diseases, 19, 225-234. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2761.1996.tb00129.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Park, S., Liu, G. Q., Liu, Q., &amp; Zhou, Y. (2018). Swine influenza virus induces RIPK1/DRP1-mediated interleukin-1 beta production. Viruses-Basel, 10, 419-436. https://doi.org/10.3390/v10080419</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Qi, L. J., Chen, Y. D., Shi, K. P., Ma, H., Wei, S., &amp; Sha, Z. X. (2021). Combining of transcriptomic and proteomic data to mine immune-related genes and proteins in the liver of Cynoglossus semilaevis challenged with Vibrio anguillarum. Comparative Biochemistry and Physiology D-Genomics &amp; Proteomics, 39, 100864. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cbd.2021.100864</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rajavel, T., Packiyaraj, P., Suryanarayanan, V., Singh, S. K., Ruckmani, K., &amp; Pandima, D. K. (2018). β-Sitosterol targets Trx/Trx1 reductase to induce apoptosis in A549 cells via ROS mediated mitochondrial dysregulation and p53 activation. Scientific Reports, 8, 2071. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-018-20311-6</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raquel, F. G., Marcos, P. P., &amp; María Dolores, G. G. (2021). An analysis of production factors for Galician-farmed turbot: From boom to stagnation. Aquaculture Economics &amp; Management, 25, 320-338.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rashmi, S., Arafat, H. M., Jai, K., Kumar, M., Kumar, U. K., &amp; Shibnath, M. (2017). Chronic fluoride exposure exacerbates headkidney pathology and causes immune commotion in Clarias gariepinus. Aquatic Toxicology, 192, 30-39. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.aquatox.2017.09.006</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rauta, P. R., Nayak, B., &amp; Das, S. (2012). Immune system and immune responses in fish and their role in comparative immunity study: A model for higher organisms. Immunology Letters, 148, 23-33. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.imlet.2012.08.003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rodriguez-Garcia, A., Hevia, D., Mayo, J. C., Gonzalez-Menendez, P., Coppo, L., Lu, J., Holmgren, A., &amp; Sainz, R. (2017). Thioredoxin 1 modulates apoptosis induced by bioactive compounds in prostate cancer cells. Redox Biology, 12, 634-647. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.redox.2017.03.025</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saber, S., &amp; El-Kader, E. A. (2021). Novel complementary coloprotective effects of metformin and MCC950 by modulating HSP90/NLRP3 interaction and inducing autophagy in rats. Inflammopharmacology, 29, 237-251.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sato, Y., Koshizuka, T., Ishibashi, K., Hashimoto, K., Ishioka, K., Ikuta, K., Yokota, S., Fujii, N., &amp; Suzutani, T. (2017). Involvement of herpes simplex virus type 1 UL13 protein kinase in induction of SOCS genes, the negative regulators of cytokine signaling. Microbiology and Immunology, 61, 159-167. https://doi.org/10.1111/1348-0421.12483</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shaikh, R. B., Santee, S., Granger, S. W., Butrovich, K., Cheung, T., Kronenberg, M., Cheroutre, H., &amp; Ware, C. F. (2001). Constitutive expression of LIGHT on T cells leads to lymphocyte activation, inflammation, and tissue destruction. Journal of Immunology, 167, 6330-6337. https://doi.org/10.4049/jimmunol.167.11.6330</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Song, L. F., Dong, X. Z., &amp; Hu, G. B. (2021). Transcriptome analysis of red sea bream (Pagrus major) head kidney and spleen infected by Vibrio anguillarum. Aquaculture Reports, 21, 100789. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.aqrep.2021.100789</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Song, Y. T., Song, L. F., Soomro, M. A., Dong, X. Z., &amp; Hu, G. B. (2021). Transcriptome analysis reveals immune-related differentially expressed genes in the hepatopancreas and gills of Penaeus vannamei after Vibrio anguillarum infection. Aquaculture Research, 52, 4303-4316.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Svensson, M., Pfeifer, J., Stockinger, B., &amp; Wick, M. J. (1997). Bacterial antigen delivery systems: Phagocytic processing of bacterial antigens for MHC-I and MHC-II presentation to T cells. Behring Institute Mitteilungen, 98, 197-211.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tort, L., Balasch, J. C., &amp; Mackenzie, S. (2003). Fish immune system. A crossroads between innate and adaptive responses. Inmunología, 22, 277-286.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weber, B., Chen, C., &amp; Milton, D. L. (2010). Colonization of fish skin is vital for Vibrio anguillarum to cause disease. Environmental Microbiology Reports, 2, 133-139. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1758-2229.2009.00120.x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xue, L., Yu, D. D., Fan, Y., Liu, Y. P., &amp; Yao, Y. G. (2019). Evolutionary selection on MDA5 and LGP2 in the chicken preserves antiviral competence in the absence of RIG-I. Journal of Genetics and Genomics, 46, 499-503. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jgg.2019.10.001</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xue, T., Liu, Y. P., Cao, M., Tian, M. Y., Zhang, L., Wang, B. B., Liu, X. L., &amp; Li, C. (2021). Revealing new landscape of turbot (Scophthalmus maximus) spleen infected with Aeromonas salmonicida through immune related circRNA-miRNA-mRNA axis. Biology-Basel, 10, 626-643. https://doi.org/10.3390/biology10070626</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhao, Y., Jiang, S., Zhang, J., Guan, X. L., Sun, B. G., &amp; Sun, L. (2021). A virulent Bacillus cereus strain from deep-sea cold seep induces pyroptosis in a manner that involves NLRP3 inflammasome, JNK pathway, and lysosomal rupture. Virulence, 12, 1362-1376.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhong, B., Yang, Y., Li, S., Wang, Y. Y., Li, Y., Diao, F. C., Lei, C. Q., He, X., Zhang, L., Tien, P., &amp; Shu, H. B. (2008). The adaptor protein MITA links virus-sensing receptors to IRF3 transcription factor activation. Immunity, 29, 538-550. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.immuni.2008.09.003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhou, X. J., Wu, F. L., Jiang, L. L., Huang, L. F., &amp; Li, G. H. (2016). Vasoactive intestinal peptide promotes immune escape of MKN45 cells by inhibiting antigen-presenting molecules of dendritic cells in vitro. International Journal of Peptide Research and Therapeutics, 22, 341-353. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10989-016-9513-0</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhu, W. T., Li, J. X., Zhang, R., Cai, Y. X., Wang, C. W., Qi, S. S., Chen, S., Liang, X. Z., Qi, N., &amp; Hou, F. J. (2019). TRAF3IP3 mediates the recruitment of TRAF3 to MAVS for antiviral innate immunity. EMBO Journal, 38, e102075.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
