<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35550066</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>13</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1097-4199</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>07</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Neuron</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Neuron</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>5-hydroxytryptamine produced by enteric serotonergic neurons initiates colorectal cancer stem cell self-renewal and tumorigenesis.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0896-6273(22)00369-5</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.neuron.2022.04.024</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Colorectal cancer stem cells (CSCs) contribute to colorectal tumorigenesis and metastasis. Colorectal CSCs reside within specialized niches and harbor self-renewal and differentiation capacities. However, the niche regulations of CSCs remain unclear. Here, we show that intestinal nerve cells are required for CSC self-renewal and colorectal tumorigenesis. Enteric serotonergic neurons produce 5-hydroxytryptamine (5-HT) to function as a modulator of CSC self-renewal. 5-HT receptors HTR1B/1D/1F are highly expressed in colorectal CSCs and engage with 5-HT to initiate Wnt/β-catenin signaling. Mechanistically, colorectal cancer (CRC)-enriched microbiota metabolite isovalerate suppresses the enrichment of the NuRD complex onto Tph2 promoter to initiate Tph2 expression, leading to 5-HT production. 5-HT signaling is correlated with CRC severity. Blocking 5-HT signaling in mice not only inhibits the self-renewal of colorectal CSCs but also displays therapeutic efficacy against CRC tumors. Our findings reveal a cross talk between intestinal neurons and tumor cells that serves as an additional layer for CSC regulation.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022 Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Pingping</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>CAS Key Laboratory of Infection and Immunity, CAS Center for Excellence in Biomacromolecules, Institute of Biophysics, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing 100101, China; School of Life Sciences, Zhengzhou University, Zhengzhou 450001, China; State Key Laboratory of Esophageal Cancer Prevention &amp; Treatment, Zhengzhou University, Zhengzhou, Henan 450052, China. Electronic address: zhup@zzu.edu.cn.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Tiankun</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>CAS Key Laboratory of Infection and Immunity, CAS Center for Excellence in Biomacromolecules, Institute of Biophysics, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing 100101, China; School of Life Sciences, Zhengzhou University, Zhengzhou 450001, China; University of Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing 100049, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Zhenzhen</ForeName>
            <Initials>Z</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Life Sciences, Zhengzhou University, Zhengzhou 450001, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Liu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Benyu</ForeName>
            <Initials>B</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>CAS Key Laboratory of Infection and Immunity, CAS Center for Excellence in Biomacromolecules, Institute of Biophysics, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing 100101, China; Research Center of Basic Medicine, Academy of Medical Sciences, Zhengzhou University, Zhengzhou, Henan 450001, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Fan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Dongdong</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>CAS Key Laboratory of RNA Biology, Institute of Biophysics, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing 100101, China; Core Facility for Protein Research, Institute of Biophysics, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing 100101, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Li</LastName>
            <ForeName>Chong</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Core Facility for Protein Research, Institute of Biophysics, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing 100101, China; Zhongke Jianlan (Beijing) Institute of Medicine, Beijing 101407, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jiayi</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>CAS Key Laboratory of Infection and Immunity, CAS Center for Excellence in Biomacromolecules, Institute of Biophysics, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing 100101, China; School of Medicine, Nankai University, 94 Weijin Road, Tianjin 300071, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>He</LastName>
            <ForeName>Luyun</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>CAS Key Laboratory of Infection and Immunity, CAS Center for Excellence in Biomacromolecules, Institute of Biophysics, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing 100101, China; State Key Laboratory of Esophageal Cancer Prevention &amp; Treatment, Zhengzhou University, Zhengzhou, Henan 450052, China; Department of Pathophysiology, School of Basic Medical Sciences, Zhengzhou University, Zhengzhou 450001, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xiaoxiao</ForeName>
            <Initials>X</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>CAS Key Laboratory of RNA Biology, Institute of Biophysics, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing 100101, China; Core Facility for Protein Research, Institute of Biophysics, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing 100101, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Du</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ying</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>CAS Key Laboratory of Infection and Immunity, CAS Center for Excellence in Biomacromolecules, Institute of Biophysics, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing 100101, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tian</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yong</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>University of Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing 100049, China; CAS Key Laboratory of RNA Biology, Institute of Biophysics, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing 100101, China. Electronic address: ytian@ibp.ac.cn.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Fan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Zusen</ForeName>
            <Initials>Z</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>CAS Key Laboratory of Infection and Immunity, CAS Center for Excellence in Biomacromolecules, Institute of Biophysics, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing 100101, China; University of Chinese Academy of Sciences, Beijing 100049, China. Electronic address: fanz@moon.ibp.ac.cn.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>07</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Neuron</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8809320</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0896-6273</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">5-HT</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">colorectal cancer stem cell</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">enteric serotonergic neuron</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">gut microbiota</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">self-renewal</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>Declaration of interests The authors declare no competing interests.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
          <Hour>12</Hour>
          <Minute>22</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35550066</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuron.2022.04.024</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">S0896-6273(22)00369-5</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
