<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35551673</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>24</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1469-7793</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>12</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>The Journal of physiology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Physiol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Increased contribution of KCa channels to muscle contraction induced vascular and blood flow responses in sedentary and exercise trained ZFDM rats.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1113/JP282981</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>In resistance arteries, endothelium-dependent hyperpolarization (EDH)-mediated vasodilatation is depressed in diabetes. We hypothesized that downregulation of KCa channel derived EDH reduces exercise-induced vasodilatation and blood flow redistribution in diabetes. To test this hypothesis, we evaluated vascular function in response to hindlimb muscle contraction, and the contribution of KCa channels in anaesthetised ZFDM, metabolic disease rats with type 2 diabetes. We also tested whether exercise training ameliorated the vascular response. Using in vivo microangiography, the hindlimb vasculature was visualized before and after rhythmic muscle contraction (0.5 s tetanus every 3 s, 20 times) evoked by sciatic nerve stimulation (40 Hz). Femoral blood flow of the contracting hindlimb was simultaneously measured by an ultrasonic flowmeter. The contribution of KCa channels was investigated in the presence and absence of apamin and charybdotoxin. We found that vascular and blood flow responses to muscle contraction were significantly impaired at the level of small artery segments in ZFDM fa/fa rats compared to its lean control fa/+ rats. The contribution of KCa channels was also smaller in fa/fa than in fa/+ rats. Low-intensity exercise training for 12 weeks in fa/fa rats demonstrated minor changes in the vascular and blood flow response to muscle contraction. However, the KCa-derived component in the response to muscle contraction was much greater in exercise trained than in sedentary fa/fa rats. These data suggest that exercise training increases the contribution of KCa channels among endothelium-dependent vasodilatory mechanisms to maintain vascular and blood flow responses to muscle contraction in this metabolic disease rat model. KEY POINTS: Microvascular dysfunction in type 2 diabetes impairs blood flow redistribution during exercise and limits the performance of skeletal muscle and may cause early fatigability. Endothelium-dependent hyperpolarization (EDH), which mediates vasodilatation in resistance arteries, is known to be depressed in animals with diabetes. Here, we report that low-intensity exercise training in ZFDM rats increased the KCa channel-derived component in the vasodilator responses to muscle contraction compared to that in sedentary rats, partly as a result of the increase in KCNN3 expression. These results suggest that low-intensity exercise training improves blood flow redistribution in contracting skeletal muscle in metabolic disease with diabetes via upregulation of EDH.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Authors. The Journal of Physiology © 2022 The Physiological Society.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sonobe</LastName>
            <ForeName>Takashi</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3589-0405</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cardiac Physiology, National Cerebral and Cardiovascular Center Research Institute, Suita, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tsuchimochi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hirotsugu</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7591-2520</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cardiac Physiology, National Cerebral and Cardiovascular Center Research Institute, Suita, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Maeda</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hisashi</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cardiac Physiology, National Cerebral and Cardiovascular Center Research Institute, Suita, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Pearson</LastName>
            <ForeName>James T</ForeName>
            <Initials>JT</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3318-5406</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cardiac Physiology, National Cerebral and Cardiovascular Center Research Institute, Suita, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Victoria Heart Institute and Monash Biomedicine Discovery Institute, Department of Physiology, Monash University, Melbourne, VIC, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Physiol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0266262</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0022-3751</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">calcium-activated potassium channels</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">endothelial dysfunction</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">exercise training</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">microangiography</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">type 2 diabetes</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
          <Hour>13</Hour>
          <Minute>45</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35551673</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1113/JP282981</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Albright, A., Franz, M., Hornsby, G., Kriska, A., Marrero, D., Ullrich, I., &amp; Verity, L. S. (2000). American college of sports medicine position stand. exercise and type 2 diabetes. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 32, 1345-1360.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Anrep, G. V., &amp; von Saalfeld, E. (1935). The blood flow through the skeletal muscle in relation to its contraction. Journal of Physiology, 85(3), 375-399.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brayden, J. E., &amp; Nelson, M. T. (1992). Regulation of arterial tone by activation of calcium-dependent potassium channels. Science, 256(5056), 532-535.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brooks, H. L., &amp; Lindsey, M. L. (2018). Guidelines for authors and reviewers on antibody use in physiology studies. American Journal of Physiology Heart and Circulatory Physiology, 314(4), H724-H732.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bryner, R. W., Ullrich, I. H., Sauers, J., Donley, D., Hornsby, G., Kolar, M., &amp; Yeater, R. (1999). Effects of resistance vs. aerobic training combined with an 800 calorie liquid diet on lean body mass and resting metabolic rate. Journal of the American College of Nutrition, 18(2), 115-121.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brøndum, E., Kold-Petersen, H., Simonsen, U., &amp; Aalkjaer, C. (2010). NS309 restores EDHF-type relaxation in mesenteric small arteries from type 2 diabetic ZDF rats. British Journal of Pharmacology, 159(1), 154-165.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Burnham, M. P., Johnson, I. T., &amp; Weston, A. H. (2006). Impaired small-conductance Ca2+-activated K+ channel-dependent EDHF responses in Type II diabetic ZDF rats. British Journal of Pharmacology, 148(4), 434-441.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Campbell, W. B., Gebremedhin, D., Pratt, P. F., &amp; Harder, D. R. (1996). Identification of epoxyeicosatrienoic acids as endothelium-derived hyperpolarizing factors. Circulation Research, 78(3), 415-423.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen, Y. C., Inagaki, T., Fujii, Y., Schwenke, D. O., Tsuchimochi, H., Edgley, A. J., Umetani, K., Zhang, Y., Kelly, D. J., Yoshimoto, M., Nagai, H., Evans, R. G., Kuwahira, I., Shirai, M., &amp; Pearson, J. T. (2016). Chronic intermittent hypoxia accelerates coronary microcirculatory dysfunction in insulin-resistant Goto-Kakizaki rats. American Journal of Physiology Regulatory, Integrative and Comparative Physiology, 311(2), R426-R439.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clifford, P. S. (2011). Local control of blood flow. Advances in Physiology Education, 35(1), 5-15.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Climent, B., Moreno, L., Martínez, P., Contreras, C., Sánchez, A., Pérez-Vizcaíno, F., García-Sacristán, A., Rivera, L., &amp; Prieto, D. (2014). Upregulation of SK3 and IK1 channels contributes to the enhanced endothelial calcium signaling and the preserved coronary relaxation in obese Zucker rats. Plos One, 9(10), e109432.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Vriese, A. S., Verbeuren, T. J., Van de Voorde, J., Lameire, N. H., &amp; Vanhoutte, P. M. (2000). Endothelial dysfunction in diabetes. British Journal of Pharmacology, 130(5), 963-974.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Domeier, T. L., &amp; Segal, S. S. (2007). Electromechanical and pharmacomechanical signalling pathways for conducted vasodilatation along endothelium of hamster feed arteries. Journal of Physiology, 579(1), 175-186.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Doughty, J. M., Plane, F., &amp; Langton, P. D. (1999). Charybdotoxin and apamin block EDHF in rat mesenteric artery if selectively applied to the endothelium. American Journal of Physiology, 276, H1107-H1112.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Edwards, G., Dora, K. A., Gardener, M. J., Garland, C. J., &amp; Weston, A. H. (1998). K+ is an endothelium-derived hyperpolarizing factor in rat arteries. Nature, 396(6708), 269-272.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eringa, E. C., Stehouwer, C. D., Roos, M. H., Westerhof, N., &amp; Sipkema, P. (2007). Selective resistance to vasoactive effects of insulin in muscle resistance arteries of obese Zucker (fa/fa) rats. American Journal of Physiology Endocrinology and Metabolism, 293(5), E1134-E1139.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Favero, M., Jiang, D. J., Chiamulera, C., Cangiano, A., &amp; Fumagalli, G. F. (2008). Expression of small-conductance calcium-activated potassium channels (SK3) in skeletal muscle: Regulation by muscle activity. Journal of Physiology, 586(19), 4763-4774.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fisslthaler, B., Popp, R., Kiss, L., Potente, M., Harder, D. R., Fleming I, &amp; Busse, R. (1999). Cytochrome P450 2C is an EDHF synthase in coronary arteries. Nature, 401(6752), 493-497.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Forbes, J. M., &amp; Cooper, M. E. (2013). Mechanisms of diabetic complications. Physiological Reviews, 93(1), 137-188.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Frisbee, J. C. (2003). Impaired skeletal muscle perfusion in obese Zucker rats. American Journal of Physiology Regulatory, Integrative and Comparative Physiology, 285(5), R1124-R1134.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fukao, M., Hattori, Y., Kanno, M., Sakuma I, &amp; Kitabatake, A. (1997). Alterations in endothelium-dependent hyperpolarization and relaxation in mesenteric arteries from streptozotocin-induced diabetic rats. British Journal of Pharmacology, 121(7), 1383-1391.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Félétou, M. (2016). Endothelium-dependent hyperpolarization and endothelial dysfunction. Journal of Cardiovascular Pharmacology, 67(5), 373-387.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gao, F., &amp; Wang, D. H. (2010a). Hypotension induced by activation of the transient receptor potential vanilloid 4 channels: role of Ca2+-activated K+ channels and sensory nerves. Journal of Hypertension, 28(1), 102-110.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gao, F., &amp; Wang, D. H. (2010b). Impairment in function and expression of transient receptor potential vanilloid type 4 in Dahl salt-sensitive rats: Significance and mechanism. Hypertension, 55(4), 1018-1025.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garland, C. J., &amp; Dora, K. A. (2017). EDH: Endothelium-dependent hyperpolarization and microvascular signalling. Acta Physiologica (Oxford, England), 219(1), 152-161.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garland, C. J., Hiley, C. R., &amp; Dora, K. A. (2011). EDHF: Spreading the influence of the endothelium. British Journal of Pharmacology, 164(3), 839-852.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gokina, N. I., Bonev, A. D., Gokin, A. P., &amp; Goloman, G. (2013). Role of impaired endothelial cell Ca(2+) signaling in uteroplacental vascular dysfunction during diabetic rat pregnancy. American Journal of Physiology Heart and Circulatory Physiology, 304(7), H935-H945.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goto, K., &amp; Kitazono, T. (2019). Endothelium-dependent hyperpolarization (EDH) in diabetes: Mechanistic insights and therapeutic implications. International Journal of Molecular Sciences, 20(15), 3737.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goto, K., Ohtsubo, T., &amp; Kitazono, T. (2018). Endothelium-dependent hyperpolarization (EDH) in hypertension: The role of endothelial ion channels. International Journal of Molecular Sciences, 19(1), 315.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guzik, T. J., Mussa, S., Gastaldi, D., Sadowski, J., Ratnatunga, C., Pillai, R., &amp; Channon, K. M. (2002). Mechanisms of increased vascular superoxide production in human diabetes mellitus: role of NAD(P)H oxidase and endothelial nitric oxide synthase. Circulation, 105(14), 1656-1662.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hald, B. O., Jacobsen, J. C., Braunstein, T. H., Inoue, R., Ito, Y., Sørensen, P. G., Holstein-Rathlou, N. H., &amp; Jensen, L. J. (2012). BKCa and KV channels limit conducted vasomotor responses in rat mesenteric terminal arterioles. Pflugers Archiv: European Journal of Physiology, 463(2), 279-295.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hamann, J. J., Buckwalter, J. B., Clifford, P. S., &amp; Shoemaker, J. K. (2004). Is the blood flow response to a single contraction determined by work performed? Journal of Applied Physiology (Bethesda, Md : 1985), 96(6), 2146-2152.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Honig, C. R., Odoroff, C. L., &amp; Frierson, J. L. (1980). Capillary recruitment in exercise: Rate, extent, uniformity, and relation to blood flow. American Journal of Physiology, 238, H31-42.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Høydal, M. A., Wisløff, U., Kemi, O. J., &amp; Ellingsen, O. (2007). Running speed and maximal oxygen uptake in rats and mice: Practical implications for exercise training. European Journal of Cardiovascular Prevention and Rehabilitation, 14(6), 753-760.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kindig, C. A., Sexton, W. L., Fedde, M. R., &amp; Poole, D. C. (1998). Skeletal muscle microcirculatory structure and hemodynamics in diabetes. Respiration Physiology, 111(2), 163-175.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lalande, S., Gusso, S., Hofman, P. L., &amp; Baldi, J. C. (2008). Reduced leg blood flow during submaximal exercise in type 2 diabetes. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 40(4), 612-617.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leo, C. H., Hart, J. L., &amp; Woodman, O. L. (2011). Impairment of both nitric oxide-mediated and EDHF-type relaxation in small mesenteric arteries from rats with streptozotocin-induced diabetes. British Journal of Pharmacology, 162(2), 365-377.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lind, A. R., &amp; Williams, C. A. (1979). The control of blood flow through human forearm muscles following brief isometric contractions. Journal of Physiology, 288, 529-547.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu, Y., Kabakov, A. Y., Xie, A., Shi, G., Singh, A. K., Sodha, N. R., Ehsan, A., Usheva, A., Agbortoko, V., Koren, G., Dudley, S. C., Sellke, F. W., &amp; Feng, J. (2020). Metabolic regulation of endothelial SK channels and human coronary microvascular function. International Journal of Cardiology, 312, 1-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lu, T., Sun, X., Li, Y., Chai, Q., Wang, X. L., &amp; Lee, H. C. (2017). Role of Nrf2 signaling in the regulation of vascular BK channel β1 subunit expression and BK channel function in high-fat diet-induced diabetic mice. Diabetes, 66(10), 2681-2690.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mackie, B. G., &amp; Terjung, R. L. (1983). Blood flow to different skeletal muscle fiber types during contraction. American Journal of Physiology, 245, H265-H275.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maeda, H., Kurose, T., &amp; Kawamata, S. (2015). Regulation of the microvascular circulation in the leg muscles, pancreas and small intestine in rats. Springerplus, 4(1), 295.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maeda, H., Kurose, T., Nosaka, S., &amp; Kawamata, S. (2014). Microvascular circulation at cool, normal and warm temperatures in rat leg muscles examined by histochemistry using Lycopersicon esculentum lectin. Acta Histochemica, 116(6), 1096-1103.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matsumoto, T., Ishida, K., Taguchi, K., Kobayashi, T., &amp; Kamata, K. (2010). Losartan normalizes endothelium-derived hyperpolarizing factor-mediated relaxation by activating Ca2+-activated K+ channels in mesenteric artery from type 2 diabetic GK rat. Journal of Pharmacological Sciences, 112(3), 299-309.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matsumoto, T., Kobayashi, T., &amp; Kamata, K. (2003). Alterations in EDHF-type relaxation and phosphodiesterase activity in mesenteric arteries from diabetic rats. American Journal of Physiology Heart and Circulatory Physiology, 285(1), H283-H291.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matsumoto, T., Noguchi, E., Ishida, K., Kobayashi, T., Yamada, N., &amp; Kamata, K. (2008). Metformin normalizes endothelial function by suppressing vasoconstrictor prostanoids in mesenteric arteries from OLETF rats, a model of type 2 diabetes. American Journal of Physiology Heart and Circulatory Physiology, 295(3), H1165-H1176.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McGahon, M. K., Dash, D. P., Arora, A., Wall, N., Dawicki, J., Simpson, D. A., Scholfield, C. N., McGeown, J. G., &amp; Curtis, T. M. (2007). Diabetes downregulates large-conductance Ca2+-activated potassium beta 1 channel subunit in retinal arteriolar smooth muscle. Circulation Research, 100, 703-711.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Milkau, M., Köhler, R., &amp; de Wit, C. (2010). Crucial importance of the endothelial K+ channel SK3 and connexin40 in arteriolar dilations during skeletal muscle contraction. Faseb Journal, 24(9), 3572-3579.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Minami, A., Ishimura, N., Harada, N., Sakamoto, S., Niwa, Y., &amp; Nakaya, Y. (2002). Exercise training improves acetylcholine-induced endothelium-dependent hyperpolarization in type 2 diabetic rats, Otsuka Long-Evans Tokushima fatty rats. Atherosclerosis, 162(1), 85-92.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mishra, R. C., Kyle, B. D., Kendrick, D. J., Svystonyuk, D., Kieser, T. M., Fedak, P. W. M., Wulff, H., &amp; Braun, A. P. (2021). KCa channel activation normalizes endothelial function in Type 2 Diabetic resistance arteries by improving intracellular Ca. Metabolism, 114, 154390.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morifuji, T., Tanaka, M., Nakanishi, R., Hirabayashi, T., Kondo, H., &amp; Fujino, H. (2021). Preventive effects of low-intensity endurance exercise for severe hyperglycemia-induced capillary regression in non-obese type 2 diabetes rat skeletal muscle. Physiological Reports, 9(2), e14712.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nagao, T., Illiano, S., &amp; Vanhoutte, P. M. (1992). Heterogeneous distribution of endothelium-dependent relaxations resistant to NG-nitro-L-arginine in rats. American Journal of Physiology, 263, H1090-H1094.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nieves-Cintrón, M., Syed, A. U., Buonarati, O. R., Rigor, R. R., Nystoriak, M. A., Ghosh, D., Sasse, K. C., Ward, S. M., Santana, L. F., Hell, J. W., &amp; Navedo, M. F. (2017). Impaired BKCa channel function in native vascular smooth muscle from humans with type 2 diabetes. Science Reports, 7(1), 14058.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nyvad, J., Mazur, A., Postnov, D. D., Straarup, M. S., Soendergaard, A. M., Staehr, C., Brøndum, E., Aalkjaer, C., &amp; Matchkov, V. V. (2017). Intravital investigation of rat mesenteric small artery tone and blood flow. Journal of Physiology, 595(15), 5037-5053.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ozkor, M. A., Hayek, S. S., Rahman, A. M., Murrow, J. R., Kavtaradze, N., Lin, J., Manatunga, A., &amp; Quyyumi, A. A. (2015). Contribution of endothelium-derived hyperpolarizing factor to exercise-induced vasodilation in health and hypercholesterolemia. Vascular Medicine, 20(1), 14-22.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Padilla, D. J., McDonough, P., Behnke, B. J., Kano, Y., Hageman, K. S., Musch, T. I., &amp; Poole, D. C. (2006). Effects of Type II diabetes on capillary hemodynamics in skeletal muscle. American Journal of Physiology Heart and Circulatory Physiology, 291(5), H2439-H2444.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pang, Z. D., Wang, Y., Song, Z., She, G., Ma, X. Z., Sun, X., Wu, W., Lai, B. C., Zhang, J., Zhang, Y., Du, X. J., Shyy, J. Y. J., &amp; Deng, X. L. (2021). AMPK upregulates K Ca 2.3 channels and ameliorates endothelial dysfunction in diet-induced obese mice. Biochemical Pharmacology, 183, 114337.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pearson, J. T., Thambyah, H. P., Waddingham, M. T., Inagaki, T., Sukumaran, V., Ngo, J. P., Ow, C. P. C., Sonobe, T., Chen, Y. C., Edgley, A. J., Fujii, Y., Du, C. K., Zhan, D. Y., Umetani, K., Kelly, D. J., Tsuchimochi, H., &amp; Shirai, M. (2021). β-blockade prevents coronary macro- and microvascular dysfunction induced by a high salt diet and insulin resistance in the Goto-Kakizaki rat. Clinical Science (London, England: 1979), 135(2), 327-346.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Percie du Sert, N., Hurst, V., Ahluwalia, A., Alam, S., Avey, M. T., Baker, M., Browne, W. J., Clark, A., Cuthill, I. C., Dirnagl, U., Emerson, M., Garner, P., Holgate, S. T., Howells, D. W., Karp, N. A., Lazic, S. E., Lidster, K., MacCallum, C. J., Macleod, M., … Würbel, H. (2020). The ARRIVE guidelines 2.0: updated guidelines for reporting animal research. Journal of Physiology, 598(18), 3793-3801.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Poitras, V. J., Hudson, R. W., &amp; Tschakovsky, M. E. (2018). Exercise intolerance in Type 2 diabetes: Is there a cardiovascular contribution? Journal of Applied Physiology (Bethesda, Md : 1985), 124(5), 1117-1139.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ray, C. J., &amp; Marshall, J. M. (2009). Elucidation in the rat of the role of adenosine and A2A-receptors in the hyperaemia of twitch and tetanic contractions. Journal of Physiology, 587(7), 1565-1578.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sacre, J. W., Jellis, C. L., Haluska, B. A., Jenkins, C., Coombes, J. S., Marwick, T. H., &amp; Keske, M. A. (2015). Association of exercise intolerance in type 2 diabetes with skeletal muscle blood flow reserve. JACC Cardiovasc Imaging, 8(8), 913-921.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schach, C., Resch, M., Schmid, P. M., Riegger, G. A., &amp; Endemann, D. H. (2014). Type 2 diabetes: Increased expression and contribution of IKCa channels to vasodilation in small mesenteric arteries of ZDF rats. American Journal of Physiology Heart and Circulatory Physiology, 307(8), H1093-H1102.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schiffrin, E. L. (1992). Reactivity of small blood vessels in hypertension: relation with structural changes. State of the art lecture. Hypertension, 19(2), II1-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schindelin, J., Arganda-Carreras, I., Frise, E., Kaynig, V., Longair, M., Pietzsch, T., Preibisch, S., Rueden, C., Saalfeld, S., Schmid, B., Tinevez, J. Y., White, D. J., Hartenstein, V., Eliceiri, K., Tomancak, P., &amp; Cardona, A. (2012). Fiji: An open-source platform for biological-image analysis. Nature Methods, 9(7), 676-682.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Segal, S. S. (1992). Communication among endothelial and smooth muscle cells coordinates blood flow control during exercise. Physiology, 7(4), 152-156.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Segal, S. S. (1994). Cell-to-cell communication coordinates blood flow control. Hypertension, 23(6_pt_2), 1113-1120.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Senefeld, J. W., Limberg, J. K., Lukaszewicz, K. M., &amp; Hunter, S. K. (2019). Exercise-induced hyperaemia is associated with knee extensor fatigability in adults with type 2 diabetes. Journal of Applied Physiology (Bethesda, Md: 1985), 126(3), 658-667.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shim, C. Y., Kim, S., Chadderdon, S., Wu, M., Qi, Y., Xie, A., Alkayed, N. J., Davidson, B. P., &amp; Lindner, J. R. (2014). Epoxyeicosatrienoic acids mediate insulin-mediated augmentation in skeletal muscle perfusion and blood volume. American Journal of Physiology Endocrinology and Metabolism, 307(12), E1097-E1104.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shimokawa, H., Yasutake, H., Fujii, K., Owada, M. K., Nakaike, R., Fukumoto, Y., Takayanagi, T., Nagao, T., Egashira, K., Fujishima, M., &amp; Takeshita, A. (1996). The importance of the hyperpolarizing mechanism increases as the vessel size decreases in endothelium-dependent relaxations in rat mesenteric circulation. Journal of Cardiovascular Pharmacology, 28(5), 703-711.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shirai, M., Schwenke, D. O., Tsuchimochi, H., Umetani, K., Yagi, N., &amp; Pearson, J. T. (2013). Synchrotron radiation imaging for advancing our understanding of cardiovascular function. Circulation Research, 112(1), 209-221.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sinkler, S. Y., &amp; Segal, S. S. (2017). Rapid versus slow ascending vasodilatation: Intercellular conduction versus flow-mediated signalling with tetanic versus rhythmic muscle contractions. Journal of Physiology, 595(23), 7149-7165.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sonobe, T., Schwenke, D. O., Pearson, J. T., Yoshimoto, M., Fujii, Y., Umetani, K., &amp; Shirai, M. (2011). Imaging of the closed-chest mouse pulmonary circulation using synchrotron radiation microangiography. Journal of Applied Physiology, 111(1), 75-80.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sonobe, T., Tsuchimochi, H., Schwenke, D. O., Pearson, J. T., &amp; Shirai, M. (2015). Treadmill running improves hindlimb arteriolar endothelial function in type 1 diabetic mice as visualized by X-ray microangiography. Cardiovascular Diabetology, 14(1), 51.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stehouwer, C. D. A. (2018). Microvascular dysfunction and hyperglycemia: A vicious cycle with widespread consequences. Diabetes, 67(9), 1729-1741.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tickle, P. G., Hendrickse, P. W., Degens, H., &amp; Egginton, S. (2020). Impaired skeletal muscle performance as a consequence of random functional capillary rarefaction can be restored with overload-dependent angiogenesis. Journal of Physiology, 598(6), 1187-1203.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vanhoutte, P. M., Shimokawa, H., Feletou, M., &amp; Tang, E. H. (2017). Endothelial dysfunction and vascular disease - a 30th anniversary update. Acta Physiologica (Oxford, England), 219(1), 22-96.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Walker, S. D., Dora, K. A., Ings, N. T., Crane, G. J., &amp; Garland, C. J. (2001). Activation of endothelial cell IK(Ca) with 1-ethyl-2-benzimidazolinone evokes smooth muscle hyperpolarization in rat isolated mesenteric artery. British Journal of Pharmacology, 134(7), 1548-1554.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weston, A. H., Absi, M., Harno, E., Geraghty, A. R., Ward, D. T., Ruat, M., Dodd, R. H., Dauban, P., &amp; Edwards, G. (2008). The expression and function of Ca(2+)-sensing receptors in rat mesenteric artery; comparative studies using a model of type II diabetes. British Journal of Pharmacology, 154(3), 652-662.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wheatley, C. M., Rattigan, S., Richards, S. M., Barrett, E. J., &amp; Clark, M. G. (2004). Skeletal muscle contraction stimulates capillary recruitment and glucose uptake in insulin-resistant obese Zucker rats. American Journal of Physiology Endocrinology and Metabolism, 287(4), E804-E809.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wilson, G. A., Wilkins, G. T., Cotter, J. D., Lamberts, R. R., Lal, S., &amp; Baldi, J. C. (2017). Impaired ventricular filling limits cardiac reserve during submaximal exercise in people with type 2 diabetes. Cardiovasc Diabetol, 16(1), 160.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wilson, G. A., Wilson, L. C., Lamberts, R. R., Majeed, K., Lal, S., Wilkins, G. T., &amp; Baldi, J. C. (2017). β-adrenergic responsiveness in the type 2 diabetic heart: Effects on cardiac reserve. Medicine and Science in Sports and Exercise, 49(5), 907-914.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xiang, L., Naik, J., &amp; Hester, R. L. (2005). Exercise-induced increase in skeletal muscle vasodilatory responses in obese Zucker rats. American Journal of Physiology Regulatory, Integrative and Comparative Physiology, 288(4), R987-R991.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yokoi, N., Hoshino, M., Hidaka, S., Yoshida, E., Beppu, M., Hoshikawa, R., Sudo, K., Kawada, A., Takagi, S., &amp; Seino, S. (2013). A novel rat model of type 2 diabetes: The Zucker fatty diabetes mellitus ZFDM rat. Journal of Diabetes Research, 2013, 1.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Young, E. J., Hill, M. A., Wiehler, W. B., Triggle, C. R., &amp; Reid, J. J. (2008). Reduced EDHF responses and connexin activity in mesenteric arteries from the insulin-resistant obese Zucker rat. Diabetologia, 51(5), 872-881.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
