<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35558860</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>16</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2046-2069</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>12</Volume>
            <Issue>22</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>05</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>RSC advances</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>RSC Adv</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Potential antimicrobial, antidiabetic, catalytic, antioxidant and ROS/RNS inhibitory activities of <i>Silybum marianum</i> mediated biosynthesized copper oxide nanoparticles.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>14069</StartPage>
          <EndPage>14083</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>14069-14083</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1039/d2ra01929a</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Use of medicinal plants for the biosynthesis of nanoparticles offers several advantages over other synthesis approaches. Plants contain a variety of bioactive compounds that can participate in reduction and capping of nanoparticles. Plant mediated synthesis has the leverage of cost effectiveness, eco-friendly approach and sustained availability. In the current study <i>Silybum marianum</i>, a medicinally valuable plant rich in silymarin content, is used as a reducing and stabilizing agent for the fabrication of nanoparticles. Biosynthesized CuO-NPs were characterized using High Performance Liquid Chromatography (HPLC), Fourier Transform Infrared Spectroscopy (FTIR), X-ray Diffraction (XRD), Scanning Electron Microscopy (SEM), and Dynamic Light Scattering (DLS) techniques. Characterization revealed that CuO-NPs having a crystalline structure showed spherical morphology with an average size of 15 nm. HPLC analysis demonstrated conjugation of various silymarin components, especially the presence of silybin A (705.06 ± 1.59 mg g<sup>-1</sup> DW). CuO-NPs exhibited strong bactericidal potency against clinically important pathogenic bacterial strains <i>e.g. Enterobacter aerogenes</i> and <i>Salmonella typhi</i> with an inhibition zone of 18 ± 1.3 mm and 17 ± 1.2 mm, respectively. Synthesized nanoparticles indicated a dose dependent cytotoxic effect against fibroblast cells exhibiting a percentage cell viability of 83.60 ± 1.505% and 55.1 ± 1.80% at 25 μg mL<sup>-1</sup> and 100 μg mL<sup>-1</sup> concentration, respectively. Moreover, CuO-NPs displayed higher antioxidant potential in terms of (TAC: 96.9 ± 0.26 μg AAE/mg), (TRP: 68.8 ± 0.35 μg AAE/mg), (DPPH: 55.5 ± 0.62%), (ABTS: 332.34 μM) and a significant value for (FRAP: 215.40 μM). Furthermore, enzyme inhibition assays also exhibited excellent enzyme inhibition potential against α-amylase (35.5 ± 1.54%), urease (78.4 ± 1.26%) and lipase (80.50.91%), respectively. Overall findings indicated that biosynthesized CuO-NPs possess immense <i>in vitro</i> biological and biomedical properties and could be used as a broad-spectrum agent for a wider range of biomedical applications.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>This journal is © The Royal Society of Chemistry.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Iqbal</LastName>
            <ForeName>Junaid</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4750-3751</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biotechnology, Quaid-i-Azam University Islamabad 45320 Pakistan juniqbal34@gmail.com anisaandleeb@bs.qau.edu.pk hajraashraf67@gmail.com bismameer786@gmail.com gzaman@bs.qau.edu.pk bhabbasi@qau.edu.pk.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Andleeb</LastName>
            <ForeName>Anisa</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biotechnology, Quaid-i-Azam University Islamabad 45320 Pakistan juniqbal34@gmail.com anisaandleeb@bs.qau.edu.pk hajraashraf67@gmail.com bismameer786@gmail.com gzaman@bs.qau.edu.pk bhabbasi@qau.edu.pk.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ashraf</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hajra</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biotechnology, Quaid-i-Azam University Islamabad 45320 Pakistan juniqbal34@gmail.com anisaandleeb@bs.qau.edu.pk hajraashraf67@gmail.com bismameer786@gmail.com gzaman@bs.qau.edu.pk bhabbasi@qau.edu.pk.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Meer</LastName>
            <ForeName>Bisma</ForeName>
            <Initials>B</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biotechnology, Quaid-i-Azam University Islamabad 45320 Pakistan juniqbal34@gmail.com anisaandleeb@bs.qau.edu.pk hajraashraf67@gmail.com bismameer786@gmail.com gzaman@bs.qau.edu.pk bhabbasi@qau.edu.pk.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mehmood</LastName>
            <ForeName>Azra</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Stem Cell &amp; Regenerative Medicine Lab, National Centre of Excellence in Molecular Biology, University of Punjab 87-West Canal Bank Road Lahore 53700 Pakistan azramehmood@cemb.edu.pk.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Jan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hasnain</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Biochemical Sciences, National Taiwan University Taipei City 10617 Taiwan rhasnain849@gmail.com.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zaman</LastName>
            <ForeName>Gouhar</ForeName>
            <Initials>G</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biotechnology, Quaid-i-Azam University Islamabad 45320 Pakistan juniqbal34@gmail.com anisaandleeb@bs.qau.edu.pk hajraashraf67@gmail.com bismameer786@gmail.com gzaman@bs.qau.edu.pk bhabbasi@qau.edu.pk.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nadeem</LastName>
            <ForeName>Muhammad</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Integrative Biosciences, CECOS University Peshawar 25100 Pakistan m.nadeem@cecos.edu.pk.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Drouet</LastName>
            <ForeName>Samantha</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Laboratoire de Biologie des Ligneux et des Grandes Cultures (LBLGC), INRAE USC1328, Université d'Orléans 45067 Orléans Cedex 2 France samantha.drouet@univ-orleans.fr hano@univ-orleans.fr.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Fazal</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hina</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Pakistan Council of Scientific and Industrial Research (PCSIR) Laboratories Complex Peshawar 25120 Pakistan hina_fazalso@yahoo.com.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Giglioli-Guivarc'h</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nathalie</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>EA2106 Biomolécules et Biotechnologies Végétales, Université Francois-Rabelais de Tours Tours France nathalie.guivarch@univ-tours.fr.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hano</LastName>
            <ForeName>Christophe</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-9938-0151</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Laboratoire de Biologie des Ligneux et des Grandes Cultures (LBLGC), INRAE USC1328, Université d'Orléans 45067 Orléans Cedex 2 France samantha.drouet@univ-orleans.fr hano@univ-orleans.fr.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Abbasi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Bilal Haider</ForeName>
            <Initials>BH</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-6529-2134</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biotechnology, Quaid-i-Azam University Islamabad 45320 Pakistan juniqbal34@gmail.com anisaandleeb@bs.qau.edu.pk hajraashraf67@gmail.com bismameer786@gmail.com gzaman@bs.qau.edu.pk bhabbasi@qau.edu.pk.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>RSC Adv</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101581657</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2046-2069</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CoiStatement>All the authors declared no competing interest.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
          <Hour>18</Hour>
          <Minute>20</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35558860</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9094097</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1039/d2ra01929a</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">d2ra01929a</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McNeil S. E. Nanotechnology for the biologist. J. Leukocyte Biol. 2005;78:585–594.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15923216</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Javed R. Usman M. Tabassum S. Zia M. Effect of capping agents: structural, optical and biological properties of ZnO nanoparticles. Appl. Surf. Sci. 2016;386:319–326.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Albanese A. Tang P. S. Chan W. C. The effect of nanoparticle size, shape, and surface chemistry on biological systems. Annu. Rev. Biomed. Eng. 2012;14:1–16.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22524388</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Laurent S. Forge D. Port M. Roch A. Robic C. Vander Elst L. Muller R. N. Magnetic iron oxide nanoparticles: synthesis, stabilization, vectorization, physicochemical characterizations, and biological applications. Chem. Rev. 2008;108:2064–2110.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18543879</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Naseer M. Aslam U. Khalid B. Chen B. Green route to synthesize Zinc Oxide Nanoparticles using leaf extracts of Cassia fistula and Melia azadarach and their antibacterial potential. Sci. Rep. 2020;10:1–10.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6959339</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31913322</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Din M. I. Rehan R. Synthesis, characterization, and applications of copper nanoparticles. Anal. Lett. 2017;50:50–62.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang C. Gao X. Chen Z. Chen Y. Chen H. Preparation, characterization and application of polysaccharide-based metallic nanoparticles: a review. Polymers. 2017;9:689.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fernandez-Garcia M. Martinez-Arias A. Hanson J. Rodriguez J. Nanostructured oxides in chemistry: characterization and properties. Chem. Rev. 2004;104:4063–4104.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15352786</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sharma P. Mehta M. Dhanjal D. S. Kaur S. Gupta G. Singh H. Thangavelu L. Rajeshkumar S. Tambuwala M. Bakshi H. A. Emerging trends in the novel drug delivery approaches for the treatment of lung cancer. Chem.-Biol. Interact. 2019;309:108720.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31226287</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vasantharaj S. Sathiyavimal S. Saravanan M. Senthilkumar P. Gnanasekaran K. Shanmugavel M. Manikandan E. Pugazhendhi A. Synthesis of ecofriendly copper oxide nanoparticles for fabrication over textile fabrics: characterization of antibacterial activity and dye degradation potential. J. Photochem. Photobiol., B. 2019;191:143–149.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30639996</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rangel W. M. Santa R. A. A. B. Riella H. G. A facile method for synthesis of nanostructured copper(II) oxide by coprecipitation. J. Mater. Res. Technol. 2020;9:994–1004.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Applerot G. Lellouche J. Lipovsky A. Nitzan Y. Lubart R. Gedanken A. Banin E. Understanding the antibacterial mechanism of CuO nanoparticles: revealing the route of induced oxidative stress. Small. 2012;8:3326–3337.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22888058</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Velsankar K. Suganya S. Muthumari P. Mohandoss S. Sudhahar S. Ecofriendly green synthesis, characterization and biomedical applications of CuO nanoparticles synthesized using leaf extract of Capsicum frutescens. J. Environ. Chem. Eng. 2021;9:106299.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chung I. M. Abdul Rahuman A. Marimuthu S. Vishnu Kirthi A. Anbarasan K. Padmini P. Rajakumar G. Green synthesis of copper nanoparticles using Eclipta prostrata leaves extract and their antioxidant and cytotoxic activities. Exp. Ther. Med. 2017;14:18–24.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5488509</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28672888</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Waris A. Din M. Ali A. Ali M. Afridi S. Baset A. Khan A. U. A comprehensive review of green synthesis of copper oxide nanoparticles and their diverse biomedical applications. Inorg. Chem. Commun. 2021;123:1387–7003.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krishnan B. Mahalingam S. Improved surface morphology of silver/copper oxide/bentonite nanocomposite using aliphatic ammonium based ionic liquid for enhanced biological activities. J. Mol. Liq. 2017;241:1044–1058.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verma N. Kumar N. Synthesis and
biomedical applications of copper oxide nanoparticles: an expanding horizon. ACS Biomater. Sci. Eng. 2019;5:1170–1188.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33405638</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salem S. S. Fouda A. Green synthesis of metallic nanoparticles and their prospective biotechnological applications: an overview. Biol. Trace Elem. Res. 2021;199:344–370.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32377944</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rehana D. Mahendiran D. Kumar R. S. Rahiman A. K. Evaluation of antioxidant and anticancer activity of copper oxide nanoparticles synthesized using medicinally important plant extracts. Biomed. Pharmacother. 2017;89:1067–1077.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28292015</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singh A. Singh N. Hussain I. Singh H. Effect of biologically synthesized copper oxide nanoparticles on metabolism and antioxidant activity to the crop plants Solanum lycopersicum and Brassica oleracea var. botrytis. J. Biotechnol. 2017;262:11–27.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28962841</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kalpana V. Devi Rajeswari V. A review on green synthesis, biomedical applications, and toxicity studies of ZnO NPs. Bioinorg. Chem. Appl. 2018;2018:1–12.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Makarov V. Love A. Sinitsyna O. Makarova S. Yaminsky I. Taliansky M. Kalinina N. “Green” nanotechnologies: synthesis of metal nanoparticles using plants. Acta Naturae. 2014;6:35–44.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3999464</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24772325</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ovais M. Khalil A. T. Raza A. Islam N. U. Ayaz M. Saravanan M. Ali M. Ahmad I. Shahid M. Shinwari Z. K. Multifunctional theranostic applications of biocompatible green-synthesized colloidal nanoparticles. Appl. Microbiol. Biotechnol. 2018;102:4393–4408.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29594356</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dipankar C. Murugan S. The green synthesis, characterization and evaluation of the biological activities of silver nanoparticles synthesized from Iresine herbstii leaf aqueous extracts. Colloids Surf., B. 2012;98:112–119.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ren G. Hu D. Cheng E. W. Vargas-Reus M. A. Reip P. Allaker R. P. Characterisation of copper oxide nanoparticles for antimicrobial applications. Int. J. Antimicrob. Agents. 2009;33:587–590.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19195845</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Javed R. Ahmed M. ul Haq I. Nisa S. Zia M. PVP and PEG doped CuO nanoparticles are more biologically active: Antibacterial, antioxidant, antidiabetic and cytotoxic perspective. Mater. Sci. Eng., C. 2017;79:108–115.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Germi K. G. Shabani F. Khodayari A. Azizian-Kalandaragh Y. Structural and biological properties of CuO nanoparticles prepared under ultrasonic irradiation. Synth. React. Inorg., Met.-Org., Nano-Met. Chem. 2014;44:1286–1290.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ahamed M. Alhadlaq H. A. Khan M. Karuppiah P. Al-Dhabi N. A. Synthesis, characterization, and antimicrobial activity of copper oxide nanoparticles. J. Nanomater. 2014;2014:4.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Katwal R. Kaur H. Sharma G. Naushad M. Pathania D. Electrochemical synthesized copper oxide nanoparticles for enhanced photocatalytic and antimicrobial activity. J. Ind. Eng. Chem. 2015;31:173–184.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jayaraj R. Deb U. Bhaskar A. Prasad G. Rao P. L. Hepatoprotective efficacy of certain flavonoids against microcystin induced toxicity in mice. Environ. Toxicol. 2007;22:472–479.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17696131</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang X. Zhang Z. Wu S.-C. Health benefits of Silybum marianum: Phytochemistry, pharmacology, and applications. J. Agric. Food Chem. 2020;68:11644–11664.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33045827</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Soto C. Pérez J. García V. Uría E. Vadillo M. Raya L. Effect of silymarin on kidneys of rats suffering from alloxan-induced diabetes mellitus. Phytomedicine. 2010;17:1090–1094.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20579862</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shaker E. Mahmoud H. Mnaa S. Silymarin, the antioxidant component and Silybum marianum extracts prevent liver damage. Food Chem. Toxicol. 2010;48:803–806.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20034535</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bahmani M. Shirzad H. Rafieian S. Rafieian-Kopaei M. Silybum marianum: beyond hepatoprotection. J. Evidence-Based Complementary Altern. Med. 2015;20:292–301.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sorbiun M. Mehr E. S. Ramazani A. Fardood S. T. Green synthesis of zinc oxide and copper oxide nanoparticles using aqueous extract of oak fruit hull (jaft) and comparing their photocatalytic degradation of basic violet 3. Int. J. Environ. Res. 2018;12:29–37.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nagajyothi P. Muthuraman P. Sreekanth T. Kim D. H. Shim J. Green synthesis: In-vitro anticancer activity of copper oxide nanoparticles against human cervical carcinoma cells. Arabian J. Chem. 2017;10:215–225.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghidan A. Y. Al-Antary T. M. Awwad A. M. Green synthesis of copper oxide nanoparticles using Punica granatum peels extract: Effect on green peach Aphid. Environ. Nanotechnol., Monit. Manage. 2016;6:95–98.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kumar P. V. Shameem U. Kollu P. Kalyani R. Pammi S. Green synthesis of copper oxide nanoparticles using Aloe vera leaf extract and its antibacterial activity against fish bacterial pathogens. BioNanoScience. 2015;5:135–139.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Naz S. Tabassum S. Freitas Fernandes N. Mujahid M. Zia M. Carcache de Blanco E. J. Anticancer and antibacterial potential of Rhus punjabensis and CuO nanoparticles. Nat. Prod. Res. 2020;34:720–725.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30320505</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bibi G. Ullah N. Mannan A. Mirza B. Antitumor, cytotoxic and antioxidant potential of Aster thomsonii extracts. Afr. J. Pharm. Pharmacol. 2011;5:252–258.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Biglar M. Soltani K. Nabati F. Bazl R. Mojab F. Amanlou M. A preliminary investigation of the jack-bean urease inhibition by randomly selected traditionally used herbal medicine. Iran. J. Pharm. Res. 2012;11:831.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3813127</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24250509</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McDougall G. J. Kulkarni N. N. Stewart D. Berry polyphenols inhibit pancreatic lipase activity in vitro. Food Chem. 2009;115:193–199.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fatima H. Khan K. Zia M. Ur-Rehman T. Mirza B. Haq I.-u. Extraction optimization of medicinally important metabolites from Datura innoxia Mill.: an in vitro biological and phytochemical investigation. BMC Complementary Altern. Med. 2015;15:1–18.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zafar H. Ali A. Ali J. S. Haq I. U. Zia M. Effect of ZnO nanoparticles on Brassica nigra seedlings and stem explants: growth dynamics and antioxidative response. Front. Plant Sci. 2016;7:535.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4837972</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27148347</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shah M. Ullah M. A. Drouet S. Younas M. Tungmunnithum D. Giglioli-Guivarc'h N. Hano C. Abbasi B. H. Interactive Effects of Light and Melatonin on Biosynthesis of Silymarin and Anti-Inflammatory Potential in Callus Cultures of Silybum marianum (L.) Gaertn. Molecules. 2019;24:1207.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nazir M. Tungmunnithum D. Bose S. Drouet S. Garros L. Giglioli-Guivarc'h N. Abbasi B. H. Hano C. Differential production of phenylpropanoid metabolites in callus cultures of Ocimum basilicum L. with distinct in vitro antioxidant activities and in vivo protective effects against UV stress. J. Agric. Food Chem. 2019;67:1847–1859.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30681331</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Choudhery M. S. Khan M. Mahmood R. Mehmood A. Khan S. N. Riazuddin S. Bone marrow derived mesenchymal stem cells from aged mice have reduced wound healing, angiogenesis, proliferation and anti-apoptosis capabilities. Cell Biol. Int. 2012;36:747–753.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22352320</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lagrimini L. Plant peroxidases: under-and over-expression in transgenic plants and physiological consequences. Plant Peroxidases. 1980;1990:59–69.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Drouet S. Abbasi B. H. Falguieres A. Ahmad W. Ferroud C. Doussot J. Vanier J. R. Lainé E. Hano C. Single laboratory validation of a quantitative core shell-based LC separation for the evaluation of silymarin variability and associated antioxidant activity of pakistani ecotypes of milk thistle (Silybum marianum L.) Molecules. 2018;23:904.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fehér J. Lengyel G. Silymarin in the prevention and treatment of liver diseases and primary liver cancer. Curr. Pharm. Biotechnol. 2012;13:210–217.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21466434</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shah M. Nawaz S. Jan H. Uddin N. Ali A. Anjum S. Giglioli-Guivarc'h N. Hano C. Abbasi B. H. Synthesis of bio-mediated silver nanoparticles from Silybum marianum and their biological and clinical activities. Mater. Sci. Eng., C. 2020;112:110889.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Apriandanu D. O. B. Yulizar Y. Tinospora crispa leaves extract for the simple preparation method of CuO nanoparticles and its characterization. Nano-Struct. Nano-Objects. 2019;20:100401.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mehr E. S. Sorbiun M. Ramazani A. Fardood S. T. Plant-mediated synthesis of zinc oxide and copper oxide nanoparticles by using ferulago angulata (schlecht) boiss extract and comparison of their photocatalytic degradation of Rhodamine B (RhB) under visible light irradiation. J. Mater. Sci.: Mater. Electron. 2018;29:1333–1340.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yulizar Y. Latifah I. Bakri R. Apriandanu D. Plants extract mediated synthesis of copper (II) oxide nanoparticles using Oldenlandia corymbosa L. leaf. AIP Conf. Proc. 2018;2023:020097.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cheirmadurai K. Biswas S. Murali R. Thanikaivelan P. Green synthesis of copper nanoparticles and conducting nanobiocomposites using plant and animal sources. RSC Adv. 2014;4:19507–19511.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rajesh K. Ajitha B. Reddy Y. A. K. Suneetha Y. Reddy P. S. Assisted green synthesis of copper nanoparticles using Syzygium aromaticum bud extract: Physical, optical and antimicrobial properties. Optik. 2018;154:593–600.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Honary S. Barabadi H. Gharaei-Fathabad E. Naghibi F. Green synthesis of copper oxide nanoparticles using Penicillium aurantiogriseum, Penicillium citrinum and Penicillium waksmanii. Dig. J. Nanomater. Bios. 2012;7:999–1005.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cuevas R. Durán N. Diez M. Tortella G. Rubilar O. Extracellular biosynthesis of copper and copper oxide nanoparticles by Stereum hirsutum, a native white-rot fungus from chilean forests. J. Nanomater. 2015;2015:7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Padil V. V. T. Černík M. Green synthesis of copper oxide nanoparticles using gum karaya as a biotemplate and their antibacterial application. Int. J. Nanomed. 2013;8:889.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fardood S. T. Ramazani A. Black tea extract mediated green synthesis of copper oxide nanoparticles. Journal of Applied Chemical Research. 2018;12:8–15.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Silva N. Ramírez S. Díaz I. Garcia A. Hassan N. Easy, quick, and reproducible sonochemical synthesis of CuO nanoparticles. Materials. 2019;12:804.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nair A. Jayakumari C. Jabbar P. Jayakumar R. Raizada N. Gopi A. George G. S. Seena T. Prevalence and associations of hypothyroidism in Indian patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus. J. Thyroid Res. 2018;2018:7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shwetha U. Latha M. Kumar C. R. Kiran M. Onkarappa H. Betageri V. S. Potential antidiabetic and anticancer activity of copper oxide nanoparticles synthesised using Areca catechu leaf extract. Adv. Nat. Sci.: Nanosci. Nanotechnol. 2021;12:025008.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ghosh S. More P. Nitnavare R. Jagtap S. Chippalkatti R. Derle A. Kitture R. Asok A. Kale S. Singh S. Antidiabetic and antioxidant properties of copper nanoparticles synthesized by medicinal plant Dioscorea bulbifera. J. Nanomed. Nanotechnol. 2015;S6:1–9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Islam N. U. Amin R. Shahid M. Amin M. Zaib S. Iqbal J. A multi-target therapeutic potential of Prunus domestica gum stabilized nanoparticles exhibited prospective anticancer, antibacterial, urease-inhibition, anti-inflammatory and analgesic properties. BMC Complementary Altern. Med. 2017;17:1–17.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sachan S. Singh A. Lipase enzyme and its diverse role in food processing industry. Everyman's Sci. 2015;4:214–218.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Choudhary M. I. Ali M. Wahab A.-t. Khan A. Rasheed S. Shyaula S. L. Rahman A.-u. New antiglycation and enzyme inhibitors from Parmotrema cooperi. Sci. China: Chem. 2011;54:1926–1931.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muthuvel A. Jothibas M. Manoharan C. Synthesis of copper oxide nanoparticles by chemical and biogenic methods: photocatalytic degradation and in vitro antioxidant activity. Nanotechnol. Environ. Eng. 2020;5:1–19.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sondi I. Salopek-Sondi B. Silver nanoparticles as antimicrobial agent: a case study on E. coli as a model for Gram-negative bacteria. J. Colloid Interface Sci. 2004;275:177–182.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15158396</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jadhav S. Gaikwad S. Nimse M. Rajbhoj A. Copper oxide nanoparticles: synthesis, characterization and their antibacterial activity. J. Cluster Sci. 2011;22:121–129.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chang Y.-N. Zhang M. Xia L. Zhang J. Xing G. The toxic effects and mechanisms of CuO and ZnO nanoparticles. Materials. 2012;5:2850–2871.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Galdiero S. Falanga A. Vitiello M. Cantisani M. Marra V. Galdiero M. Silver nanoparticles as potential antiviral agents. Molecules. 2011;16:8894–8918.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6264685</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22024958</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mukhopadhyay R. Kazi J. Debnath M. C. Synthesis and characterization of copper nanoparticles stabilized with Quisqualis indica extract: evaluation of its cytotoxicity and apoptosis in B16F10 melanoma cells. Biomed. Pharmacother. 2018;97:1373–1385.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29156527</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Karim M. N. Singh M. Weerathunge P. Bian P. Zheng R. Dekiwadia C. Ahmed T. Walia S. Della Gaspera E. Singh S. Visible-light-triggered reactive-oxygen-species-mediated antibacterial activity of peroxidase-mimic CuO nanorods. ACS Appl. Nano Mater. 2018;1:1694–1704.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sousa C. A. Soares H. M. Soares E. V. Nickel oxide (NiO) nanoparticles induce loss of cell viability in yeast mediated by oxidative stress. Chem. Res. Toxicol. 2018;31:658–665.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30043610</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
