<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35567597</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>14</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1552-4833</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>14</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>American journal of medical genetics. Part A</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Am J Med Genet A</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Expanding ACTA2 genotypes with corresponding phenotypes overlapping with smooth muscle dysfunction syndrome.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ajmg.a.62775</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Pathogenic variants in ACTA2, encoding smooth muscle α-actin, predispose to thoracic aortic aneurysms and dissections. ACTA2 variants altering arginine 179 predispose to a more severe, multisystemic disease termed smooth muscle dysfunction syndrome (SMDS; OMIM 613834). Vascular complications of SMDS include patent ductus arteriosus (PDA) or aortopulmonary window, early-onset thoracic aortic disease (TAD), moyamoya-like cerebrovascular disease, and primary pulmonary hypertension. Patients also have dysfunction of other smooth muscle-dependent systems, including congenital mydriasis, hypotonic bladder, and gut hypoperistalsis. Here, we describe five patients with novel heterozygous ACTA2 missense variants, p.Arg179Gly, p.Met46Arg, p.Thr204Ile, p.Arg39Cys, and p.Ile66Asn, who have clinical complications that align or overlap with SMDS. Patients with the ACTA2 p.Arg179Gly and p.Thr204Ile variants display classic features of SMDS. The patient with the ACTA2 p.Met46Arg variant exhibits exclusively vascular complications of SMDS, including early-onset TAD, PDA, and moyamoya-like cerebrovascular disease. The patient with the ACTA2 p.Ile66Asn variant has an unusual vascular complication, a large fusiform internal carotid artery aneurysm. The patient with the ACTA2 p.Arg39Cys variant has pulmonary, gastrointestinal, and genitourinary complications of SMDS but no vascular manifestations. Identifying pathogenic ACTA2 variants associated with features of SMDS is critical for aggressive surveillance and management of vascular and nonvascular complications and delineating the molecular pathogenesis of SMDS.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kaw</LastName>
            <ForeName>Anita</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3690-711X</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Medical Genetic, Department of Internal Medicine, McGovern Medical School, University of Texas Health Science Center at Houston, Houston, Texas, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kaw</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kaveeta</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Medical Genetic, Department of Internal Medicine, McGovern Medical School, University of Texas Health Science Center at Houston, Houston, Texas, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hostetler</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ellen M</ForeName>
            <Initials>EM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Medical Genetic, Department of Internal Medicine, McGovern Medical School, University of Texas Health Science Center at Houston, Houston, Texas, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Beleza-Meireles</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ana</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Bristol Regional Clinical Genetics Service, St Michael's Hospital, Bristol, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Smith-Collins</LastName>
            <ForeName>Adam</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Regional Neonatal Intensive Care Unit, St Michael's Hospital, Bristol, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Armstrong</LastName>
            <ForeName>Catherine</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Bristol Royal Hospital for Children, Bristol, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Scurr</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ingrid</ForeName>
            <Initials>I</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Bristol Regional Clinical Genetics Service, St Michael's Hospital, Bristol, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Cotts</LastName>
            <ForeName>Timothy</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Pediatric Cardiology, Department of Pediatrics, Michigan Medicine, University of Michigan at Ann Arbor, Ann Arbor, Michigan, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Aatre</LastName>
            <ForeName>Rajani</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Franklin Cardiovascular Center, Department of Internal Medicine, Michigan Medicine, University of Michigan at Ann Arbor, Ann Arbor, Michigan, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bamshad</LastName>
            <ForeName>Michael J</ForeName>
            <Initials>MJ</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Medical Genetics, Department of Pediatrics, University of Washington, Seattle, Washington, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Earl</LastName>
            <ForeName>Dawn</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Medical Genetics, Department of Pediatrics, University of Washington, Seattle, Washington, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Groner</LastName>
            <ForeName>Abraham</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, Department of Pediatrics, The University of Chicago, Chicago, Illinois, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Agre</LastName>
            <ForeName>Katherine</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Invitae, San Francisco, California, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Raveh</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yehuda</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4780-2743</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Anesthesia, University of Miami/Jackson Memorial Hospital, Miami, Florida, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kwartler</LastName>
            <ForeName>Callie S</ForeName>
            <Initials>CS</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3722-9939</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Medical Genetic, Department of Internal Medicine, McGovern Medical School, University of Texas Health Science Center at Houston, Houston, Texas, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Milewicz</LastName>
            <ForeName>Dianna M</ForeName>
            <Initials>DM</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7806-0068</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Medical Genetic, Department of Internal Medicine, McGovern Medical School, University of Texas Health Science Center at Houston, Houston, Texas, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <GrantList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>NIH R01HL109942</GrantID>
            <Acronym>NH</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>NIH TL1TR003169</GrantID>
            <Acronym>NH</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>NIH UL1TR003167</GrantID>
            <Acronym>NH</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>NIH T32GM120011</GrantID>
            <Acronym>NH</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>RO1HL146583</GrantID>
            <Acronym>NH</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
        </GrantList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Am J Med Genet A</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101235741</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1552-4825</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ACTA2</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Smooth Muscle Dysfunction Syndrome</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">thoracic aortic disease</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
          <Hour>11</Hour>
          <Minute>2</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35567597</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ajmg.a.62775</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Amans, M. R., Stout, C., Fox, C., Narvid, J., Hetts, S. W., Cooke, D. L., Higashida, R. T., Dowd, C. F., McSwain, H., &amp; Halbach, V. V. (2013). Cerebral arteriopathy associated with Arg179His ACTA2 mutation. BML Case Reports, 2013. https://doi.org/10.1136/bcr-2013-010997</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Biesecker, L. G., Adam, M. P., Alkuraya, F. S., Amemiya, A. R., Bamshad, M. J., Beck, A. E., Bennett, J. T., Bird, L. M., Carey, J. C., Chung, B., Clark, R. D., Cox, T. C., Curry, C., Dinulos, M. B. P., Dobyns, W. B., Giampietro, P. F., Girisha, K. M., Glass, I. A., Graham, J. M., Jr., … Zarate, Y. A. (2021). A dyadic approach to the delineation of diagnostic entities in clinical genomics. American Journal of Human Genetics, 108(1), 8-15. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ajhg.2020.11.013</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Diness, B. R., Palmquist, R. N., Norling, R., Hove, H., Bundgaard, H., Hertz, J. M., Kondziella, D., Krieger, D., Dunø, M., &amp; Grønborg, S. (2020). Expanding the cerebrovascular phenotype of the p.R258H variant in ACTA2 related hereditary thoracic aortic disease (HTAD). Journal of the Neurological Sciences, 415, 116897. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jns.2020.116897</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gauthier, J., Ouled Amar Bencheikh, B., Hamdan, F. F., Harrison, S. M., Baker, L. A., Couture, F., Thiffault, I., Ouazzani, R., Samuels, M. E., Mitchell, G. A., Rouleau, G. A., Michaud, J. L., &amp; Soucy, J.-F. (2015). A homozygous loss-of-function variant in MYH11 in a case with megacystis-microcolon-intestinal hypoperistalsis syndrome. European Journal of Human Genetics, 23(9), 1266-1268. https://doi.org/10.1038/ejhg.2014.256</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Georgescu, M. M., Pinho Mda, C., Richardson, T. E., Torrealba, J., Buja, L. M., Milewicz, D. M., Raisanen, J. M., &amp; Burns, D. K. (2015). The defining pathology of the new clinical and histopathologic entity ACTA2-related cerebrovascular disease. Acta Neuropathologica Communications, 3, 81. https://doi.org/10.1186/s40478-015-0262-7</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guo, D. C., Pannu, H., Tran-Fadulu, V., Papke, C. L., Yu, R. K., Avidan, N., Bourgeois, S., Estrera, A. L., Safi, H. J., Sparks, E., Amor, D., Ades, L., McConnell, V., Willoughby, C. E., Abuelo, D., Willing, M., Lewis, R. A., Kim, D. H., Scherer, S., … Milewicz, D. M. (2007). Mutations in smooth muscle alpha-actin (ACTA2) lead to thoracic aortic aneurysms and dissections. Nature Genetics, 39(12), 1488-1493. https://doi.org/10.1038/ng.2007.6</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guo, D. C., Papke, C. L., Tran-Fadulu, V., Regalado, E. S., Avidan, N., Johnson, R. J., Kim, D. H., Pannu, H., Willing, M. C., Sparks, E., Pyeritz, R. E., Singh, M. N., Dalman, R. L., Grotta, J. C., Marian, A. J., Boerwinkle, E. A., Frazier, L. Q., LeMaire, S. A., Coselli, J. S., … Milewicz, D. M. (2009). Mutations in smooth muscle alpha-actin (ACTA2) cause coronary artery disease, stroke, and moyamoya disease, along with thoracic aortic disease. American Journal of Human Genetics, 84(5), 617-627. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ajhg.2009.04.007</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Halim, D., Brosens, E., Muller, F., Wangler, M. F., Beaudet, A. L., Lupski, J. R., Akdemir, Z. H. C., Doukas, M., Stoop, H. J., de Graaf, B. M., Brouwer, R. W. W., van Ijcken, W. F. J., Oury, J.-F., Rosenblatt, J., Burns, A. J., Tibboel, D., Hofstra, R. M. W., &amp; Alves, M. M. (2017). Loss-of-function variants in MYLK cause recessive megacystis microcolon intestinal hypoperistalsis syndrome. The American Journal of Human Genetics, 101(1), 123-129. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ajhg.2017.05.011</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hoffjan, S., Waldmüller, S., Blankenfeldt, W., Kötting, J., Gehle, P., Binner, P., Epplen, J. T., &amp; Scheffold, T. (2011). Three novel mutations in the ACTA2 gene in German patients with thoracic aortic aneurysms and dissections. European Journal of Human Genetics, 19(5), 520-524. https://doi.org/10.1038/ejhg.2010.239</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ke, T., Han, M., Zhao, M., Wang, Q. K., Zhang, H., Zhao, Y., Ruan, X., Li, H., Xu, C., &amp; Sun, T. (2016). Alpha-actin-2 mutations in Chinese patients with a non-syndromatic thoracic aortic aneurysm. BMC Medical Genetics, 17(1), 45. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12881-016-0310-6</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lauer, A., Speroni, S. L., Patel, J. B., Regalado, E., Choi, M., Smith, E., Kalpathy-Kramer, J., Caruso, P., Milewicz, D. M., &amp; Musolino, P. L. (2021). Cerebrovascular disease progression in patients with ACTA2 Arg179 pathogenic variants. Neurology, 96(4), e538-e552. https://doi.org/10.1212/wnl.0000000000011210</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lu, H., Fagnant, P. M., Bookwalter, C. S., Joel, P., &amp; Trybus, K. M. (2015). Vascular disease-causing mutation R258C in ACTA2 disrupts actin dynamics and interaction with myosin. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, 112(31), E4168-E4177. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1507587112</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lu, H., Fagnant, P. M., Krementsova, E. B., &amp; Trybus, K. M. (2016). Severe molecular defects exhibited by the R179H mutation in human vascular smooth muscle α-actin. The Journal of Biological Chemistry, 291(41), 21729-21739. https://doi.org/10.1074/jbc.M116.744011</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mc Glacken-Byrne, A. B., Prentice, D., Roshandel, D., Brown, M. R., Tuch, P., Yau, K. S. Y., Sivadorai, P., Davis, M. R., Laing, N. G., &amp; Chen, F. K. (2020). High-resolution iris and retinal imaging in multisystemic smooth muscle dysfunction syndrome due to a novel Asn117Lys substitution in ACTA2: A case report. BMC Ophthalmology, 20(1), 68. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12886-020-01344-w</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Milewicz, D. M., Guo, D. C., Tran-Fadulu, V., Lafont, A. L., Papke, C. L., Inamoto, S., Kwartler, C. S., &amp; Pannu, H. (2008). Genetic basis of thoracic aortic aneurysms and dissections: Focus on smooth muscle cell contractile dysfunction. Annual Review of Genomics and Human Genetics, 9, 283-302. https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev.genom.8.080706.092303</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Milewicz, D. M., Ostergaard, J. R., Ala-Kokko, L. M., Khan, N., Grange, D. K., Mendoza-Londono, R., Bradley, T. J., Olney, A. H., Ades, L., Maher, J. F., Guo, D., Buja, L. M., Kim, D., Hyland, J. C., &amp; Regalado, E. S. (2010). De novo ACTA2 mutation causes a novel syndrome of multisystemic smooth muscle dysfunction. American Journal of Medical Genetics. Part A, 152A(10), 2437-2443. https://doi.org/10.1002/ajmg.a.33657</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Milewicz, D. M., Trybus, K. M., Guo, D. C., Sweeney, H. L., Regalado, E., Kamm, K., &amp; Stull, J. T. (2017). Altered smooth muscle cell force generation as a driver of thoracic aortic aneurysms and dissections. Arteriosclerosis, Thrombosis, and Vascular Biology, 37(1), 26-34. https://doi.org/10.1161/atvbaha.116.303229</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morisaki, H., Akutsu, K., Ogino, H., Kondo, N., Yamanaka, I., Tsutsumi, Y., Yoshimuta, T., Okajima, T., Matsuda, H., Minatoya, K., Sasaki, H., Tanaka, H., Ishibashi-Ueda, H., &amp; Morisaki, T. (2009). Mutation of ACTA2 gene as an important cause of familial and nonfamilial nonsyndromatic thoracic aortic aneurysm and/or dissection (TAAD). Human Mutation, 30(10), 1406-1411. https://doi.org/10.1002/humu.21081</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Munot, P., Saunders, D. E., Milewicz, D. M., Regalado, E. S., Ostergaard, J. R., Braun, K. P., Kerr, T., Lichtenbelt, K. D., Philip, S., Rittey, C., Jacques, T. S., Cox, T. C., &amp; Ganesan, V. (2012). A novel distinctive cerebrovascular phenotype is associated with heterozygous Arg179 ACTA2 mutations. Brain, 135(Pt 8), 2506-2514. https://doi.org/10.1093/brain/aws172</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pinto, M. (2020). A novel ACTA2 gene disease-causing variant presenting with a complex brain phenotype. Sinapse, 20(4), 181-183. https://doi.org/10.46531/sinapse/CC/200032/2020</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Regalado, E. S., Guo, D.-C., Prakash, S., Bensend, T. A., Flynn, K., Estrera, A., Safi, H., Liang, D., Hyland, J., Child, A., Arno, G., Boileau, C., Jondeau, G., Braverman, A., Moran, R., Morisaki, T., Morisaki, H., Pyeritz, R., Coselli, J., … Milewicz, D. M. (2015). Aortic disease presentation and outcome associated with ACTA2 mutations. Circulation: Cardiovascular Genetics, 8(3), 457-464. https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCGENETICS.114.000943</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Regalado, E. S., Mellor-Crummey, L., De Backer, J., Braverman, A. C., Ades, L., Benedict, S., Bradley, T. J., Brickner, M. E., Chatfield, K. C., Child, A., Feist, C., Holmes, K. W., Iannucci, G., Lorenz, B., Mark, P., Morisaki, T., Morisaki, H., Morris, S. A., Mitchell, A. L., … Milewicz, D. M. (2018, Oct). Clinical history and management recommendations of the smooth muscle dysfunction syndrome due to ACTA2 arginine 179 alterations. Genetics in Medicine, 20(10), 1206-1215. https://doi.org/10.1038/gim.2017.245</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Richer, J., Milewicz, D. M., Gow, R., de Nanassy, J., Maharajh, G., Miller, E., Oppenheimer, L., Weiler, G., &amp; O'Connor, M. (2012). R179H mutation in ACTA2 expanding the phenotype to include prune-belly sequence and skin manifestations. American Journal of Medical Genetics Part A, 158A(3), 664-668. https://doi.org/10.1002/ajmg.a.35206</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shalhub, S., Roman, M. J., Eagle, K. A., LeMaire, S. A., Zhang, Q., Evangelista, A., &amp; Milewicz, D. M. (2020). Type B aortic dissection in young individuals with confirmed and presumed heritable thoracic aortic disease. The Annals of Thoracic Surgery, 109(2), 534-540. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.athoracsur.2019.07.004</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang, Q., Zhang, J., Wang, H., Feng, Q., Luo, F., &amp; Xie, J. (2019). Compound heterozygous variants in MYH11 underlie autosomal recessive megacystis-microcolon-intestinal hypoperistalsis syndrome in a Chinese family. Journal of Human Genetics, 64(11), 1067-1073. https://doi.org/10.1038/s10038-019-0651-z</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ware, S. M., Shikany, A., Landis, B. J., James, J. F., &amp; Hinton, R. B. (2014). Twins with progressive thoracic aortic aneurysm, recurrent dissection and ACTA2 mutation. Pediatrics, 134(4), e1218-e1223. https://doi.org/10.1542/peds.2013-2503</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang, A., Jo, A., Grajewski, K., &amp; Kim, J. (2019). Characteristic cerebrovascular findings associated with ACTA2 gene mutations. Canadian Journal of Neurological Sciences, 46(3), 342-343. https://doi.org/10.1017/cjn.2019.20</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35567597</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>14</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1552-4833</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>14</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>American journal of medical genetics. Part A</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Am J Med Genet A</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Expanding ACTA2 genotypes with corresponding phenotypes overlapping with smooth muscle dysfunction syndrome.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/ajmg.a.62775</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Pathogenic variants in ACTA2, encoding smooth muscle α-actin, predispose to thoracic aortic aneurysms and dissections. ACTA2 variants altering arginine 179 predispose to a more severe, multisystemic disease termed smooth muscle dysfunction syndrome (SMDS; OMIM 613834). Vascular complications of SMDS include patent ductus arteriosus (PDA) or aortopulmonary window, early-onset thoracic aortic disease (TAD), moyamoya-like cerebrovascular disease, and primary pulmonary hypertension. Patients also have dysfunction of other smooth muscle-dependent systems, including congenital mydriasis, hypotonic bladder, and gut hypoperistalsis. Here, we describe five patients with novel heterozygous ACTA2 missense variants, p.Arg179Gly, p.Met46Arg, p.Thr204Ile, p.Arg39Cys, and p.Ile66Asn, who have clinical complications that align or overlap with SMDS. Patients with the ACTA2 p.Arg179Gly and p.Thr204Ile variants display classic features of SMDS. The patient with the ACTA2 p.Met46Arg variant exhibits exclusively vascular complications of SMDS, including early-onset TAD, PDA, and moyamoya-like cerebrovascular disease. The patient with the ACTA2 p.Ile66Asn variant has an unusual vascular complication, a large fusiform internal carotid artery aneurysm. The patient with the ACTA2 p.Arg39Cys variant has pulmonary, gastrointestinal, and genitourinary complications of SMDS but no vascular manifestations. Identifying pathogenic ACTA2 variants associated with features of SMDS is critical for aggressive surveillance and management of vascular and nonvascular complications and delineating the molecular pathogenesis of SMDS.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kaw</LastName>
            <ForeName>Anita</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3690-711X</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Medical Genetic, Department of Internal Medicine, McGovern Medical School, University of Texas Health Science Center at Houston, Houston, Texas, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kaw</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kaveeta</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Medical Genetic, Department of Internal Medicine, McGovern Medical School, University of Texas Health Science Center at Houston, Houston, Texas, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hostetler</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ellen M</ForeName>
            <Initials>EM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Medical Genetic, Department of Internal Medicine, McGovern Medical School, University of Texas Health Science Center at Houston, Houston, Texas, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Beleza-Meireles</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ana</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Bristol Regional Clinical Genetics Service, St Michael's Hospital, Bristol, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Smith-Collins</LastName>
            <ForeName>Adam</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Regional Neonatal Intensive Care Unit, St Michael's Hospital, Bristol, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Armstrong</LastName>
            <ForeName>Catherine</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Bristol Royal Hospital for Children, Bristol, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Scurr</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ingrid</ForeName>
            <Initials>I</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Bristol Regional Clinical Genetics Service, St Michael's Hospital, Bristol, UK.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Cotts</LastName>
            <ForeName>Timothy</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Pediatric Cardiology, Department of Pediatrics, Michigan Medicine, University of Michigan at Ann Arbor, Ann Arbor, Michigan, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Aatre</LastName>
            <ForeName>Rajani</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Franklin Cardiovascular Center, Department of Internal Medicine, Michigan Medicine, University of Michigan at Ann Arbor, Ann Arbor, Michigan, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bamshad</LastName>
            <ForeName>Michael J</ForeName>
            <Initials>MJ</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Medical Genetics, Department of Pediatrics, University of Washington, Seattle, Washington, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Earl</LastName>
            <ForeName>Dawn</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Medical Genetics, Department of Pediatrics, University of Washington, Seattle, Washington, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Groner</LastName>
            <ForeName>Abraham</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Cardiology, Department of Pediatrics, The University of Chicago, Chicago, Illinois, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Agre</LastName>
            <ForeName>Katherine</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Invitae, San Francisco, California, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Raveh</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yehuda</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4780-2743</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Anesthesia, University of Miami/Jackson Memorial Hospital, Miami, Florida, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kwartler</LastName>
            <ForeName>Callie S</ForeName>
            <Initials>CS</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3722-9939</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Medical Genetic, Department of Internal Medicine, McGovern Medical School, University of Texas Health Science Center at Houston, Houston, Texas, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Milewicz</LastName>
            <ForeName>Dianna M</ForeName>
            <Initials>DM</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7806-0068</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Medical Genetic, Department of Internal Medicine, McGovern Medical School, University of Texas Health Science Center at Houston, Houston, Texas, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <GrantList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>NIH R01HL109942</GrantID>
            <Acronym>NH</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>NIH TL1TR003169</GrantID>
            <Acronym>NH</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>NIH UL1TR003167</GrantID>
            <Acronym>NH</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>NIH T32GM120011</GrantID>
            <Acronym>NH</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>RO1HL146583</GrantID>
            <Acronym>NH</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
        </GrantList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Am J Med Genet A</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101235741</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1552-4825</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ACTA2</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Smooth Muscle Dysfunction Syndrome</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">thoracic aortic disease</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
          <Hour>11</Hour>
          <Minute>2</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35567597</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ajmg.a.62775</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Amans, M. R., Stout, C., Fox, C., Narvid, J., Hetts, S. W., Cooke, D. L., Higashida, R. T., Dowd, C. F., McSwain, H., &amp; Halbach, V. V. (2013). Cerebral arteriopathy associated with Arg179His ACTA2 mutation. BML Case Reports, 2013. https://doi.org/10.1136/bcr-2013-010997</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Biesecker, L. G., Adam, M. P., Alkuraya, F. S., Amemiya, A. R., Bamshad, M. J., Beck, A. E., Bennett, J. T., Bird, L. M., Carey, J. C., Chung, B., Clark, R. D., Cox, T. C., Curry, C., Dinulos, M. B. P., Dobyns, W. B., Giampietro, P. F., Girisha, K. M., Glass, I. A., Graham, J. M., Jr., … Zarate, Y. A. (2021). A dyadic approach to the delineation of diagnostic entities in clinical genomics. American Journal of Human Genetics, 108(1), 8-15. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ajhg.2020.11.013</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Diness, B. R., Palmquist, R. N., Norling, R., Hove, H., Bundgaard, H., Hertz, J. M., Kondziella, D., Krieger, D., Dunø, M., &amp; Grønborg, S. (2020). Expanding the cerebrovascular phenotype of the p.R258H variant in ACTA2 related hereditary thoracic aortic disease (HTAD). Journal of the Neurological Sciences, 415, 116897. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jns.2020.116897</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gauthier, J., Ouled Amar Bencheikh, B., Hamdan, F. F., Harrison, S. M., Baker, L. A., Couture, F., Thiffault, I., Ouazzani, R., Samuels, M. E., Mitchell, G. A., Rouleau, G. A., Michaud, J. L., &amp; Soucy, J.-F. (2015). A homozygous loss-of-function variant in MYH11 in a case with megacystis-microcolon-intestinal hypoperistalsis syndrome. European Journal of Human Genetics, 23(9), 1266-1268. https://doi.org/10.1038/ejhg.2014.256</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Georgescu, M. M., Pinho Mda, C., Richardson, T. E., Torrealba, J., Buja, L. M., Milewicz, D. M., Raisanen, J. M., &amp; Burns, D. K. (2015). The defining pathology of the new clinical and histopathologic entity ACTA2-related cerebrovascular disease. Acta Neuropathologica Communications, 3, 81. https://doi.org/10.1186/s40478-015-0262-7</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guo, D. C., Pannu, H., Tran-Fadulu, V., Papke, C. L., Yu, R. K., Avidan, N., Bourgeois, S., Estrera, A. L., Safi, H. J., Sparks, E., Amor, D., Ades, L., McConnell, V., Willoughby, C. E., Abuelo, D., Willing, M., Lewis, R. A., Kim, D. H., Scherer, S., … Milewicz, D. M. (2007). Mutations in smooth muscle alpha-actin (ACTA2) lead to thoracic aortic aneurysms and dissections. Nature Genetics, 39(12), 1488-1493. https://doi.org/10.1038/ng.2007.6</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guo, D. C., Papke, C. L., Tran-Fadulu, V., Regalado, E. S., Avidan, N., Johnson, R. J., Kim, D. H., Pannu, H., Willing, M. C., Sparks, E., Pyeritz, R. E., Singh, M. N., Dalman, R. L., Grotta, J. C., Marian, A. J., Boerwinkle, E. A., Frazier, L. Q., LeMaire, S. A., Coselli, J. S., … Milewicz, D. M. (2009). Mutations in smooth muscle alpha-actin (ACTA2) cause coronary artery disease, stroke, and moyamoya disease, along with thoracic aortic disease. American Journal of Human Genetics, 84(5), 617-627. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ajhg.2009.04.007</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Halim, D., Brosens, E., Muller, F., Wangler, M. F., Beaudet, A. L., Lupski, J. R., Akdemir, Z. H. C., Doukas, M., Stoop, H. J., de Graaf, B. M., Brouwer, R. W. W., van Ijcken, W. F. J., Oury, J.-F., Rosenblatt, J., Burns, A. J., Tibboel, D., Hofstra, R. M. W., &amp; Alves, M. M. (2017). Loss-of-function variants in MYLK cause recessive megacystis microcolon intestinal hypoperistalsis syndrome. The American Journal of Human Genetics, 101(1), 123-129. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ajhg.2017.05.011</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hoffjan, S., Waldmüller, S., Blankenfeldt, W., Kötting, J., Gehle, P., Binner, P., Epplen, J. T., &amp; Scheffold, T. (2011). Three novel mutations in the ACTA2 gene in German patients with thoracic aortic aneurysms and dissections. European Journal of Human Genetics, 19(5), 520-524. https://doi.org/10.1038/ejhg.2010.239</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ke, T., Han, M., Zhao, M., Wang, Q. K., Zhang, H., Zhao, Y., Ruan, X., Li, H., Xu, C., &amp; Sun, T. (2016). Alpha-actin-2 mutations in Chinese patients with a non-syndromatic thoracic aortic aneurysm. BMC Medical Genetics, 17(1), 45. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12881-016-0310-6</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lauer, A., Speroni, S. L., Patel, J. B., Regalado, E., Choi, M., Smith, E., Kalpathy-Kramer, J., Caruso, P., Milewicz, D. M., &amp; Musolino, P. L. (2021). Cerebrovascular disease progression in patients with ACTA2 Arg179 pathogenic variants. Neurology, 96(4), e538-e552. https://doi.org/10.1212/wnl.0000000000011210</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lu, H., Fagnant, P. M., Bookwalter, C. S., Joel, P., &amp; Trybus, K. M. (2015). Vascular disease-causing mutation R258C in ACTA2 disrupts actin dynamics and interaction with myosin. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, 112(31), E4168-E4177. https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.1507587112</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lu, H., Fagnant, P. M., Krementsova, E. B., &amp; Trybus, K. M. (2016). Severe molecular defects exhibited by the R179H mutation in human vascular smooth muscle α-actin. The Journal of Biological Chemistry, 291(41), 21729-21739. https://doi.org/10.1074/jbc.M116.744011</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mc Glacken-Byrne, A. B., Prentice, D., Roshandel, D., Brown, M. R., Tuch, P., Yau, K. S. Y., Sivadorai, P., Davis, M. R., Laing, N. G., &amp; Chen, F. K. (2020). High-resolution iris and retinal imaging in multisystemic smooth muscle dysfunction syndrome due to a novel Asn117Lys substitution in ACTA2: A case report. BMC Ophthalmology, 20(1), 68. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12886-020-01344-w</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Milewicz, D. M., Guo, D. C., Tran-Fadulu, V., Lafont, A. L., Papke, C. L., Inamoto, S., Kwartler, C. S., &amp; Pannu, H. (2008). Genetic basis of thoracic aortic aneurysms and dissections: Focus on smooth muscle cell contractile dysfunction. Annual Review of Genomics and Human Genetics, 9, 283-302. https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev.genom.8.080706.092303</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Milewicz, D. M., Ostergaard, J. R., Ala-Kokko, L. M., Khan, N., Grange, D. K., Mendoza-Londono, R., Bradley, T. J., Olney, A. H., Ades, L., Maher, J. F., Guo, D., Buja, L. M., Kim, D., Hyland, J. C., &amp; Regalado, E. S. (2010). De novo ACTA2 mutation causes a novel syndrome of multisystemic smooth muscle dysfunction. American Journal of Medical Genetics. Part A, 152A(10), 2437-2443. https://doi.org/10.1002/ajmg.a.33657</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Milewicz, D. M., Trybus, K. M., Guo, D. C., Sweeney, H. L., Regalado, E., Kamm, K., &amp; Stull, J. T. (2017). Altered smooth muscle cell force generation as a driver of thoracic aortic aneurysms and dissections. Arteriosclerosis, Thrombosis, and Vascular Biology, 37(1), 26-34. https://doi.org/10.1161/atvbaha.116.303229</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morisaki, H., Akutsu, K., Ogino, H., Kondo, N., Yamanaka, I., Tsutsumi, Y., Yoshimuta, T., Okajima, T., Matsuda, H., Minatoya, K., Sasaki, H., Tanaka, H., Ishibashi-Ueda, H., &amp; Morisaki, T. (2009). Mutation of ACTA2 gene as an important cause of familial and nonfamilial nonsyndromatic thoracic aortic aneurysm and/or dissection (TAAD). Human Mutation, 30(10), 1406-1411. https://doi.org/10.1002/humu.21081</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Munot, P., Saunders, D. E., Milewicz, D. M., Regalado, E. S., Ostergaard, J. R., Braun, K. P., Kerr, T., Lichtenbelt, K. D., Philip, S., Rittey, C., Jacques, T. S., Cox, T. C., &amp; Ganesan, V. (2012). A novel distinctive cerebrovascular phenotype is associated with heterozygous Arg179 ACTA2 mutations. Brain, 135(Pt 8), 2506-2514. https://doi.org/10.1093/brain/aws172</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pinto, M. (2020). A novel ACTA2 gene disease-causing variant presenting with a complex brain phenotype. Sinapse, 20(4), 181-183. https://doi.org/10.46531/sinapse/CC/200032/2020</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Regalado, E. S., Guo, D.-C., Prakash, S., Bensend, T. A., Flynn, K., Estrera, A., Safi, H., Liang, D., Hyland, J., Child, A., Arno, G., Boileau, C., Jondeau, G., Braverman, A., Moran, R., Morisaki, T., Morisaki, H., Pyeritz, R., Coselli, J., … Milewicz, D. M. (2015). Aortic disease presentation and outcome associated with ACTA2 mutations. Circulation: Cardiovascular Genetics, 8(3), 457-464. https://doi.org/10.1161/CIRCGENETICS.114.000943</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Regalado, E. S., Mellor-Crummey, L., De Backer, J., Braverman, A. C., Ades, L., Benedict, S., Bradley, T. J., Brickner, M. E., Chatfield, K. C., Child, A., Feist, C., Holmes, K. W., Iannucci, G., Lorenz, B., Mark, P., Morisaki, T., Morisaki, H., Morris, S. A., Mitchell, A. L., … Milewicz, D. M. (2018, Oct). Clinical history and management recommendations of the smooth muscle dysfunction syndrome due to ACTA2 arginine 179 alterations. Genetics in Medicine, 20(10), 1206-1215. https://doi.org/10.1038/gim.2017.245</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Richer, J., Milewicz, D. M., Gow, R., de Nanassy, J., Maharajh, G., Miller, E., Oppenheimer, L., Weiler, G., &amp; O'Connor, M. (2012). R179H mutation in ACTA2 expanding the phenotype to include prune-belly sequence and skin manifestations. American Journal of Medical Genetics Part A, 158A(3), 664-668. https://doi.org/10.1002/ajmg.a.35206</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shalhub, S., Roman, M. J., Eagle, K. A., LeMaire, S. A., Zhang, Q., Evangelista, A., &amp; Milewicz, D. M. (2020). Type B aortic dissection in young individuals with confirmed and presumed heritable thoracic aortic disease. The Annals of Thoracic Surgery, 109(2), 534-540. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.athoracsur.2019.07.004</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang, Q., Zhang, J., Wang, H., Feng, Q., Luo, F., &amp; Xie, J. (2019). Compound heterozygous variants in MYH11 underlie autosomal recessive megacystis-microcolon-intestinal hypoperistalsis syndrome in a Chinese family. Journal of Human Genetics, 64(11), 1067-1073. https://doi.org/10.1038/s10038-019-0651-z</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ware, S. M., Shikany, A., Landis, B. J., James, J. F., &amp; Hinton, R. B. (2014). Twins with progressive thoracic aortic aneurysm, recurrent dissection and ACTA2 mutation. Pediatrics, 134(4), e1218-e1223. https://doi.org/10.1542/peds.2013-2503</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang, A., Jo, A., Grajewski, K., &amp; Kim, J. (2019). Characteristic cerebrovascular findings associated with ACTA2 gene mutations. Canadian Journal of Neurological Sciences, 46(3), 342-343. https://doi.org/10.1017/cjn.2019.20</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
