<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35561724</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>17</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>18</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2214-109X</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>10</Volume>
            <Issue>6</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>The Lancet. Global health</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Lancet Glob Health</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Determining thresholds for spatial urban design and transport features that support walking to create healthy and sustainable cities: findings from the IPEN Adult study.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e895</StartPage>
          <EndPage>e906</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e895-e906</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/S2214-109X(22)00068-7</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S2214-109X(22)00068-7</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>An essential characteristic of a healthy and sustainable city is a physically active population. Effective policies for healthy and sustainable cities require evidence-informed quantitative targets. We aimed to identify the minimum thresholds for urban design and transport features associated with two physical activity criteria: at least 80% probability of engaging in any walking for transport and WHO's target of at least 15% relative reduction in insufficient physical activity through walking. The International Physical Activity and the Environment Network Adult (known as IPEN) study (N=11 615; 14 cities across ten countries) provided data on local urban design and transport features linked to walking. Associations of these features with the probability of engaging in any walking for transport and sufficient physical activity (≥150 min/week) by walking were estimated, and thresholds associated with the physical activity criteria were determined. Curvilinear associations of population, street intersection, and public transport densities with walking were found. Neighbourhoods exceeding around 5700 people per km<sup>2</sup>, 100 intersections per km<sup>2</sup>, and 25 public transport stops per km<sup>2</sup> were associated with meeting one or both physical activity criteria. Shorter distances to the nearest park were associated with more physical activity. We use the results to suggest specific target values for each feature as benchmarks for progression towards creating healthy and sustainable cities.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022 The Author(s). Published by Elsevier Ltd. This is an Open Access article under the CC BY 4.0 license. Published by Elsevier Ltd.. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Cerin</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ester</ForeName>
            <Initials>E</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Mary MacKillop Institute for Health Research, Australian Catholic University, Melbourne, VIC, Australia; School of Public Health, The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, Hong Kong Special Administrative Region, China. Electronic address: ester.cerin@acu.edu.au.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sallis</LastName>
            <ForeName>James F</ForeName>
            <Initials>JF</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Mary MacKillop Institute for Health Research, Australian Catholic University, Melbourne, VIC, Australia; Herbert Wertheim School of Public Health and Human Longevity Science, University of California San Diego, CA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Salvo</LastName>
            <ForeName>Deborah</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Prevention Research Center, Brown School, Washington University in St Louis, St Louis, MO, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hinckson</LastName>
            <ForeName>Erica</ForeName>
            <Initials>E</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Human Potential Centre, School of Sport and Recreation, Auckland University of Technology, Auckland, New Zealand.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Conway</LastName>
            <ForeName>Terry L</ForeName>
            <Initials>TL</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Herbert Wertheim School of Public Health and Human Longevity Science, University of California San Diego, CA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Owen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Neville</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Centre for Urban Transitions, Swinburne University of Technology and Baker Heart and Diabetes Institute, Melbourne, VIC, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>van Dyck</LastName>
            <ForeName>Delfien</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Movement and Sports Sciences, Faculty of Medicine and Sports Sciences, Ghent University, Ghent, Belgium.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lowe</LastName>
            <ForeName>Melanie</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Melbourne Centre for Cities, University of Melbourne, Melbourne, VIC, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Higgs</LastName>
            <ForeName>Carl</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Healthy Liveable Cities Lab, RMIT University, Melbourne, VIC, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Moudon</LastName>
            <ForeName>Anne Vernez</ForeName>
            <Initials>AV</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Urban Planning and Design, Urban Form Lab, University of Washington, Seattle, WA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Adams</LastName>
            <ForeName>Marc A</ForeName>
            <Initials>MA</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>College of Health Solutions, Senior Global Futures Scientist, Julie Ann Wrigley Global Futures Laboratory, Arizona State University, Phoenix, AZ, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Cain</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kelli L</ForeName>
            <Initials>KL</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Herbert Wertheim School of Public Health and Human Longevity Science, University of California San Diego, CA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Christiansen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Lars Breum</ForeName>
            <Initials>LB</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Sports Science and Clinical Biomechanics, University of Southern Denmark, Odense, Denmark.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Davey</LastName>
            <ForeName>Rachel</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Health Research Institute, University of Canberra, Canberra, ACT, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Dygrýn</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jan</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Faculty of Physical Culture, Palacký University Olomouc, Olomouc, Czech Republic.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Frank</LastName>
            <ForeName>Lawrence D</ForeName>
            <Initials>LD</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Urban Studies and Planning, University of California San Diego, CA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Reis</LastName>
            <ForeName>Rodrigo</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Prevention Research Center, Brown School, Washington University in St Louis, St Louis, MO, USA; Graduate Program in Urban Management, Pontifical Catholic University of Parana, Curitiba, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sarmiento</LastName>
            <ForeName>Olga L</ForeName>
            <Initials>OL</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Medicine at Universidad de los Andes, Bogotá, Colombia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Adlakha</LastName>
            <ForeName>Deepti</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Landscape Architecture and Environmental Planning, Natural Learning Initiative, College of Design, North Carolina State University, Raleigh, NC, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Boeing</LastName>
            <ForeName>Geoff</ForeName>
            <Initials>G</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Urban Planning and Spatial Analysis, Sol Price School of Public Policy, University of Southern California, Los Angeles, California, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Liu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Shiqin</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Public Policy and Urban Affairs, Northeastern University, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Giles-Corti</LastName>
            <ForeName>Billie</ForeName>
            <Initials>B</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Healthy Liveable Cities Lab, RMIT University, Melbourne, VIC, Australia; School of Population Health, The University of Western Australia, Perth, WA, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Lancet Glob Health</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101613665</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2214-109X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002947" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Cities</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004779" MajorTopicYN="Y">Environment Design</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006304" MajorTopicYN="N">Health Status</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012111" MajorTopicYN="N">Residence Characteristics</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014186" MajorTopicYN="N">Transportation</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016138" MajorTopicYN="Y">Walking</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <CoiStatement>Declaration of interests JFS reports grants from US National Institutes of Health (NIH), during the conduct of the study; personal fees from Sports, Play, and Active Recreation for Kids (SPARK) programmes of Gopher Sport, other from Rails to Trails Conservancy, outside the submitted work; and a copyright on SPARK physical activity programmes with royalties paid by Gopher Sport. MAA reports grants from National Heart, Lung and Blood Institute at the National Institutes of Health (R01HL111378) during the conduct of the study. KLC reports grants from NIH, during the conduct of the study. GB reports grants from The Public Good Projects, during the conduct of the study. BG-C reports a Senior Principal Research Fellowship (GNT1107672) and grant (number 1061404) support from National Health and Medical Research Council (NHMRC) during the conduct of the study. EC and JFS were supported by the Australian Catholic University. NHMRC funding supported CH through a Centre for Research Excellence in Healthy Liveable Communities (#1061404). DA was supported by an Impact Acceleration Award from the Economic and Social Research Council and funding from the Global Challenges Research Fund administered by the Department for the Economy, Northern Ireland, UK. SL was supported by the experiential fellowships from College of Social Science and Humanities, Northeastern University, Boston, USA. DS was supported by Washington University in St Louis, Center for Diabetes Translation Research (#P30DK092950 from National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive Diseases [NIDDK]/NIH) and by the Cooperative Agreement Number U48DP006395 from the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC). The content of this article is solely the responsibility of the authors and does not represent the official views of any of the NIDDK/NIH, CDC, or of any of the funding agencies supporting this work. Funding sources had no role in writing the manuscript or the decision to submit for publication. We have not been paid to write this article by a pharmaceutical company or other agency. The IPEN Adult study was partly supported by the National Cancer Institute (NCI) of the NIH. US data collection and coordinating centre processing was supported by NIH grants R01 HL67350 (National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute) and R01 CA127296 (NCI). The study in Bogota, Colombia was funded by Colciencias (grant 519_2010), Fogarty, and CeiBA. NO was supported by National Health and Medical Research Council Program Grant (grant number 569940), NHMRC Senior Principal Research Fellowship (number 1003960), and by the Victorian Government's Operational Infrastructure Support Program. The Danish study was partly funded by the Municipality of Aarhus. Data collection in the Czech Republic was supported by the grant Ministry of Education, Youth and Sports (MSM 6198959221). Data collection in New Zealand was supported by the Health Research Council of New Zealand (grant 07/356). Data collection in Mexico was supported by the CDC Foundation, which received an unrestricted grant from The Coca-Cola Company. The UK study was funded by the Medical Research Council under the National Preventive Research Initiative. All authors had access to the data in the study and accept responsibility to submit for publication. All other authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
          <Hour>20</Hour>
          <Minute>9</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35561724</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2214-109X(22)00068-7</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">S2214-109X(22)00068-7</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35561724</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>17</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>18</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2214-109X</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>10</Volume>
            <Issue>6</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>The Lancet. Global health</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Lancet Glob Health</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Determining thresholds for spatial urban design and transport features that support walking to create healthy and sustainable cities: findings from the IPEN Adult study.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e895</StartPage>
          <EndPage>e906</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e895-e906</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/S2214-109X(22)00068-7</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S2214-109X(22)00068-7</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>An essential characteristic of a healthy and sustainable city is a physically active population. Effective policies for healthy and sustainable cities require evidence-informed quantitative targets. We aimed to identify the minimum thresholds for urban design and transport features associated with two physical activity criteria: at least 80% probability of engaging in any walking for transport and WHO's target of at least 15% relative reduction in insufficient physical activity through walking. The International Physical Activity and the Environment Network Adult (known as IPEN) study (N=11 615; 14 cities across ten countries) provided data on local urban design and transport features linked to walking. Associations of these features with the probability of engaging in any walking for transport and sufficient physical activity (≥150 min/week) by walking were estimated, and thresholds associated with the physical activity criteria were determined. Curvilinear associations of population, street intersection, and public transport densities with walking were found. Neighbourhoods exceeding around 5700 people per km<sup>2</sup>, 100 intersections per km<sup>2</sup>, and 25 public transport stops per km<sup>2</sup> were associated with meeting one or both physical activity criteria. Shorter distances to the nearest park were associated with more physical activity. We use the results to suggest specific target values for each feature as benchmarks for progression towards creating healthy and sustainable cities.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022 The Author(s). Published by Elsevier Ltd. This is an Open Access article under the CC BY 4.0 license. Published by Elsevier Ltd.. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Cerin</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ester</ForeName>
            <Initials>E</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Mary MacKillop Institute for Health Research, Australian Catholic University, Melbourne, VIC, Australia; School of Public Health, The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, Hong Kong Special Administrative Region, China. Electronic address: ester.cerin@acu.edu.au.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sallis</LastName>
            <ForeName>James F</ForeName>
            <Initials>JF</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Mary MacKillop Institute for Health Research, Australian Catholic University, Melbourne, VIC, Australia; Herbert Wertheim School of Public Health and Human Longevity Science, University of California San Diego, CA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Salvo</LastName>
            <ForeName>Deborah</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Prevention Research Center, Brown School, Washington University in St Louis, St Louis, MO, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hinckson</LastName>
            <ForeName>Erica</ForeName>
            <Initials>E</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Human Potential Centre, School of Sport and Recreation, Auckland University of Technology, Auckland, New Zealand.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Conway</LastName>
            <ForeName>Terry L</ForeName>
            <Initials>TL</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Herbert Wertheim School of Public Health and Human Longevity Science, University of California San Diego, CA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Owen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Neville</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Centre for Urban Transitions, Swinburne University of Technology and Baker Heart and Diabetes Institute, Melbourne, VIC, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>van Dyck</LastName>
            <ForeName>Delfien</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Movement and Sports Sciences, Faculty of Medicine and Sports Sciences, Ghent University, Ghent, Belgium.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lowe</LastName>
            <ForeName>Melanie</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Melbourne Centre for Cities, University of Melbourne, Melbourne, VIC, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Higgs</LastName>
            <ForeName>Carl</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Healthy Liveable Cities Lab, RMIT University, Melbourne, VIC, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Moudon</LastName>
            <ForeName>Anne Vernez</ForeName>
            <Initials>AV</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Urban Planning and Design, Urban Form Lab, University of Washington, Seattle, WA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Adams</LastName>
            <ForeName>Marc A</ForeName>
            <Initials>MA</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>College of Health Solutions, Senior Global Futures Scientist, Julie Ann Wrigley Global Futures Laboratory, Arizona State University, Phoenix, AZ, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Cain</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kelli L</ForeName>
            <Initials>KL</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Herbert Wertheim School of Public Health and Human Longevity Science, University of California San Diego, CA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Christiansen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Lars Breum</ForeName>
            <Initials>LB</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Sports Science and Clinical Biomechanics, University of Southern Denmark, Odense, Denmark.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Davey</LastName>
            <ForeName>Rachel</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Health Research Institute, University of Canberra, Canberra, ACT, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Dygrýn</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jan</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Faculty of Physical Culture, Palacký University Olomouc, Olomouc, Czech Republic.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Frank</LastName>
            <ForeName>Lawrence D</ForeName>
            <Initials>LD</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Urban Studies and Planning, University of California San Diego, CA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Reis</LastName>
            <ForeName>Rodrigo</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Prevention Research Center, Brown School, Washington University in St Louis, St Louis, MO, USA; Graduate Program in Urban Management, Pontifical Catholic University of Parana, Curitiba, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sarmiento</LastName>
            <ForeName>Olga L</ForeName>
            <Initials>OL</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Medicine at Universidad de los Andes, Bogotá, Colombia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Adlakha</LastName>
            <ForeName>Deepti</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Landscape Architecture and Environmental Planning, Natural Learning Initiative, College of Design, North Carolina State University, Raleigh, NC, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Boeing</LastName>
            <ForeName>Geoff</ForeName>
            <Initials>G</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Urban Planning and Spatial Analysis, Sol Price School of Public Policy, University of Southern California, Los Angeles, California, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Liu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Shiqin</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Public Policy and Urban Affairs, Northeastern University, Boston, MA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Giles-Corti</LastName>
            <ForeName>Billie</ForeName>
            <Initials>B</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Healthy Liveable Cities Lab, RMIT University, Melbourne, VIC, Australia; School of Population Health, The University of Western Australia, Perth, WA, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Lancet Glob Health</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101613665</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2214-109X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002947" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Cities</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004779" MajorTopicYN="Y">Environment Design</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006304" MajorTopicYN="N">Health Status</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012111" MajorTopicYN="N">Residence Characteristics</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014186" MajorTopicYN="N">Transportation</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016138" MajorTopicYN="Y">Walking</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <CoiStatement>Declaration of interests JFS reports grants from US National Institutes of Health (NIH), during the conduct of the study; personal fees from Sports, Play, and Active Recreation for Kids (SPARK) programmes of Gopher Sport, other from Rails to Trails Conservancy, outside the submitted work; and a copyright on SPARK physical activity programmes with royalties paid by Gopher Sport. MAA reports grants from National Heart, Lung and Blood Institute at the National Institutes of Health (R01HL111378) during the conduct of the study. KLC reports grants from NIH, during the conduct of the study. GB reports grants from The Public Good Projects, during the conduct of the study. BG-C reports a Senior Principal Research Fellowship (GNT1107672) and grant (number 1061404) support from National Health and Medical Research Council (NHMRC) during the conduct of the study. EC and JFS were supported by the Australian Catholic University. NHMRC funding supported CH through a Centre for Research Excellence in Healthy Liveable Communities (#1061404). DA was supported by an Impact Acceleration Award from the Economic and Social Research Council and funding from the Global Challenges Research Fund administered by the Department for the Economy, Northern Ireland, UK. SL was supported by the experiential fellowships from College of Social Science and Humanities, Northeastern University, Boston, USA. DS was supported by Washington University in St Louis, Center for Diabetes Translation Research (#P30DK092950 from National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive Diseases [NIDDK]/NIH) and by the Cooperative Agreement Number U48DP006395 from the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC). The content of this article is solely the responsibility of the authors and does not represent the official views of any of the NIDDK/NIH, CDC, or of any of the funding agencies supporting this work. Funding sources had no role in writing the manuscript or the decision to submit for publication. We have not been paid to write this article by a pharmaceutical company or other agency. The IPEN Adult study was partly supported by the National Cancer Institute (NCI) of the NIH. US data collection and coordinating centre processing was supported by NIH grants R01 HL67350 (National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute) and R01 CA127296 (NCI). The study in Bogota, Colombia was funded by Colciencias (grant 519_2010), Fogarty, and CeiBA. NO was supported by National Health and Medical Research Council Program Grant (grant number 569940), NHMRC Senior Principal Research Fellowship (number 1003960), and by the Victorian Government's Operational Infrastructure Support Program. The Danish study was partly funded by the Municipality of Aarhus. Data collection in the Czech Republic was supported by the grant Ministry of Education, Youth and Sports (MSM 6198959221). Data collection in New Zealand was supported by the Health Research Council of New Zealand (grant 07/356). Data collection in Mexico was supported by the CDC Foundation, which received an unrestricted grant from The Coca-Cola Company. The UK study was funded by the Medical Research Council under the National Preventive Research Initiative. All authors had access to the data in the study and accept responsibility to submit for publication. All other authors declare no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
          <Hour>20</Hour>
          <Minute>9</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35561724</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2214-109X(22)00068-7</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">S2214-109X(22)00068-7</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
