<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35562327</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>13</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1759-7714</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>13</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Thoracic cancer</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Thorac Cancer</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>A randomized phase II study of docetaxel or pemetrexed with or without the continuation of gefitinib after disease progression in elderly patients with non-small cell lung cancer harboring EGFR mutations (JMTO LC12-01).</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/1759-7714.14465</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Gefitinib (G) is a recommended molecular-targeted agent for elderly patients with epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR)-mutant non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC). Docetaxel (Doc) and pemetrexed (Pem) have similar efficacies, and either is often used as the sole agent during treatment. The efficacy of continuing G after progressive disease (PD) develops has been reported. It remains unclear whether the continuation of G in combination with a single cytotoxic agent beyond PD is beneficial for elderly patients. Here, we conducted a randomized phase II study to assess the efficacy and safety of cytotoxic chemotherapy with G for elderly patients with progressive EGFR-mutant NSCLC.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Elderly patients with EGFR-mutant NSCLC with PD previously treated with G were enrolled. Patients received Pem 500 mg/m or Doc 60 mg/m every 21 days and were randomly assigned to receive chemotherapy with 250 mg G (G+ Doc/Pem arm) or without G (Doc/Pem arm) until further disease progression or unacceptable toxicity.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">This trial was terminated early owing to slow accrual. A group of 22 patients underwent analysis. The primary endpoint, progression-free survival (PFS), was significantly longer in the G + Doc/Pem arm (median: 1.6 months vs. 5.6 months, hazard ratio = 0.40, 95% CI: 0.16-0.99, p = 0.0391). Adverse events ≥ grade 3 were more frequent in the G + Doc/Pem arm (45.5% vs. 90.9%, p = 0.032).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Patients on G and Pem or Doc beyond PD showed a longer PFS than those on single-agent chemotherapy; however, it was associated with increased toxicity.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Authors. Thoracic Cancer published by China Lung Oncology Group and John Wiley &amp; Sons Australia, Ltd.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Asami</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kazuhiro</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5077-0826</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Asami Naika Clinic, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ando</LastName>
            <ForeName>Masahiko</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Advanced Medicine, Nagoya University Hospital, Nagoya, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nishimura</LastName>
            <ForeName>Takashi</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Kyoto Katsura Hospital, Kyoto, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yokoi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Takashi</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Oncology, Hyogo College of Medicine, Hyogo, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tamura</LastName>
            <ForeName>Atsuhisa</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Center for Pulmonary Diseases, Tokyo National Hospital, Tokyo, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Minato</LastName>
            <ForeName>Koichi</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Gunma Prefectural Cancer Center, Gunma, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mori</LastName>
            <ForeName>Masahide</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Oncology, National Hospital Organization Osaka Toneyama Medical Center, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ogushi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Fumitaka</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3525-3457</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Kochi National Hospital, Kochi, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yamamoto</LastName>
            <ForeName>Akiyoshi</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Takamatsu Red Cross Hospital, Kagawa, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yoshioka</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hiroshige</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Oncology, Kansai Medical University Hospital, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kawahara</LastName>
            <ForeName>Masaaki</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, KKR Otemae Hospital, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Atagi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Shinji</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Thoracic Oncology, National Hospital Organization Kinki-Chuo Chest Medical Center, Osaka, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>Singapore</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Thorac Cancer</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101531441</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1759-7706</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chemotherapy</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">elderly</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">epidermal growth factor receptor mutation</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">gefitinib</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">non-small cell lung cancer</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
          <Hour>22</Hour>
          <Minute>33</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35562327</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/1759-7714.14465</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barta JA, Powell CA, Wisnivesky JP. Global epidemiology of lung cancer. Ann Glob Health. 2019;85:8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Death rates fall for 8 of 10 top causes; Alzheimer's up to no. 6. Hosp Health Netw. 2008;82:127.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Travis WD, Rekhtman N, Riley GJ, Geisinger KR, Asamura H, Brambilla E, et al. Pathologic diagnosis of advanced lung cancer based on small biopsies and cytology: a paradigm shift. J Thorac Oncol. 2010;5:411-4.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yamaguchi T, Nishiura H. Predicting the epidemiological dynamics of lung cancer in Japan. J Clin Med. 2019;8:326.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Takayuki N, Keiko T, Junji U, Yoshiko K, Nobuyo T, Tadaaki Y, et al. Advanced non-small-cell lng cancer in elderly patients: patient features and therapeutic management. Biomed Res Int. 2018;2018:8202971.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kudoh S, Takeda K, Nakagawa K, Takada M, Katakami N, Matsui K, et al. Phase III study of docetaxel compared with vinorelbine in elderly patients with advanced non-small-cell lung cancer: results of the West Japan thoracic oncology group trial (WJTOG 9904). J Clin Oncol. 2006;24:3657-63.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weiss GJ, Langer C, Rosell R, Hanna N, Shepherd F, Einhorn LH, et al. Elderly patients benefit from second-line cytotoxic chemotherapy: a subset analysis of a randomized phase III trial of pemetrexed compared with docetaxel in patients with previously treated advanced non-small-cell lung cancer. J Clin Oncol. 2006;24:4405-11.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gridelli C, Brodowicz T, Langer CJ, Peterson P, Islam M, Guba SC, et al. Pemetrexed therapy in elderly patients with good performance status: analysis of two phase III trials of patients with nonsquamous non-small-cell lung cancer. Clin Lung Cancer. 2012;13:340-6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mok TS, Wu YL, Thongprasert S, Yang CH, Chu DT, Saijo N, et al. Gefitinib or carboplatin-paclitaxel in pulmonary adenocarcinoma. N Engl J Med. 2009;361:947-57.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mitsudomi T, Morita S, Yatabe Y, Negoro S, Okamoto I, Tsurutani J, et al. Gefitinib versus cisplatin plus docetaxel in patients with non-small-cell lung cancer harbouring mutations of the epidermal growth factor receptor (WJTOG3405): an open label, randomised phase 3 trial. Lancet Oncol. 2010;11:121-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maemondo M, Inoue A, Kobayashi K, Sugawara S, Oizumi S, Isobe H, et al. Gefitinib or chemotherapy for non-small-cell lung cancer with mutated EGFR. N Engl J Med. 2010;362:2380-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maemondo M, Minegishi Y, Inoue A, Kobayashi K, Harada M, Okinaga S, et al. First-line gefitinib in patients aged 75 or older with advanced non-small cell lung cancer harboring epidermal growth factor receptor mutations: NEJ 003 study. J Thorac Oncol. 2012;7:1417-22.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Asami K, Koizumi T, Hirai K, Ameshima S, Tsukadaira A, Morozumi N, et al. Gefitinib as first-line treatment in elderly epidermal growth factor receptor-mutated patients with advanced lung adenocarcinoma: results of a Nagano lung cancer research group study. Clin Lung Cancer. 2011;12:387-92.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Manegold C, Gatzemeier U, Buchholz E, Smith RP, Fandi A. A pilot trial of gefitinib in combination with docetaxel in patients with locally advanced or metastatic non-small-cell lung cancer. Clin Lung Cancer. 2005;6:343-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yoshimura N, Okishio K, Mitsuoka S, Kimura T, Kawaguchi T, Kobayashi M, et al. Prospective assessment of continuation of erlotinib or gefitinib in patients with acquired resistance to erlotinib or gefitinib followed by the addition of pemetrexed. J Thorac Oncol. 2013;8:96-101.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chaft JE, Oxnard GR, Sima CS, Kris MG, Miller VA, Riely GJ. Disease flare after tyrosine kinase inhibitor discontinuation in patients with EGFR-mutant lung cancer and acquired resistance to erlotinib or gefitinib: implications for clinical trial design. Clin Cancer Res. 2011;17:6298-303.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Asami K, Okuma T, Hirashima T, Kawahara M, Atagi S, Kawaguchi T, et al. Continued treatment with gefitinib beyond progressive disease benefits patients with activating EGFR mutations. Lung Cancer. 2013;79:276-82.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schoenfeld D. The asymptotic properties of nonparametric tests for comparing survival distributions. Biometrika. 1981;68:316-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gridelli C, Perrone F, Gallo C, Cigolari S, Rossi A, Piantedosi F, et al. Chemotherapy for elderly patients with advanced non-small-cell lung cancer: the multicenter Italian lung cancer in the elderly study (MILES) phase III randomized trial. J Natl Cancer Inst. 2003;95:362-72.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Inoue A, Kobayashi K, Maemondo M, Sugawara S, Oizumi S, Isobe H, et al. Updated overall survival results from a randomized phase III trial comparing gefitinib with carboplatin-paclitaxel for chemo-naive non-small cell lung cancer with sensitive EGFR gene mutations (NEJ002). Ann Oncol. 2013;24:54-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yoshioka H, Shimokawa M, Seto T, Morita S, Yatabe Y, Okamoto I, et al. Final overall survival results of WJTOG3405, a randomized phase III trial comparing gefitinib versus cisplatin with docetaxel as the first-line treatment for patients with stage IIIB/IV or postoperative recurrent EGFR mutation-positive non-small-cell lung cancer. Ann Oncol. 2019;30:1978-84.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ohe Y, Ohashi Y, Kubota K, Tamura T, Nakagawa K, Negoro S, et al. Randomized phase III study of cisplatin plus irinotecan versus carboplatin plus paclitaxel, cisplatin plus gemcitabine, and cisplatin plus vinorelbine for advanced non-small-cell lung cancer: Four-Arm Cooperative Study in Japan. Ann Oncol. 2007;18:317-23.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scagliotti GV, Parikh P, von Pawel J, Biesma B, Vansteenkiste J, Manegold C, et al. Phase III study comparing cisplatin plus gemcitabine with cisplatin plus pemetrexed in chemotherapy-naive patients with advanced-stage non-small-cell lung cancer. J Clin Oncol. 2008;26:3543-51.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abe T, Takeda K, Ohe Y, Kudoh S, Ichinose Y, Okamoto H, et al. Randomized phase III trial comparing weekly docetaxel plus cisplatin versus docetaxel monotherapy every 3 weeks in elderly patients with advanced non-small-cell lung cancer: the intergroup trial JCOG0803/WJOG4307L. J Clin Oncol. 2015;33:575-81.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Okamoto I, Nokihara H, Nomura S, Niho S, Sugawara S, Horinouchi H, et al. Comparison of carboplatin plus pemetrexed followed by maintenance pemetrexed with docetaxel monotherapy in elderly patients with advanced nonsquamous non-small cell lung cancer: a phase 3 randomized clinical trial. JAMA. Oncologia. 2020;e196828.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Quoix E, Zalcman G, Oster JP, Westeel V, Pichon E, Lavolé A, et al. Carboplatin and weekly paclitaxel doublet chemotherapy compared with monotherapy in elderly patients with advanced non-small-cell lung cancer: IFCT-0501 randomised, phase 3 trial. Lancet. 2011;378:1079-88.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gridelli C, Aapro M, Ardizzoni A, Balducci L, de Marinis F, Kelly K, et al. Treatment of advanced non-small-cell lung cancer in the elderly: results of an international expert panel. J Clin Oncol. 2005;23:3125-37.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Takayuki N, Keiko T, Junji U, Yoshiko K, Nobuyo T, Tadaaki Y, et al. Advanced non-small-cell lung cancer in elderly patients: patient features and therapeutic management. Biomed Res Int. 2018;2018:8202971.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Frasci G, Lorusso V, Panza N, Comella P, Nicolella G, Bianco A, et al. Gemcitabine plus vinorelbine versus vinorelbine alone in elderly patients with advanced non-small-cell lung cancer. J Clin Oncol. 2000;18:2529-36.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hanna N, Shepherd FA, Fossella FV, Pereira JR, de Marinis F, von Pawel J, et al. Randomized phase III trial of pemetrexed versus docetaxel in patients with non-small-cell lung cancer previously treated with chemotherapy. J Clin Oncol. 2004;22:1589-97.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fukuda M, Kitazaki T, Ogawara D, Ichiki M, Mukae H, Maruyama R, et al. Randomized phase II study of pemetrexed or pemetrexed plus bevacizumab for elderly patients with previously untreated non-squamous non-small cell lung cancer: results of the lung oncology group in Kyushu (LOGIK1201). Lung Cancer. 2019;132:1-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hata A, Katakami N, Hattori Y, Tanaka K, Fujita S, Kotani Y, et al. Pemetrexed monotherapy for chemo-näive elderly (aged ≥ 80) patients with non-squamous non-small cell lung cancer: results from combined analysis of two single arm phase II studies (HANSHIN002 and 003). Cancer Chemother Pharmacol. 2017;79:689-95.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giaccone G, Herbst RS, Manegold C, Scagliotti G, Rosell R, Miller V, et al. Gefitinib in combination with gemcitabine and cisplatin in advanced non-small-cell lung cancer: a phase III trial--INTACT 1. J Clin Oncol. 2004;22:777-84.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Herbst RS, Giaccone G, Schiller JH, Natale RB, Miller V, Manegold C, et al. Gefitinib in combination with paclitaxel and carboplatin in advanced non-small-cell lung cancer: a phase III trial--INTACT 2. J Clin Oncol. 2004;22:785-94.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Simon GR, Extermann M, Chiappori A, Williams CC, Begum M, Kapoor R, et al. Phase 2 trial of docetaxel and gefitinib in the first-line treatment of patients with advanced nonsmall-cell lung cancer (NSCLC) who are 70 years of age or older. Cancer. 2008;112:2021-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Noronha V, Patil VM, Joshi A, Menon N, Chougule A, Mahajan A, et al. Gefitinib versus gefitinib plus pemetrexed and carboplatin chemotherapy in EGFR-mutated lung cancer. J Clin Oncol. 2020;38:124-36.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goldberg SB, Oxnard GR, Digumarthy S, Muzikansky A, Jackman DM, Lennes IT, et al. Chemotherapy with erlotinib or chemotherapy alone in advanced non-small cell lung cancer with acquired resistance to EGFR tyrosine kinase inhibitors. Oncologist. 2013;18:1214-20.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Soria JC, Wu YL, Nakagawa K, Kim SW, Yang JJ, Ahn MJ, et al. Gefitinib plus chemotherapy versus placebo plus chemotherapy in EGFR-mutation-positive non-small-cell lung cancer after progression on first-line gefitinib (IMPRESS): a phase 3 randomised trial. Lancet Oncol. 2015;16:990-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu SG, Liu YN, Tsai MF, Chang YL, Yu CJ, Yang PC, et al. The mechanism of acquired resistance to irreversible EGFR tyrosine kinase inhibitor-afatinib in lung adenocarcinoma patients. Oncotarget. 2016;7:12404-13.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goss G, Tsai CM, Shepherd FA, Bazhenova L, Lee JS, Chang GC, et al. Osimertinib for pretreated EGFR Thr790Met-positive advanced non-small-cell lung cancer (AURA2): a multicentre, open-label, single-arm, phase 2 study. Lancet Oncol. 2016;17:1643-52.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mok TS, Wu YL, Papadimitrakopoulou VA. Osimertinib in EGFR T790M-positive lung cancer. N Engl J Med. 2017;376:1993-4.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang JJ, Chen HJ, Yan HH, Zhang XC, Zhou Q, Su J, et al. Clinical modes of EGFR tyrosine kinase inhibitor failure and subsequent management in advanced non-small cell lung cancer. Lung Cancer. 2013;79:33-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Park K, Yu CJ, Kim SW, Lin MC, Sriuranpong V, Tsai CM, et al. First-line erlotinib therapy until and beyond response evaluation criteria in solid tumors progression in Asian patients with epidermal growth factor receptor mutation-positive non-small-cell lung cancer: the ASPIRATION study. JAMA Oncol. 2016;2:305-12.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lim SW, Park S, Kim Y, Cho JH, Park SE, Lee H, et al. Continuation of gefitinib beyond progression in patients with EGFR mutation-positive non-small-cell lung cancer: a phase II single-arm trial. Lung Cancer. 2018;124:293-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gridelli C, Langer C, Maione P, Rossi A, Schild SE. Lung cancer in the elderly. J Clin Oncol. 2007;25:1898-907.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
