<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35579856</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>17</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1936-0568</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>17</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Head and neck pathology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Head Neck Pathol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Oral Lichen Planus: Associations Between Histomorphometric Characteristics and White and Red Lesions.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s12105-022-01442-9</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Histomorphometry seems to provide more rigid quantitative elements for histological analysis and to bring less subjectivity to the diagnosis of oral lichen planus lesions (OLP). This study aimed to verify the association between white and red lesions and histomorphometric characteristics of OLP lesions. This retrospective cross-sectional study assessed 48 hematoxylin- and eosin-stained histological sections from incisional biopsies obtained from OLP cases. A single previously calibrated evaluator performed the light microscopy analyses to evaluate morphological and morphometric parameters. Analyses of associations among variables were performed using the Fisher's exact test. Morphometric variables were assessed using the Mann-Whitney non-parametric test. Comparisons among the three groups (age range) were performed using the Kruskal-Wallis test. In this study, 81.2% of the participants were women aged &lt; 50 years. Keratosis, acanthosis, and inflammatory infiltrates were noted in 10.4, 10.4, and 37.5% of moderate/severe cases, respectively. Inflammatory infiltrate (52.1%), papillary projections (54.2%), saw teeth (12.5%), basal layer degeneration (39.6%), and Civatte bodies (68.8%) were also observed. There was no significant association between lesion type and clinicopathological variables (p &gt; 0.05) or between lesion type and histological (p &gt; 0.05) and morphometric variables (p &gt; 0.05). Furthermore, the morphometric variables analyzed did not differ between white and red lesions (p &gt; 0.05) or in their associations with clinicopathological variables (p &gt; 0.05). The results of this investigation showed no associations between white and red OLP lesions and the histomorphometric characteristics evaluated.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Science+Business Media, LLC, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sanches</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ana Carla Barletta</ForeName>
            <Initials>ACB</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2342-6584</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Postgraduate Program in Interactive Processes of Organs and Systems of the Institute of Health Sciences, Federal University of Bahia, Salvador, Brazil. acbsanches@hotmail.com.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Laboratório de Bioquímica Oral, Instituto de Ciências da Saúde (UFBA), Av. Reitor Miguel Calmon, s/n. Sala 410. Vale do Canela, Salvador, Brazil. acbsanches@hotmail.com.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Pires</LastName>
            <ForeName>Alessandra Laís Pinho Valente</ForeName>
            <Initials>ALPV</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>PhD in Public Health, State University of Feira de Santana, Bahia, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Medrado</LastName>
            <ForeName>Alena Ribeiro Alves Peixoto</ForeName>
            <Initials>ARAP</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Human Pathology, Federal University of Bahia, Salvador, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Bahiana School of Medicine and Public Health, Salvador, Bahia, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>de Almeida Reis</LastName>
            <ForeName>Silvia Regina</ForeName>
            <Initials>SR</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Bahiana School of Medicine and Public Health, Salvador, Bahia, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Pathology, Berlin's Free University, Berlin, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Freitas</LastName>
            <ForeName>Valéria Souza</ForeName>
            <Initials>VS</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Oral Pathology, Federal University of Rio Grande do Norte, Natal, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Dentistry Course, State University of Feira de Santana, Feira de Santana, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Postgraduate Program in Public Health, State University of Feira de Santana, Bahia, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Martins</LastName>
            <ForeName>Gabriela Botelho</ForeName>
            <Initials>GB</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Postgraduate Program in Interactive Processes of Organs and Systems of the Institute of Health Sciences, Federal University of Bahia, Salvador, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Clinical Stomatology, PUCRS, Porto Alegre, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Health Sciences, Federal University of Bahia, Salvador, Brazil.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Head Neck Pathol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101304010</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1936-055X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Epithelium</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Inflammation</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Morphological and microscopic findings</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Oral lichen planus</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>11</Hour>
          <Minute>20</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35579856</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12105-022-01442-9</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s12105-022-01442-9</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Warnakulasuriya S, Johnson NW, Van der Waal I. Nomenclature and classification of potentially malignant disorders of the oral mucosa. J Oral Pathol Med. 2007;36:575–80.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0714.2007.00582.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gonzalez-Moles MA, Warnakulasuriya S, González-Ruiz I, González-Ruiz L, Avén A, Lenouvel D, et al. Worldwide prevalence of oral lichen planus: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Oral Oncol. 2020;106:104688.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.oraloncology.2020.104688</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barbosa NG, Silveira EJD, Lima ENA, Oliveira PT, Soares MSM, Medeiros AMC. Factors associated with clinical characteristics and symptoms in a case series of oral lichen planus. Int J Dermatol. 2015;54:e1–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ijd.12485</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carvalho CHP, Santos BRM, Vieira CC, Lima ENA, Santos PPA, Freitas RA. An epidemiological study of immune-mediated skin diseases affecting the oral cavity. An Bras Dermatol. 2011;86(5):905–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/S0365-05962011000500007</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lima SL, De Arruda JA, Abreu LG, Mesquita RA, Ribeiro-Rotta RF, Mendonça EF, et al. Clinicopathologic data of individuals with oral lichen planus: a Brazilian case series. J Clin Exp Dent. 2019;11(12):e1109–19.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31824590</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6894913</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nogueira PA, Carneiro S, Ramos-e-Silva M. Oral lichen planus: an update on its pathogenesis. Int J Dermatol. 2015;54:1005–10.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ijd.12918</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cassol-Spanemberg J, Blanco-Carrión A, Rodríguez-deRivera-Campillo ME, Estrugo-Devesa A, Jané-Salas E, López-López J. Cutaneous, genital and oral lichen planus: a descriptive study of 274 patients. Med Oral Patol Oral Cir Bucal. 2019;24(1):e1–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30573709</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alberdi-Navarro J, Marichalar-Mendia X, Lartitegui-Sebastián M-J, Gainza-Cirauqui M-L, Echebarria-Goikouria M-A, Aguirre-Urizar J-M. Histopathological Characterization of the oral lichenoid disease subtypes and the relation with the clinical data. Med Oral Patol Oral Cir Bucal. 2017;22(3):e307–13.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28390133</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5432079</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gopalakrishnan A, Balan A, Kumar NR, Haris PS, Bindu P. Malignant potential of oral lichen planus an analysis of literature over the past 20 years. Int J Appl Dent Sci. 2016;2:1–5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boñar-Alvarez AP, Sayáns MP, Garcia-Garcia A, Chamorro-Petronacci C, Gándara-Vila P, Luces-González R, et al. Correlation between clinical and pathological features oral lichen planus. Medicine. 2019;98:8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000014614</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>WHO Collaborating Centre for Precancerous Lesions. Definition of leukoplasia and related lesions: an aid to studies on oral precancer. Oral Surg Oral Med Oral Pathol. 1978;46:518–39.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0030-4220(78)90383-3</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cheng YL, Gould A, Kurago Z, Fantasia J, Muller S. Diagnosis of oral lichen planus: a position paper of the American Academy of Oral and Maxillofacial Pathology. Oral Max Pathol. 2016;122:332–54.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Venkatesiah SS, Kale AD, Hallikeremath SR, Kotrashetti VS. Histomorphometric analysis of nuclear and cellular volumetric alterations in oral lichen planus, lichenoid lesions and normal oral mucosa using image analysis software. Indian J Dent Res. 2013;24(2):277.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4103/0970-9290.116678</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lopéz-Jornet P, Camacho-Alonso F, Molia-Miñano F. Quantitative analysis of epitelial papillae in patients with oral lichen planus. JEADV. 2009;23:692–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19298481</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brant JMC, Vasconcelos AC, Rodrigues LV. Role of apoptosis in erosive and reticular oral lichen planus exhibiting variable epithelial thickness. Braz Dent J. 2008;19(3):179–85.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/S0103-64402008000300001</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Van der Meij EH, Van der Waal I. Lack of clinicopathologiccorrelation in the diagnosis of oral lichen planus based on the presently available diagnostic criteria and suggestions for modifications. J Oral Pathol Med. 2003;32:507–12.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1034/j.1600-0714.2003.00125.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giuliani M, Troiano G, Cordaro M, et al. Rate of malignant transformation of oral lichen planus: a systematic review. Oral Dis. 2019;25(3):693–709.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/odi.12885</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guan G, Mei L, Polonowita A, Hussaini H, Seo B, Rich AM. Malignant transformation in oral lichen planus and lichenoid lesions: a 14 year longitudinal retrospective cohort study of 829 patients in New Zealand. Oral Surg Oral Med Oral Pathol Oral Radiol. 2020;130(4):411–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.oooo.2020.07.002</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Feldmeyer L, Cazzaniga S, Borradori L, Beltraminelli H. Oral lichen planus and oral lichenoid lesions—na analysis of clinical and histophatological features. J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol. 2020;34(2):e104–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jdv.15981</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aghbari SMH, Abushouk AI, Attia A, Elmaraezy A, Menshawy A, Ahmed MS. Malignant transformation of oral lichen planus and oral lichenoid lesions: a meta-analysis of 20095 patient data. Oral Oncol. 2017;68:92–102.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.oraloncology.2017.03.012</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Casparis S, Borm JM, Tektas S, Corsalini M, Gioco G, Lo Muzio L, et al. Oral lichen planus (OLP), oral lichenoid lesions (OLL), oral dysplasia, and oral cancer: retrospective analysis of clinicopathological data from 2002–2011. Oral Maxillofac Surg. 2015;19:149–56.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10006-014-0469-y</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carvalho MFMS, Cavalieri D, Nascimento S, Lourenço TGB, Ramos DVR, Pasqualin DC, et al. cytokines levels and salivary microbiome play a potential role in oral lichen planus diagnosis. Sci Rep. 2019;9:18137.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-019-54615-y</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zucoloto ML, Shibakura MEW, Pavanin JV, Garcia FT, da Silva Santos PS, Maciel AP. Severity of oral lichen planus and oral lichenoid lesions is associated with anxiety. Clin Oral Investig. 2019;23:4441–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00784-019-02892-2</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Manczyk B, Golda J, Biniak A, Reszelewska K, Mazur B, Zajac K, et al. Evaluation of depression, anxiety and stress levels in patients with oral lichen planus. J Oral Sci. 2019;61(3):391–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2334/josnusd.18-0113</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cox T, Woodhead J, Nelson BL. Reticular oral lichen planus. Head Neck Pathol. 2020;14(1):192–4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12105-018-0983-6</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brant JM, Aguiar MCF, Grandinetti HA, Rodrigues LV, Vasconcelos AC. A comparative study of apoptosis in reticular and erosive oral lichen planus. Braz Dent J. 2012;23:564–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/S0103-64402012000500016</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Anitua E, Piñas L, Alkhraisat MH. Histopathological features of oral lichen planus and its response to corticosteroid therapy: a retrospective study. Medicine. 2019;98(51):e18321.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000018321</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sano SM, Quarracino MC, Aguas SC. Sensitivity of direct immunofluorescence in oral diseases. Study of 125 cases. Med Oral Patol Oral Cir Bucal. 2008;5:287–91.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Navas-Alfaro SE, Fonseca EC, Guzman-Silva MA, Rochael MC. Análise histopatológica comparativa entre líquen plano oral e cutâneo. J Bras Patol Med Lab. 2003;39(4):351–60.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/S1676-24442003000400013</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bascones-Ilundain C, Gonzalez-Moles MA, Esparza-Gómez G, Gil-Montoya JA, Bascones-Martínez A. Importance of apoptotic mechanisms in inflammatory infiltrate of oral lichen planus lesions. Anticancer Res. 2006;26:357–62.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16475718</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gorouhi F, Davari P, Fazel N. Cutaneous and mucosal lichen planus: a comprehensive review of clinical subtypes, risk factors, diagnosis, and prognosis. Sci World J. 2014;14:1–22.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2014/742826</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
