<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35579871</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1473-6578</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>35</Volume>
            <Issue>3</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>01</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Current opinion in psychiatry</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Curr Opin Psychiatry</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Psychopharmacology of agitation in acute psychotic and manic episodes.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>171</StartPage>
          <EndPage>176</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>171-176</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/YCO.0000000000000787</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="PURPOSE OF REVIEW" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To provide updated guidance for the medication treatment of acute agitation in the setting of psychosis or mania on inpatient psychiatric units.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RECENT FINDINGS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">This topic presented challenges: studies are sparse, tend to be under-powered, and are difficult to compare. Though there have been few recent studies, there have been several recent meta-analyses, Cochrane reviews, and published guidelines that sift through the primarily older evidence as well as more recent trials. The reviewers often do not agree on what seems to have the best evidence for efficacy and safety.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="SUMMARY" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">We conclude that the best approach is to summarize in some detail the evidence for each possible treatment and the interpretations published recently on each of those treatments, and then present recommendations for medication management in tiered rankings, based on the authors' qualitative review of the data and opinions. For oral treatment, the first-tier options are (alphabetically) haloperidol with lorazepam, lorazepam alone, and olanzapine. The second tier includes haloperidol with promethazine, loxapine inhaler, and risperidone alone. Tier 3 includes asenapine and quetiapine. For intramuscular treatment, the first-tier includes haloperidol plus promethazine, and olanzapine alone, and the second-tier includes haloperidol with lorazepam, and lorazepam alone.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Stetson</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sean R</ForeName>
            <Initials>SR</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>US Department of Veterans Affairs, VA Boston Healthcare System, Boston.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Osser</LastName>
            <ForeName>David N</ForeName>
            <Initials>DN</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>US Department of Veterans Affairs, VA Boston Healthcare System, Brockton Division, Brockton, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>02</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Curr Opin Psychiatry</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8809880</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0951-7367</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D014150">Antipsychotic Agents</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>12794-10-4</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D001569">Benzodiazepines</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>FF28EJQ494</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D011398">Promethazine</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>J6292F8L3D</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D006220">Haloperidol</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>N7U69T4SZR</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000077152">Olanzapine</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>O26FZP769L</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D008140">Lorazepam</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014150" MajorTopicYN="Y">Antipsychotic Agents</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001569" MajorTopicYN="N">Benzodiazepines</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004359" MajorTopicYN="N">Drug Therapy, Combination</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006220" MajorTopicYN="N">Haloperidol</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008140" MajorTopicYN="N">Lorazepam</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000087122" MajorTopicYN="N">Mania</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000077152" MajorTopicYN="N">Olanzapine</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011398" MajorTopicYN="N">Promethazine</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011595" MajorTopicYN="N">Psychomotor Agitation</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011600" MajorTopicYN="Y">Psychopharmacology</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011618" MajorTopicYN="Y">Psychotic Disorders</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000150" MajorTopicYN="N">complications</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>11</Hour>
          <Minute>23</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35579871</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/YCO.0000000000000787</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">00001504-202205000-00007</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ansari A, Osser DN, Lai LS. Ovsiew F, Munich RL, et al. Pharmacologic approach to the psychiatric inpatient. Principles ofinpatient psychiatry. New York: Lippincott Williams &amp; Wilkins; 2008. 44–47.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Osser DN, Sigadel R. Short-term inpatient pharmacotherapy of schizophrenia. Harv Rev Psychiatry 2001; 9:89–104.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pratts M, Citrome L, Grant W, et al. A single-dose, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial of sublingual asenapine for acute agitation. Acta Psychiatr Scand 2014; 130:61–68.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ahmed U, Jones H, Adams CE. Chlorpromazine for psychosis induced aggression or agitation. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 2010; (4):CD007445.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Citrome L, Volavka J. Violent patients in the emergency setting. Psychiatr Clin North Am 1999; 22:789–801.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cuomo A, Chioccioli M, Cattaneo CI, et al. Effectiveness of intramuscular chlorpromazine for rapid treatment of psychomotor agitation: a naturalistic, retrospective, and observational study. J Clin Psychopharmacol 2021; 41:613–614.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Isbister GK, Calver LA, Page CB, et al. Randomized controlled trial of intramuscular droperidol versus midazolam for violence and acute behavioral disturbance: the DORM study. Ann Emerg Med 2010; 56:392e1–401e1.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Calver L, Drinkwater V, Gupta R, et al. Droperidol v. haloperidol for sedation of aggressive behaviour in acute mental health: randomised controlled trial. Br J Psychiatry 2015; 206:223–228.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Calver L, Drinkwater V, Isbister GK. A prospective study of high dose sedation for rapid tranquilisation of acute behavioural disturbance in an acute mental health unit. BMC Psychiatry 2013; 13:1–6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Taylor DM, Yap CY, Knott JC, et al. Midazolam-droperidol, droperidol, or olanzapine for acute agitation: a randomized clinical trial. Ann Emerg Med 2017; 69:318.e1–326.e1.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kao LW, Kirk MA, Evers SJ, et al. QT prolongation, and sudden death: what is the evidence? Ann Emerg Med 2003; 41:546–558.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Horowitz BZ, Bizovi K, Moreno R. Droperidol—behind the black box warning. Acad Emerg Med 2002; 9:615–618.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Van Zwieten K, Mullins ME, Jang T. Droperidol and the black box warning. Ann Emerg Med 2004; 43:139–140.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Calver L, Page CB, Downes MA, et al. The safety and effectiveness of droperidol for sedation of acute behavioral disturbance in the emergency department. Ann Emerg Med 2015; 66:230.e1–238.e1.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khokhar MA, Rathbone J. Droperidol for psychosis-induced aggression or agitation. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 2016; (12):CD002830.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bak M, Weltens I, Bervoets C, et al. The pharmacological management of agitated and aggressive behaviour: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Eur Psychiatry 2019; 57:78–100.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Taylor DM, Barnes TR, Young AH. Acutely disturbed or violent behavior in schizophrenia and related psychoses. Maudsley prescribing guidelines in psychiatry 14th ed John Wiley &amp; Sons; 2021. 56–66.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ostinelli EG, Brooke-Powney MJ, Li X, Adams CE. Haloperidol for psychosis-induced aggression or agitation (rapid tranquillisation). Cochrane Database Syst Rev 2017; (7):CD009377.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zun LS. Evidence-based review of pharmacotherapy for acute agitation. Part 1. Onset of efficacy. J Emerg Med 2018; 54:364–374.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pacciardi B, Mauri M, Cargioli C, et al. Issues in the management of acute agitation: how much current guidelines consider safety? Front Psychiatry 2013; 4:26.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zun LS. Evidence-based review of pharmacotherapy for acute agitation. Part 2. Safety. J Emerg Med 2018; 54:522–532.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Battaglia J, Moss S, Rush J, et al. Haloperidol, lorazepam, or both for psychotic agitation? A multicenter, prospective, double-blind, emergency department study. Am J Emerg Med 1997; 15:335–340.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gillies D, Sampson S, Beck A, Rathbone J. Benzodiazepines for psychosis-induced aggression or agitation. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 2013; (4):CD003079.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Powney MJ, Adams CE, Jones H. Haloperidol for psychosis-induced aggression or agitation (rapid tranquillisation). Cochrane Database Syst Rev 2012; (11):CD009377.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baldacara L, Sanches M, Cordeiro DC, Jackowski AP. Rapid tranquilization for agitated patients in emergency psychiatric rooms: a randomized trial of olanzapine, ziprasidone, haloperidol plus promethazine, haloperidol plus midazolam and haloperidol alone. Braz J Psychiatry 2011; 33:30–39.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mantovani C, Labate CM, Sponholz A Jr, et al. Are low doses of antipsychotics effective in the management of psychomotor agitation? Arandomized, rated-blind trial of 4 intramuscular interventions. J Clin Psychopharmacol 2013; 33:306–312.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huf G, Alexander J, Gandhi P, Allen MH. Haloperidol plus promethazine for psychosis-induced aggression. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 2016; 11:CD005146.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kwentus J, Riesenberg RA, Marandi M, et al. Rapid acute treatment of agitation in patients with bipolar I disorder: a multicenter, randomized, placebo-controlled clinical trial with inhaled loxapine. Bipolar Disord 2012; 14:31–40.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Allen MH, Feifel D, Lesem MD, et al. Efficacy and safety of loxapine for inhalation in the treatment of agitation in patients with schizophrenia: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. J Clin Psychiatry 2011; 72:1313–1321.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lesem MD, Tran-Johnson TK, Riesenberg RA, et al. Rapid acute treatmentof agitation in individuals with schizophrenia: multicentre, randomised, placebo-controlled study of inhaled loxapine. Br J Psychiatry 2011; 198:51–58.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nobay F, Simon BC, Levitt MA, Dresden GM. A prospective, double-blind, randomized trial of midazolam versus haloperidol versus lorazepam in the chemical restraint of violentand severely agitated patients. Acad Emerg Med 2004; 11:744–749.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>TREC Collaborative Group. Rapid tranquillisation for agitated patients in emergency psychiatric rooms: a randomised trial of midazolam versus halo-peridol plus promethazine. BMJ 2003; 327:708–713.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Citrome L. Comparison of intramuscular ziprasidone, olanzapine, or aripipra-zole for agitation: a quantitative review of efficacy and safety. J Clin Psychiatry 2007; 68:1876–1885.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raveendran NS, Tharyan P, Alexander J, Adams CE. Rapid tranquillisation in psychiatric emergency settings in India: pragmatic randomised controlled trial of intramuscular olanzapine versus intramuscular haloperidol plus prometha-zine. BMJ 2007; 335:865.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kishi T, Matsunaga S, Iwata N. Intramuscular olanzapine for agitated patients: a systematic review and meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. J Psychiatr Res 2015; 68:198–209.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Perrin E, Anand E, Dyachkova Y, et al. A prospective, observational study of the safety and effectiveness of intramuscular psychotropic treatment in acutely agitated patients with schizophrenia and bipolar mania. Eur Psychiatry 2012; 27:234–239.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hahn MK, Wolever TM, Arenovich T, et al. Acute effects of single-dose olanzapine on metabolic, endocrine, and inflammatory markers in healthy controls. J Clin Psychopharmacol 2013; 33:740–746.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eli Lilly. Company. Zyprexa Zydis product information. Indiana: Indianapolis; 2005.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Currier GW, Trenton AJ, Walsh PG, van Wijngaarden E. A pilot, open-label safety study of quetiapine for treatment of moderate psychotic agitation in the emergency setting. J Psychiatric Pract 2006; 12:223–228.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith C, Hopper A, Campillo A, et al. Use of quetiapine in the emergency departmentfor acute agitation and associated physiologic effects. Ann Emerg Med 2014; 64:S138.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ostinelli EG, Hussein M, Ahmed U, et al. Risperidone for psychosis-induced aggression or agitation (rapid tranquillisation). Cochrane Database Syst Rev 2018; (4):Cd009412.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roerig (division of Pfizer). Geodon prescribing recommendations. New York City, New York; 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Simpson JR Jr, Thompson CR, Beckson M. Impact of orally disintegrating olanzapine on use of intramuscular antipsychotics, seclusion, and restraintin an acute inpatient psychiatric setting. J Clin Psychopharmacol 2006; 26:333–335.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Currier GW, Simpson GM. Risperidone liquid concentrate and oral lorazepam versus intramuscular haloperidol and intramuscular lorazepam for treatmentof psychotic agitation. J Clin Psychiatry 2001; 62:153–157.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Currier GW, Chou JC, Feifel D, et al. Acute treatment of psychotic agitation: a randomized comparison of oral treatment with risperidone and lorazepam versus intramuscular treatment with haloperidol and lorazepam. J Clin Psychiatry 2004; 65:386–394.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hsu W-Y, Huang S-S, Lee B-S, Chiu N-Y. Comparison of intramuscular olanzapine, orally disintegrating olanzapine tablets, oral risperidone solution, and intramuscular haloperidol in the management of acute agitation in an acute care psychiatric ward in Taiwan. J Clin Psychopharmacol 2010; 30:230–234.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
