<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35579628</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1530-6860</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>36</Volume>
            <Issue>6</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>FASEB journal : official publication of the Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>FASEB J</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Pharmacomicrobiomics: Influence of gut microbiota on drug and xenobiotic metabolism.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e22350</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e22350</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1096/fj.202101986R</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Gut microbiota is the most diverse and complex biological ecosystem, which is estimated to consist of greater than 5 million distinct genes and 100 trillion cells which are in constant communication with the host environment. The interaction between the gut microbiota and drugs and other xenobiotic compounds is bidirectional, quite complicated, and not fully understood yet. The impact of xenobiotics from pollution, manufacturing processes or from the environment is harmful to human health at varying degrees and this needs to be recognized and addressed. The gut microbiota is capable of biotransforming/metabolizing of various drugs and xenobiotic compounds as well as altering the activity and toxicity of these substances, thereby influencing how a host responds to drugs and xenobiotics and this emerging field is known as pharmacomicrobiomics. In this review, we discussed different mechanisms of drug-gut microbiota interaction and highlighted the influence of drug-gut microbiome interactions on the clinical response in humans.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Authors. The FASEB Journal published by Wiley Periodicals LLC on behalf of Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Dikeocha</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ifeoma Julieth</ForeName>
            <Initials>IJ</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, University of Cyberjaya, Cyberjaya, Malaysia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Al-Kabsi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Abdelkodose Mohammed</ForeName>
            <Initials>AM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, University of Cyberjaya, Cyberjaya, Malaysia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Miftahussurur</LastName>
            <ForeName>Muhammad</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Helicobacter Pylori and Microbiota Study Group, Institute of Tropical Disease, Universitas Airlangga, Surabaya, Indonesia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Gastroentero-Hepatology, Department of Internal Medicine, Faculty of Medicine, Dr. Soetomo Teaching Hospital, Universitas Airlangga, Surabaya, Indonesia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Alshawsh</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mohammed Abdullah</ForeName>
            <Initials>MA</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8342-5183</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology, Faculty of Medicine, Universiti Malaya, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>FASEB J</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8804484</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0892-6638</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D015262">Xenobiotics</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017753" MajorTopicYN="N">Ecosystem</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000069196" MajorTopicYN="Y">Gastrointestinal Microbiome</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015262" MajorTopicYN="N">Xenobiotics</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000378" MajorTopicYN="N">metabolism</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">drug metabolism</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">gut microbiota</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">microbiome</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacomicrobiomics</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">xenobiotics</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>11</Hour>
          <Minute>3</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35579628</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1096/fj.202101986R</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gill SR, Pop M, DeBoy RT, et al. Metagenomic analysis of the human distal gut microbiome. Science. 2006;312(5778):1355-1359.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rinninella E, Raoul P, Cintoni M, et al. What is the healthy gut microbiota composition? A changing ecosystem across age, environment, diet, and diseases. Microorganisms. 2019;7(1):14.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peterson J, Garges S, Giovanni M, et al. The NIH human microbiome project. Genome Res. 2009;19(12):2317-2323.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>ElRakaiby M, Dutilh BE, Rizkallah MR, Boleij A, Cole JN, Aziz RK. Pharmacomicrobiomics: the impact of human microbiome variations on systems pharmacology and personalized therapeutics. Omics. 2014;18(7):402-414. doi:10.1089/omi.2014.0018</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abdelsalam NA, Ramadan AT, ElRakaiby MT, Aziz RK. Toxicomicrobiomics: the human microbiome vs. pharmaceutical, dietary, and environmental xenobiotics. Front Pharmacol. 2020;11:390. doi:10.3389/fphar.2020.00390</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yatsunenko T, Rey FE, Manary MJ, et al. Human gut microbiome viewed across age and geography. Nature. 2012;486(7402):222-227.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koppel N, Rekdal VM, Balskus EP. Chemical transformation of xenobiotics by the human gut microbiota. Science. 2017;356(6344):aag2770.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mallick H, Ma S, Franzosa EA, Vatanen T, Morgan XC, Huttenhower C. Experimental design and quantitative analysis of microbial community multiomics. Genome Biol. 2017;18(1):228.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Diakite A, Dubourg G, Dione N, et al. Optimization and standardization of the culturomics technique for human microbiome exploration. Sci Rep. 2020;10(1):1-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abdallah RA, Beye M, Diop A, Bakour S, Raoult D, Fournier P-E. The impact of culturomics on taxonomy in clinical microbiology. Antonie Van Leeuwenhoek. 2017;110(10):1327-1337.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scher JU, Nayak RR, Ubeda C, Turnbaugh PJ, Abramson SB. Pharmacomicrobiomics in inflammatory arthritis: gut microbiome as modulator of therapeutic response. Nat Rev Rheumatol. 2020;16(5):282-292.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aziz R. Rethinking pharmacogenomics in an ecosystem: drug-microbiome interactions, pharmacomicrobiomics, and personalized medicine for the human supraorganism. Curr Pharmacogenomics Pers Med. 2012;10(4):258-261.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rizkallah MR, Saad R, Aziz RK. The Human Microbiome Project, personalized medicine and the birth of pharmacomicrobiomics. Curr Pharmacogenomics Pers Med. 2010;8(3):182-193.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aziz RK. Interview with Prof. Ramy K. Aziz, Cairo University. The dawn of pharmacomicrobiomics. Omics. 2018;22(4):295-297.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aguilera M, Vergara P, Martinez V. Stress and antibiotics alter luminal and wall-adhered microbiota and enhance the local expression of visceral sensory-related systems in mice. Neurogastroenterol Motil. 2013;25(8):e515-e529.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu J, Xu C, Chen X, et al. Regulation of an antioxidant blend on intestinal redox status and major microbiota in early weaned piglets. Nutrition. 2014;30(5):584-589.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goldman P, Peppercorn MA, Goldin BR. Metabolism of drugs by microorganisms in the intestine. Am J Clin Nutr. 1974;27(11):1348-1355.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wilson ID, Nicholson JK. Gut microbiome interactions with drug metabolism, efficacy, and toxicity. Transl Res. 2017;179:204-222. doi:10.1016/j.trsl.2016.08.002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gratz SW, Duncan G, Richardson AJ. The human fecal microbiota metabolizes deoxynivalenol and deoxynivalenol-3-glucoside and may be responsible for urinary deepoxy-deoxynivalenol. Appl Environ Microbiol. 2013;79(6):1821-1825.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rybak MJ, Le J, Lodise TP, et al. Therapeutic monitoring of vancomycin for serious methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus infections: a revised consensus guideline and review by the American Society of Health-System Pharmacists, the Infectious Diseases Society of America, the Pediatric Infectious Diseases Society, and the Society of Infectious Diseases Pharmacists. Am J Health SystPharm. 2020;77(11):835-864.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jin MJ, Kim IS, Kim D-H, Yoo HH. Effects of intestinal microbiota on the bioavailability of geniposide in rats. J Agric Food Chem. 2014;62(40):9632-9636.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yoo D-H, Kim IS, Van Le TK, Jung I-H, Yoo HH, Kim D-H. Gut microbiota-mediated drug interactions between lovastatin and antibiotics. Drug Metab Dispos. 2014;42(9):1508-1513.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim DH. Gut microbiota-mediated drug-antibiotic interactions. Drug Metab Dispos. 2015;43(10):1581-1589. doi:10.1124/dmd.115.063867</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jin MJ, Kim U, Kim IS, et al. Effects of gut microflora on pharmacokinetics of hesperidin: a study on non-antibiotic and pseudo-germ-free rats. J Toxicol Environ Health A. 2010;73(21-22):1441-1450.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clayton TA, Baker D, Lindon JC, Everett JR, Nicholson JK. Pharmacometabonomic identification of a significant host-microbiome metabolic interaction affecting human drug metabolism. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 2009;106(34):14728-14733.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mathan V, Wiederman J, Dobkin J, Lindenbaum J. Geographic differences in digoxin inactivation, a metabolic activity of the human anaerobic gut flora. Gut. 1989;30(7):971-977.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Francino M. Antibiotics and the human gut microbiome: dysbioses and accumulation of resistances. Front Microbiol. 2015;6:1543.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zemanová N, Anzenbacher P, Zapletalová I, et al. The role of the microbiome and psychosocial stress in the expression and activity of drug metabolizing enzymes in mice. Sci Rep. 2020;10(1):8529. doi:10.1038/s41598-020-65595-9</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Falony G, Joossens M, Vieira-Silva S, et al. Population-level analysis of gut microbiome variation. Science. 2016;352(6285):560-564.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shin N-R, Lee J-C, Lee H-Y, et al. An increase in the Akkermansia spp. population induced by metformin treatment improves glucose homeostasis in diet-induced obese mice. Gut. 2014;63(5):727-735.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sun Y, Zhang J, Zhao A, Li W, Feng Q, Wang R. Effects of intestinal flora on the pharmacokinetics and pharmacodynamics of aspirin in high-altitude hypoxia. PLoS One. 2020;15(3):e0230197. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0230197</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Forslund K, Hildebrand F, Nielsen T, et al. Disentangling type 2 diabetes and metformin treatment signatures in the human gut microbiota. Nature. 2015;528(7581):262-266.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu H, Esteve E, Tremaroli V, et al. Metformin alters the gut microbiome of individuals with treatment-naive type 2 diabetes, contributing to the therapeutic effects of the drug. Nat Med. 2017;23(7):850-858.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Colebrook L, Buttle GA, O’meara R. The mode of action of p-aminobenzenesulphonamide and prontosil in haemolytic streptococcal infections. Lancet. 1936;228(5910):1323-1326.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nicholson JK, Wilson ID. Understanding global systems biology: metabonomics and the continuum of metabolism. Nat Rev Drug Discovery. 2003;2(8):668-676.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dial S, Alrasadi K, Manoukian C, Huang A, Menzies D. Risk of Clostridium difficile diarrhea among hospital inpatients prescribed proton pump inhibitors: cohort and case-control studies. CMAJ. 2004;171(1):33-38.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Imhann F, Bonder MJ, Vich Vila A, et al. Proton pump inhibitors affect the gut microbiome. Gut. 2016;65(5):740-748.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jackson MA, Goodrich JK, Maxan M-E, et al. Proton pump inhibitors alter the composition of the gut microbiota. Gut. 2016;65(5):749-756.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tan HJ, Mahadeva S, Menon J, et al. Statements of the Malaysian Society of Gastroenterology &amp; Hepatology and the National Heart Association of Malaysia task force 2012 working party on the use of antiplatelet therapy and proton pump inhibitors in the prevention of gastrointestinal bleeding. J Dig Dis. 2013;14(1):1-10.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chia CTW, Lim WP, Vu CKF. Inappropriate use of proton pump inhibitors in a local setting. Singapore Med J. 2014;55(7):363-366.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li H, He J, Jia W. The influence of gut microbiota on drug metabolism and toxicity. Expert Opin Drug Metab Toxicol. 2016;12(1):31-40. doi:10.1517/17425255.2016.1121234</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lindenbaum J, Rund DG, Butler Jr VP, Tse-Eng D, Saha JR. Inactivation of digoxin by the gut flora: reversal by antibiotic therapy. N Engl J Med. 1981;305(14):789-794.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Magnusson J, Bergdahl B, Bogentoft C, Jonsson U. Metabolism of digoxin and absorption site. Br J Clin Pharmacol. 1982;14(2):284-285.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haiser HJ, Gootenberg DB, Chatman K, Sirasani G, Balskus EP, Turnbaugh PJ. Predicting and manipulating cardiac drug inactivation by the human gut bacterium Eggerthella lenta. Science. 2013;341(6143):295-298.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koppel N, Bisanz JE, Pandelia M-E, Turnbaugh PJ, Balskus EP. Discovery and characterization of a prevalent human gut bacterial enzyme sufficient for the inactivation of a family of plant toxins. eLife. 2018;7:e33953.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Spady DK. Recent Advances in the Medical Therapy of Inflammatory Bowel Disease. UT Southwestern Health Sciences Digital Library and Learning Center; 1995.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khan AA, Guthrie G, Johnston H, Truelove S, Williamson D. Tissue and bacterial splitting of sulphasalazine. Clin Sci. 1983;64(3):349-354.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee HJ, Zhang H, Orlovich DA, Fawcett JP. The influence of probiotic treatment on sulfasalazine metabolism in rat. Xenobiotica. 2012;42(8):791-797.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Crouwel F, Buiter HJC, de Boer NK. Gut microbiota-driven drug metabolism in inflammatory bowel disease. J Crohns Colitis. 2021;15(2):307-315. doi:10.1093/ecco-jcc/jjaa143</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mohiuddin AK. Cost of biotech drug development and affordability issues in LMICs. Arch Biomed Eng Biotechnol. 2019;2(3):538.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Steffens LS, Nicholson S, Paul LV, Nord CE, Patrick S, Abratt VR. Bacteroides fragilis RecA protein overexpression causes resistance to metronidazole. Res Microbiol. 2010;161(5):346-354.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ashida N, Ijichi K, Watanabe Y, Machida H. Metabolism of 5′-ether prodrugs of 1-β-d-Arabinofuranosyl-E-5-(2-bromovinyl) uracil in rats. Biochem Pharmacol. 1993;46(12):2201-2207.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nakayama H, Kinouchi T, Kataoka K, Akimoto S, Matsuda Y, Ohnishi Y. Intestinal anaerobic bacteria hydrolyse sorivudine, producing the high blood concentration of 5-(E)-(2-bromovinyl) uracil that increases the level and toxicity of 5-fluorouracil. Pharmacogenet Genomics. 1997;7(1):35-43.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Strong H, Renwick A, George C, Liu Y, Hill M. The reduction of sulphinpyrazone and sulindac by intestinal bacteria. Xenobiotica. 1987;17(6):685-696.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grundmann O. The gut microbiome and pre-systemic metabolism: current state and evolving research. J Drug Metab Toxicol. 2010;1:104.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Övervik E, Lindeskog P, Midtvedt T, Gustafsson J. Mutagen excretion and cytochrome P-450-dependent activity in germfree and conventional rats fed a diet containing fried meat. Food Chem Toxicol. 1990;28(4):253-261.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Michalopoulos GK. Liver regeneration. Liver Biol Pathobiol; 2020;12:566-584.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meinl W, Sczesny S, Brigelius-Flohe R, Blaut M, Glatt H. Impact of gut microbiota on intestinal and hepatic levels of phase 2 xenobiotic-metabolizing enzymes in the rat. Drug Metab Dispos. 2009;37(6):1179-1186.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nicholson JK, Wilson ID. Opinion: understanding global systems biology: metabonomics and the continuum of metabolism. Nat Rev Drug Discov. 2003;2(8):668-676.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nogacka AM, Gómez-Martín M, Suárez A, González-Bernardo O, de los Reyes-Gavilán CG, González S. Xenobiotics formed during food processing: their relation with the intestinal microbiota and colorectal cancer. Int J Mol Sci. 2019;20(8):2051.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carmody RN, Turnbaugh PJ. Host-microbial interactions in the metabolism of therapeutic and diet-derived xenobiotics. J Clin Investig. 2014;124(10):4173-4181.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sharon G, Garg N, Debelius J, Knight R, Dorrestein PC, Mazmanian SK. Specialized metabolites from the microbiome in health and disease. Cell Metab. 2014;20(5):719-730.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Suez J, Korem T, Zilberman-Schapira G, Segal E, Elinav E. Non-caloric artificial sweeteners and the microbiome: findings and challenges. Gut Microbes. 2015;6(2):149-155.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sinha R. An epidemiologic approach to studying heterocyclic amines. Mutat Res. 2002;506:197-204.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang J, Empl MT, Schwab C, et al. Gut microbial transformation of the dietary imidazoquinoxaline mutagen MelQx reduces its cytotoxic and mutagenic potency. Toxicol Sci. 2017;159(1):266-276.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chassaing B, Koren O, Goodrich JK, et al. Dietary emulsifiers impact the mouse gut microbiota promoting colitis and metabolic syndrome. Nature. 2015;519:92-96.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gičević A, Hindija L, Karačić A. Toxicity of Azo Dyes in Pharmaceutical Industry. Springer; 2019;581-587.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Misal SA, Gawai KR. Azoreductase: a key player of xenobiotic metabolism. Bioresour Bioprocess. 2018;5(1):17. doi:10.1186/s40643-018-0206-8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zahran SA, Ali-Tammam M, Hashem AM, Aziz RK, Ali AE. Azoreductase activity of dye-decolorizing bacteria isolated from the human gut microbiota. Sci Rep. 2019;9(1):5508. doi:10.1038/s41598-019-41894-8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Halden RU, Lindeman AE, Aiello AE, et al. The Florence statement on triclosan and triclocarban. Environ Health Perspect. 2017;125(6):064501.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Petrie B, Barden R, Kasprzyk-Hordern B. A review on emerging contaminants in wastewaters and the environment: current knowledge, understudied areas and recommendations for future monitoring. Water Res. 2015;72:3-27. doi:10.1016/j.watres.2014.08.053</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dong M, Xu X, Huang Q, et al. Dose-dependent effects of triclocarban exposure on lipid homeostasis in rats. Chem Res Toxicol. 2019;32(11):2320-2328.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Poole AC, Pischel L, Ley C, et al. Crossover control study of the effect of personal care products containing triclosan on the microbiome. mSphere. 2016;1(3):e00056-15.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang H, Wang W, Romano KA, et al. A common antimicrobial additive increases colonic inflammation and colitis-associated colon tumorigenesis in mice. Sci Transl Med. 2018;10(443):eaan4116.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peterson MA, McMaster SA, Riechers DE, Skelton J, Stahlman PW. 2, 4-D past, present, and future: a review. Weed Technol. 2016;30(2):303-345.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tu P, Gao B, Chi L, et al. Subchronic low-dose 2, 4-D exposure changed plasma acylcarnitine levels and induced gut microbiome perturbations in mice. Sci Rep. 2019;9(1):1-11.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chi L, Xue J, Tu P, Lai Y, Ru H, Lu K. Gut microbiome disruption altered the biotransformation and liver toxicity of arsenic in mice. Arch Toxicol. 2019;93(1):25-35. doi:10.1007/s00204-018-2332-7</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lu K, Abo RP, Schlieper KA, et al. Arsenic exposure perturbs the gut microbiome and its metabolic profile in mice: an integrated metagenomics and metabolomics analysis. Environ Health Perspect. 2014;122(3):284-291.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yin N, Zhang Z, Cai X, Du H, Sun G, Cui Y. In vitro method to assess soil arsenic metabolism by human gut microbiota: arsenic speciation and distribution. Environ Sci Technol. 2015;49(17):10675-10681. doi:10.1021/acs.est.5b03046</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pellock SJ, Walton WG, Ervin SM, et al. Discovery and characterization of FMN-binding β-glucuronidases in the human gut microbiome. J Mol Biol. 2019;431(5):970-980.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tozaki H, Emi Y, Horisaka E, Fujita T, Yamamoto A, Muranishi S. Degradation of insulin and calcitonin and their protection by various protease inhibitors in rat caecal contents: implications in peptide delivery to the colon. J Pharm Pharmacol. 1997;49(2):164-168.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saitta KS, Zhang C, Lee KK, Fujimoto K, Redinbo MR, Boelsterli UA. Bacterial β-glucuronidase inhibition protects mice against enteropathy induced by indomethacin, ketoprofen or diclofenac: mode of action and pharmacokinetics. Xenobiotica. 2014;44(1):28-35.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swanson HI. Drug metabolism by the host and gut microbiota: a partnership or rivalry? Drug Metab Dispos. 2015;43(10):1499-1504.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Markey SP. Pathways of Drug Metabolism. Principles of Clinical Pharmacology. Elsevier; 2007;143-162.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Collins SL, Patterson AD. The gut microbiome: an orchestrator of xenobiotic metabolism. Acta Pharm Sin B. 2020;10(1):19-32. doi:10.1016/j.apsb.2019.12.001</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Higuchi K, Umegaki E, Watanabe T, et al. Present status and strategy of NSAIDs-induced small bowel injury. J Gastroenterol. 2009;44(9):879-888.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dabek M, McCrae SI, Stevens VJ, Duncan SH, Louis P. Distribution of β-glucosidase and β-glucuronidase activity and of β-glucuronidase gene gus in human colonic bacteria. FEMS Microbiol Ecol. 2008;66(3):487-495.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wallace BD, Wang H, Lane KT, et al. Alleviating cancer drug toxicity by inhibiting a bacterial enzyme. Science. 2010;330(6005):831-835.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lam KN, Alexander M, Turnbaugh PJ. Precision medicine goes microscopic: engineering the microbiome to improve drug outcomes. Cell Host Microbe. 2019;26(1):22-34. doi:10.1016/j.chom.2019.06.011</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhu W, Winter MG, Byndloss MX, et al. Precision editing of the gut microbiota ameliorates colitis. Nature. 2018;553(7687):208-211.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Merril CR, Scholl D, Adhya SL. The prospect for bacteriophage therapy in Western medicine. Nat Rev Drug Discov. 2003;2(6):489-497.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alfarouk KO, Stock C-M, Taylor S, et al. Resistance to cancer chemotherapy: failure in drug response from ADME to P-gp. Cancer Cell Int. 2015;15:1-13. doi:10.1186/s12935-015-0221-1</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blagosklonny MV. How avastin potentiates chemotherapeutic drugs: action and reaction in antiangiogenic therapy. Cancer Biol Ther. 2005;4(12):1307-1310.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Winkler GC, Barle EL, Galati G, Kluwe WM. Functional differentiation of cytotoxic cancer drugs and targeted cancer therapeutics. Regul Toxicol Pharmacol. 2014;70(1):46-53.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li W, Deng X, Chen T. Exploring the modulatory effects of gut microbiota in anti-cancer therapy. Front Oncol. 2021;11:644454. doi:10.3389/fonc.2021.644454</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Secombe KR, Coller JK, Gibson RJ, Wardill HR, Bowen JM. The bidirectional interaction of the gut microbiome and the innate immune system: implications for chemotherapy-induced gastrointestinal toxicity. Int J Cancer. 2019;144(10):2365-2376. doi:10.1002/ijc.31836</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Takemura N, Kawasaki T, Kunisawa J, et al. Blockade of TLR3 protects mice from lethal radiation-induced gastrointestinal syndrome. Nat Commun. 2014;5(1):1-15.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stringer AM, Gibson RJ, Logan RM, et al. Gastrointestinal microflora and mucins may play a critical role in the development of 5-Fluorouracil-induced gastrointestinal mucositis. Exp Biol Med. 2009;234(4):430-441.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Flint HJ, Scott KP, Louis P, Duncan SH. The role of the gut microbiota in nutrition and health. Nat Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2012;9(10):577-589. doi:10.1038/nrgastro.2012.156</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khan AA, Nema V, Khan Z. Current status of probiotics for prevention and management of gastrointestinal cancers. Exp Opin Biol Ther. 2021;21(3):413-422.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dikeocha IJ, Al-Kabsi AM, Eid EE, Hussin S, Alshawsh MA. Probiotics supplementation in patients with colorectal cancer: a systematic review of randomized controlled trials. Nutr Rev. 2022;80(1):22-49.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Finlay BB, Goldszmid R, Honda K, Trinchieri G, Wargo J, Zitvogel L. Can we harness the microbiota to enhance the efficacy of cancer immunotherapy? Nat Rev Immunol. 2020;20(9):522-528.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lin XB, Dieleman LA, Ketabi A, et al. Irinotecan (CPT-11) chemotherapy alters intestinal microbiota in tumour bearing rats. PLoS One. 2012;7(7):e39764.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Viaud S, Saccheri F, Mignot G, et al. The intestinal microbiota modulates the anticancer immune effects of cyclophosphamide. Science. 2013;342(6161):971-976.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Okuda H, Nishiyama T, Ogura K, et al. Lethal drug interactions of sorivudine, a new antiviral drug, with oral 5-fluorouracil prodrugs. Drug Metab Dispos. 1997;25(2):270-273.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schieber M, Chandel NS. ROS function in redox signaling and oxidative stress. Curr Biol. 2014;24(10):R453-R462.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
