<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35571481</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">2364-3722</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>10</Volume>
            <Issue>5</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Endoscopy international open</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Endosc Int Open</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Improved detection of early gastric cancer with linked color imaging using an ultrathin endoscope: a video-based analysis.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>E644</StartPage>
          <EndPage>E652</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>E644-E652</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1055/a-1793-9414</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText><b>Background and study aims </b> Ultrathin endoscopy causes a minimal gag reflex and has minimal effects on cardiopulmonary function. Linked color imaging (LCI) is useful for detection of malignancies in the digestive tract. The aim of this study was to clarify whether LCI with ultrathin endoscopy facilitates detection of early gastric cancer (EGC) despite its lower resolution compared with high-resolution white light imaging (WLI) with standard endoscopy. <b>Patients and methods </b> This was a retrospective analysis with prospectively collected video, including consecutive 166 cases of EGC or gastric atrophy alone. Ninety seconds of screening video was collected using standard and ultrathin endoscopes with both WLI and LCI for each case. Three expert endoscopists assessed each video and the sensitivity of detecting EGC calculated. Color difference calculations were performed. <b>Results </b> Sensitivities using ultrathin WLI, ultrathin LCI, standard WLI, and standard LCI for the identification of cancer were 66.0 %, 80.3 %, 69.9 %, and 84.0 %, respectively. The color difference between malignant lesions and surrounding mucosa with ultrathin LCI and standard LCI were significantly higher than using ultrathin WLI or standard WLI, supported subjectively by the visibility score. Ultrathin LCI color difference and visibility score were significantly higher than standard WLI. <b>Conclusions </b> LCI with a low-resolution ultrathin endoscope is superior to WLI with a high-resolution standard endoscope for gastric cancer screening. This suggests that the high color contrast between EGC and the surrounding mucosa is more important than high-resolution images.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>The Author(s). This is an open access article published by Thieme under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution-NonDerivative-NonCommercial License, permitting copying and reproduction so long as the original work is given appropriate credit. Contents may not be used for commercial purposes, or adapted, remixed, transformed or built upon. (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/).</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Khurelbaatar</LastName>
            <ForeName>Tsevelnorov</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology, Department of Medicine, Jichi Medical University, Shimotsuke, Tochigi, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Mongolia-Japan Hospital, Mongolian National University of Medical Sciences, Ulaanbaatar, Mongolia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Miura</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yoshimasa</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology, Department of Medicine, Jichi Medical University, Shimotsuke, Tochigi, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Osawa</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hiroyuki</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology, Department of Medicine, Jichi Medical University, Shimotsuke, Tochigi, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ino</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yuji</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology, Department of Medicine, Jichi Medical University, Shimotsuke, Tochigi, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Takezawa</LastName>
            <ForeName>Takahito</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology, Department of Medicine, Jichi Medical University, Shimotsuke, Tochigi, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Iwashita</LastName>
            <ForeName>Chihiro</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology, Department of Medicine, Jichi Medical University, Shimotsuke, Tochigi, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nomoto</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yoshie</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology, Department of Medicine, Jichi Medical University, Shimotsuke, Tochigi, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tsunoda</LastName>
            <ForeName>Masato</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology, Department of Medicine, Jichi Medical University, Shimotsuke, Tochigi, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ueno</LastName>
            <ForeName>Takashi</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology, Department of Medicine, Jichi Medical University, Shimotsuke, Tochigi, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Takahashi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Haruo</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology, Department of Medicine, Jichi Medical University, Shimotsuke, Tochigi, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nagayama</LastName>
            <ForeName>Manabu</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology, Department of Medicine, Jichi Medical University, Shimotsuke, Tochigi, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Fukuda</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hisashi</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology, Department of Medicine, Jichi Medical University, Shimotsuke, Tochigi, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lefor</LastName>
            <ForeName>Alan Kawarai</ForeName>
            <Initials>AK</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Surgery, Jichi Medical University, Shimotsuke, Tochigi, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yamamoto</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hironori</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology, Department of Medicine, Jichi Medical University, Shimotsuke, Tochigi, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Endosc Int Open</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101639919</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2196-9736</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CoiStatement>Competing interests Dr. Yamamoto has patents for ESD devices and double-balloon endoscopy produced by Fujifilm Corporation. He has a consultant relationship with the Fujifilm Corporation and has received honoraria, grants, and royalties from the company. Drs. Osawa and Miura have received honoraria from Fujifilm Corporation.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>3</Hour>
          <Minute>59</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35571481</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9106443</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/a-1793-9414</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yagi J, Adachi K, Arima N et al.A prospective randomized comparative study on the safety and tolerability of transnasal esophagogastroduodenoscopy. Endoscopy. 2005;37:1226–1231.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16329022</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Murata A, Akahoshi K, Sumida Y et al.Prospective randomized trial of transnasal versus peroral endoscopy using an ultrathin videoendoscope in unsedated patients. J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2007;22:482–485.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17376037</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garcia R T, Cello J P, Nguyen M H et al.Unsedated ultrathin EGD is well accepted when compared with conventional sedated EGD: a multicenter randomized trial. Gastroenterology. 2003;125:1606–1612.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14724812</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thota P N, Zuccaro G Jr, Vargo J J, 2nd et al.A randomized prospective trial comparing unsedated esophagoscopy via transnasal and transoral routes using a 4-mm video endoscope with conventional endoscopy with sedation. Endoscopy. 2005;37:559–565.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15933930</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Preiss C, Charton J P, Schumacher B et al.A randomized trial of unsedated transnasal small-caliber esophagogastroduodenoscopy (EGD) versus peroral small-caliber EGD versus conventional EGD. Endoscopy. 2003;35:641–646.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12929057</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mori A, Ohashi N, Tatebe H et al.Autonomic nervous function in upper gastrointestinal endoscopy: A prospective randomized comparison between transnasal and oral procedures. J Gastroenterol. 2008;43:38–44.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18297434</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mori A, Ohashi N, Maruyama T et al.Cardiovascular tolerance in upper gastrointestinal endoscopy using an ultrathin scope: prospective randomized comparison between transnasal and transoral procedures. Digest Endosc. 2008;20:79–83.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tatsumi Y, Harada A, Matsumoto T et al.Current status and evaluation of transnasal esophagogastroduodenoscopy. Digest Endosc. 2009;21:141–146.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Toyoizumi H, Kaise M, Arakawa H et al.Ultrathin endoscopy versus high-resolution endoscopy for diagnosing superficial gastric neoplasia. Gastrointest Endosc. 2009;70:240–245.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19386304</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zaman A, Hahn M, Hapke R et al.A randomized trial of peroral versus transnasal unsedated endoscopy using an ultrathin videoendoscope. Gastrointest Endosc. 1999;49:279–284.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10049408</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Faulx A L, Catanzaro A, Zyzanski S et al.Patient tolerance and acceptance of unsedated ultrathin esophagoscopy. Gastrointest Endosc. 2002;55:620–623.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11979240</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Birkner B, Fritz N, Schatke W et al.A prospective randomized comparison of unsedated ultrathin versus standard esophagogastroduodenoscopy in routine outpatient gastroenterology practice: does it work better through the nose? Endoscopy. 2003;35:647–651.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12929058</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yoshida Y, Hayami Y, Matuoka M et al.Comparison of endoscopic detection rate of early gastric cancer and gastric adenoma using transnasal egd with that of transoral EGD. Digest Endosc. 2008;20:184–189.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ono S, Kawada K, Dohi O et al.Linked color imaging focused on neoplasm detection in the upper gastrointestinal tract : a randomized trial. Ann Internal Med. 2021;174:18–24.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33076693</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gotoda T, Uedo N, Yoshinaga S et al.Basic principles and practice of gastric cancer screening using high-definition white-light gastroscopy: Eyes can only see what the brain knows. Dig Endosc. 2016;28:2–15.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26836611</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yoshida N, Naito Y, Murakami T et al.Linked color imaging improves the visibility of colorectal polyps: a video study. Endosc Int Open. 2017;5:E518–E525.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5462607</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28596985</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kanzaki H, Takenaka R, Kawahara Y et al.Linked color imaging (LCI), a novel image-enhanced endoscopy technology, emphasizes the color of early gastric cancer. Endosc Int Open. 2017;5:E1005–e1013.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5634856</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29159276</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fukuda H, Miura Y, Osawa H et al.Linked color imaging can enhance recognition of early gastric cancer by high color contrast to surrounding gastric intestinal metaplasia. J Gastroenterol. 2019;54:396–406.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30291440</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Takeda T, Nagahara A, Ishizuka K et al.Improved Visibility of barrett’s esophagus with linked color imaging: inter- and intra-rater reliability and quantitative analysis. Digestion. 2018;97:183–194.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29320766</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pierre S A, Ferrandino M N, Simmons W N et al.High definition laparoscopy: objective assessment of performance characteristics and comparison with standard laparoscopy. J Endourol. 2009;23:523–528.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19250028</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yabe H. Magnifying ratio and resolution of electronic endoscopes. Digest Endosc. 2002;14:S88–S90.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Osawa H, Yamamoto H, Miura Y et al.Diagnosis of depressed-type early gastric cancer using small-caliber endoscopy with flexible spectral imaging color enhancement. Digest Endosc. 2012;24:231–236.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Osawa H, Yamamoto H, Yamada N et al.Diagnosis of endoscopic Barrett's esophagus by transnasal flexible spectral imaging color enhancement. J Gastroenterol. 2009;44:1125–1132.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19714289</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Osawa H, Yamamoto H, Miura Y et al.Blue laser imaging provides excellent endoscopic images of upper gastrointestinal lesions. Video J Encycloped GI Endosc. 2014;1:607–610.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Osawa H, Miura Y, Takezawa T et al.Linked color imaging and blue laser imaging for upper gastrointestinal screening. Clin Endosc. 2018;51:513–526.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6283759</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30384402</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen H N, Wang Z, Li X et al.Helicobacter pylori eradication cannot reduce the risk of gastric cancer in patients with intestinal metaplasia and dysplasia: evidence from a meta-analysis. Gastric Cancer. 2016;19:166–175.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25609452</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saka A, Yagi K, Nimura S. Endoscopic and histological features of gastric cancers after successful Helicobacter pylori eradication therapy. Gastric Cancer. 2016;19:524–530.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25752268</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Takahashi H, Miura Y, Osawa H et al.Blue laser imaging with a small-caliber endoscope facilitates detection of early gastric cancer. Clin Endosc. 2019;52:273–277.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6547336</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30103296</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Toma S, Osawa H, Yoshizawa M et al.Diagnosis of small flat early gastric cancer by flexible spectral imaging color enhancement. Clin J Gastroenterol. 2010;3:88–91.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26190001</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
