<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35576095</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>16</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1708-0428</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>16</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Obesity surgery</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Obes Surg</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Impact of Intragastric Balloon Placement on the Stomach Wall: A Prospective Cohort Study.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s11695-022-06101-0</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Endoscopic intragastric balloon (IGB) placement is a minimally invasive treatment for morbid obesity that is sometimes used as a preparatory step before surgical intervention. This study was performed to analyze the changes in the stomach wall induced by IGB placement, with particular emphasis on pathomorphology, inflammatory markers, and tissue growth factors.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="MATERIAL AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">In total, 30 patients with morbid obesity were prospectively analyzed. A total of 16 patients with body mass index (BMI) ≥ 53 kg/m<sup>2</sup> underwent two-stage treatment comprising IGB placement followed by laparoscopic sleeve gastrectomy (LSG) (IGB group), while 14 patients underwent one-stage LSG (non-IGB group). The gastric specimens removed during LSG were examined. The two groups were compared regarding the surgical results, microscopic structure and inflammatory process exponents of the stomach wall, and receptors for selected tissue growth factors.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The IGB group had a longer median hospital stay than that of the non-IGB group. Compared with the non-IGB group, the IGB group had a thicker stomach wall, more submucosal fibrosis, and increased amounts of growth factors and inflammatory markers.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Patients with IGB placement before LSG showed greater changes in the stomach wall than those of patients who received LSG alone. IGB placement was associated with stomach muscle layer thickening, submucosal fibrosis, and increased levels of inflammatory markers and tissue growth factors.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Science+Business Media, LLC, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Rzepa</LastName>
            <ForeName>Anna</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>2nd Department of General Surgery, Jagiellonian University Medical College, Krakow, Poland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wysocki</LastName>
            <ForeName>Michał</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>2nd Department of General Surgery, Jagiellonian University Medical College, Krakow, Poland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hankus</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jerzy</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pathomorphology, Jagiellonian University Medical College, Krakow, Poland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Szpor</LastName>
            <ForeName>Joanna</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pathomorphology, Jagiellonian University Medical College, Krakow, Poland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Dworak</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jadwiga</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>2nd Department of General Surgery, Jagiellonian University Medical College, Krakow, Poland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wierdak</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mateusz</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>2nd Department of General Surgery, Jagiellonian University Medical College, Krakow, Poland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Małczak</LastName>
            <ForeName>Piotr</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>2nd Department of General Surgery, Jagiellonian University Medical College, Krakow, Poland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Stefura</LastName>
            <ForeName>Tomasz</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>2nd Department of General Surgery, Jagiellonian University Medical College, Krakow, Poland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Korbut</LastName>
            <ForeName>Edyta</ForeName>
            <Initials>E</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Physiology, Jagiellonian University Medical College, Krakow, Poland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Surmiak</LastName>
            <ForeName>Marcin</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Physiology, Jagiellonian University Medical College, Krakow, Poland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Magierowski</LastName>
            <ForeName>Marcin</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Physiology, Jagiellonian University Medical College, Krakow, Poland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Pędziwiatr</LastName>
            <ForeName>Michał</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>2nd Department of General Surgery, Jagiellonian University Medical College, Krakow, Poland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Major</LastName>
            <ForeName>Piotr</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6552-7979</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>2nd Department of General Surgery, Jagiellonian University Medical College, Krakow, Poland. piotr.major@uj.edu.pl.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Obes Surg</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9106714</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0960-8923</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Intragastric balloon</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pathomorphology</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sleeve gastrectomy</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>31</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>13</Hour>
          <Minute>26</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35576095</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11695-022-06101-0</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s11695-022-06101-0</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maciejewski ML Arterburn DE Van Scoyoc L et al. Bariatric surgery and long-term durability of weight loss. JAMA Surg. Epub ahead of print 2016 https://doi.org/10.1001/jamasurg.2016.2317</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dworak J, Wysocki M, Rzepa A, et al. Learning curve for laparoscopic Roux-en-Y gastric bypass based on the experience of a newly created bariatric center. Polish J Surg. Epub ahead of print 2020. https://doi.org/10.5604/01.3001.0014.1513 .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aguilar-Olivos NE, Almeda-Valdes P, Aguilar-Salinas CA, et al. The role of bariatric surgery in the management of nonalcoholic fatty liver disease and metabolic syndrome. Metab Clin Exp. Epub ahead of print 2016. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.metabol.2015.09.004 .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wilkinson KH, Helm M, Lak K, et al. The risk of post-operative complications in super-super obesity compared to super obesity in accredited bariatric surgery centers. Obes Surg. 2019;29:2964–71.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11695-019-03942-0</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stefura T, Droś J, Kacprzyk A, et al. Influence of preoperative weight loss on outcomes of bariatric surgery for patients under the enhanced recovery after surgery protocol. Obes Surg. . Epub ahead of print 2019. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11695-018-03660-z .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nielsen L V., Nielsen MS, Schmidt JB, et al. Efficacy of a liquid low-energy formula diet in achieving preoperative target weight loss before bariatric surgery. J Nutr Sci. Epub ahead of print 2016. https://doi.org/10.1017/jns.2016.13 .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ball W, Raza SS, Loy J, et al. Effectiveness of intra-gastric balloon as a bridge to definitive surgery in the super obese. Obes Surg. Epub ahead of print 2019. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11695-019-03794-8 .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ashrafian H, Monnich M, Braby TS, et al. Intragastric balloon outcomes in super-obesity: a 16-year city center hospital series. Surg Obes Relat Dis. Epub ahead of print 2018. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.soard.2018.07.010 .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee Y, Dang JT, Switzer N, et al. Bridging interventions before bariatric surgery in patients with BMI ≥ 50 kg/m2: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Surg Endosc. Epub ahead of print 2019. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00464-019-07027-y .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Choi SJ, Choi HS Various intragastric balloons under clinical investigation. Clinical Endoscopy. Epub ahead of print 2018. https://doi.org/10.5946/ce.2018.140 .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Major P, Wysocki M, Pędziwiatr M, et al. More stapler firings increase the risk of perioperative morbidity after laparoscopic sleeve gastrectomy. Wideochirurgia I Inne Tech Maloinwazyjne. Epub ahead of print 2018. https://doi.org/10.5114/wiitm.2017.70197 .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Magierowska K, Bakalarz D, Wójcik D, et al. Evidence for cytoprotective effect of carbon monoxide donor in the development of acute esophagitis leading to acute esophageal epithelium lesions. Cells. Epub ahead of print 2020. https://doi.org/10.3390/cells9051203 .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>DeBakey M, Ochsner A. Bezoars and concretions. A comprehensive review of the literature with an analysis of 303 collected cases and a presentation of 8 additional cases. Surgery. Epub ahead of print 1939. https://doi.org/10.5555/uri:pii:S0039606039904289 .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gleysteen JJ. A history of intragastric balloons. Surg Obes Relat Dis. Epub ahead of print 2016. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.soard.2015.10.074 .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Da Silva JR, Proença L, Rodrigues A, et al. Intragastric balloon for obesity treatment: safety, tolerance, and efficacy. GE Port J Gastroenterol. Epub ahead of print 2018. https://doi.org/10.1159/000485428 .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mafort TT, Madeira E, Madeira M, et al. Six-month intragastric balloon treatment for obesity improves lung function, body composition, and metabolic syndrome. Obes Surg. . Epub ahead of print 2014. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11695-013-1061-5 .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Atef E, Zalata KR, Atef H, et al. Increased proliferative activity accompanies the local inflammatory response of gastric mucosa after intragastric balloon insertion. Dig Dis Sci. . Epub ahead of print 2016. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10620-016-4344-6 .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>PÉRISSÉ LGS, ECBC-RJ PCMP, RIBEIRO KF. Gastric wall changes after intragastric balloon placement: a preliminary experience. Rev Col Bras Cir. Epub ahead of print 2016. https://doi.org/10.1590/0100-69912016004011 .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Joffe OY, Molnar IM, Tarasyuk T V, et al. Morphological changes of gastric mucosa after insertion of intragastric balloon. Klin Khir.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rawlins L, Rawlins MP, Teel D. Human tissue thickness measurements from excised sleeve gastrectomy specimens. Surg Endosc. Epub ahead of print 2014. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00464-013-3264-1 .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barski K, Binda A, Kudlicka E, et al. Gastric wall thickness and stapling in laparoscopic sleeve gastrectomy - a literature review. Wideochirurgia I Inne Techniki Maloinwazyjne. Epub ahead of print 2018. https://doi.org/10.5114/wiitm.2018.73362 .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hering I, Dörries L, Flemming S, Krietenstein L, Koschker A-K , Fassnacht M, Germer C-T. Hankir M. Impact of preoperative weight loss achieved by gastric balloon on peri- and postoperative outcomes of bariatric surgery in super-obese patients: a retrospective matched-pair analysis Langenbecks Arch Surg 2022 Mar 8 https://doi.org/10.1007/s00423-022-02472-1</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martin C, Torre L, Herrera L, Rivero M, Ferrer M, Pacheco D, Rios M, Martin R, Martin J, Vazquez-Echarri J, Merino. Preoperative intragastric balloon in morbid obesity is unable to decrease early postoperative morbidity of bariatric surgery (sleeve gastrectomy and gastric bypass): a clinical assay. Surg Endosc. 2020;34(6):2519–31. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00464-019-07061-w) .</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00464-019-07061-w)</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
