<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35574994</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>16</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1469-3178</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>16</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>EMBO reports</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>EMBO Rep</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Nlrp3 inflammasome activation in macrophages suffices for inducing autoinflammation in mice.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e54339</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e54339</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.15252/embr.202154339</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Cryopyrin-associated periodic syndromes (CAPS) are a spectrum of autoinflammatory disorders caused by gain-of-function NLRP3 mutant proteins that form hyperactive inflammasomes leading to overproduction of the pro-inflammatory cytokines IL-1β and IL-18. Expressing the murine gain-of-function Nlrp3<sup>A350V</sup> mutant selectively in neutrophils recapitulates several autoinflammatory features of human CAPS, but the potential contribution of macrophage inflammasome hyperactivation to CAPS development is poorly defined. Here, we show that expressing Nlrp3<sup>A350V</sup> in macrophages is sufficient for driving severe multi-organ autoinflammation leading to perinatal lethality in mice. In addition, we show that macrophages contribute to autoinflammation also in adult mice, as depleting macrophages in mice ubiquitously expressing Nlrp3<sup>A350V</sup> significantly diminishes splenic and hepatic IL-1β production. Interestingly, inflammation induced by macrophage-selective Nlrp3<sup>A350V</sup> expression does not provoke an influx of mature neutrophils, while neutrophil influx is still occurring in macrophage-depleted mice with body-wide Nlrp3<sup>A350V</sup> expression. These observations identify macrophages as important cellular drivers of CAPS in mice and support a cooperative cellular model of CAPS development in which macrophages and neutrophils act independently of each other in propagating severe autoinflammation.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Authors.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Frising</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ulrika C</ForeName>
            <Initials>UC</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2314-7326</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine and Paediatrics, Ghent University, Ghent, Belgium.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>VIB-UGent Center for Inflammation Research, VIB, Ghent, Belgium.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ribo</LastName>
            <ForeName>Silvia</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8983-827X</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine and Paediatrics, Ghent University, Ghent, Belgium.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>VIB-UGent Center for Inflammation Research, VIB, Ghent, Belgium.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Doglio</LastName>
            <ForeName>M Giulia</ForeName>
            <Initials>MG</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5499-0252</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine and Paediatrics, Ghent University, Ghent, Belgium.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>VIB-UGent Center for Inflammation Research, VIB, Ghent, Belgium.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Malissen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Bernard</ForeName>
            <Initials>B</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1340-9342</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Centre d'Immunologie de Marseille-Luminy, Aix-Marseille Université, INSERM, CNRS, Marseille, France.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>van Loo</LastName>
            <ForeName>Geert</ForeName>
            <Initials>G</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8427-4775</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>VIB-UGent Center for Inflammation Research, VIB, Ghent, Belgium.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Molecular Biology, Ghent University, Ghent, Belgium.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wullaert</LastName>
            <ForeName>Andy</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5012-654X</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine and Paediatrics, Ghent University, Ghent, Belgium.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>VIB-UGent Center for Inflammation Research, VIB, Ghent, Belgium.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Laboratory of Protein Chemistry, Proteomics and Epigenetic Signalling (PPES), Department of Biomedical Sciences, University of Antwerp, Antwerp, Belgium.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>EMBO Rep</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>100963049</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1469-221X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Nlrp3</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cryopyrin-associated periodic syndromes</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">inflammasome</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">interleukin-1β</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">macrophage</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>24</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35574994</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15252/embr.202154339</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abram CL, Roberge GL, Hu Y, Lowell CA (2014) Comparative analysis of the efficiency and specificity of myeloid-Cre deleting strains using ROSA-EYFP reporter mice. J Immunol Methods 408: 89-100</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aksentijevich I, Nowak M, Mallah M, Chae JJ, Watford WT, Hofmann SR, Stein L, Russo R, Goldsmith D, Dent P et al (2002) De novo CIAS1 mutations, cytokine activation, and evidence for genetic heterogeneity in patients with neonatal-onset multisystem inflammatory disease (NOMID): a new member of the expanding family of pyrin-associated autoinflammatory diseases. Arthritis Rheum 46: 3340-3348</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Booshehri LM, Hoffman HM (2019) CAPS and NLRP3. J Clin Immunol 39: 277-286</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brydges SD, Broderick L, McGeough MD, Pena CA, Mueller JL, Hoffman HM (2013) Divergence of IL-1, IL-18, and cell death in NLRP3 inflammasomopathies. J Clin Invest 123: 4695-4705</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brydges SD, Mueller JL, McGeough MD, Pena CA, Misaghi A, Gandhi C, Putnam CD, Boyle DL, Firestein GS, Horner AA et al (2009) Inflammasome-mediated disease animal models reveal roles for innate but not adaptive immunity. Immunity 30: 875-887</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Calcagno DM, Chu A, Gaul S, Taghdiri N, Toomu A, Leszczynska A, Kaufmann B, Papouchado B, Wree A, Geisler L et al (2022) NOD-like receptor protein 3 activation causes spontaneous inflammation and fibrosis that mimics human NASH. Hepatology, https://doi.org/10.1002/hep.32320</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Camilli G, Bohm M, Piffer AC, Lavenir R, Williams DL, Neven B, Grateau G, Georgin-Lavialle S, Quintin J (2020) beta-Glucan-induced reprogramming of human macrophages inhibits NLRP3 inflammasome activation in cryopyrinopathies. J Clin Invest 130: 4561-4573</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Erlich Z, Shlomovitz I, Edry-Botzer L, Cohen H, Frank D, Wang H, Lew AM, Lawlor KE, Zhan Y, Vince JE et al (2019) Macrophages, rather than DCs, are responsible for inflammasome activity in the GM-CSF BMDC model. Nat Immunol 20: 397-406</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Evrard M, Kwok IWH, Chong SZ, Teng KWW, Becht E, Chen J, Sieow JL, Penny HL, Ching GC, Devi S et al (2018) Developmental analysis of bone marrow neutrophils reveals populations specialized in expansion, trafficking, and effector functions. Immunity 48: 364-379.e8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Feldmann J, Prieur AM, Quartier P, Berquin P, Certain S, Cortis E, Teillac-Hamel D, Fischer A, de Saint BG (2002) Chronic infantile neurological cutaneous and articular syndrome is caused by mutations in CIAS1, a gene highly expressed in polymorphonuclear cells and chondrocytes. Am J Hum Genet 71: 198-203</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gautier EL, Shay T, Miller J, Greter M, Jakubzick C, Ivanov S, Helft J, Chow A, Elpek KG, Gordonov S et al (2012) Gene-expression profiles and transcriptional regulatory pathways that underlie the identity and diversity of mouse tissue macrophages. Nat Immunol 13: 1118-1128</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guilliams M, Mildner A, Yona S (2018) Developmental and functional heterogeneity of monocytes. Immunity 49: 595-613</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guilliams M, Thierry GR, Bonnardel J, Bajenoff M (2020) Establishment and maintenance of the macrophage niche. Immunity 52: 434-451</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hoffman HM, Broderick L (2016) The role of the inflammasome in patients with autoinflammatory diseases. J Allergy Clin Immunol 138: 3-14</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hoffman HM, Mueller JL, Broide DH, Wanderer AA, Kolodner RD (2001a) Mutation of a new gene encoding a putative pyrin-like protein causes familial cold autoinflammatory syndrome and Muckle-Wells syndrome. Nat Genet 29: 301-305</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hoffman HM, Wanderer AA, Broide DH (2001b) Familial cold autoinflammatory syndrome: phenotype and genotype of an autosomal dominant periodic fever. J Allergy Clin Immunol 108: 615-620</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khoyratty TE, Ai Z, Ballesteros I, Eames HL, Mathie S, Martín-Salamanca S, Wang L, Hemmings A, Willemsen N, von Werz V et al (2021) Distinct transcription factor networks control neutrophil-driven inflammation. Nat Immunol 22: 1093-1106</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kwok I, Becht E, Xia YU, Ng M, Teh YC, Tan L, Evrard M, Li JLY, Tran HTN, Tan Y et al (2020) Combinatorial single-cell analyses of granulocyte-monocyte progenitor heterogeneity reveals an early uni-potent neutrophil progenitor. Immunity 53: 303-318.e5</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lachmann HJ, Kone-Paut I, Kuemmerle-Deschner JB, Leslie KS, Hachulla E, Quartier P, Gitton X, Widmer A, Patel N, Hawkins PN et al (2009) Use of canakinumab in the cryopyrin-associated periodic syndrome. N Engl J Med 360: 2416-2425</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McGeough MD, Pena CA, Mueller JL, Pociask DA, Broderick L, Hoffman HM, Brydges SD (2012) Cutting edge: IL-6 is a marker of inflammation with no direct role in inflammasome-mediated mouse models. J Immunol 189: 2707-2711</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McGeough MD, Wree A, Inzaugarat ME, Haimovich A, Johnson CD, Pena CA, Goldbach-Mansky R, Broderick L, Feldstein AE, Hoffman HM (2017) TNF regulates transcription of NLRP3 inflammasome components and inflammatory molecules in cryopyrinopathies. J Clin Invest 127: 4488-4497</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nakamura Y, Franchi L, Kambe N, Meng G, Strober W, Nunez G (2012) Critical role for mast cells in interleukin-1beta-driven skin inflammation associated with an activating mutation in the nlrp3 protein. Immunity 37: 85-95</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rojo R, Raper A, Ozdemir DD, Lefevre L, Grabert K, Wollscheid-Lengeling E, Bradford B, Caruso M, Gazova I, Sánchez A et al (2019) Deletion of a Csf1r enhancer selectively impacts CSF1R expression and development of tissue macrophage populations. Nat Commun 10: 3215</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Van Rooijen N, Sanders A (1994) Liposome mediated depletion of macrophages: mechanism of action, preparation of liposomes and applications. J Immunol Methods 174: 83-93</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schuster-Gaul S, Geisler LJ, McGeough MD, Johnson CD, Zagorska A, Li LI, Wree A, Barry V, Mikaelian I, Jih LJ et al (2020) ASK1 inhibition reduces cell death and hepatic fibrosis in an Nlrp3 mutant liver injury model. JCI Insight 5: e123294</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scott CL, T’Jonck W, Martens L, Todorov H, Sichien D, Soen B, Bonnardel J, De Prijck S, Vandamme N, Cannoodt R et al (2018) The transcription factor ZEB2 is required to maintain the tissue-specific identities of macrophages. Immunity 49: 312-325.e5</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stackowicz J, Gaudenzio N, Serhan N, Conde E, Godon O, Marichal T, Starkl P, Balbino B, Roers A, Bruhns P et al (2021) Neutrophil-specific gain-of-function mutations in Nlrp3 promote development of cryopyrin-associated periodic syndrome. J Exp Med 218: e20201466</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Touitou I, Lesage S, McDermott M, Cuisset L, Hoffman H, Dode C, Shoham N, Aganna E, Hugot J-P, Wise C et al (2004) Infevers: an evolving mutation database for auto-inflammatory syndromes. Hum Mutat 24: 194-198</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vande Walle L, Stowe IB, Šácha P, Lee BL, Demon D, Fossoul A, Van Hauwermeiren F, Saavedra PHV, Šimon P, Šubrt V et al (2019) MCC950/CRID3 potently targets the NACHT domain of wild-type NLRP3 but not disease-associated mutants for inflammasome inhibition. PLoS Biol 17: e3000354</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ventura A, Kirsch DG, McLaughlin ME, Tuveson DA, Grimm J, Lintault L, Newman J, Reczek EE, Weissleder R, Jacks T (2007) Restoration of p53 function leads to tumour regression in vivo. Nature 445: 661-665</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vilaysane A, Chun J, Seamone ME, Wang W, Chin R, Hirota S, Li Y, Clark SA, Tschopp J, Trpkov K et al (2010) The NLRP3 inflammasome promotes renal inflammation and contributes to CKD. J Am Soc Nephrol 21: 1732-1744</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xiao J, Wang C, Yao J-C, Alippe Y, Xu C, Kress D, Civitelli R, Abu-Amer Y, Kanneganti T-D, Link DC et al (2018) Gasdermin D mediates the pathogenesis of neonatal-onset multisystem inflammatory disease in mice. PLoS Biol 16: e3000047</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yanez A, Coetzee SG, Olsson A, Muench DE, Berman BP, Hazelett DJ, Salomonis N, Grimes HL, Goodridge HS (2017) Granulocyte-monocyte progenitors and monocyte-dendritic cell progenitors independently produce functionally distinct monocytes. Immunity 47: 890-902 e894</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
