<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35575633</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>23</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1520-5010</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>16</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Chemical research in toxicology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Chem Res Toxicol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Neutrophil Myeloperoxidase-Mediated N-Demethylation of Quetiapine Leads to <i>N</i>-Desalkylquetiapine, a Pharmacologically Active Cytochrome P450 Metabolite.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1021/acs.chemrestox.2c00008</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The atypical antipsychotic drugs, quetiapine and clozapine, are associated with idiosyncratic drug reactions (such as agranulocytosis or neutropenia) that are thought to involve reactive metabolites. Neutrophil myeloperoxidase (MPO) metabolism of quetiapine is not well-studied, but is metabolized by cytochrome P450. Based on structural similarity to clozapine, we hypothesized that quetiapine can be metabolized by MPO and that there is overlap between cytochrome P450 and MPO metabolism of quetiapine. The interaction of quetiapine and clozapine with MPO and MPO chlorination activity was studied using UV-vis spectrophotometry. The metabolites were characterized using liquid chromatography-mass spectrometry (LC-MS), and electron paramagnetic resonance (EPR) spectroscopy was used for detecting drug-catalyzed glutathione oxidation. In the presence of quetiapine, MPO compound II accumulated for about 7.5 min, whereas in the presence of clozapine, MPO compound II was not observed as it was rapidly reduced back to the resting state. Increasing quetiapine concentrations resulted in a decrease in MPO chlorination activity, while the opposite result was found in the case of clozapine. UV-vis spectral studies showed no change when quetiapine was oxidized in the absence and presence of chloride anion (Cl<sup>-</sup>, to catalyze chlorination reactions). Significant changes, however, were observed in the same assay with clozapine, where Cl<sup>-</sup> appeared to hinder the rate of clozapine metabolism. The MPO-catalyzed hydroxylated and dealkylated metabolites of quetiapine and hydroxylated metabolites of clozapine were observed from the LC-MS analyses, particularly when Cl<sup>-</sup> was included in the reaction. In addition, hydroxylated, dealkylated, and a proposed sulfoxide metabolite of quetiapine were also observed in the reaction catalyzed by human microsomes/NADPH. Lastly, compared to quetiapine, clozapine metabolism by MPO/H<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub> and glutathione produced more glutathionyl radicals using EPR spin trapping. In conclusion, MPO/H<sub>2</sub>O<sub>2</sub>/Cl<sup>-</sup> was shown to metabolize quetiapine to S-oxidation and P450-like dealkylation products, and quetiapine metabolites were generally less reactive than clozapine.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Rashid</LastName>
            <ForeName>Md Harunur</ForeName>
            <Initials>MH</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Faculty of Pharmacy and Pharmaceutical Sciences, University of Alberta, Edmonton, Alberta T6G 2E1, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Food and Radiation Biology, Bangladesh Atomic Energy Commission, 1207 Dhaka, Bangladesh.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Babu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Dinesh</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5922-1081</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Faculty of Pharmacy and Pharmaceutical Sciences, University of Alberta, Edmonton, Alberta T6G 2E1, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tran</LastName>
            <ForeName>Newton</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Faculty of Pharmacy and Pharmaceutical Sciences, University of Alberta, Edmonton, Alberta T6G 2E1, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Reiz</LastName>
            <ForeName>Béla</ForeName>
            <Initials>B</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2312-1441</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Chemistry, Faculty of Sciences, University of Alberta, Edmonton, Alberta T6G 2G2, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Siraki</LastName>
            <ForeName>Arno G</ForeName>
            <Initials>AG</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8317-947X</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Faculty of Pharmacy and Pharmaceutical Sciences, University of Alberta, Edmonton, Alberta T6G 2E1, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Chem Res Toxicol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8807448</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0893-228X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>9</Hour>
          <Minute>52</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35575633</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/acs.chemrestox.2c00008</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
