<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35575880</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>16</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1365-4632</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>16</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>International journal of dermatology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Int J Dermatol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>The genomic and proteomic landscape in oral lichen planus versus oral squamous cell carcinoma: a scoping review.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/ijd.16273</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Oral lichen planus (OLP), a World Health Organization (WHO)-classified oral potentially malignant condition, confers a 1% risk of transformation to oral squamous cell carcinoma (OSCC). There does not appear to be a consensus understanding of the underlying molecular events. This scoping review aimed to identify critical molecular pathways and highlight gaps in existing knowledge on malignant transformation in OLP.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Following Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analysis Protocols (PRISMA-P) guidelines, a comprehensive literature search and methodical screening identified 61 relevant studies detailing molecular differences between OLP and OSCC.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Molecular changes shared between OLP and OSCC included those affecting cellular proliferation (altered p53 expression, hypermethylation of p16/CDKN2A, MYC gains, increased ki-67), apoptosis (increased bcl-2 and survivin expression), extracellular matrix (ECM) remodeling (increased matrix metalloproteinase [MMP] expression), and transcriptional control (altered bmi1 and microRNA [miRNA] expression). In addition, some molecular alterations accumulated incrementally from control to OLP to OSCC or were present in higher-risk erosive variants of OLP or transformed OLP. Few studies included rigorous diagnostic inclusion criteria or unbiased discovery methods.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Results of this review support the potentially malignant nature of OLP and imply that molecular events associated with malignant transformation may be heterogeneous. In addition, findings in this review highlight the need for additional studies using rigorous diagnostic inclusion criteria and unbiased discovery methods to further understand this process.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 the International Society of Dermatology.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Xie</LastName>
            <ForeName>Fangyi</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5524-2750</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, MN, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Meves</LastName>
            <ForeName>Alexander</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7462-8288</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, MN, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biochemistry and Molecular Biology, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, MN, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lehman</LastName>
            <ForeName>Julia S</ForeName>
            <Initials>JS</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7389-3853</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, MN, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Laboratory Medicine and Pathology, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, MN, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Int J Dermatol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0243704</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0011-9059</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>13</Hour>
          <Minute>13</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35575880</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ijd.16273</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boyd AS, Neldner KH. Lichen planus. J Am Acad Dermatol 1991; 25: 593-619.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Warnakulasuriya S, Kujan O, Aguirre-Urizar JM, et al. Oral potentially malignant disorders: a consensus report from an international seminar on nomenclature and classification, convened by the WHO collaborating Centre for Oral Cancer. Oral Dis 2021; 27: 1862-1880.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gonzalez-Moles MA, Ramos-Garcia P, Warnakulasuriya S. An appraisal of highest quality studies reporting malignant transformation of oral lichen planus based on a systematic review. Oral Dis 2020; 03: 03.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aghbari SMH, Abushouk AI, Attia A, et al. Malignant transformation of oral lichen planus and oral lichenoid lesions: a meta-analysis of 20095 patient data. Oral Oncol 2017; 68: 92-102.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Idrees M, Kujan O, Shearston K, et al. Oral lichen planus has a very low malignant transformation rate: a systematic review and meta-analysis using strict diagnostic and inclusion criteria. J Oral Pathol Med 2020; 25: 25.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iocca O, Sollecito TP, Alawi F, et al. Potentially malignant disorders of the oral cavity and oral dysplasia: a systematic review and meta-analysis of malignant transformation rate by subtype. Head Neck 2020; 42: 539-555.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gonzalez-Moles MA, Scully C, Gil-Montoya JA. Oral lichen planus: controversies surrounding malignant transformation. Oral Dis 2008; 14: 229-243.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gonzalez-Moles MA, Warnakulasuriya S, Gonzalez-Ruiz I, et al. Clinicopathological and prognostic characteristics of oral squamous cell carcinomas arising in patients with oral lichen planus: a systematic review and a comprehensive meta-analysis. Oral Oncol 2020; 106: 104688.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van der Meij EH, van der Waal I. Lack of clinicopathologic correlation in the diagnosis of oral lichen planus based on the presently available diagnostic criteria and suggestions for modifications. J Oral Pathol Med 2003; 32: 507-512.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cheng Y-SL, Gould A, Kurago Z, et al. Diagnosis of oral lichen planus: a position paper of the American Academy of Oral and maxillofacial pathology. Oral surg Oral med Oral Pathol Oral Radiol 2016; 122: 332-354.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kramer IRH, Lucas RB, Pindborg JJ. Definition of leukoplakia and related lesions: an aid to studies on oral precancer. Oral Surg Oral Med Oral Pathol 1978; 46: 518-539.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gonzalez-Moles MA, Ruiz-Avila I, Gonzalez-Ruiz L, et al. Malignant transformation risk of oral lichen planus: a systematic review and comprehensive meta-analysis. Oral Oncol 2019; 96: 121-130.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yoo BC, Kim KH, Woo SM, et al. Clinical multi-omics strategies for the effective cancer management. J Proteome 2018; 188: 97-106.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hanahan D, Weinberg RA. Hallmarks of cancer: the next generation. Cell 2011; 144: 646-674.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krithikadatta J, Gopikrishna V, Datta M. CRIS guidelines (checklist for reporting in-vitro studies): a concept note on the need for standardized guidelines for improving quality and transparency in reporting in-vitro studies in experimental dental research. J Conserv Dent 2014; 17: 301-304.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guyatt G, Oxman AD, Akl EA, et al. GRADE guidelines: 1. Introduction-GRADE evidence profiles and summary of findings tables. J Clin Epidemiol 2011; 64: 383-394.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eckert S. Re: Is there a quality scale to rate quality of in-vitro studies for a systematic review? 2017. https://www.researchgate.net/post/Is_there_a_quality_scale_to_rate_quality_of_in-vitro_studies_for_a_systematic_review#:~:text=Laboratory%20studies%20may%20be%20acceptable,vitro%20studies%20are%20not%20appropriate</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gu Z, Gu L, Eils R, et al. Circlize implements and enhances circular visualization in R. Bioinformatics 2014; 30: 2811-2812.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krzywinski M, Schein J, Birol I, et al. Circos: an information aesthetic for comparative genomics. Genome Res 2009; 19: 1639-1645.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee J-J, Kuo M-Y, Cheng S-J, et al. Higher expressions of p53 and proliferating cell nuclear antigen (PCNA) in atrophic oral lichen planus and patients with areca quid chewing. Oral Surg Oral Med Oral Pathol Oral Radiol Endod 2005; 99: 471-478.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leyva-Huerta E-R, Ledesma-Montes C, Rojo-Botello R-E, et al. P53 and bcl-2 immunoexpression in patients with oral lichen planus and oral squamous cell carcinoma. Med Oral Patol Oral Cir Bucal 2012; 17: e745-e750.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Safadi RA, Al Jaber SZ, Hammad HM, et al. Oral lichen planus shows higher expressions of tumor suppressor gene products of p53 and p21 compared to oral mucositis. An immunohistochemical study. Arch Oral Biol 2010; 55: 454-461.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Valente G, Pagano M, Carrozzo M, et al. Sequential immunohistochemical p53 expression in biopsies of oral lichen planus undergoing malignant evolution. J Oral Pathol Med 2001; 30: 135-140.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Sousa FACG, Paradella TC, Carvalho YR, et al. Comparative analysis of the expression of proliferating cell nuclear antigen, p53, bax, and bcl-2 in oral lichen planus and oral squamous cell carcinoma. Ann Diagn Pathol 2009; 13: 308-312.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oliveira Alves M, Balducci I, Rodarte Carvalho Y, et al. Evaluation of the expression of p53, MDM2, and SUMO-1 in oral lichen planus. Oral Dis 2013; 19: 775-780.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martin-Ezquerra G, Salgado R, Toll A, et al. Multiple genetic copy number alterations in oral squamous cell carcinoma: Study of MYC, TP53, CCDN1, EGFR and ERBB2 status in primary and metastatic tumours. Br J Dermatol 2010; 163: 1028-1035.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tabatabaei SH, Sheikhha MH, Karbasi MHA, et al. Evaluation of polymorphism of P53 protein codon 72 in oral lichen planus by PCR technique. J Dent Res Dent Clin Dent Prospects 2018; 12: 245-251.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zarate AM, Don J, Secchi D, et al. Study of the TP53 codon 72 polymorphism in oral cancer and oral potentially malignant disorders in argentine patients. Tumour Biol 2017; 39: 1010428317699113.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giacomelli L, Oluwadara O, Chiappe G, et al. Relationship between human oral lichen planus and oral squamous cell carcinoma at a genomic level: a datamining study. Bioinformation 2009; 4: 258-262.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baghaei F, Shojaei S, Afshar-Moghaddam N, et al. Study of P21 expression in Oral lichen planus and Oral squamous cell carcinoma by immunohistochemical technique. J Dent (Shiraz) 2015; 16: 156-161.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goel S, Khurana N, Marwah A, et al. Expression of cdk4 and p16 in Oral lichen planus. J Oral Maxillofac Res 2015; 6: e4.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hadzi-Mihailovic M, Stanimirovic D, Pasoski B. Role of tumor suppressor protein p16 in patients with oral lichen planus. J 2020; 25: 1193-1198.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salehinejad J, Sharifi N, Amirchaghmaghi M, et al. Immunohistochemical expression of p16 protein in oral squamous cell carcinoma and lichen planus. Ann Diagn Pathol 2014; 18: 210-213.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chujo T, Yoshida K, Takai R, et al. Analysis of DNA methylation of E-cadherin and p16ink4a in oral lichen planus/oral lichenoid lesions. Clin 2020; 03: 03.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dang J, Bian Y-Q, Sun JY, et al. MicroRNA-137 promoter methylation in oral lichen planus and oral squamous cell carcinoma. J Oral Pathol Med 2013; 42: 315-321.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen Y, Zhang W, Geng N, et al. MMPs, TIMP-2, and TGF-beta1 in the cancerization of oral lichen planus. Head Neck 2008; 30: 1237-1245.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muniz JM, Bibiano Borges CR, Beghini M, et al. Galectin-9 as an important marker in the differential diagnosis between oral squamous cell carcinoma, oral leukoplakia and oral lichen planus. Immunobiology 2015; 220: 1006-1011.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li T-J, Cui J. COX-2, MMP-7 expression in oral lichen planus and oral squamous cell carcinoma. Asian Pac J Trop Med 2013; 6: 640-643.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Loncar-Brzak B, Klobucar M, Veliki-Dalic I, et al. Expression of small leucine-rich extracellular matrix proteoglycans biglycan and lumican reveals oral lichen planus malignant potential. Clin Oral Investig 2018; 22: 1071-1082.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nafarzadeh S, Jafari S, Bijani A. Assessment of bax and bcl-2 immunoexpression in patients with oral lichen planus and oral squamous cell carcinoma. Int J Mol Cell Med 2013; 2: 136-142.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pavic I, Balicevic D, Vrdoljak B, et al. The significance of FHIT and BCL-2 in patients with oral lichen planus in comparison to the healthy oral mucosa and oral squamous cell cancer. Libr Oncol 2017; 45: 9-14.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sudha VM, Hemavathy S. Role of bcl-2 oncoprotein in oral potentially malignant disorders and squamous cell carcinoma: an immunohistochemical study. Indian J Dent Res 2011; 22: 520-525.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Angelin D, Nair BJ. Comparative evaluation of survivin expression in leukoplakia, lichen planus, and oral squamous cell carcinoma: an immunohistochemical study. J Cancer Res Ther 2020; 16: 569-574.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shi W, Yang J, Li S, et al. Potential involvement of miR-375 in the premalignant progression of oral squamous cell carcinoma mediated via transcription factor KLF5. Oncotarget 2015; 6: 40172-40185.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Suganya G, Bavle RM, Paremala K, et al. Survivin expression in oral lichen planus: Role in malignant transformation. J Oral Maxillofac Pathol 2016; 20: 234-238.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang Q, Guo B, Sun H, et al. Identification of the key genes implicated in the transformation of OLP to OSCC using RNA-sequencing. Oncol Rep 2017; 37: 2355-2365.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu J, Yang Q, Sun H, et al. The circ-AMOTL1/ENO1 Axis implicated in the tumorigenesis of OLP-associated Oral squamous cell carcinoma. Cancer Manag Res 2020; 12: 7219-7230.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chattopadhyay E, Singh R, Ray A, et al. Expression deregulation of mir31 and CXCL12 in two types of oral precancers and cancer: importance in progression of precancer and cancer. Sci 2016; 6: 32735.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Sarkar N, Roy R, Mitra JK, et al. A quest for miRNA bio-marker: a track back approach from gingivo buccal cancer to two different types of precancers. PLoS One 2014; 9: e104839.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gholizadeh N, Emami Razavi A, Mohammadpour H, et al. Association of MAPK and its regulatory miRNAs (603, 4301, 8485, and 4731) with the malignant transformation of oral lichen planus. Mol Biol Rep 2020; 47: 1223-1232.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Prasad G, Seers C, Reynolds E, et al. A panel of microRNAs can be used to determine oral squamous cell carcinoma. J Oral Pathol Med 2017; 46: 940-948.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roy R, Singh R, Chattopadhyay E, et al. MicroRNA and target gene expression based clustering of oral cancer, precancer and normal tissues. Gene 2016; 593: 58-63.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dumont P, Leu JI, Della Pietra AC 3rd, George DL, Murphy M. The codon 72 polymorphic variants of p53 have markedly different apoptotic potential. Nat Genet 2003;33:357-65.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sengupta S, Harris CC. p53: traffic cop at the crossroads of DNA repair and recombination. Nat Rev Mol Cell Biol 2005; 6: 44-55.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Petitjean A, Mathe E, Kato S, et al. Impact of mutant p53 functional properties on TP53 mutation patterns and tumor phenotype: lessons from recent developments in the IARC TP53 database. Hum Mutat 2007; 28: 622-629.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oren M, Rotter V. Mutant p53 gain-of-function in cancer. Cold Spring Harb Perspect Biol 2010; 2: a001107.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Egeblad M, Werb Z. New functions for the matrix metalloproteinases in cancer progression. Nat Rev Cancer 2002; 2: 161-174.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Winkler J, Abisoye-Ogunniyan A, Metcalf KJ, et al. Concepts of extracellular matrix remodelling in tumour progression and metastasis. Nat Commun 2020; 11: 5120.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thomas GT, Lewis MP, Speight PM. Matrix metalloproteinases and oral cancer. Oral Oncol 1999; 35: 227-233.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang X, Pursell B, Lu S, et al. Regulation of beta 4-integrin expression by epigenetic modifications in the mammary gland and during the epithelial-to-mesenchymal transition. J Cell Sci 2009; 122: 2473-2480.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kalluri R, Weinberg RA. The basics of epithelial-mesenchymal transition. J Clin Invest 2009; 119: 1420-1428.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sagari S, Sanadhya S, Doddamani M, et al. Molecular markers in oral lichen planus: a systematic review. Journal of oral and maxillofacial pathology 2016; 20: 115-121.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tampa M, Caruntu C, Mitran M, et al. Markers of Oral lichen planus malignant transformation. Dis Markers 2018; 2018: 1959506.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Atai Z, Khodadadi-Bohlouli Z, Navabi N. Molecular markers as an indicator in the malignant potential of oral lichen planus: a systematic review. J Oral Health Oral Epidemiol 2017; 6: 54-62.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Georgakopoulou EA, Achtari MD, Achtaris M, et al. Oral lichen planus as a preneoplastic inflammatory model. J Biomed Biotechnol 2012; 2012: 759626.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rai V, Mukherjee R, Ghosh AK, et al. "Omics" in oral cancer: new approaches for biomarker discovery. Arch Oral Biol 2018; 87: 15-34.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sonis ST, Amaral MR. Could the PI3K canonical pathway be a common link between chronic inflammatory conditions and oral carcinogenesis? J Oral Pathol Med. 2016; 45: 469-474.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gonzalez-Moles MA, Ramos-Garcia P, Warnakulasuriya S. The importance of understanding the terminology on oral lichenoid lesions for future research: In reply. Oral Oncol 2021; 117: 105282.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gonzalez-Moles MA, Warnakulasuriya S, Gonzalez-Ruiz I, et al. Clinical interpretation of findings from a systematic review and a comprehensive meta-analysis on clinicopathological and prognostic characteristics of oral squamous cell carcinomas (OSCC) arising in patients with oral lichen planus (OLP): author's reply. Oral Oncol 2021; 113: 105036.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
