<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35578244</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>20</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">1477-5956</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>20</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>16</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Proteome science</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Proteome Sci</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>A novel nanobody as therapeutics target for EGFR-positive colorectal cancer therapy: exploring the effects of the nanobody on SW480 cells using proteomics approach.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>9</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>9</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">9</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12953-022-00190-6</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR) overexpression is found in metastatic colorectal cancer (mCRC). Targeted molecular therapies such as monoclonal antibodies (mAbs) and tyrosine kinase inhibitors (TKI) are becoming more precise, targeting specifically for cancer therapeutics. However, there are adverse effects of currently available anti-EGFR drugs, including drug-resistant and side effects. Nanobodies can overcome these limitations. Our previous study has found that cell-penetrable nanobodies targeted at EGFR-tyrosine kinase were significantly reduced EGFR-positive lung cancer cells viability and proliferation. The aim of the present study was to determine the effect of cell-penetrable nanobody (R9VH36) on cell viability and proteomic profile in EGFR-positive human colorectal cancer cell lines.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The human colorectal carcinoma cell line (SW480) was treated with R9VH36, compared with gefitinib. Cell viability was monitored using the MTT cell viability assay. The proteomic profiling was analyzed by LC-MS/MS .</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The half-maximal inhibitory concentration (IC<sub>50</sub>) values determined for R9VH36 and gefitinib against SW480 were 527 ± 0.03 nM and 13.31 ± 0.02 μM, respectively. Moreover, both the gefitinib-treated group and nanobody-treated group had completely different proteome profiles. A total 6626 differentially expressed proteins were identified. PCA analysis revealed different proteome profiling in R9VH36 experiment. There were 8 proteins in R9VH36 that significantly exhibited opposite expression directions when compared to gefitinib. These proteins are involved in DNA-damage checkpoint processes.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The proteomics explored those 6,626 proteins had different expressions between R9VH36 and gefitinib. There were 8 proteins in R9VH36 exhibited opposite expression direction when comparing to gefitinib. Our findings suggest that R9VH36 has the potential to be an alternative remedy for treating EGFR-positive colon cancer.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y">
            <LastName>Lamtha</LastName>
            <ForeName>Thomanai</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biochemistry, Faculty of Science, Laboratory of Protein Engineering and Bioinformatics, Kasetsart University, Ngam Wong Wan, Chatuchak, Bangkok, 10900, Thailand.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y">
            <LastName>Krobthong</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sucheewin</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biochemistry, Faculty of Science, Mahidol University, Bangkok, Thailand.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Center for Neuroscience, Faculty of Science, Mahidol University, Bangkok, 10400, Thailand.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yingchutrakul</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yodying</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Center for Neuroscience, Faculty of Science, Mahidol University, Bangkok, 10400, Thailand.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>National Omics Center, NSTDA, Pathum Thani, 12120, Thailand.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Samutrtai</LastName>
            <ForeName>Pawitrabhorn</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutical Sciences, Faculty of Pharmacy, Chiang Mai University, Chiang Mai, 50200, Thailand.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gerner</LastName>
            <ForeName>Christopher</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Analytical Chemistry, University of Vienna, Währinger Straße 38, 1090, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tabtimmai</LastName>
            <ForeName>Lueacha</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biotechnology, Faculty of Applied Science, King Mongkut's University of Technology North Bangkok, Bangkok, 10800, Thailand.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Choowongkomon</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kiattawee</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biochemistry, Faculty of Science, Laboratory of Protein Engineering and Bioinformatics, Kasetsart University, Ngam Wong Wan, Chatuchak, Bangkok, 10900, Thailand. kiattawee.c@ku.th.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Proteome Sci</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101170539</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1477-5956</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Antibodies</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gefitinib</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">LC–MS/MS</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Protein interactions</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SW480</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Tyrosine kinase inhibitors</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>23</Hour>
          <Minute>48</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35578244</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9109347</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12953-022-00190-6</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12953-022-00190-6</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Costi R, Leonardi F, Zanoni D, Violi V, Roncoroni L. Palliative care and end-stage colorectal cancer management: the surgeon meets the oncologist. World J Gastroenterol. 2014;20:7602–7621. doi: 10.3748/wjg.v20.i24.7602.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3748/wjg.v20.i24.7602</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4069290</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24976699</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Perez-Gracia JL, Sanmamed MF, Bosch A, Patino-Garcia A, Schalper KA, Segura V, Bellmunt J, Tabernero J, Sweeney CJ, Choueiri TK, et al.  Strategies to design clinical studies to identify predictive biomarkers in cancer research. Cancer Treat Rev. 2017;53:79–97. doi: 10.1016/j.ctrv.2016.12.005.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ctrv.2016.12.005</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28088073</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hutchinson RA, Adams RA, McArt DG, Salto-Tellez M, Jasani B, Hamilton PW. Epidermal growth factor receptor immunohistochemistry: new opportunities in metastatic colorectal cancer. J Transl Med. 2015;13:217. doi: 10.1186/s12967-015-0531-z.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12967-015-0531-z</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4492076</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26149458</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Porebska I, Harlozinska A, Bojarowski T. Expression of the tyrosine kinase activity growth factor receptors (EGFR, ERB B2, ERB B3) in colorectal adenocarcinomas and adenomas. Tumour Biol. 2000;21:105–115. doi: 10.1159/000030116.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000030116</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10686540</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Klapper LN, Kirschbaum MH, Sela M, Yarden Y. Biochemical and clinical implications of the ErbB/HER signaling network of growth factor receptors. Adv Cancer Res. 2000;77:25–79. doi: 10.1016/S0065-230X(08)60784-8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0065-230X(08)60784-8</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10549355</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Olayioye MA, Neve RM, Lane HA, Hynes NE. The ErbB signaling network: receptor heterodimerization in development and cancer. EMBO J. 2000;19:3159–3167. doi: 10.1093/emboj/19.13.3159.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/emboj/19.13.3159</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC313958</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10880430</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Piawah S, Venook AP. Targeted therapy for colorectal cancer metastases: a review of current methods of molecularly targeted therapy and the use of tumor biomarkers in the treatment of metastatic colorectal cancer. Cancer. 2019;125:4139–4147. doi: 10.1002/cncr.32163.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cncr.32163</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31433498</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khan K, Valeri N, Dearman C, Rao S, Watkins D, Starling N, Chau I, Cunningham D. Targeting EGFR pathway in metastatic colorectal cancer- tumour heterogeniety and convergent evolution. Crit Rev Oncol Hematol. 2019;143:153–163. doi: 10.1016/j.critrevonc.2019.09.001.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.critrevonc.2019.09.001</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31678702</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Taniguchi H, Yamanaka T, Sakai D, Muro K, Yamazaki K, Nakata S, Kimura H, Ruff P, Kim TW, Peeters M et al. Efficacy of Panitumumab and Cetuximab in Patients with Colorectal Cancer Previously Treated with Bevacizumab; a Combined Analysis of Individual Patient Data from ASPECCT and WJOG6510G. Cancers (Basel). 2020;12. 10.3390/cancers12071715.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Van Cutsem E, Cervantes A, Adam R, Sobrero A, Van Krieken JH, Aderka D, Aranda Aguilar E, Bardelli A, Benson A, Bodoky G, et al.  ESMO consensus guidelines for the management of patients with metastatic colorectal cancer. Ann Oncol. 2016;27:1386–1422. doi: 10.1093/annonc/mdw235.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/annonc/mdw235</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27380959</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gazdar AF. Activating and resistance mutations of EGFR in non-small-cell lung cancer: role in clinical response to EGFR tyrosine kinase inhibitors. Oncogene. 2009;28(Suppl 1):S24–31. doi: 10.1038/onc.2009.198.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/onc.2009.198</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2849651</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19680293</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rosenzweig SA. Acquired resistance to drugs targeting tyrosine kinases. Adv Cancer Res. 2018;138:71–98. doi: 10.1016/bs.acr.2018.02.003.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/bs.acr.2018.02.003</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5985159</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29551130</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huang L, Jiang S, Shi Y. Tyrosine kinase inhibitors for solid tumors in the past 20 years (2001–2020) J Hematol Oncol. 2020;13:143. doi: 10.1186/s13045-020-00977-0.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13045-020-00977-0</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7590700</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33109256</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kosaka T, Yamaki E, Mogi A, Kuwano H. Mechanisms of resistance to EGFR TKIs and development of a new generation of drugs in non-small-cell lung cancer. J Biomed Biotechnol. 2011;2011:165214. doi: 10.1155/2011/165214.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2011/165214</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3114474</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21687596</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Prewett M, Bassi R, Paz K, Amatulli M, Deevi D, Li H, Wang S, Witte L, Samakoglu S, Tonra JR. Estimating preclinical efficacy targets utilizing cetuximab efficacy in KRAS mutant and wild-type colorectal cancer models. Anticancer Res. 2011;31:2149–2160.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21737635</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhao X, Ning Q, Mo Z, Tang S. A promising cancer diagnosis and treatment strategy: targeted cancer therapy and imaging based on antibody fragment. Artif Cells Nanomed Biotechnol. 2019;47:3621–3630. doi: 10.1080/21691401.2019.1657875.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/21691401.2019.1657875</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31468992</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lu RM, Hwang YC, Liu IJ, Lee CC, Tsai HZ, Li HJ, Wu HC. Development of therapeutic antibodies for the treatment of diseases. J Biomed Sci. 2020;27:1. doi: 10.1186/s12929-019-0592-z.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12929-019-0592-z</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6939334</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31894001</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bao G, Tang M, Zhao J, Zhu X. Nanobody: a promising toolkit for molecular imaging and disease therapy. EJNMMI Res. 2021;11:6. doi: 10.1186/s13550-021-00750-5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13550-021-00750-5</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7815856</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33464410</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roovers RC, Vosjan MJ, Laeremans T, el Khoulati R, de Bruin RC, Ferguson KM, Verkleij AJ, van Dongen GA, van Bergen en Henegouwen PM. A biparatopic anti-EGFR nanobody efficiently inhibits solid tumour growth. Int J Cancer. 2011;129:2013–2024. 10.1002/ijc.26145.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tabtimmai L, Suphakun P, Srisook P, Kiriwan D, Phanthong S, Kiatwuthinon P, Chaicumpa W, Choowongkomon K. Cell-penetrable nanobodies (transbodies) that inhibit the tyrosine kinase activity of EGFR leading to the impediment of human lung adenocarcinoma cell motility and survival. J Cell Biochem. 2019;120:18077–18087. doi: 10.1002/jcb.29111.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcb.29111</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31172597</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vizcaino JA, Cote RG, Csordas A, Dianes JA, Fabregat A, Foster JM, Griss J, Alpi E, Birim M, Contell J, et al.  The PRoteomics IDEntifications (PRIDE) database and associated tools: status in 2013. Nucleic Acids Res. 2013;41:D1063–1069. doi: 10.1093/nar/gks1262.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gks1262</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3531176</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23203882</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krobthong S, Yingchutrakul Y, Visessanguan W, Mahatnirunkul T, Samutrtai P, Chaichana C, Papan P, Choowongkomon K. Study of the lipolysis effect of nanoliposome-encapsulated ganoderma lucidum protein hydrolysates on adipocyte cells using proteomics approach. Foods. 2021;10:2157. doi: 10.3390/foods10092157.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/foods10092157</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8468392</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34574267</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nielsen SD, Jansson T, Le TT, Jensen S, Eggers N, Rauh V, Sundekilde UK, Sørensen J, Andersen HJ, Bertram HC, et al.  Correlation between sensory properties and peptides derived from hydrolysed-lactose UHT milk during storage. Int Dairy J. 2017;68:23–31. doi: 10.1016/j.idairyj.2016.12.013.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.idairyj.2016.12.013</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dallas DC, Guerrero A Fau - Parker EA, Parker Ea Fau - Garay LA, Garay La Fau - Bhandari A, Bhandari A Fau - Lebrilla CB, Lebrilla Cb Fau - Barile D, Barile D Fau - German JB, German JB. Peptidomic profile of milk of Holstein cows at peak lactation. J Agric Food Chem. 2014;62(1):58–65.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schulze WX, Mann M. A novel proteomic screen for peptide-protein interactions. J Biol Chem. 2004;279:10756–10764. doi: 10.1074/jbc.M309909200.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.M309909200</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14679214</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Siepen JA, Keevil EJ, Knight D, Hubbard SJ. Prediction of missed cleavage sites in tryptic peptides aids protein identification in proteomics. J Proteome Res. 2007;6:399–408. doi: 10.1021/pr060507u.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/pr060507u</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2664920</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17203985</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elias JE, Gygi SP. Target-decoy search strategy for increased confidence in large-scale protein identifications by mass spectrometry. Nat Methods. 2007;4:207–214. doi: 10.1038/nmeth1019.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nmeth1019</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17327847</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wei R, Wang J, Su M, Jia E, Chen S, Chen T, Ni Y. Missing value imputation approach for mass spectrometry-based metabolomics data. Sci Rep. 2018;8:663. doi: 10.1038/s41598-017-19120-0.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-017-19120-0</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5766532</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29330539</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goonesekere NCW, Wang X, Ludwig L, Guda C. A meta-analysis of pancreatic microarray datasets yields new targets as cancer genes and biomarkers. PLoS One. 2014;9:e93046. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0093046.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0093046</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3989178</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24740004</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
