<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35572462</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>14</Volume>
            <Issue>5</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Cureus</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Differential Retrospective Analysis in Oral Cancerous, Pre-cancerous, and Benign Tissue Biopsies.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e24956</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e24956</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e24956</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.24956</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Background/Aim Oral epithelia demonstrate a broad spectrum of pre-cancerous, cancerous, and benign lesions. The aim of this study was to record and analyze the prevalence of various oral and intraosseous lesions, highlighting malignancies that are hard to clinically identify as such too. Materials and methods A series of 536 oral lesions were collected covering a period of 8.5 years. Epidemiological and clinico-histopathological data were stratified and analyzed retrospectively. Results According to extensive differential analysis, the male to female ratio for oral squamous cell carcinoma was estimated at 1:1, for pre-cancerous lesions at 1:2, and for lichen planus at 1:5. The prevalent diagnostic category were cysts (n = 223, 41.6%). The biological behavior of lesions differed among anatomic sites (P&lt;0.001). Concordance between clinical suspicion of pre-cancerous or malignant lesions and histological verification was 96.4% (P&lt;0.001). Conclusions Primary intraosseous squamous cell carcinoma, acinic cell carcinoma, clear cell myoepithelial carcinoma, aggressive osteoblastoma/parosteal osteosarcoma, and undifferentiated carcinoma raised no clinical suspicion of malignancy reflecting the importance of training in oral biopsy taking.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022, Goutzanis et al.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Goutzanis</LastName>
            <ForeName>Lampros</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Oral and Maxillofacial Surgery, National and Kapodistrian University of Athens, Dental School, Athens, GRC.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cysts</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">oral biopsy</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">oral cancer</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">oral lesion</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">pre-cancerous lesions</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">prevalence</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>4</Hour>
          <Minute>13</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35572462</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9102769</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.24956</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oral biopsy in dental practice. Mota-Ramírez A, Silvestre FJ, Simó JM. http://www.medicinaoral.com/pubmed/medoralv12_i7_pE504.pdf Med Oral Patol Oral Cir Bucal. 2007;12:504–510.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oral and maxillofacial pathologies in young- and middle-aged adults. Almoznino G, Zadik Y, Vered M, et al.  Oral Dis. 2015;21:493–500.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25580799</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>The use of biopsy in dental practice. The position of the American Academy of Oral and Maxillofacial Pathology. Melrose RJ, Handlers JP, Kerpel S, Summerlin DJ, Tomich CJ. https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/17899726/ Gen Dent. 2007;55:457–461.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17899726</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>An analysis of oral biopsies extracted from 1995 to 2009, in an oral medicine and surgery unit in Galicia (Spain) Sixto-Requeijo R, Diniz-Freitas M, Torreira-Lorenzo JC, García-García A, Gándara-Rey JM. Med Oral Patol Oral Cir Bucal. 2012;17:0–22.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>An analysis of oral and maxillofacial pathology found in children over a 30-year period. Jones AV, Franklin CD. Int J Paediatr Dent. 2006;16:19–30.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16364089</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Intra-osseous lesions in Greek children and adolescents. A study based on biopsy material over a 26-year period. Skiavounou A, Iakovou M, Kontos-Toutouzas J, Kanellopoulou A, Papanikolaou S. J Clin Pediatr Dent. 2005;30:153–156.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16491971</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Biopsied jaw lesions in Kuwait: a six-year retrospective analysis. Ali MA. Med Princ Pract. 2011;20:550–555.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21986014</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Relative incidence of odontogenic tumours and oral and jaw cysts in a Canadian population. Daley TD, Wysocki GP, Pringle GA. Oral Surg Oral Med Oral Pathol. 1994;77:276–280.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8170660</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Odontogenic tumors: a review of 319 cases in a Nigerian teaching hospital. Ladeinde AL, Ajayi OF, Ogunlewe MO, Adeyemo WL, Arotiba GT, Bamgbose BO, Akinwande JA. Oral Surg Oral Med Oral Pathol Oral Radiol Endod. 2005;99:191–195.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15660091</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Epidemiological study of intraosseous lesions of the stomatognathic or maxillomandibular complex diagnosed by a reference centre in Brazil from 2006-2017. Farias JG, Souza RC, Hassam SF, Cardoso JA, Ramos TC, Santos HK. Br J Oral Maxillofac Surg. 2019;57:632–637.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31200980</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Recurrence of oral mucocoeles in adolescents after excision. Won YJ, Kang SH. Br J Oral Maxillofac Surg. 2018;56:77–78.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29179979</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>An analysis of oral and maxillofacial pathology found in adults over a 30-year period. Jones AV, Franklin CD. J Oral Pathol Med. 2006;35:392–401.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16827841</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>A retrospective study of 51,781 adult oral and maxillofacial biopsies. Dovigi EA, Kwok EY, Eversole LR, Dovigi AJ. J Am Dent Assoc. 2016;147:170–176.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26562725</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>The spectrum of histological findings in oral biopsies. Ahern J, Toner M, O’ Regan E, Nunn J. https://www.imj.ie/wp-content/uploads/2019/12/The-Spectrum-of-Histological-Findings-in-Oral-Biopsies.pdf. Ir Med J. 2019;112:1017–1025.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32081194</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>El-Naggar AK, Chan JKC, Grandis JR, Takata T, Slootweg PJ. Lyon, France: International Agency for Research on Cancer (IARC) Press; 2017. WHO Classification of Head and Neck Tumours, 4th edn.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oral cancer in men and women: are there differences? Kruse AL, Bredell M, Grätz KW. Oral Maxillofac Surg. 2011;15:51–55.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21052752</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Odontogenic cysts: a clinical study of 695 cases. Meningaud JP, Oprean N, Pitak-Arnnop P, Bertrand JC. J Oral Sci. 2006;48:59–62.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16858133</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>The use by general dental practitioners of an oral pathology diagnostic service over a 20-year period: the Birmingham Dental Hospital experience. Williams HK, Hey AA, Browne RM. Br Dent J. 1997;182:424–429.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9217339</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Concordance between clinical and histopathologic diagnoses of oral mucosal lesions. Patel KJ, De Silva HL, Tong DC, Love RM. J Oral Maxillofac Surg. 2011;69:125–133.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20971541</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Accuracy of dentists in the clinical diagnosis of oral lesions. Kondori I, Mottin R, Laskin D. https://www.quintessence-publishing.com/deu/en/article/840421. Quintessence Int. 2011;42:575–577.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21716985</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Histological investigations in ambulatory oral surgery practice. Kivovics M, Mihalyi S, Suba Z, Gyulai -Gaal S. https://ojs.mtak.hu/index.php/fogorv-szemle/article/view/5448/4293. Fogorv Sz. 2012;105:9–12.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22530364</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>The accuracy of clinical diagnosis of oral lesions and patient-specific risk factors that affect diagnosis. Forman MS, Chuang SK, August M. J Oral Maxillofac Surg. 2015;73:1932–1937.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25981860</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>The limitations of the clinical oral examination in detecting dysplastic oral lesions and oral squamous cell carcinoma. Epstein JB, Güneri P, Boyacioglu H, Abt E. J Am Dent Assoc. 2012;143:1332–1342.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23204089</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chromosome 17 in situ hybridization grid-based analysis in oral squamous cell carcinoma. Chrysovergis A, Papanikolaou V, Mastronikolis N, et al.  Anticancer Res. 2020;40:3759–3764.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32620615</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Impact of chromosome 9 numerical imbalances in oral squamous cell carcinoma: a pilot grid-based centromere analysis. Kyrodimos E, Chrysovergis A, Mastronikolis N, et al.  Diagnostics (Basel) 2020;10:501.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Double positivity for HPV DNA/P16INK4a does not influence survival of patients with oral squamous cell carcinoma. Alsharif U, Hofmann M, Gebhard M, Tharun L, Rades D, Sieg P, Hakim SG. Anticancer Res. 2021;41:5557–5568.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34732426</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>The connection between MicroRNAs and oral cancer pathogenesis: emerging biomarkers in oral cancer management. Osan C, Chira S, Nutu AM, Braicu C, Baciut M, Korban SS, Berindan-Neagoe I. Genes (Basel) 2021;12:1989.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8700798</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34946938</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>microRNAs in oral cancer: moving from bench to bed as next generation medicine. D'Souza W, Kumar A. Oral Oncol. 2020;111:104916.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32711289</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Multiple microRNA signature panel as promising potential for diagnosis and prognosis of head and neck cancer. Subha ST, Chin JW, Cheah YK, Mohtarrudin N, Saidi HI. Mol Biol Rep. 2022;49:1501–1511.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34837627</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Potential oncogenic role and prognostic implication of MicroRNA-155-5p in oral squamous cell carcinoma. Kim H, Yang JM, Ahn SH, Jeong WJ, Chung JH, Paik JH. Anticancer Res. 2018;38:5193–5200.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30194167</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
