<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35570281</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1472-6874</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>22</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>15</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>BMC women's health</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>BMC Womens Health</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>What are the prospects for the hormonal IUD in the public sector? A mixed-method study of the user population in Zambia.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>178</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>178</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">178</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12905-022-01745-7</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The levonorgestrel-releasing intrauterine device (IUD)-also known as the hormonal IUD-is a highly effective contraceptive method that has not been widely available in the public sector in Zambia. Early introduction efforts can provide critical insights into the characteristics of users, reasons for method choice, and experiences getting their method.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We conducted a survey with 710 public sector clients who received a hormonal IUD, copper IUD, implant or injectable in two provinces of Zambia, and additional in-depth interviews with 29 women. We performed descriptive analyses of survey data and fitted multivariable logistic regression models to assess factors associated with hormonal IUD use. Qualitative interviews were analyzed thematically.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Factors associated with hormonal IUD use included full-time or self-employment (relative to both implant and copper IUD use), as well as being older, wealthier, and partner not being aware of method use (relative to implant use only). Common reasons for choosing long-acting methods were duration, perception that the method was "right for my body," and convenience. In addition, a portion of hormonal IUD acceptors mentioned effectiveness, potential for discreet use, few or manageable side effects, and treatment for heavy or painful periods. Between 83 and 95% of women said that they were counseled about menstrual changes and/or non-bleeding side effects; however, more hormonal IUD acceptors recalled being counseled on the possibility of experiencing reduced bleeding (88%) than amenorrhea (43%). Qualitative interviews indicate that women seek methods with minimal or tolerable side effects. While most women reported their partner was aware of method use, men may be more consistently involved in the decision to use contraception rather than in the choice of a particular method. Qualitative results show an appreciation of the lifestyle benefits of reduced bleeding (especially lighter bleeding), although amenorrhea can be cause for concern.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Initial efforts to introduce the hormonal IUD can provide valuable learnings that can inform broader method introduction to expand choice and better suit women's needs in Zambia and elsewhere. Scale-up plans should include emphasis on high quality counseling and demand generation. The government of Zambia is committed to increasing access to high-quality contraception and making more choices available to users. To date, the hormonal IUD, a highly effective, long-lasting contraceptive has not been widely available in the country. A study in pilot introduction settings provided insights into why women chose the methods, their characteristics, and their experiences getting their methods. The 710 women in the study received family planning services in public sector settings in two provinces in Zambia. Women in the study who received a hormonal IUD, copper IUD, implant, or injectable completed a quantitative survey; in-depth interviews were also conducted with 29 women. Results showed common reasons for choosing the long-acting methods (hormonal IUD, copper IUD or implants) were their duration, perception that the method was "right for my body," and convenience. In addition, some hormonal IUD acceptors indicated that they were attracted to the method's effectiveness, potential for discreet use, few or manageable side effects, and treatment for heavy or painful periods. Qualitative interviews with women also showed that women want contraceptive methods that lead to minimal or tolerable side effects. Male partners were typically aware of contraceptive use; however, men were less involved with decisions about the particular method women selected. Use of the hormonal IUD can lead to reduced menstrual bleeding, and in the interviews, women indicated that they liked reduced bleeding (especially lighter bleeding), although amenorrhea (paused bleeding) can be cause for concern. The results can help inform broader method introduction.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Brunie</LastName>
            <ForeName>Aurélie</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>FHI 360, Washington, DC, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lydon</LastName>
            <ForeName>Megan</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>FHI 360, Durham, NC, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Stankevitz</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kayla</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>FHI 360, Durham, NC, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chintu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Namwinga</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Society for Family Health, Lusaka, Zambia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>UNAIDS, Geneva, Switzerland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Brennan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Claire</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>FHI 360, Durham, NC, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>RTI, Research Triangle Park, NC, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Danna</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kendal</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>PSI, Washington, DC, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Rademacher</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kate H</ForeName>
            <Initials>KH</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7015-5073</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>FHI 360, Durham, NC, USA. krademacher@fhi360.org.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>BMC Womens Health</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101088690</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1472-6874</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D003271">Contraceptive Agents, Female</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>5W7SIA7YZW</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D016912">Levonorgestrel</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000568" MajorTopicYN="N">Amenorrhea</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003267" MajorTopicYN="N">Contraception</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000379" MajorTopicYN="N">methods</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003271" MajorTopicYN="Y">Contraceptive Agents, Female</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006470" MajorTopicYN="N">Hemorrhage</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007434" MajorTopicYN="Y">Intrauterine Devices</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016912" MajorTopicYN="N">Levonorgestrel</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000009" MajorTopicYN="N">adverse effects</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017150" MajorTopicYN="N">Public Sector</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D015024" MajorTopicYN="N" Type="Geographic">Zambia</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Contraceptive</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Family planning</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hormonal IUD</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Levonorgestrel releasing intrauterine device</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Long-acting</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Menstrual bleeding</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Zambia</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no competing interests.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
          <Hour>23</Hour>
          <Minute>23</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35570281</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9107745</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12905-022-01745-7</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12905-022-01745-7</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bahamondes L, Fernandes A, Monteiro I, Bahamondes MV. Long-acting reversible contraceptive (LARCs) methods. Best Pract Res Clin Obstet Gynaecol. 2020;66:28–40. doi: 10.1016/j.bpobgyn.2019.12.002.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bpobgyn.2019.12.002</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32014434</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grandi G, Farulla A, Sileo FG, Facchinetti F. Levonorgestrel-releasing intra-uterine systems as female contraceptives. Expert Opin Pharmacother. 2018;19(7):677–686. doi: 10.1080/14656566.2018.1462337.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14656566.2018.1462337</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29637798</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lowe RF, Prata N. Hemoglobin and serum ferritin levels in women using copper-releasing or levonorgestrel-releasing intrauterine devices: a systematic review. Contracept. 2013;87(4):486–496. doi: 10.1016/j.contraception.2012.09.025.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.contraception.2012.09.025</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hubacher D, Kavanaugh M. Historical record-setting trends in IUD use in the United States. Contracept. 2018;98(6):467–470. doi: 10.1016/j.contraception.2018.05.016.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.contraception.2018.05.016</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hubacher D. The levonorgestrel intrauterine system: reasons to expand access to the public sector of Africa. Glob Health Sci Pract. 2015;3(4):532–537. doi: 10.9745/GHSP-D-15-00178.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.9745/GHSP-D-15-00178</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4682579</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26681701</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hormonal IUS Access Group. Hormonal IUS access group updates for key stakeholders: April 2020. https://www.iusportal.org/ourlibrary/Coordination/global/Hormonal-IUS-Access-Group-Updates-for-Key-Stakeholders. Accessed 3 Mar 2020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rademacher KH, Sripipatana T, Pfitzer A, Mackay A, Thurston S, Jackson A, et al.  A global learning agenda for the levonorgestrel intrauterine system (LNG IUS): addressing challenges and opportunities to increase access. Glob Health Sci Pract. 2018;6(4):635–643. doi: 10.9745/GHSP-D-18-00383.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.9745/GHSP-D-18-00383</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6370355</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30591573</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hubacher D, Masaba R, Manduku CK, Chen M, Veena V. The levonorgestrel intrauterine system: cohort study to assess satisfaction in a postpartum population in Kenya. Contracept. 2015;91(4):295300. doi: 10.1016/j.contraception.2015.01.009.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.contraception.2015.01.009</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Todd CS, Jones HE, Langwenya N, Hoover DR, Chen PL, Petro G, et al.  Safety and continued use of the levonorgestrel intrauterine system as compared with the copper intrauterine device among women living with HIV in South Africa: a randomized controlled trial. PLoS Med. 2020;17(5):e1003110. doi: 10.1371/journal.pmed.1003110.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pmed.1003110</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7244096</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32442189</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nyarko P, Adohinzin C, Tapsoba P, Esantsi S, Townsend J, Kanlisi N, et al.   Acceptability and promotion strategies for LNG-IUS in Ghana: a public health assessment. Population Council, Regional Office for Sub-Saharan Africa; 2009. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nanda G, Rademacher KH, Solomon M, Mercer S, Wawire J, Ngahu R. Experiences with the Levonorgestrel Intrauterine System (LNG-IUS) in Kenya: qualitative interviews with Mirena users and their partners. Eur J Contracept Reprod Health Care. 2018;10:1–6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rademacher KH, Solomon M, Brett T, Bratt JH, Pascual C, Njunguru J, et al.  Expanding access to a new, more affordable Levonorgestrel Intrauterine System in Kenya: service delivery costs compared with other contraceptive methods and perspectives of key opinion leaders. Glob Health Sci Pract. 2016;4(Suppl 2):S83–93. doi: 10.9745/GHSP-D-15-00327.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.9745/GHSP-D-15-00327</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4990165</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27540128</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eva G, Nanda G, Rademacher KH, Mackay A, Negedu O, Taiwo A, et al.  Experiences with the Levonorgestrel Intrauterine System among clients, providers and key opinion leaders: a mixed-methods study in Nigeria. Glob Health Sci Pract. 2018;6(4):680–692. doi: 10.9745/GHSP-D-18-00242.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.9745/GHSP-D-18-00242</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6370358</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30591576</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brunie A, Rademacher KH, Nwala AA, Danna K, Saleh M, Afolabi K. Provision of the levonorgestrel intrauterine system in Nigeria: provider perspectives and service delivery costs. Gates Open Res. 2020;4:119. doi: 10.12688/gatesopenres.13135.1.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12688/gatesopenres.13135.1</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7463110</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32908965</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>FHI 360, Society for Family Health, PSI, WomanCare Global: market assessment for potential introduction of a new hormonal IUCD in Zambia. Report. 2016. https://6dc13253-8668-46dc-80d3-a17a285a56f3.filesusr.com/ugd/3c50c1_aecf6b77cb0f4ea6b65b71bb61f03774.pdf. Accessed 3 Nov 2020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hormonal IUS Access Group: Phase 1 Countries: January 2021. https://www.iusportal.org/ourlibrary/Coordination/Global/Jan-2021---Current-Hormonal-IUS-Phase-1-and-Phase-2-countries. Accessed 1 Mar 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sitrin D, Pfitzer A, Ndirangu G, Kamanga A, Onguti B, Ontiri S, et al.  Expanding contraceptive method choice with a hormonal IUS intrauterine system: results from mixed methods studies in Kenya and Zambia. Glob Health Sci Pract. 2021;9:89–106. doi: 10.9745/GHSP-D-20-00556.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.9745/GHSP-D-20-00556</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8087423</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33724921</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Neukom J, Chilambwe J, Mkandawire J, Mbewe RK, Hubacher D. Dedicated providers of long-acting reversible contraception: new approach in Zambia. Contraception. 2011;83(5):447–452. doi: 10.1016/j.contraception.2010.08.021.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.contraception.2010.08.021</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21477688</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mbizvo MT, Bellows N, Rosen JG, Mupeta S, Mwiche CA, Bellows B. Family planning in Zambia: an investment pillar for economic development. Gates Open Res. 2020;3(1459):1459. doi: 10.12688/gatesopenres.12989.2.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12688/gatesopenres.12989.2</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7429446</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32832855</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ministry of Community Development, Mother and Child Health (MCDMCH): Family Planning Services: Integrated Family Planning Scale-up Plan 2013–2020. http://ec2-54-210-230-186.compute1.amazonaws.com/wpcontent/uploads/2016/07/CIP_Zambia.pdf. Accessed 5 Feb 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brunie A, Nwala AA, Stankevitz K, Lydon M, Danna K, Afolabi K, Rademacher KH. Factors affecting uptake of the levonorgestrel-releasing intrauterine device: a mixed-method study of social franchise clients in Nigeria. PLoS ONE. 2021;16(9):e0257769. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0257769.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0257769</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8480829</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34587200</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zambia Statistics Agency, Ministry of Health (MOH) Zambia, and ICF: Zambia Demographic and Health Survey 2018. Lusaka; 2019.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>International Contraceptive Access Foundation: about the projects. https://ica-foundation.org/projects/about-the-projects/. Accessed 5 Feb 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Danna K, Jackson A, Mann C, Harris D. Expanding effective contraceptive options: lessons learned from the introduction of the Levonorgestrel Intrauterine System (LNG-IUS) in Zambia and Madagascar. 2019. http://www.wcgcares.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/EECO-LNG-IUS-Case-Study.pdf.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brunie A, Stankevitz K, Nwala AA, Nqumayo M, Chen M, Danna K, Afolabi K, Rademacher KG. Expanding ling-acting contraceptive options: a prospective cohort study of the hormonal intrauterine device, copper intrauterine device, and implants in Nigeria and Zambia. Lancet Glob Health. 2021;9(10):e1431–e1441. doi: 10.1016/S2214-109X(21)00318-1.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S2214-109X(21)00318-1</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8440225</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34474001</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Staveteig S, Mallick L, Winter R. Uptake and discontinuation of long acting reversible contraceptives (LARCs) in low-income countries. In: DHS analytical studies no. 54. ICF International; 2015.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Namey E, Guest G, McKenna K, Chen M. Evaluating bang for the buck: a cost-effectiveness comparison between individual interviews and focus groups based on thematic saturation levels. Am J Eval. 2016;37(3):425–440. doi: 10.1177/1098214016630406.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1098214016630406</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Equity Tool. https://www.equitytool.org/. Accessed 3 Nov 2020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kibira SPS, Karp C, Wood SN, Desta S, Galadanci H, Makumbi FE, et al.  Covert use of contraception in three sub-Saharan African countries: a qualitative exploration of motivations and challenges. BMC Public Health. 2020;20(1):865. doi: 10.1186/s12889-020-08977-y.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12889-020-08977-y</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7275340</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32503485</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Castle S, Askew I. Contraceptive discontinuation: reasons, challenges, and solutions. Population Council; 2015. http://ec2-54-210-230-186.compute-1.amazonaws.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/FP2020_ContraceptiveDiscontinuation_SinglePage_Revise_02.15.16.pdf. Accessed 8 Aug 2018.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brunie A, Callahan RL, Mackenzie A, Kibira PS, Wayack-Pambè M. Developing acceptable contraceptive methods: Mixed-method findings from Burkina Faso and Uganda. Gates Open Res. 2019;3:1205. doi: 10.12688/gatesopenres.12953.1.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.12688/gatesopenres.12953.1</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6963344</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31984310</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Polis CB, Hussain R, Berry A. There might be blood: a scoping review on women's responses to contraceptive-induced menstrual bleeding changes. Reprod Health. 2018;15(1):114. doi: 10.1186/s12978-018-0561-0.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12978-018-0561-0</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6020216</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29940996</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Spotnitz M, Natarajan K, Ryan P, Westhoff C. Relative risk of cervical neoplasms among copper and Levonorgestrel-releasing intrauterine system users. Obstet Gynecol. 2020;135(2):319–327. doi: 10.1097/AOG.0000000000003656.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/AOG.0000000000003656</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7012337</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31923062</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
