<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35579222</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>17</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1475-1313</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>17</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Ophthalmic &amp; physiological optics : the journal of the British College of Ophthalmic Opticians (Optometrists)</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Ophthalmic Physiol Opt</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Corneal oedema during open-eye fenestrated scleral lens wear.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/opo.13005</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Studies examining the effect of fenestrating soft and corneal rigid contact lenses upon corneal oedema have yielded conflicting results. Although often utilised in clinical practice, no studies have quantified the effect of fenestrating a scleral contact lens upon corneal oedema. Therefore, the aim of this experiment was to examine the effect of incorporating a single peripheral fenestration on central corneal oedema during short-term open-eye scleral lens wear, while controlling for potential confounding variables.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Nine participants (mean age 30 years) with normal corneas wore a fenestrated (1 × 0.3 mm limbal fenestration) and non-fenestrated scleral lens (both lenses manufactured using a material Dk of 141 × 10<sup>-11</sup>  cm<sup>3</sup> O<sub>2</sub> (cm)/[(sec.)(cm<sup>2</sup> )(mmHg)]) under open-eye conditions on separate days. Scleral lens thickness profiles were measured using a high-resolution optical coherence tomographer (OCT). Epithelial, stromal and total central corneal oedema were also measured using the OCT immediately after lens application and following 90 min of wear, prior to lens removal.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">After adjusting for differences in initial central fluid reservoir thickness and scleral lens thickness between the two lens conditions, the mean (standard error) total corrected central corneal oedema was 0.50 (0.36)% for the fenestrated lens and 0.62 (0.16)% for the non-fenestrated lens. This small difference was not statistically significant (t<sub>8</sub>  = 2.31, p = 0.81) and represents a 19% relative reduction in central corneal oedema. Similarly, epithelial (t<sub>8</sub>  = 2.31, p = 0.82) and stromal (t<sub>8</sub>  = 2.31, p = 0.92) corneal oedema were not significantly different following the fenestrated and non-fenestrated wearing conditions.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Central corneal oedema in healthy corneas was comparable between fenestrated and non-fenestrated high Dk scleral lenses under short-term open-eye conditions when controlling for lens oxygen transmissibility and initial central fluid reservoir thickness.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Authors. Ophthalmic and Physiological Optics published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd on behalf of College of Optometrists.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Fisher</LastName>
            <ForeName>Damien</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4413-5196</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Contact Lens and Visual Optics Laboratory, School of Optometry and Vision Science, Centre for Vision and Eye Research, Queensland University of Technology, Brisbane, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Collins</LastName>
            <ForeName>Michael J</ForeName>
            <Initials>MJ</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5226-5498</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Contact Lens and Visual Optics Laboratory, School of Optometry and Vision Science, Centre for Vision and Eye Research, Queensland University of Technology, Brisbane, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Vincent</LastName>
            <ForeName>Stephen J</ForeName>
            <Initials>SJ</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-5998-1320</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Contact Lens and Visual Optics Laboratory, School of Optometry and Vision Science, Centre for Vision and Eye Research, Queensland University of Technology, Brisbane, Queensland, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Ophthalmic Physiol Opt</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8208839</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0275-5408</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">corneal oedema</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">fluid reservoir</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lens fenestration</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">scleral lens</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tear exchange</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>43</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35579222</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/opo.13005</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hill RM, Leighton AJ. Effects of contact lens apertures on corneal respiration under dynamic conditions. Am J Optom Arch Am Acad Optom. 1968;45:65-79.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harris MG, Barreto DJ, Matthews MS. The effect of peripherally fenestrated contact lenses on corneal edema. Am J Optom Physiol Opt. 1977;54:27-30.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brennan NA, Efron N, Carney LG. The effects of fenestrating soft contact lenses on corneal swelling: a re-examination. Clin Exp Optom. 1986;69:120-3.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rho CR, Pandey C, Kim SY, Kim MS. Corneal swelling caused by conventional and new-design low-Dk soft contact lenses following a 10-day daily wear trial regime. Cont Lens Anterior Eye. 2014;37:38-43.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dallos J. Sattler's veil. Br J Ophthalmol. 1946;30:607-13.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bier N. The tolerance factor and Sattler's veil as influenced by a new development of contact lens making. Am J Optom Arch Am Acad Optom. 1947;24:611-5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dallos J. The myth of oxygen permeability. J Br Cont Lens Assoc. 1980;3:28-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bier N. The practice of ventilated contact lenses. Am J Optom Arch Am Acad Optom. 1949;26:120-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dhallu SK, Huarte ST, Bilkhu PS, Boychev N, Wolffsohn JS. Effect of scleral lens oxygen permeability on corneal physiology. Optom Vis Sci. 2020;97:669-75.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pullum KW, Stapleton FJ. Scleral lens induced corneal swelling: what is the effect of varying Dk and lens thickness? CLAO J. 1997;23:259-63.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tan B, Tse V, Kim YH, Lin K, Zhou Y, Lin MC. Effects of scleral-lens oxygen transmissibility on corneal thickness: a pilot study. Cont Lens Anterior Eye. 2019;42:366-72.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pullum KW, Hobley AJ, Davison C. 100+ Dk: does thickness make much difference? J Br Cont Lens Assoc. 1991;14:17-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fisher D, Collins MJ, Vincent SJ. Scleral lens thickness and corneal edema under open eye conditions. Eye Cont Lens. 2022;48. https://doi.org/10.1097/ICL.0000000000000888</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Esen F, Toker E. Influence of apical clearance on mini-scleral lens settling, clinical performance, and corneal thickness changes. Eye Cont Lens. 2017;43:230-5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fisher D, Collins M, Vincent SJ. Fluid reservoir thickness and corneal oedema during closed eye scleral lens wear. Cont Lens Anterior Eye. 2021;44:102-7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fisher D, Collins MJ, Vincent SJ. Fluid reservoir thickness and corneal edema during open-eye scleral lens wear. Optom Vis Sci. 2020;97:683-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ko L, Maurice D, Ruben M. Fluid exchange under scleral contact lenses in relation to wearing time. Br J Ophthalmol. 1970;54:486-9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fadel D, Ezekiel DF. Fenestrated scleral lenses: Back to the origins? Review of their benefits and fitting techniques. Optom Vis Sci. 2020;97:807-20.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vincent SJ, Alonso-Caneiro D, Kricancic H, Collins MJ. Scleral contact lens thickness profiles: the relationship between average and centre lens thickness. Cont Lens Anterior Eye. 2019;42:55-62.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fisher D, Collins MJ, Vincent SJ. Anterior segment optical coherence tomography scanning protocols and corneal thickness repeatability. Cont Lens Anterior Eye. 2020;43:433-40.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swarbrick HA, Hiew R, Kee AV, Peterson S, Tahhan N. Apical clearance rigid contact lenses induce corneal steepening. Optom Vis Sci. 2004;81:427-35.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Litoff D, Pristaw AI, Smith RS, Gold RM. Argon laser fenestration of a SoftPerm contact lens. CLAO J. 1992;18:95-6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mountford J, Carkeet N, Carney L. Corneal thickness changes during scleral lens wear: effect of gas permeability. Int Cont Lens Clin. 1994;21:19-22.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ezekiel D. Gas permeable haptic lenses. J Br Cont Lens Assoc. 1983;6:158-61.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Efron N, Carney LG. Effect of fenestrating soft contact-lenses on corneal oxygen availability. Am J Optom Physiol Opt. 1983;60:503-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harris MG, Maas GD, Prigge E. The effect of fenestrated contact lenses on central corneal clouding. Int Cont Lens Clin. 1975;2:35-8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
