<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35578028</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>16</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1420-908X</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>16</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Inflammation research : official journal of the European Histamine Research Society ... [et al.]</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Inflamm Res</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Prolonged effects of DPP-4 inhibitors on steato-hepatitic changes in Sprague-Dawley rats fed a high-cholesterol diet.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00011-022-01572-4</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Sitagliptin and other dipeptidyl peptidase (DPP)-4 inhibitors/gliptins are antidiabetic drugs known to improve lipid profile, and confer anti-inflammatory and anti-fibrotic effects, which are independent of their hypoglycemic effects. However, in our previous short-term (35 days) studies, we showed that sitagliptin accentuates the hepato-inflammatory effects of high dietary cholesterol (Cho) in male Sprague-Dawley rats. Since most type 2 diabetics also present with lipid abnormalities and use DPP-4 inhibitors for glucose management, the present study was conducted to assess the impact of sitagliptin during long-term (98 days) feeding of a high Cho diet. An additional component of the present investigation was the inclusion of other gliptins to determine if hepatic steatosis, necro-inflammation, and fibrosis were specific to sitagliptin or are class effects.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Adult male Sprague-Dawley rats were fed control or high Cho (2.0%) diets, and gavaged daily (from day 30 through 98) with vehicle or DPP-4 inhibitors (sitagliptin or alogliptin or saxagliptin). On day 99 after a 4 h fast, rats were euthanized. Blood and liver samples were collected to measure lipids and cytokines, and for histopathological evaluation, determination of hepatic lesions (steatosis, necrosis, inflammation, and fibrosis) using specific staining and immunohistochemical methods.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Compared to controls, the high Cho diet produced a robust increase in NASH like phenotype that included increased expression of hepatic (Tnfa, Il1b, and Mcp1) and circulatory (TNFα and IL-1β) markers of inflammation, steatosis, necrosis, fibrosis, and mononuclear cell infiltration. These mononuclear cells were identified as macrophages and T cells, and their recruitment in the liver was facilitated by marked increases in endothelium-expressed cell adhesion molecules. Importantly, treatment with DPP-4 inhibitors (3 tested) neither alleviated the pathologic responses induced by high Cho diet nor improved lipid profile.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The potential lipid lowering effects of DPP-4 inhibitors were diminished by high Cho (a significant risk factor for inducing liver damage). The robust inflammatory responses induced by high Cho feeding in long-term experiment were not exacerbated by DPP-4 inhibitors and a consistent hepatic inflammatory environment persisted, implying a prospective physiological adaptation.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Nature Switzerland AG.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Pathak</LastName>
            <ForeName>Rashmi</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Environmental Toxicology, Southern University and A&amp;M College, 209, Lee Hall, Baton Rouge, LA, 70813, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Comparative Biomedical Sciences, School of Veterinary Medicine, Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, LA, 70803, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kumar</LastName>
            <ForeName>Avinash</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Environmental Toxicology, Southern University and A&amp;M College, 209, Lee Hall, Baton Rouge, LA, 70813, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biological Sciences, Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge, LA, 70803, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Pennington Biomedical Research Center, Baton Rouge, LA, 70808, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Palfrey</LastName>
            <ForeName>Henry A</ForeName>
            <Initials>HA</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Environmental Toxicology, Southern University and A&amp;M College, 209, Lee Hall, Baton Rouge, LA, 70813, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Stone</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kirsten P</ForeName>
            <Initials>KP</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Nutrient Sensing and Adipocyte Signaling, Pennington Biomedical Research Center, Baton Rouge, LA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Raju</LastName>
            <ForeName>Narayan R</ForeName>
            <Initials>NR</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Pathology Research Laboratory Inc, South San Francisco, CA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gettys</LastName>
            <ForeName>Thomas W</ForeName>
            <Initials>TW</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Nutrient Sensing and Adipocyte Signaling, Pennington Biomedical Research Center, Baton Rouge, LA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Murthy</LastName>
            <ForeName>Subramanyam N</ForeName>
            <Initials>SN</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4338-2542</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Environmental Toxicology, Southern University and A&amp;M College, 209, Lee Hall, Baton Rouge, LA, 70813, USA. s_murthy@subr.edu.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>Switzerland</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Inflamm Res</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9508160</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1023-3830</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">DPP-4 inhibitor</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fibrosis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Hypercholesterolemia</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Inflammation</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">NAFLD</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Necrosis</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>23</Hour>
          <Minute>29</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35578028</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00011-022-01572-4</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00011-022-01572-4</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Younossi ZM, Koenig AB, Abdelatif D, Fazel Y, Henry L, Wymer M. Global epidemiology of nonalcoholic fatty liver disease—meta-analytic assessment of prevalence, incidence, and outcomes. Hepatology. 2016;64(1):73–84.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26707365</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hep.28431</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vernon G, Baranova A, Younossi Z. Systematic review: the epidemiology and natural history of non-alcoholic fatty liver disease and non-alcoholic steatohepatitis in adults. Aliment Pharmacol Ther. 2011;34(3):274–85.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21623852</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2036.2011.04724.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bellentani S. The epidemiology of non-alcoholic fatty liver disease. Liver Int. 2017;37:81–4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28052624</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/liv.13299</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tu LN, Showalter MR, Cajka T, Fan S, Pillai VV, Fiehn O, et al. Metabolomic characteristics of cholesterol-induced non-obese nonalcoholic fatty liver disease in mice. Sci Rep. 2017;7(1):1–14.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-016-0028-x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kerr TA, Davidson NO. Cholesterol and NAFLD: renewed focus on an old villain. Hepatol (Baltimore, MD). 2012;56(5):1995.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hep.26088</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arguello G, Balboa E, Arrese M, Zanlungo S. Recent insights on the role of cholesterol in non-alcoholic fatty liver disease. Biochim et Biophys Acta BBA Mol Basis Dis. 2015;1852(9):1765–78.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bbadis.2015.05.015</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sarwar R, Pierce N, Koppe S. Obesity and nonalcoholic fatty liver disease: current perspectives. Diabetes Metab Syndrome Obes Targets Ther. 2018;11:533.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/DMSO.S146339</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fabbrini E, Sullivan S, Klein S. Obesity and nonalcoholic fatty liver disease: biochemical, metabolic, and clinical implications. Hepatology. 2010;51(2):679–89.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20041406</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/hep.23280</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Targher G, Corey KE, Byrne CD, Roden M. The complex link between NAFLD and type 2 diabetes mellitus—mechanisms and treatments. Nat Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2021;8:1–14.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alam S, Ghosh J, Mustafa G, Kamal M, Ahmad N. Effect of sitagliptin on hepatic histological activity and fibrosis of nonalcoholic steatohepatitis patients: a 1-year randomized control trial. Hepatic Med Evid Res. 2018;10:23.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/HMER.S158053</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaji K, Yoshiji H, Ikenaka Y, Noguchi R, Aihara Y, Douhara A, et al. Dipeptidyl peptidase-4 inhibitor attenuates hepatic fibrosis via suppression of activated hepatic stellate cell in rats. J Gastroenterol. 2014;49(3):481–91.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23475323</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00535-013-0783-4</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maiztegui B, Borelli MI, Madrid VG, Del Zotto H, Raschia MA, Francini F, et al. Sitagliptin prevents the development of metabolic and hormonal disturbances, increased β-cell apoptosis and liver steatosis induced by a fructose-rich diet in normal rats. Clin Sci. 2011;120(2):73–80.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1042/CS20100372</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shirakawa J, Fujii H, Ohnuma K, Sato K, Ito Y, Kaji M, et al. Diet-induced adipose tissue inflammation and liver steatosis are prevented by DPP-4 inhibition in diabetic mice. Diabetes. 2011;60(4):1246–57.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21330637</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3064098</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/db10-1338</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Akaslan SB, Degertekin CK, Yilmaz G, Cakir N, Arslan M, Toruner FB. Effects of sitagliptin on nonalcoholic fatty liver disease in diet-induced obese rats. Metab Syndr Relat Disord. 2013;11(4):243–50.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23544853</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1089/met.2012.0128</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kern M, Klöting N, Niessen HG, Thomas L, Stiller D, Mark M, et al. Linagliptin improves insulin sensitivity and hepatic steatosis in diet-induced obesity. PLoS ONE. 2012;7(6):38744.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0038744</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Klein T, Fujii M, Sandel J, Shibazaki Y, Wakamatsu K, Mark M, et al. Linagliptin alleviates hepatic steatosis and inflammation in a mouse model of non-alcoholic steatohepatitis. Med Mol Morphol. 2014;47(3):137–49.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24048504</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00795-013-0053-9</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aroor AR, Habibi J, Ford DA, Nistala R, Lastra G, Manrique C, et al. Dipeptidyl peptidase-4 inhibition ameliorates Western diet–induced hepatic steatosis and insulin resistance through hepatic lipid remodeling and modulation of hepatic mitochondrial function. Diabetes. 2015;64(6):1988–2001.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25605806</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4439570</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2337/db14-0804</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ohyama T, Sato K, Yamazaki Y, Hashizume H, Horiguchi N, Kakizaki S, et al. MK-0626, a selective DPP-4 inhibitor, attenuates hepatic steatosis in ob/ob mice. World J Gastroenterol: WJG. 2014;20(43):16227.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25473177</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4239511</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3748/wjg.v20.i43.16227</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Itou M, Kawaguchi T, Taniguchi E, Oriishi T, Sata M. Dipeptidyl peptidase IV inhibitor improves insulin resistance and steatosis in a refractory nonalcoholic fatty liver disease patient: a case report. Case Rep Gastroenterol. 2012;6(2):538–44.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22949894</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3432996</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000341510</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iwasaki T, Yoneda M, Inamori M, Shirakawa J, Higurashi T, Maeda S, et al. Sitagliptin as a novel treatment agent for non-alcoholic Fatty liver disease patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus. Hepatogastroenterology. 2011;58(112):2103–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22024083</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5754/hge11263</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yilmaz Y, Yonal O, Deyneli O, Celikel CA, Kalayci C, Duman DG. Effects of sitagliptin in diabetic patients with nonalcoholic steatohepatitis. Acta Gastro-Enterol Belg. 2012;75(2):240–4.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kanazawa I, Tanaka K-I, Sugimoto T. DPP-4 inhibitors improve liver dysfunction in type 2 diabetes mellitus. Med Sci Monit Int Med J Exp Clin Res. 2014;20:1662.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matsubara J, Sugiyama S, Akiyama E, Iwashita S, Kurokawa H, Ohba K, et al. Dipeptidyl peptidase-4 inhibitor, sitagliptin, improves endothelial dysfunction in association with its anti-inflammatory effects in patients with coronary artery disease and uncontrolled diabetes. Circ J. 2013;77(5):1337–44.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23386232</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1253/circj.CJ-12-1168</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kubota Y, Miyamoto M, Takagi G, Ikeda T, Kirinoki-Ichikawa S, Tanaka K, et al. The dipeptidyl peptidase-4 inhibitor sitagliptin improves vascular endothelial function in type 2 diabetes. J Korean Med Sci. 2012;27(11):1364–70.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23166419</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3492672</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3346/jkms.2012.27.11.1364</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gomez N, Touihri K, Matheeussen V, Da Costa AM, Mahmoudabady M, Mathieu M, et al. Dipeptidyl peptidase IV inhibition improves cardiorenal function in overpacing-induced heart failure. Eur J Heart Fail. 2012;14(1):14–21.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22045924</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurjhf/hfr146</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sakamoto Y, Oyama JI, Ikeda H, Kuroki S, Gondo S, Iwamoto T, et al. Effects of sitagliptin beyond glycemic control: focus on quality of life. Cardiovasc Diabetol. 2013;12(1):1–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1475-2840-12-35</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rouse R, Xu L, Stewart S, Zhang J. High fat diet and GLP-1 drugs induce pancreatic injury in mice. Toxicol Appl Pharmacol. 2014;276(2):104–14.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24534256</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.taap.2014.01.021</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shahbaz A, Aziz K, Umair M, Sharifzadeh M, Sachmechi I. Acute liver injury induced by sitagliptin: report of two cases and review of literature. Cureus. 2018;10(6).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Toyoda-Akui M, Yokomori H, Kaneko F, Shimizu Y, Takeuchi H, Tahara K, et al. A case of drug-induced hepatic injury associated with sitagliptin. Intern Med. 2011;50(9):1015–20.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21532224</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2169/internalmedicine.50.5057</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Packer M. Worsening heart failure during the use of DPP-4 inhibitors: pathophysiological mechanisms, clinical risks, and potential influence of concomitant antidiabetic medications. JACC Heart Fail. 2018;6(6):445–51.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29525332</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jchf.2017.12.016</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pathak R, Kumar A, Palfrey HA, Forney LA, Stone KP, Raju NR, et al. The incretin enhancer, sitagliptin, exacerbates expression of hepatic inflammatory markers in rats fed a high-cholesterol diet. Inflamm Res. 2019;68(7):581–95.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31073849</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6602907</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00011-019-01243-x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kumar A, Pathak R, Palfrey HA, Stone KP, Gettys TW, Murthy SN. High levels of dietary methionine improves sitagliptin-induced hepatotoxicity by attenuating oxidative stress in hypercholesterolemic rats. Nutr Metab. 2020;17(1):1–14.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12986-019-0422-z</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Püschel GP, Henkel J. Dietary cholesterol does not break your heart but kills your liver. Porto Biomed J. 2018;3(1):e12.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31595236</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pbj.0000000000000012</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Malhotra P, Gill RK, Saksena S, Alrefai WA. Disturbances in cholesterol homeostasis and non-alcoholic fatty liver diseases. Front Med. 2020;7:467.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fmed.2020.00467</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vergnes L, Phan J, Tafuri S, Reue K, Strauss M. Cholesterol and cholate components of an atherogenic diet induce distinct stages of hepatic inflammatory gene expression. J Biol Chem. 2003;278(44):42774–84.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12923166</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1074/jbc.M306022200</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mells JE, Fu PP, Kumar P, Smith T, Karpen SJ, Anania FA. Saturated fat and cholesterol are critical to inducing murine metabolic syndrome with robust nonalcoholic steatohepatitis. J Nutr Biochem. 2015;26(3):285–92.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25577467</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jnutbio.2014.11.002</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Angelico F, Ferro D, Baratta F. Is the mediterranean diet the best approach to NAFLD treatment today? Multidisciplinary Digital Publishing Institute; 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hosseini Z, Whiting SJ, Vatanparast H. Current evidence on the association of the metabolic syndrome and dietary patterns in a global perspective. Nutr Res Rev. 2016;29(2):152–62.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27955720</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S095442241600007X</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Razavi Zade M, Telkabadi MH, Bahmani F, Salehi B, Farshbaf S, Asemi Z. The effects of DASH diet on weight loss and metabolic status in adults with non-alcoholic fatty liver disease: a randomized clinical trial. Liver Int. 2016;36(4):563–71.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26503843</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/liv.12990</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fukuhara T, Hyogo H, Ochi H, Fujino H, Kan H, Naeshiro N, et al. Efficacy and safety of sitagliptin for the treatment of nonalcoholic fatty liver disease with type 2 diabetes mellitus. Hepatogastroenterology. 2014;61(130):323–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24901133</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arase Y, Kawamura Y, Seko Y, Kobayashi M, Suzuki F, Suzuki Y, et al. Efficacy and safety in sitagliptin therapy for diabetes complicated by non-alcoholic fatty liver disease. Hepatol Res. 2013;43(11):1163–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23489256</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/hepr.12077</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cui J, Philo L, Nguyen P, Hofflich H, Hernandez C, Bettencourt R, et al. Sitagliptin vs placebo for non-alcoholic fatty liver disease: a randomized controlled trial. J Hepatol. 2016;65(2):369–76.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27151177</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5081213</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jhep.2016.04.021</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Joy TR, McKenzie CA, Tirona RG, Summers K, Seney S, Chakrabarti S, et al. Sitagliptin in patients with non-alcoholic steatohepatitis: a randomized, placebo-controlled trial. World J Gastroenterol. 2017;23(1):141.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28104990</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5221278</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3748/wjg.v23.i1.141</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
