<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35575587</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1581-3207</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>56</Volume>
            <Issue>2</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>17</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Radiology and oncology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Radiol Oncol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Ribociclib plus letrozole in patients with hormone receptor-positive, HER2-negative advanced breast cancer with no prior endocrine therapy: subgroup safety analysis from the phase 3b CompLEEment-1 trial.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>238</StartPage>
          <EndPage>247</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>238-247</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2478/raon-2022-0020</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">The CDK4/6 inhibitor, ribociclib in combination with endocrine therapy significantly improved progression-free survival in the first line setting in post-menopausal patients with HR+/HER2- advanced breast cancer (ABC) in a pivotal phase 3, placebo-controlled trial (MONALEESA-2) and demonstrated superior overall survival in premenopausal patients with HR+/HER2- ABC (MONALEESA-7). The multinational, phase 3b, CompLEEment-1 trial, which assessed the safety and efficacy of ribociclib plus letrozole in a broader population of patients who have not received prior endocrine therapy for advanced disease, is the largest phase 3 clinical trial to date to evaluate the safety and efficacy of a CDK4/6 inhibitor. We report a subanalysis of data from patients (N = 339) enrolled in the central and south European countries of the SERCE (Southern Europe, RUC, Central Europe) cluster of CompLEEment-1.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="PATIENTS AND METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Men and women of any menopausal status with HR+/HER2- ABC received once-daily oral ribociclib 600 mg (3-weeks on/1-week-off), plus letrozole 2.5 mg continuously. Men/premenopausal women also received a GnRH-agonist. The primary outcome was the number of patients with adverse events (AEs) over a timeframe of approximately 36 months. Time-to-progression, overall response rate, and clinical benefit rate were also measured.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Safety results in the SERCE subgroup were consistent with those in the pivotal clinical trials of ribociclib in combination with endocrine therapy. Treatment-related AEs leading to dose adjustments/interruption occurred in 63.1% of patients but led to treatment discontinuation in only 10.6%. The most common treatment-related AEs of grade ≥ 3 were neutropenia and transaminase elevations. There were no fatal treatment-related events.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">These findings from the SERCE subgroup support the safety and manageable tolerability of ribociclib in a broad range of patients with HR+/HER2- ABC more representative of patients in real-world clinical practice.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 Simona Borstnar, Marketa Palacova, Aleksandra Łacko, Constanta Timcheva, Einav Nili Gal-Yam, Konstantinos Papazisis, Juraj Beniak, Pavol Kudela, Gábor Rubovszky, published by Sciendo.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Borstnar</LastName>
            <ForeName>Simona</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medical Oncology, Institute of Oncology Ljubljana, Ljubljana, Slovenia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Palacova</LastName>
            <ForeName>Marketa</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Clinic of Comprehensive Cancer Care, Masaryk Memorial Cancer Institute, Brno, Czech Republic.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Łacko</LastName>
            <ForeName>Aleksandra</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Clinical Oncology, Wroclaw University of Medicine, Wrocław, Poland, and Breast Unit, Lower Silesian Oncology Centre, Wroclaw, Poland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Timcheva</LastName>
            <ForeName>Constanta</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Medical Oncology Clinic, Multiprofile Hospital for Active Treatment "Nadezhda" Sofia, Sofia, Bulgaria.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gal-Yam</LastName>
            <ForeName>Einav Nili</ForeName>
            <Initials>EN</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Talpiot medical leadership program, Institute of Oncology, Chaim Sheba Medical Center, Tel-Hashomer; affiliated to the Sackler School of Medicine, Tel-Aviv University, Tel-Aviv, Israel.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Papazisis</LastName>
            <ForeName>Konstantinos</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Euromedica General Clinic of Thessaloniki, Thessaloniki, Greece.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Beniak</LastName>
            <ForeName>Juraj</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Regional Cancer Center, Poprad, Slovakia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kudela</LastName>
            <ForeName>Pavol</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Novartis Slovakia s.r.o., Bratislava, Slovakia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Rubovszky</LastName>
            <ForeName>Gábor</ForeName>
            <Initials>G</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Oncological Internal Medicine and Clinical Pharmacology, National Institute of Oncology, Budapest, Hungary.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D017428">Clinical Trial, Phase III</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>Poland</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Radiol Oncol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9317213</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1318-2099</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000631">Aminopyridines</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D011687">Purines</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D011960">Receptors, Estrogen</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D011980">Receptors, Progesterone</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>7LKK855W8I</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D000077289">Letrozole</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>EC 2.7.10.1</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D018719">Receptor, ErbB-2</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>TK8ERE8P56</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="C000589651">ribociclib</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000631" MajorTopicYN="N">Aminopyridines</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000971" MajorTopicYN="N">Antineoplastic Combined Chemotherapy Protocols</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001943" MajorTopicYN="Y">Breast Neoplasms</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000077289" MajorTopicYN="N">Letrozole</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011687" MajorTopicYN="N">Purines</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D018719" MajorTopicYN="N">Receptor, ErbB-2</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011960" MajorTopicYN="N">Receptors, Estrogen</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011980" MajorTopicYN="N">Receptors, Progesterone</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000627" MajorTopicYN="N">therapeutic use</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CDK4/6 inhibitor</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CompLEEment-1 trial</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">HER2−</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">HR+</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">advanced breast cancer</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ribociclib</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>9</Hour>
          <Minute>14</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35575587</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2478/raon-2022-0020</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">raon-2022-0020</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ferlay J, Colombet M, Soerjomataram I, Mathers C, Parkin DM, Pineros M, et al. Estimating the global cancer incidence and mortality in 2018: GLOBOCAN sources and methods. Int J Cancer 2019; 144: 1941-53. doi: 10.1002/ijc.31937</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bray F, Ferlay J, Soerjomataram I, Siegel RL, Torre LA, Jemal A. Global cancer statistics 2018: GLOBOCAN estimates of incidence and mortality worldwide for 36 cancers in 185 countries. CA Cancer J Clin 2018; 68: 394-424. doi: 10.3322/caac.21492</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yousef AJA. Male breast cancer: epidemiology and risk factors. Semin Oncol 2017; 44:. 267-72. doi: 10.1053/j.seminoncol.2017.11.002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Turashvili G, Brogi E. Tumor heterogeneity in breast cancer. Front Med 2017; 4: 227. doi: 10.3389/fmed.2017.00227</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Howlader N, Cronin KA, Kurian AW, Andridge R. Differences in breast cancer survival by molecular subtypes in the United States. Cancer Epidemiol Biomarkers Prev 2018; 27: 619-26. doi: 10.1158/1055-9965.EPI-17-0627</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>National Institute for Health and Care Excellence (NICE). Advanced breast cancer: diagnosis and treatment CG81. Updated 2017. [Internet]. [cited 2022 Jan 15]. Available at: https://www.nice.org.uk/guidance/cg81</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cardoso F, Paluch-Shimon S, Senkus E, Curigliano G, Aapro MS, Andre F, et al. 5th ESO-ESMO international consensus guidelines for advanced breast cancer (ABC 5). Ann Oncol 2020; 31: 1623-49. doi: 10.1016/j.annonc.2020.09.010</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gradishar WJ, Anderson BO, Balassanian R, Blair SL, Burstein HJ, Cyr A, et al. Breast cancer, version 4.2017, NCCN Clinical Practice Guidelines in Oncology. J Natl Compr Canc Netw 2018; 16: 310-20. doi: 10.6004/jnccn.2018.0012</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Telli ML, Gradishar WJ, Ward JH. NCCN Guidelines updates: breast cancer. J Natl Compr Canc Netw 2019; 17: 552-5. doi: 10.6004/jnccn.2019.5006</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Robertson JFR, Bondarenko IM, Trishkina E, Dvorkin M, Panasci L, Manikhas A et al. Fulvestrant 500 mg versus anastrozole 1 mg for hormone receptor-positive advanced breast cancer (FALCON): an international, randomised, double-blind, phase 3 trial. Lancet 2016; 388: 2997-3005. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(16)32389-3</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yamamoto-Ibusuki M, Arnedos M, Andre F. Targeted therapies for ER+/ HER2- metastatic breast cancer. BMC Med 2015; 13: 137. doi: 10.1186/s12916-015-0369-5</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Araki K, Miyoshi Y. Mechanism of resistance to endocrine therapy in breast cancer: the important role of PI3K/Akt/mTOR in estrogen receptor-positive, HER2-negative breast cancer. Breast Cancer 2018; 25: 392-401. doi: 10.1007/s12282-017-0812-x</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>AlFakeeh A, Brezden-Masley C. Overcoming endocrine resistance in hormone receptor-positive breast cancer. Curr Oncol 2018; 25(Suppl 1): S18-27. doi: 10.3747/co.25.3752</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hamilton E, Infante JR. Targeting CDK4/6 in patients with cancer. Cancer Treat Rev 2016; 45: 129-38. doi: 10.1016/j.ctrv.2016.03.002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Finn RS, Martin M, Rugo HS, Jones S, Im SA, Gelmon K, et al. Palbociclib and letrozole in advanced breast cancer. N Engl J Med 2016; 375: 1925-36. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1607303</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sledge GW Jr, Toi M, Neven P, Sohn J, Inoue K, Pivot X, et al. MONARCH 2: abemaciclib in combination with fulvestrant in women with HR+/HER2-advanced breast cancer who had progressed while receiving endocrine therapy. J Clin Oncol 2017; 35: 2875-84. doi: 10.1200/JCO.2017.73.7585</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hortobagyi GN, Stemmer SM, Burris HA, Yap YS, Sonke GS, Paluch-Shimon S, et al. Ribociclib as first-line therapy for HR-positive, advanced breast cancer. N Engl J Med 2016; 375: 1738-48. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1609709</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tripathy D, Bardia A, Sellers WR. Ribociclib (LEE011): mechanism of action and clinical impact of this selective cyclin-dependent kinase 4/6 inhibitor in various solid tumors. Clin Cancer Res 2017; 23: 3251-62. doi:10.1158/1078-0432.Ccr-16-3157</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hortobagyi GN, Stemmer SM, Burris HA, Yap YS, Sonke GS, Paluch-Shimon S, et al. Updated results from MONALEESA-2, a phase III trial of first-line ribociclib plus letrozole versus placebo plus letrozole in hormone receptor-positive, HER2-negative advanced breast cancer. Ann Oncol 2018; 29: 15417. doi: 10.1093/annonc/mdy155</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Slamon DJ, Neven P, Chia S, Fasching PA, De Laurentiis M, Im SA, et al. Phase III randomized study of ribociclib and fulvestrant in hormone receptor-positive, human epidermal growth factor receptor 2-negative advanced breast cancer: MONALEESA-3. J Clin Oncol 2018; 36: 2465-72. doi: 10.1200/JCO.2018.78.9909</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tripathy D, Im SA, Colleoni M, Franke F, Bardia A, Harbeck N et al. Ribociclib plus endocrine therapy for premenopausal women with hormone-receptor-positive, advanced breast cancer (MONALEESA-7): a randomised phase 3 trial. Lancet Oncol 2018; 19: 904-15. doi: 10.1016/S1470-2045(18)30292-4</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hortobagyi GN, Stemmer SM, Burris HA, Yap YS, Sonke GS, Hart L, et al. Overall survival with ribociclib plus letrozole in advanced breast cancer. N Engl J Med 2022; 386: 942-50. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa2114663</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tripathy D, Im S, Colleoni M, Franke F, Bardia A, Harbeck N, et al. Updated overall survival (OS) results from the phase III MONALEESA-7 trial of pre- or perimenopausal patients with hormone receptor positive epidermal growth factor receptor 2 negative (HR+/HER2−) advanced breast cancer (ABC) treated with endocrine therapy (ET) ± ribociclib. [Abstract PD2-04]. San Antonio Breast Cancer Virtual Symposium, San Antonio, Texas, USA, December 8-12, 2020. doi: 10.1158/1538-7445.SABCS20-PD2-04</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Slamon DJ, Neven P, Chia S, Fasching PA, De Laurentiis M, Im SA, et al. Overall survival with ribociclib plus fulvestrant in advanced breast cancer. N Engl J Med 2020; 382: 514-24. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1911149</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>DeLaurentiis M, Neven P, Jerusalem GHM, Bachelot TD, Jacot W, Dent SF, et al. Ribociclib (RIBO) + letrozole (LET) in patients (pts) with hormone receptor-positive (HR+), human epidermal growth factor receptor 2-negative (HER2–) advanced breast cancer (ABC) with no prior endocrine therapy (ET) for ABC: Preliminary results from the phase 3b CompLEEment-1 trial. [Abstract 1056P]. J Clin Oncol 2018; 36: 1056. doi: 10.1200/JCO.2018.36.15_suppl.1056</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Laurentiis M, Borstnar S, Campone M, Warner E, Bofill JS, Jacot W, et al. Full population results from the core phase of CompLEEment-1, a phase 3b study of ribociclib plus letrozole as first-line therapy for advanced breast cancer in an expanded population. Breast Cancer Res Treat 2021; 189: 68999. doi: 10.1007/s10549-021-06334-0</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bilgin B, Sendur MAN, Sener Dede D, Akinci MB, Yalcin B. A current and comprehensive review of cyclin-dependent kinase inhibitors for the treatment of metastatic breast cancer. Curr Med Res Opin 2017; 33: 1559-69. doi: 10.1080/03007995.2017.1348344</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Finn RS, Aleshin A, Slamon DJ. Targeting the cyclin-dependent kinases (CDK) 4/6 in estrogen receptor-positive breast cancers. Breast Cancer Res 2016; 18: 17. doi: 10.1186/s13058-015-0661-5</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verma S, O’Shaughnessy J, Burris HA, Campone M, Alba E, Chandiwana D, et al. Health-related quality of life of postmenopausal women with hormone receptor-positive, human epidermal growth factor receptor 2-negative advanced breast cancer treated with ribociclib + letrozole: results from MONALEESA-2. Breast Cancer Res Treat 2018; 170: 535-45. doi:10.1007/s10549-018-4769-z</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
