<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35573524</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>14</Volume>
            <Issue>4</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Apr</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Cureus</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Healthcare Disparities in the Management of Indolent Mycosis Fungoides.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e24098</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e24098</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e24098</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.24098</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Mycosis fungoides represents the most common cutaneous T-cell lymphoma, clinically manifested with evolving skin lesions, including patches, plaques, tumors, and erythroderma. Early diagnosis remains difficult to establish because it mimics several benign skin conditions, but maintaining a high index of suspicion for the disease is essential in preventing the progression of a potentially fatal disease. We report the case of a 69-year-old female who presented in our dermatology clinic in 2018 with scaly, indurated, itchy erythematous-violaceus patches and plaques, and tumors disseminated throughout the skin evolving for nine years. Skin biopsy supplemented with immunohistochemical staining established the diagnosis of mycosis fungoides. Due to the equivocal clinical presentation and the lack of extracutaneous manifestations, the patient received conventional therapy according to the stage of the disease. The rapidly progressive evolution of the cutaneous lesions in the last year of the disease determined the patient's death despite instituting systemic chemotherapy. Patient follow-up and a multidisciplinary approach are essential to diagnose and manage this disease in its early stages. This will prevent the progression to a life-threatening malignancy and the use of immunosuppressive therapy, which can cause serious side effects.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022, Banciu et al.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Banciu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mădălina Laura</ForeName>
            <Initials>ML</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Dermatology, Elias Emergency University Hospital, Bucharest, ROU.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Dobrica</LastName>
            <ForeName>Elena Codruta</ForeName>
            <Initials>EC</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Pathophysiology, University of Medicine and Pharmacy of Craiova, Craiova, ROU.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Soare</LastName>
            <ForeName>Cristina</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Dermatology, Elias Emergency University Hospital, Bucharest, ROU.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Malciu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ana Maria</ForeName>
            <Initials>AM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Dermatology, Elias Emergency University Hospital, Bucharest, ROU.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Voiculescu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Vlad Mihai</ForeName>
            <Initials>VM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Dermatology, Elias Emergency University Hospital, Bucharest, ROU.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Dermatology, Carol Davila University of Medicine and Pharmacy, Bucharest, ROU.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>04</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">chemotherapy</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cutaneous t-cell lymphoma</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">large plaque parapsoriasis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">mycosis fungoides</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">retinoids</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>4</Hour>
          <Minute>29</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35573524</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9106548</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.24098</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vaidya T, Badri T. Treasure Island, FL: StatPearls Publishing; 202130137856. Mycosis Fungoides.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clinical and epidemiological profile of patients with early stage mycosis fungoides. Amorim GM, Niemeyer-Corbellini JP, Quintella DC, Cuzzi T, Ramos-E-Silva M. An Bras Dermatol. 2018;93:546–552.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6063099</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30066762</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mycosis fungoides and Sézary Syndrome: an integrative review of the pathophysiology, molecular drivers, and targeted therapy. García-Díaz N, Piris MÁ, Ortiz-Romero PL, Vaqué JP. Cancers. 2021;13:1–24.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clinical stage IA (limited patch and plaque) mycosis fungoides. A long-term outcome analysis. Kim YH, Jensen RA, Watanabe GL, Varghese A, Hoppe RT. Arch Dermatol. 1996;132:1309–1313.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8915308</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mycosis fungoides and Sézary syndrome: clinical, histopathological and immunohistochemical review and update. Yamashita T, Abbade LP, Marques ME, Marques SA. An Bras Dermatol. 2012;87:817–828.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3699909</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23197199</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>The 2018 update of the WHO-EORTC classification for primary cutaneous lymphomas. Willemze R, Cerroni L, Kempf W, Berti E, Facchetti F, Swerdlow SH, Jaffe ES. Blood. 2019;133:1703–1714.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6473500</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30635287</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>NCCN Guidelines Insights: primary cutaneous lymphomas, Version 2.2020. Mehta-Shah N, Horwitz SM, Ansell S, et al.  J Natl Compr Canc Netw. 2020;18:522–536.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32380458</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>DNA from human polyomaviruses, MWPyV, HPyV6, HPyV7, HPyV9 and HPyV12 in cutaneous T-cell lymphomas. Bergallo M, Daprà V, Fava P, et al.  Anticancer Res. 2018;38:4111–4114.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29970537</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>The patch stage of mycosis fungoides. Criteria for histologic diagnosis. Sanchez JL, Ackerman AB. http://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/549480/ Am J Dermatopathol. 1979;1:5–26.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">549480</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mycosis fungoides. Zinzani PL, Ferreri AJ, Cerroni L. Crit Rev Oncol Hematol. 2008;65:172–182.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17950613</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Time course, clinical pathways, and long-term hazards risk trends of disease progression in patients with classic mycosis fungoides: a multicenter, retrospective follow-up study from the Italian Group of Cutaneous Lymphomas. Quaglino P, Pimpinelli N, Berti E, et al.  Cancer. 2012;118:5830–5839.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22674564</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Prognosis in cutaneous T-cell lymphoma by skin stage: long-term survival in 489 patients. Zackheim HS, Amin S, Kashani-Sabet M, McMillan A. J Am Acad Dermatol. 1999;40:418–425.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10071312</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Long-term outcomes of 1,263 patients with mycosis fungoides and Sézary syndrome from 1982 to 2009. Talpur R, Singh L, Daulat S, et al.  Clin Cancer Res. 2012;18:5051–5060.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3857608</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22850569</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Prognostic factors of patients with mycosis fungoides. Bahalı AG, Su O, Cengiz FP, Emiroğlu N, Ozkaya DB, Onsun N. Postepy Dermatol Alergol. 2020;37:796–799.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7675080</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33240023</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Prognostic significance of serum lactate dehydrogenase in Saudi Patients with mycosis fungoides: a retrospective study of 47 patients. Saif FA. J Clin Exp Dermatol Res. 2016;7:1–4.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lactate dehydrogenase A: a key player in carcinogenesis and potential target in cancer therapy. Feng Y, Xiong Y, Qiao T, Li X, Jia L, Han Y. Cancer Med. 2018;7:6124–6136.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6308051</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30403008</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>The current management of mycosis fungoides and Sézary syndrome and the role of radiotherapy: Principles and indications. Mazzeo E, Rubino L, Buglione M, et al.  Rep Pract Oncol Radiother. 2014;19:77–91.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4054991</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24936325</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chemotherapy with etoposide, vincristine, doxorubicin, bolus cyclophosphamide, and oral prednisone in patients with refractory cutaneous T-cell lymphoma. Akpek G, Koh HK, Bogen S, O'Hara C, Foss FM. http://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/10506727/ Cancer. 1999;86:1368–1376.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10506727</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lack of durable disease control with chemotherapy for mycosis fungoides and Sézary syndrome: a comparative study of systemic therapy. Hughes CF, Khot A, McCormack C, et al.  Blood. 2015;125:71–81.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25336628</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>How I treat mycosis fungoides and Sézary syndrome. Prince HM, Whittaker S, Hoppe RT. Blood. 2009;114:4337–4353.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19696197</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
