<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35570406</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>24</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1468-3083</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>15</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of the European Academy of Dermatology and Venereology : JEADV</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Potential role of INTERLEUKIN-17 in the pathogenesis of oral lichen planus: a systematic review with META-analysis.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/jdv.18219</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Oral lichen planus (OLP) is a chronic inflammatory mucocutaneous disease of unknown aetiology, which may evolve into squamous cell carcinoma. Recent advances on OLP pathogenesis suggest the presence of Th17 cells and the up-regulation of interleukin-17 (IL-17) expression are crucial events. Our aim was to test the hypothesis in the literature about an important role of IL-17 in OLP by systematically investigating the overexpression of IL-17 in the lesional tissue and blood from OLP patients and healthy controls. A total of 22 studies comprising 658 OLP patients and 362 control subjects fulfilled inclusion criteria were subjected to meta-analysis. The assessment of IL-17 in the lesional tissue by quantitative real-time polymerase chain reaction (PCR) revealed a significant elevation in the OLP group (RR:1.35 95%CI: 0.20-2.50, I<sup>2</sup>  = 92%). There was a statistical overexpression of IL-17 in the serum of OLP group detected by ELISA (RR:2.47 95%CI: 1.17-3.77, I<sup>2</sup>  = 97%) and flow cytometry (RR:3.04 95%CI: 0.69-5.39, I<sup>2</sup>  = 97%). In the erosive OLP group, the tissue IL-17 assessed by PCR was higher than in reticular OLP patients (RR:0.78 95%CI: 0.21-1.36, I<sup>2</sup>  = 0%). Peripheral assessment of IL-17 by ELISA (RR:1.43 95%CI: 0.01-2.85, I<sup>2</sup>  = 94%) and flow cytometry (RR:1.55 95%CI: 0.29-2.81, I<sup>2</sup>  = 89%) revealed significant elevation in erosive OLP group. The dominating overexpression of IL-17 and Th17 cells in the local inflammatory infíltrate and serum of OLP patients confirms its role, probably in the interaction between T cells and keratinocytes. Notably, the upregulation of IL-17 is more intense in erosive than in reticular OLP suggesting a positive correlation between IL-17 levels and disease severity. Further research is warranted to investigate the potential role of anti-IL-17 drugs to manage this chronic condition.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 European Academy of Dermatology and Venereology.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Husein-ElAhmed</LastName>
            <ForeName>H</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-7869-0206</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Dermatology and Venereology, Hospital de Baza, Granada, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Translational Research Institute, Hamad Medical Corporation, Doha, Qatar.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Steinhoff</LastName>
            <ForeName>M</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Translational Research Institute, Hamad Medical Corporation, Doha, Qatar.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Dermatology and Venereology, Hamad Medical Corporation, Doha, Qatar.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Weill Cornell Medicine-Qatar, College of Medicine, Doha, Qatar.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Qatar University, Medical School, Doha, Qatar.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Dermatology, Weill Cornell Medicine, New York, NY, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Eur Acad Dermatol Venereol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9216037</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0926-9959</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>2</Hour>
          <Minute>23</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35570406</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/jdv.18219</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>References</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Rossi SS, Ciarrocca K. Oral lichen planus and lichenoid mucositis. Dent Clin N Am 2014; 58: 299-313.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gonzalez-Moles MA, Scully C, Gil-Montoya JA. Oral lichen planus: controversies surrounding malignant transformation. Oral Dis 2008; 14: 229-243.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tao XA, Xia J, Chen X-B et al. FOXP3 T regulatory cells in lesions of oral lichen planus correlated with disease activity. Oral Dis 2010; 16: 76-82.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pekiner FN, Demirel GY, Borahan MO, Ozbayrak S. Cytokine profiles in serum of patients with oral lichen planus. Cytokine 2012; 60: 701-706.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Korn T, Bettelli E, Oukka M, Kuchroo VK. IL-17 and Th17 cells. Annu Rev Immunol 2009; 27: 485-517.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmidt T, Solimani F, Pollmann R et al. TH1/TH17 cell recognition of desmoglein 3 and bullous pemphigoid antigen 180 in patients with lichen planus. J Allergy Clin Immunol 2018; 142: 669-72.e7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dong C. TH17 cells in development: an updated view of their molecular identity and genetic programming. Nat Rev Immunol 2008; 8: 337-348.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McGeachy MJ, Chen Y, Tato CM et al. The interleukin 23 receptor is essential for the terminal differentiation of interleukin 17-producing effector T helper cells in vivo. Nat Immunol 2009; 10: 314-324.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Onishi RM, Gaffen SL. Interleukin-17 and its target genes: mechanisms of interleukin-17 function in disease. Immunology 2010; 129: 311-321.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Buhl AL, Wenzel J. Interleukin-36 in infectious and inflammatory skin diseases. Front Immunol 2019; 24: 1162.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lu R, Zhou G, Du G et al. Expression of T-bet and GATA-3 in peripheral blood mononuclear cells of patients with oral lichen planus. Arch Oral Biol 2011; 56: 499-505.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Charazinska-Carewicz K, Ganowicz E, Krol M et al. Assessment of the peripheral immunocompetent cells in patients with reticular and atrophic-erosive lichen planus. Oral Surg Oral Med Oral Pathol Oral Radiol Endod 2008; 105: 202-205.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu GX, Sun JT, Yang MX et al. OPN promotes survival of activated T cells by up-regulating CD44 in patients with oral lichen planus. Clin Immunol 2011; 138: 291-298.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moher D, Liberati A. Tetzlaff jet al. Preferred reporting items forsystematic reviews and meta-analyses: the PRISMA statement. OpenMed 2009; 3: e123-e130.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Critical evaluation of the Newcastle-Ottawa scale for the assessment of the quality of nonrandomized studies in meta-analyses. Stang a. Eur J Epidemiol 2010 Sep; 25: 603-605.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carvalho MF, Cavalieri D, Do Nascimento S et al. Cytokines levels and salivary microbiome play a potential role in Oral lichen planus diagnosis. Sci Rep 2019; 9: 18137.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Domingues R, de Carvalho GC, Aoki V, da Silva Duarte AJ, Sato MN. Activation of myeloid dendritic cells, effector cells and regulatory T cells in lichen planus. J Transl Med 2016; 14: 171.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Firth FA, Friedlander LT, Parachuru VP, Kardos TB, Seymour GJ, Rich AM. Regulation of immune cells in oral lichen planus. Arch Dermatol Res 2015; 307: 333-339.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gueiros LA, Arão T, Souza T et al. IL17A polymorphism and elevated IL17A serum levels are associated with oral lichen planus. Oral Dis 2018; 24: 377-383.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Javvadi LR, Parachuru VP, Milne TJ, Seymour GJ, Rich AM. Regulatory T-cells and IL17A(+) cells infiltrate oral lichen planus lesions. Pathology 2016; 48: 564-573.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kumaran MS, Bishnoi A, Srivastava N et al. Significant reduction in the expression of interleukins-17A, 22 and 23A, forkhead box p3 and interferon gamma delineates lichen planus pigmentosus from lichen planus. Arch Dermatol Res 2019; 311: 519-527.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lu R, Zeng X, Han Q et al. Overexpression and selectively regulatory roles of IL-23/IL-17 axis in the lesions of oral lichen planus. Mediators Inflamm 2014; 2014: 701094.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mahmoud SB, Anwar MK, Shaker OG, El Sharkawy DA. Possible relation between vitamin D and Interleukin-17 in the pathogenesis of lichen planus. Dermatology 2021; 237: 896-901.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Monteiro BV, Pereira Jdos S, Nonaka CF, Godoy GP, da Silveira ÉJ, Miguel MC. Immunoexpression of Th17-related cytokines in oral lichen planus. Appl Immunohistochem Mol Morphol 2015 Jul; 23: 409-415.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Piccinni MP, Lombardelli L, Logiodice F et al. Potential pathogenetic role of Th17, Th0, and Th2 cells in erosive and reticular oral lichen planus. Oral Dis 2014; 20: 212-218.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pouralibaba F, Babaloo Z, Pakdel F, Aghazadeh M. Serum level of interleukin 17 in patients with erosive and non erosive Oral lichen planus. J Dent Res Dent Clin Dent Prospects 2013; 7: 91-94.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shaker O, Hassan AS. Possible role of interleukin-17 in the pathogenesis of lichen planus. Br J Dermatol 2012; 166: 1367-1368.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shan J, Shen C, Fang J, Li S, Fan Y. Potential roles of the CCL17-CCR4 axis in immunopathogenesis of oral lichen planus. J Oral Pathol Med 2020; 49: 328-334.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shen Z, Gao X, Ma L, Zhou Z, Shen X, Liu W. Expression of Foxp3 and interleukin-17 in lichen planus lesions with emphasis on difference in oral and cutaneous variants. Arch Dermatol Res 2014; 306: 441-446.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shen Z, Zhang C, Zhou Z, Liu W, Shi L, Shen X. Altered expression of interleukin-17A and its targeting microRNAs in oral lichen planus: a pilot study. Oral Surg Oral Med Oral Pathol Oral Radiol 2016; 122: 619-624.e1.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang H, Luo Z, Lei L et al. Interaction between oral lichen planus and chronic periodontitis with Th17-associated cytokines in serum. Inflammation 2013; 36: 696-704.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang H, Han Q, Luo Z et al. Oral lichen planus may enhance the expression of Th17-associated cytokines in local lesions of chronic periodontitis. Clin Oral Investig 2014; 18: 1647-1654.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang H, Bai J, Luo Z, Fu J, Wang H, Sun Z. Overexpression and varied clinical significance of Th9 versus Th17 cells in distinct subtypes of oral lichen planus. Arch Oral Biol 2017; 80: 110-116.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xie S, Ding L, Xiong Z, Zhu S. Implications of Th1 and Th17 cells in pathogenesis of oral lichen planus. J Huazhong Univ Sci Technolog Med Sci 2012; 32: 451-457.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zare R, Mohtasham N, Ghazi N et al. Evaluation of correlation between transcription factors and IL-17 in oral and cutaneous lichen planus lesions and leukocytes. Cytokine 2021; 148: 155696.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhou L, Cao T, Wang Y et al. Frequently increased but functionally impaired CD4+CD25+ regulatory T cells in patients with Oral lichen planus. Inflammation 2016; 39: 1205-1215.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Żychowska M, Batycka-Baran A, Baran W. Increased serum level and high tissue Immunoexpression of interleukin 17 in cutaneous lichen planus: a novel therapeutic target for recalcitrant cases? Dis Markers 2020; 24: 6521274.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stockinger B, Omenetti S. The dichotomous nature of T helper 17 cells. Nat Rev Immunol 2017; 17: 535-544.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ogura H, Murakami M, Okuyama Y et al. Interleukin-17 promotes autoimmunity by triggering a positivefeedback loop via interleukin-6 induction. Immunity 2008; 29: 628-636.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Puerta-Arias JD, Mejía SP, González Á. The role of the Interleukin-17 Axis and neutrophils in the pathogenesis of endemic and systemic mycoses. Front Cell Infect Microbiol 2020; 14: 595301.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gadenne AS, Strucke R, Dunn D, Wagner M, Bleicher P, Bigby M. Tcell lines derived from lesional skin of lichen planus patients contain a distinctive population of T-cell receptor gamma delta-bearing cells. J Invest Dermatol 1994; 103: 347-351.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cai Y, Shen X, Ding C et al. Pivotal role of dermal IL-17-producing γδ T cells in skin inflammation. Immunity 2011; 35: 596-610.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>James SP. Detection of Cytokine mRNA Expression by PCR. Curr Protoc Immunol 2001; Chapter 10:unit 10.23. https://doi.org/10.1002/0471142735.im1023s10</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Karatsaidis A, Schreurs O, Helgeland K et al. Erythematous and reticular forms of oral lichen planus and oral lichenoid reactions differ in pathological features related to disease activity. J Oral Pathol Med 2003; 32: 275-281.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pereira JS, Monteiro BV, Nonaka CF et al. FoxP3(+) T regulatory cells in oral lichen planus and its correlation with the distinct clinical appearance of the lesions. Int J Exp Pathol 2012; 93: 287-294.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eyerich K, Dimartino V, Cavani A. IL-17 and IL-22 in immunity: driving protection and pathology. Eur J Immunol 2017; 47: 607-614.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Feng T, Qin H, Wang L, Benveniste EN, Elson CO, Cong Y. Th17 cells induce colitis and promote Th1 cell responses through IL-17 induction of innate IL-12 and IL-23 production. J Immunol 2011; 186: 6313-6318.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martin-Orozco N, Chung Y, Chang SH, Wang YH, Dong C. Th17 cells promote pancreatic inflammation but only induce diabetes efficiently in lymphopenic hosts after conversion into Th1 cells. Eur J Immunol 2009; 39: 216-224.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bending D, De La Peña H, Veldhoen M et al. Highly purified Th17 cells from BDC2.5NOD mice convert into Th1-like cells in NOD/SCID recipient mice. J Clin Invest 2009; 119: 565-572.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zheng Y, Danilenko DM, Valdez P et al. Interleukin-22, a TH17 cytokine, mediates IL-23-induced dermal inflammation and acanthosis. Nature 2007; 445: 648-651.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pandiyan P, Zhu J. Origin and functions of proinflammatory cytokine producing Foxp3+ regulatory Tcells. Cytokine 2015; 76: 13-24.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Duarte JH, Zelenay S, Bergman ML, Martins AC, Demengeot J. Natural Treg cells spontaneously differentiate into pathogenic helper cells in lymphopenic conditions. Eur J Immunol 2009; 39: 948-955.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beriou G, Costantino CM, Ashley CW et al. IL-17-producing human peripheral regulatory T cells retain suppressive function. Blood 2009; 113: 4240-4249.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hovhannisyan Z, Treatman J, Littman DR, Mayer L. Characterization of interleukin-17-producing regulatory T cells in inflamed intestinal mucosa from patients with inflammatory bowel diseases. Gastroenterology 2011; 140: 957-965.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bovenschen HJ, van de Kerkhof PC, van Erp PE, Woestenenk R, Joosten I, Koenen HJ. Foxp3+ regulatory T cells of psoriasis patients easily differentiate into IL-17A-producing cells and are found in lesional skin. Journal of Investigative Dermatology 2011; 131: 1853-1860.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mardani M, Mofidi H, Dastgheib L, Ranjbar S, Hamidizadeh N. Elevated serum Interleukin-23 levels in patients with Oral and cutaneous lichen planus. Mediators Inflamm 2021; 12: 5578568.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sparber F, LeibundGut-Landmann S. Interleukin-17 in antifungal immunity. Pathogens 2019; 8(2): 54 Published 2019 Apr 22.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sugerman PB, Voltz MJ, Savage NW, Basford KE, Seymour GJ. Phenotypic and functional analysis of peripheral blood lymphocytes in oral lichen planus. J Oral Pathol Med 1992; 21: 445-450.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Karagouni EE, Dotsika EN, Sklavounou A. Alteration in peripheral blood mononuclear cell function and serum cytokines in oral lichen planus. J Oral Pathol Med 1994; 23: 28-35.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wasilewska A, Winiarska M, Olszewska M, Rudnicka L. Interleukin-17 inhibitors. A new era in treatment of psoriasis and other skin diseases. Postepy Dermatol Alergol 2016; 33: 247-252.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Solimani F, Pollmann R, Schmidt T et al. Therapeutic targeting of Th17/Tc17 cells leads to clinical improvement of lichen planus. Front Immunol 2019; 31: 1808.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ismail FF, Sinclair R. Clinical healing of erosive oral lichen planus with tildrakizumab implicates the interleukin-23/interleukin-17 pathway in the pathogenesis of lichen planus. Australas J Dermatol 2020; 61: e244-e245.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Qian H, Jiao L, Fan Z, Wang L, Liu B, Miao G. Analysis of immunologic function changes in lichen planus after clinical treatment. Med Sci Monit 2018; 24: 8716-8721.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pietschke K, Holstein J, Meier K et al. The inflammation in cutaneous lichen planus is dominated by IFN-ϒ and IL-21-a basis for therapeutic JAK1 inhibition. Exp Dermatol 2021; 30: 262-270.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>https://www.clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04300296?cond=lichen+planus&amp;draw=3&amp;rank=39. Accessed in March 24 2022</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>https://www.clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT05030415?cond=lichen+planus&amp;draw=3&amp;rank=42. Accessed in March 24 2022</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huang Y, Lou H, Wang C, Zhang L. Impact of cigarette smoke and IL-17A activation on asthmatic patients with chronic rhinosinusitis. Rhinology 2019; 57: 57-66.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Siew LQC, Wu SY, Ying S, Corrigan CJ. Cigarette smoking increases bronchial mucosal IL-17A expression in asthmatics, which acts in concert with environmental aeroallergens to engender neutrophilic inflammation. Clin Exp Allergy 2017; 47: 740-750.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
