<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35579463</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>23</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2165-0497</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>17</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Microbiology spectrum</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Microbiol Spectr</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Identification of a Host-Targeted Compound to Control Typhoid Fever.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e0061922</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e0061922</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1128/spectrum.00619-22</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Typhoid fever is caused primarily by the enteric microbe Salmonella enterica serovar Typhi and remains a major global health problem with approximately 14 million new infections and 136,000 fatalities annually. While there are antibiotic options available to treat the disease, the global increase in multidrug-resistant strains necessitates alternative therapeutic options. Host-targeted therapeutics present a promising anti-infective strategy against intracellular bacterial pathogens. A cell-based assay identified a compound that inhibits <i>Salmonella</i> proliferation in infected cells, 2-(3-hydroxypropyl)-1-(3-phenoxyphenyl)-1,2-dihydrochromeno[2,3-c]pyrrole-3,9-dione (KH-1), which is devoid of direct activity against <i>Salmonella</i>. The compound inhibits the growth of both antibiotic-sensitive and -resistant <i>Salmonella</i> strains inside macrophages and reduces lactate dehydrogenase (LDH) release from <i>Salmonella</i>-infected cells. Subsequent screening of KH-1 commercial analogs identified 2-(4-fluorobenzyl)-1-(3-phenoxyphenyl)-1,2-dihydrochromeno[2,3-c] pyrrole-3,9-dione (KH-1-2), which is more effective in controlling <i>Salmonella</i> growth inside macrophages. <i>In vitro</i> KH-1-2 treatment of <i>Salmonella</i> infection resulted in an 8- to 10-fold reduction in bacterial load in infected macrophages. In combination with suboptimal ciprofloxacin treatment, KH-1-2 further reduces <i>Salmonella</i> growth inside macrophages. The toxicity and efficacy of KH-1-2 in controlling <i>Salmonella</i> infection were examined <i>in vivo</i> using a mouse model of typhoid fever. No significant compound-related clinical signs and histological findings of the liver, spleen, or kidney were observed from uninfected mice that were intraperitoneally treated with KH-1-2. KH-1-2 significantly protected mice from a lethal dose of infection by an antibiotic-resistant <i>Salmonella</i> strain. Thus, our study provides support that this is a promising lead compound for the development of a novel host-targeted therapeutic agent to control typhoid fever. <b>IMPORTANCE</b> <i>Salmonella</i> spp. cause significant morbidity and mortality worldwide. Typhoidal spp. (e.g., <i>S.</i> Typhi) cause a systemic disease typically treated with antibiotics. However, growing antibiotic resistance is resulting in increased treatment failures. We screened a compound library for those that would reduce <i>Salmonella</i>-induced macrophage toxicity, identifying compound KH-1. KH-1 has no direct effects on the bacteria but limits <i>Salmonella</i> survival in macrophages and protects against lethal infection in a mouse model of typhoid fever. A suboptimal concentration of ciprofloxacin worked in conjunction with the compound to further decrease <i>Salmonella</i> survival in macrophages. An analog (KH-1-2) was identified that possessed increased activity <i>in vitro</i> in macrophages and <i>in vivo</i> against both antibiotic-sensitive and -resistant strains. Thus, we report the identification of a lead compound that may be a useful scaffold as a host-directed antimicrobial against typhoid fever.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hoang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ky V</ForeName>
            <Initials>KV</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Center for Microbial Pathogenesis, Abigail Wexner Research Institute at Nationwide Children's Hospital, Columbus, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Infectious Diseases Institute, The Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Woolard</LastName>
            <ForeName>Katherine</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Chemistry and Biochemistry, University of Notre Dame, Notre Dame, Indiana, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ching</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Center for Microbial Pathogenesis, Abigail Wexner Research Institute at Nationwide Children's Hospital, Columbus, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Veterinary Biosciences, College of Veterinary Medicine, The Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Melander</LastName>
            <ForeName>Christian</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Chemistry and Biochemistry, University of Notre Dame, Notre Dame, Indiana, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gunn</LastName>
            <ForeName>John S</ForeName>
            <Initials>JS</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2848-8346</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Center for Microbial Pathogenesis, Abigail Wexner Research Institute at Nationwide Children's Hospital, Columbus, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Infectious Diseases Institute, The Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pediatrics, The Ohio State University College of Medicine, Columbus, Ohio, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Microbiol Spectr</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101634614</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2165-0497</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">KH-1-2</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Salmonella Typhi</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">host-targeted therapy</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">immunomodulation</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">typhoid fever</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>9</Hour>
          <Minute>13</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35579463</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/spectrum.00619-22</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
