<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35576751</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>24</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">2210-2612</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>95</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>04</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>International journal of surgery case reports</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Int J Surg Case Rep</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Diabetic mastopathy: A rare clinicopathologic entity with considerable autoimmune potential.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>107151</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>107151</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">107151</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.ijscr.2022.107151</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S2210-2612(22)00397-2</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION AND IMPORTANCE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Diabetic mastopathy is a rare entity affecting diabetic patients. It has been previously linked to type 1 diabetes mellitus; however, due to the several accompanying conditions, a theory of autoimmune factors contributing to the origin of this condition has been on the rise. In this paper, we report a case of diabetic mastopathy associated with several autoimmune diseases to highlight the immunological potential of this condition.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CASE PRESENTATION" NlmCategory="METHODS">A 25-year-old female, known to have type 1 diabetes mellitus, hypertension, hypothyroidism, adrenal insufficiency, dilated cardiomyopathy and end-stage renal disease, was referred to our clinic for a breast lump. Radiological investigations showed a dense mass with irregular borders in the retroareolar area of the left breast. A core biopsy was obtained which revealed keloid-like fibrosis along with lymphocytes infiltrated, suggestive of lymphocytic mastopathy.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CLINICAL DISCUSSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Fibrous mastopathy has been merely attributed to a long-standing use of insulin therapy by diabetic patients; recent observations, however, proved the major contribution of immunity to etiopathogenesis. Even though human leukocyte antigen (HLA) association has not been supported in the literature, the histological changes of breast lymphocytic infiltrate are seen in patients who not only have T1DM, but also thyroiditis, systemic lupus erythematosus, Sjogren's syndrome, and Addison's disease. The frequent presence of several possible autoimmune conditions has promoted the theory of an autoimmune process affecting connective tissues, however, these claims are yet to be proven by future studies.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Recent observations have proved the major contribution of immunity to etiopathogenesis of diabetic mastopathy. We shed light on the role of the immune system in triggering the disease process by reporting a case of diabetic mastopathy with a cluster of autoimmune diseases. Future studies should explore the genetic background of the condition as it would potentially have several clinical implications. The discussed pathophysiologic explanations raise the possibility of autoimmunity as a key driver in pathogenesis and indicate the need to change the nomenclature of this condition.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Ltd.. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Boumarah</LastName>
            <ForeName>Dhuha N</ForeName>
            <Initials>DN</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Surgery, King Fahd University Hospital, Imam Abdulrahman Bin Faisal University, Saudi Arabia. Electronic address: Dohanahar@gmail.com.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>AlSinan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ali S</ForeName>
            <Initials>AS</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Surgery, King Fahd University Hospital, Imam Abdulrahman Bin Faisal University, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>AlMaher</LastName>
            <ForeName>Eman M</ForeName>
            <Initials>EM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Surgery, Security Forces Hospital, Dammam, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mashhour</LastName>
            <ForeName>Miral</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pathology, King Fahad Specialist Hospital, Dammam, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>AlDuhileb</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mohammed</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Surgery, King Fahad Specialist Hospital, Dammam, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>04</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Int J Surg Case Rep</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101529872</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2210-2612</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Autoimmune</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Case report</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Diabetes</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mastopathy</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>None declared.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
          <Hour>18</Hour>
          <Minute>20</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35576751</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9118609</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijscr.2022.107151</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">S2210-2612(22)00397-2</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Agochukwu N.B., Wong L. Diabetic mastopathy: a systematic review of surgical management of a rare breast disease. Ann. Plast. Surg. 2017;78:471–475.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28272124</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Corbetta Machado M., Regalo G. Lymphocytic mastopathy – a rare entity and a diagnostic challenge. Int.J.Surg.Case Rep. 2020:1–3.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen L., Tsang J., Ni Y., Chan S., Chan K., Zhang S., et al.  Lymphocyte subsets contribute to the degree of lobulitis and ductitis in sclerosing lymphocytic lobulitis of the breast. J. Clin. Pathol. 2015;69(6):527–532.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26582743</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tomaszewski J.E., Brooks J.S.J., Hicks D., et al.  Diabetic mastopathy: a distinctive clinicopathologic entity. Hum. Pathol. 1992;23:780–786.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1612578</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Seidman J.D., Schnaper L.A., Phillips L.E. Mastopathy in insulin-requiring diabetes mellitus. Hum. Pathol. 1994;25:819–824.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8056424</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dorokhova O., Fineberg S., Koenigsberg T., Wang Y. Diabetic mastopathy, a clinicopathological correlation of 34 cases. Pathol. Int. 2012;62(10):660–664.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23005592</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Agha R.A., Franchi T., Sohrabi C., Mathew G., for the SCARE Group  The SCARE 2020 guideline: updating consensus Surgical CAse REport (SCARE) guidelines. Int. J. Surg. 2020;84:226–230.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33181358</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Soler N.G., Khardori R. Fibrous disease of the breast, thyroiditis, and cheiroarthropathy in type 1 diabetes mellitus. Lancet. 1984;1:193–194.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6141337</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ely K.A., Tse G., Simpson J.F., Clarfeld R., Page D.L. Diabetic mastopathy: a clinicopathologic review. Am. J. Clin. Pathol. 2000;113:541–545.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10761456</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chan C.-l.R., Ho R.S.L., Shek T.W.H., Kwong A. Diabetic mastopathy. Breast J. 2013;19:533–538.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23895671</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pluchinotta A.M., Talenti E., Lodovichetti G., et al.  Diabetic fibrous breast disease: a clinical entity that mimics cancer. Eur. J. Surg. Oncol. 1995;21:207–209.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7720901</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weinstein S.P., Conant E.F., Orel S.G., et al.  Diabetic mastopathy in men: imaging findings in two patients. Radiology. 2001;219:797–799.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11376272</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thorncroft K., Forsyth L., Desmond S., Audisio R. The diagnosis and management of diabetic mastopathy. Breast J. 2007;13(6):607–613.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17983405</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Camuto P.M., Zetrenne E., Ponn T. Diabetic mastopathy: a report of 5 cases and a review of literature. Arch. Surg. 2000;135:1190–1193.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11030878</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Decraene J., Van Ongeval C., Clinckemaillie G., Wilddiers H. Sclerosing lymphocytic lobulitis mimicking a tumor relapse in a young woman with a history of breast cancer. J. Belg. Soc. Radiol. 2015;99:72–75.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6032652</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30039071</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee A., Bateman A., Turner S., Theaker J., Howell W. HLA class II DRB1 and DQB1 allelic polymorphism and sclerosing lymphocytic lobulitis of the breast. J. Clin. Pathol. 1999;52(6):445–449.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC501432</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10562813</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schwartz I.S., Strauchen J.A. Lymphocytic mastopathy. An autoimmune disease of the breast? Am. J. Clin. Pathol. 1990;93:725–730.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1693260</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goulabchand R., Hafidi A., et al.  Mastitis in autoimmune diseases: review of the literature, diagnostic pathway, and pathophysiological key players. J. Clin. Med. 2020;9(4):958. doi: 10.3390/jcm9040958. Published 2020 Mar 30.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/jcm9040958</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kudva Y., Reynolds C., O’Brien T., Powell C., Oberg A., Crotty T. “Diabetic Mastopathy”, or sclerosing lymphocytic lobulitis, is strongly associated with type 1 diabetes. Diabetes Care. 2002;25(1):121–126.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11772912</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wood E., Propeck P. Atypical sonographic presentation of diabetic mastopathy: a case report and literature review. J.Clin.Imaging Sci. 2021;11:60.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8645490</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34877067</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Logan W.W., Hoffman N.Y. Diabetic fibrous breast disease. Radiology. 1989;172:667–670.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2672091</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
