<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35583298</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>22</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1087-2981</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>27</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Dec</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Medical education online</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Med Educ Online</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Student loan debt and financial education: a qualitative analysis of resident perceptions and implications for resident well-being.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>2075303</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>2075303</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">2075303</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1080/10872981.2022.2075303</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>High educational debt is prevalent among resident physicians and correlates with adverse well-being outcomes, including symptoms of stress and burnout. Residents also report low financial literacy levels, affecting financial well-being. Understanding resident viewpoints toward financial well-being initiatives is crucial to develop targeted resident financial well-being programs. This study aims to examine residents' experiences financing their medical education and how these experiences influence well-being and attitudes toward financial education in residency. We recruited residents from a Southern California health system with residency programs in Family Medicine, Internal Medicine, General Surgery, Orthopaedic Surgery, and Psychiatry. We contacted residents by email and text message to participate in semi-structured interviews. We conducted interviews from October 2020 to March 2021 and analyzed 59 resident interviews using reflexive thematic analysis. Among residents, 76% (45/59) had ≥ $200,000 in student loans. Residents perceived mounting medical education debt as unfairly burdensome for trainees engaged in socially beneficial work, leaving residents feeling undervalued - a feeling heightened by the stressors of the COVID-19 pandemic - and hampering well-being. Compartmentalizing debt attenuated financial stressors but often made financial education seem less pressing. A subset of residents described how financial planning restored some agency and enhanced well-being, noting that protected didactic time for financial education was crucial. Resident interviews provide practical guidance regarding designing financial education sessions. Desired education included managing debt, retirement planning, and the business of medicine. How residents framed educational debt and their degree of financial literacy impacted their well-being and sense of agency. Residents proposed that residency programs can aid in stress mitigation by providing residents with skills to help manage debt and plan for retirement. To reduce clinician indebtedness, this approach needs to occur in tandem with systemic changes to financing medical education.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Garrett</LastName>
            <ForeName>Cameryn C</ForeName>
            <Initials>CC</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Graduate Medical Education, Community Memorial Health System, Ventura, California, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Doonan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ronda L</ForeName>
            <Initials>RL</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Graduate Medical Education, Community Memorial Health System, Ventura, California, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Pyle</LastName>
            <ForeName>Casey</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Orthopaedic Surgery Residency Program, Community Memorial Health System, Ventura, California, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Azimov</LastName>
            <ForeName>Michelle B</ForeName>
            <Initials>MB</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Graduate Medical Education, Community Memorial Health System, Ventura, California, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Med Educ Online</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9806550</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1087-2981</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000086382" MajorTopicYN="Y">COVID-19</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007396" MajorTopicYN="Y">Internship and Residency</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009985" MajorTopicYN="Y">Orthopedics</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D058873" MajorTopicYN="N">Pandemics</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014146" MajorTopicYN="N">Training Support</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">debt</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">medical education</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">qualitative methods</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">student loans</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">well-being</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>No potential conflict of interest was reported by the authors.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>8</Hour>
          <Minute>43</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35583298</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9122352</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10872981.2022.2075303</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>American Association of Colleges of Osteopathic Medicine . 2019-2020 Academic Year Graduating Seniors Survey Summary Report. https://www.aacom.org/docs/default-source/data-and-trends/aacom-2019-2020-graduating-seniors-survey-summary-report.pdf?sfvrsn=406a0897_4. Accessed 2021 Dec
14.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Association of American Medical Colleges . Medical School Graduation Questionnaire: 2020 All Schools Summary Report. https://www.aamc.org/media/46851/download. Cited 2021 Dec
14.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pisaniello MS, Asahina AT, Bacchi S, et al. Effect of medical student debt on mental health, academic performance and specialty choice: a systematic review. BMJ Open. 2019;9(7):e029980.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>West CP, Shanafelt TD, Kolars JC.. 
Quality of life, burnout, educational debt, and medical knowledge among internal medicine residents. JAMA. 2011;306(9):952–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21900135</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhou AY, Panagioti M, Esmail A, et al. Factors associated with burnout and stress in trainee physicians: a systematic review and meta-analysis. JAMA Network Open. 2020;3(8):e2013761.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7435345</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32809031</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine . 2019. Taking action against clinician burnout: A systems approach to professional well-being. Washington, DC: The National Academies Press. 10.17226/25521</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.17226/25521</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>The Accreditation Council for Graduate Medical Education . ACGME Common Program Requirements. https://www.acgme.org/what-we-do/accreditation/common-program-requirements. Cited 2021 Dec
10.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Okanlawon T.
Resident and Fellow Burnout: Create a Holistic, Supportive Culture of Well-Being. American Medical Association. https://edhub.ama-assn.org/steps-forward/module/2702511. Cited 2021 Nov
18.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ahmad FA, White AJ, Hiller KM, et al. An assessment of residents’ and fellows’ personal finance literacy: an unmet medical education need. Int J Med Educ. 2017;8:192–204.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5457786</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28557777</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McKillip R, Ernst M, Ahn J, et al. Toward a resident personal finance curriculum: quantifying resident financial circumstances, needs, and interests. Cureus. 2018;10(4):e2540.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6019332</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29951347</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shappell E, Ahn J and Ahmed N, et al.$3$2 (2018). Personal Finance Education for Residents: a Qualitative Study of Resident Perspectives. AEM Educ Train, 2(3), 195–203. 10.1002/aet2.10090</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/aet2.10090</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6050061</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30051089</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Young TP, Brown MM and Reibling ET, et al.$3$2 (2016). Effect of Educational Debt on Emergency Medicine Residents: a Qualitative Study Using Individual Interviews. Ann Emerg Med, 68(4), 409–418. 10.1016/j.annemergmed.2016.04.013</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.annemergmed.2016.04.013</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27181080</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lusardi A. Financial literacy and the need for financial education: evidence and implications. Swiss J Econ Stat. 2019;155(1):1.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wong R, Ng P, Bonino J, et al. Financial attitudes and behaviors of internal medicine and internal medicine-pediatrics residents. J Grad Med Educ. 2018;10(6):639–645.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6314372</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30619520</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tong A, Sainsbury P, Craig J. Consolidated criteria for reporting qualitative research (COREQ): a 32-item checklist for interviews and focus groups. Int J Qual Health Care. 2007;19(6):349–357.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17872937</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Braun V, Clarke V. Thematic analysis: a practical guide. Thousand Oaks CA: SAGE Publications Inc; 2022.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Braun V, Clarke V. Using thematic analysis in psychology. Qual Res Psychol. 2006;3(2):77–101.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Willig C. Introducing qualitative research in psychology. 3rd ed. Maidenhead England: Open University Press; 2013.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Braun V, Clarke V. Reflecting on reflexive thematic analysis. Qual Res Sport Exerc Health. 2019;11(4):589–597.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brown W. Neoliberalized knowledge. Hist Present. 2011;1(1):113–129.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Federal Student Aid . COVID-19 Emergency Relief and Federal Student Aid. Office of the Department of Education. https://studentaid.gov/announcements-events/covid-19. Cited 2021 Nov
23.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hughes MT, Rushton CH. Ethics and well-being: the health professions and the COVID-19 pandemic. Acad Med. 2022. 
97
3
S98–S103 . published online ahead of print, 16
Nov
https://journals.lww.com/academicmedicine/Fulltext/2022/03001/Ethics_and_Well_Being__The_Health_Professions_and.16.aspx. DOI:10.1097/acm.0000000000004524.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/acm.0000000000004524</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8855760</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34789657</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cox CL. ‘Healthcare heroes’: problems with media focus on heroism from healthcare workers during the COVID-19 pandemic. J Med Ethics. 2020;46(8):510–513.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7316119</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32546658</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Phillips JP, Wilbanks DM, Salinas DF, et al. Educational debt in the context of career planning: a qualitative exploration of medical student perceptions. Teach Learn Med. 2016;28(3):243–251.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27152504</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dyrbye L, Shanafelt T. A narrative review on burnout experienced by medical students and residents. Med Educ. 2016;50(1):132–149.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26695473</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jennings JD, Quinn C, Ly JA, et al. Orthopaedic surgery resident financial literacy: an assessment of knowledge in debt, investment, and retirement savings. Am Surg. 2019;85(4):353–358.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31043194</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rohlfing J, Navarro R, Maniya OZ, et al. Medical student debt and major life choices other than specialty. Med Educ Online. 2014;19(1):25603.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4229497</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25391976</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
