<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35588325</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1432-1920</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>19</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Neuroradiology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Neuroradiology</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Altered white matter structural connectivity in primary Sjögren's syndrome: a link-based analysis.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00234-022-02970-5</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Cognitive impairment has been revealed in primary Sjögren's syndrome (pSS). However, the underlying white matter structural connectivity (SC) changes have not been studied. This study aimed to investigate the altered white matter brain network in patients with pSS using diffusion tensor imaging (DTI).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Forty-one pSS patients and sixty matched healthy controls (HCs) underwent neuropsychological tests and the subsequent MRI examinations. The clinical data were gathered from the medical record. The structural brain network was established using DTI, and a link-based comparison was performed between patients with pSS and HCs (false discovery rate correction, P &lt; 0.05). Furthermore, the mean fractional anisotropy (FA) of the altered SCs was correlated with the neuropsychological tests and clinical data in patients with pSS (Bonferroni correction, P &lt; 0.05).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Compared with HCs, patients with pSS mainly exhibited decreased SC in the frontal and parietal lobes and some parts of the temporal and occipital lobes. In addition, increased SC was found between the right caudate nucleus and right median cingulate/paracingulate gyri. Specifically, the reduced SC between the left middle temporal gyrus and left middle occipital gyrus was negatively correlated with white matter high signal intensity (WMH).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Patients with pSS showed diffusely decreased SC mainly in the frontoparietal network and exhibited a negative correlation between the reduced SC and WMH. SC represents a potential biomarker for preclinical brain impairment in patients with pSS.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer-Verlag GmbH Germany, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xiao-Dong</ForeName>
            <Initials>XD</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Tianjin First Central Hospital, Tianjin Institute of Imaging Medicine, No.24 Fu Kang Road, Nan Kai District, Tianjin, 300192, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Li</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jing-Li</ForeName>
            <Initials>JL</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Tianjin Medical University Cancer Institute and Hospital, Tianjin Medical University, Tianjin, 300060, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhou</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jia-Min</ForeName>
            <Initials>JM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Tianjin First Central Hospital, Tianjin Institute of Imaging Medicine, No.24 Fu Kang Road, Nan Kai District, Tianjin, 300192, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Zi-Ning</ForeName>
            <Initials>ZN</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Tianjin First Central Hospital, Tianjin Institute of Imaging Medicine, No.24 Fu Kang Road, Nan Kai District, Tianjin, 300192, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhao</LastName>
            <ForeName>Lin-Ru</ForeName>
            <Initials>LR</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology, Tianjin First Central Hospital, Tianjin, 300192, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Shen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Wen</ForeName>
            <Initials>W</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Tianjin First Central Hospital, Tianjin Institute of Imaging Medicine, No.24 Fu Kang Road, Nan Kai District, Tianjin, 300192, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Xu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jun-Hai</ForeName>
            <Initials>JH</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Tianjin Key Laboratory of Cognitive Computing and Application, College of Intelligence and Computing, Tianjin University, Tianjin, 300350, China. jhxu@tju.edu.cn.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Cheng</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yue</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3159-4924</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Tianjin First Central Hospital, Tianjin Institute of Imaging Medicine, No.24 Fu Kang Road, Nan Kai District, Tianjin, 300192, China. chengyue200017076@163.com.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>Germany</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Neuroradiology</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>1302751</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0028-3940</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Brain networks</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Diffusion tensor imaging</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Magnetic resonance imaging</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Primary Sjögren’s syndrome</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Structural connectivity</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>16</Hour>
          <Minute>50</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35588325</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00234-022-02970-5</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00234-022-02970-5</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nocturne G, Mariette X (2013) Advances in understanding the pathogenesis of primary Sjogren’s syndrome. Nat Rev Rheumatol 9(9):544–556. https://doi.org/10.1038/nrrheum.2013.110</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrrheum.2013.110</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23857130</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Soliotis FC, Mavragani CP, Moutsopoulos HM (2014) Central nervous system involvement in Sjogren’s syndrome. Ann Rheum Dis 63(6):616–620. https://doi.org/10.1136/ard.2003.019497</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/ard.2003.019497</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koçer B, Tezcan ME, Batur HZ, Haznedaroğlu Ş, Göker B, İrkeç C, Çetinkaya R (2016) Cognition, depression, fatigue, and quality of life in primary Sjögren’s syndrome: correlations. Brain Behav 6(12):e00586. https://doi.org/10.1002/brb3.586</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/brb3.586</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28032007</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5167008</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mekinian A, Tennenbaum J, Lahuna C, Dellal A, Belfeki N, Capron J, Januel E, Stankoff B, Alamowitch S, Fain O (2020) Primary Sjögren’s syndrome: central and peripheral nervous system involvements. Clin Exp Rheumatol 38 Suppl 126(4):103–109. Epub 2020 Oct 22.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Akasbi M, Berenguer J, Saiz A, Brito-Zerón P, Pérez-De-Lis M, Bové A, Diaz-Lagares C, Retamozo S, Blanco Y, Perez-Alvarez R, Bosch X, Sisó A, Graus F, Ramos-Casals M (2012) White matter abnormalities in primary Sjögren syndrome. QJM 105(5):433–443. https://doi.org/10.1093/qjmed/hcr218</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/qjmed/hcr218</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22156707</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tzarouchi LC, Tsifetaki N, Konitsiotis S, Zikou A, Astrakas L, Drosos A, Argyropoulou MI (2011) CNS involvement in primary Sjogren syndrome: assessment of gray and white matter changes with MRI and voxel-based morphometry. AJR Am J Roentgenol 197(5):1207–1212. https://doi.org/10.2214/AJR.10.5984</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2214/AJR.10.5984</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22021516</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lauvsnes MB, Beyer MK, Appenzeller S, Greve OJ, Harboe E, Gøransson LG, Tjensvoll AB, Omdal R (2014) Loss of cerebral white matter in primary Sjögren’s syndrome: a controlled volumetric magnetic resonance imaging study. Eur J Neurol 21(10):1324–1329. https://doi.org/10.1111/ene.12486</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.12486</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24943133</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lauvsnes MB, Beyer MK, Kvaløy JT, Greve OJ, Appenzeller S, Kvivik I, Harboe E, Tjensvoll AB, Gøransson LG, Omdal R (2014) Association of hippocampal atrophy with cerebrospinal fluid antibodies against the NR2 subtype of the N-methyl-D-aspartate receptor in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus and patients with primary Sjögren’s syndrome. Arthritis Rheumatol 66(12):3387–3394. https://doi.org/10.1002/art.38852</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/art.38852</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25156222</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Segal BM, Mueller BA, Zhu X, Prosser R, Pogatchnik B, Holker E, Carpenter AF, Lim KO (2010) Disruption of brain white matter microstructure in primary Sjögren’s syndrome: evidence from diffusion tensor imaging. Rheumatology (Oxford) 49(8):1530–1539. https://doi.org/10.1093/rheumatology/keq070</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/rheumatology/keq070</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tzarouchi LC, Zikou AK, Tsifetaki N, Astrakas LG, Konitsiotis S, Voulgari P, Drosos A, Argyropoulou MI (2014) White matter water diffusion changes in primary Sjögren syndrome. AJNR Am J Neuroradiol 35(4):680–685. https://doi.org/10.3174/ajnr.A3756</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3174/ajnr.A3756</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24184520</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">7965820</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Andrianopoulou A, Zikou AK, Astrakas LG, Gerolymatou N, Xydis V, Voulgari P, Kiortsis DN, Argyropoulou MI (2020) Functional connectivity and microstructural changes of the brain in primary Sjögren syndrome: the relationship with depression. Acta Radiol 61(12):1684–1694. https://doi.org/10.1177/0284185120909982</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0284185120909982</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32212831</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xing W, Shi W, Leng Y, Sun X, Guan T, Liao W, Wang X (2018) Resting-state fMRI in primary Sjögren syndrome. Acta Radiol 59(9):1091–1096. https://doi.org/10.1177/0284185117749993</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0284185117749993</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29310446</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang XD, Zhao LR, Zhou JM, Su YY, Ke J, Cheng Y, Li JL, Shen W (2020) Altered hippocampal functional connectivity in primary Sjögren syndrome: a resting-state fMRI study. Lupus 29(5):446–454. https://doi.org/10.1177/0961203320908936</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0961203320908936</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32075510</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang XD, Ke J, Li JL, Su YY, Zhou JM, Zhao LR, Huang LX, Cheng Y, Shen W (2021) Different cerebral functional segregation in Sjogren’s syndrome with or without systemic lupus erythematosus revealed by amplitude of low-frequency fluctuation. Acta Radiol 20:2841851211032441. https://doi.org/10.1177/02841851211032441</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/02841851211032441</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sporns O, Tononi G, Kötter R (2005) The human connectome: a structural description of the human brain. PLoS Comput Biol 1(4):e42. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pcbi.0010042</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pcbi.0010042</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16201007</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">1239902</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>de Lange SC, Scholtens LH, Alzheimer’s Disease Neuroimaging Initiative, van den Berg LH, Boks MP, Bozzali M, Cahn W, Dannlowski U, Durston S, Geuze E, van Haren NEM, Hillegers MHJ, Koch K, Jurado MÁ, Mancini M, Marqués-Iturria I, Meinert S, Ophoff RA, Reess TJ, Repple J, Kahn RS, van den Heuvel MP, (2019) Shared vulnerability for connectome alterations across psychiatric and neurological brain disorders. Nat Hum Behav 3(9):988–998. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41562-019-0659-6</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41562-019-0659-6</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31384023</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sierk A, Daniels JK, Manthey A, Kok JG, Leemans A, Gaebler M, Lamke JP, Kruschwitz J, Walter H (2018) White matter network alterations in patients with depersonalization/derealization disorder. J Psychiatry Neurosci 43(5):347–357. https://doi.org/10.1503/jpn.170110</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1503/jpn.170110</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30125247</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6158023</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang LJ, Zheng G, Zhang L, Zhong J, Wu S, Qi R, Li Q, Wang L, Lu G (2012) Altered brain functional connectivity in patients with cirrhosis and minimal hepatic encephalopathy: a functional MR imaging study. Radiology 265(2):528–536. http:// doi.org/ https://doi.org/10.1148/radiol.12120185 .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shiboski CH, Shiboski SC, Seror R, Criswell LA, Labetoulle M, Lietman TM, Rasmussen A, Scofield H, Vitali C, Bowman SJ, Mariette X; International Sjögren’s Syndrome Criteria Working Group (2017) 2016 American College of Rheumatology/European League Against Rheumatism classification criteria for primary Sjogren’s syndrome: a consensus and data-driven methodology involving three international patient cohorts. Ann Rheum Dis 69(1):35–45. https://doi.org/10.1002/art.39859</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/art.39859</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fazekas F, Chawluk JB, Alavi A, Hurtig HI, Zimmerman RA (1987) MR signal abnormalities at 1.5 T in Alzheimer’s dementia and normal aging. AJR Am J Roentgenol 149(2):351–356. https://doi.org/10.2214/ajr.149.2.351 .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tzourio-Mazoyer N, Landeau B, Papathanassiou D, Crivello F, Etard O, Delcroix N, Mazoyer B, Joliot M (2002) Automated anatomical labeling of activations in SPM using a macroscopic anatomical parcellation of the MNI MRI single-subject brain. Neuroimage 15(1):273–289. https://doi.org/10.1006/nimg.2001.0978</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1006/nimg.2001.0978</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11771995</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li SJ, Wang Y, Qian L, Liu G, Liu SF, Zou LP, Zhang JS, Hu N, Chen XQ, Yu SY, Guo SL, Li K, He MW, Wu HT, Qiu JX, Zhang L, Wang YL, Lou X, Ma L (2018) Alterations of white matter connectivity in preschool children with autism spectrum disorder. Radiology 288(1):209–217. https://doi.org/10.1148/radiol.2018170059</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1148/radiol.2018170059</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29584599</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang Y, Deng F, Jia Y, Wang J, Zhong S, Huang H, Chen L, Chen G, Hu H, Huang L, Huang R (2019) Disrupted rich club organization and structural brain connectome in unmedicated bipolar disorder. Psychol Med 49(3):510–518. https://doi.org/10.1017/S0033291718001150</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0033291718001150</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29734951</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lim KO, Helpern JA (2002) Neuropsychiatric applications of DTI — a review. NMR Biomed 15(7–8):587–593. https://doi.org/10.1002/nbm.789</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/nbm.789</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12489105</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gong G, Rosa-Neto P, Carbonell F, Chen ZJ, He Y, Evans AC (2009) Age- and gender-related differences in the cortical anatomical network. J Neurosci 29(50):15684–15693. https://doi.org/10.1523/JNEUROSCI.2308-09.2009</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.2308-09.2009</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20016083</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2831804</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Davies K, Mirza K, Tarn J, Howard-Tripp N, Bowman SJ, Lendrem D, Primary UK, Sjögren’s Syndrome Registry, Ng WF, (2019) Fatigue in primary Sjögren’s syndrome (pSS) is associated with lower levels of proinflammatory cytokines: a validation study. Rheumatol Int 39(11):1867–1873. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00296-019-04354-0</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00296-019-04354-0</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31250166</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6791914</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pierpaoli C, Barnett A, Pajevic S, Chen R, Penix LR, Virta A, Basser P (2001) Water diffusion changes in Wallerian degeneration and their dependence on white matter architecture. Neuroimage 13(6 Pt 1):1174–1185. https://doi.org/10.1006/nimg.2001.0765</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1006/nimg.2001.0765</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11352623</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Estiasari R, Matsushita T, Masaki K, Akiyama T, Yonekawa T, Isobe N, Kira J (2012) Comparison of clinical, immunological and neuroimaging features between anti-aquaporin-4 antibody-positive and antibody-negative Sjogren’s syndrome patients with central nervous system manifestations. Mult Scler 18(6):807–816. https://doi.org/10.1177/1352458511431727 (Epub 2012 Jan 30 PMID: 22291033)</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1352458511431727</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22291033</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alexander EL, Neurologic disease in Sjögren’s syndrome: mononuclear inflammatory vasculopathy affecting central, peripheral nervous system and muscle, (1993) A clinical review and update of immunopathogenesis. Rheum Dis Clin North Am 19(4):869–908</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0889-857X(21)00211-8</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Retamozo S, Flores-Chavez A, Consuegra-Fernández M, Lozano F, Ramos-Casals M, Brito-Zerón P (2018) Cytokines as therapeutic targets in primary Sjögren syndrome. Pharmacol Ther 184:81–97. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pharmthera.2017.10.019</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pharmthera.2017.10.019</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29092775</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Le Guern V, Belin C, Henegar C, Moroni C, Maillet D, Lacau C, Dumas JL, Vigneron N, Guillevin L (2010) Cognitive function and 99mTc-ECD brain SPECT are significantly correlated in patients with primary Sjogren syndrome: a case-control study. Ann Rheum Dis 69(1):132–137. https://doi.org/10.1136/ard.2008.090811</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/ard.2008.090811</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19158115</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reginold W, Sam K, Poublanc J, Fisher J, Crawley A, Mikulis DJ (2018) Impact of white matter hyperintensities on surrounding white matter tracts. Neuroradiology 60(9):933–944. https://doi.org/10.1007/s00234-018-2053-x</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00234-018-2053-x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30030550</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tullberg M, Fletcher E, DeCarli C, Mungas D, Reed BR, Harvey DJ, Weiner MW, Chui HC, Jagust WJ (2004) White matter lesions impair frontal lobe function regardless of their location. Neurology 63(2):246–253. https://doi.org/10.1212/01.wnl.0000130530.55104.b5</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/01.wnl.0000130530.55104.b5</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15277616</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen H, Huang L, Yang D, Ye Q, Guo M, Qin R, Luo C, Li M, Ye L, Zhang B, Xu Y (2019) Nodal Global Efficiency in Front-Parietal Lobe Mediated Periventricular White Matter Hyperintensity (PWMH)-Related Cognitive Impairment. Front Aging Neurosci 11:347. https://doi.org/10.3389/fnagi.2019.00347</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnagi.2019.00347</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31920627</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6914700</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meijer KA, Steenwijk MD, Douw L, Schoonheim MM, Geurts JJG (2020) Long-range connections are more severely damaged and relevant for cognition in multiple sclerosis. Brain 143(1):150–160. https://doi.org/10.1093/brain/awz355</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/brain/awz355</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31730165</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee SH, Niznikiewicz M, Asami T, Otsuka T, Salisbury DF, Shenton ME, McCarley RW (2016) Initial and progressive gray matter abnormalities in insular gyrus and temporal pole in first-episode schizophrenia contrasted with first-episode affective psychosis. Schizophr Bull 42(3):790–801. https://doi.org/10.1093/schbul/sbv177</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/schbul/sbv177</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26675295</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wisniewski I, Wendling AS, Manning L, Steinhoff BJ (2012) Visuo-spatial memory tests in right temporal lobe epilepsy foci: clinical validity. Epilepsy Behav 23(3):254–260. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.yebeh.2011.12.006</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yebeh.2011.12.006</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22341968</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Benedictis A, Duffau H, Paradiso B, Grandi E, Balbi S, Granieri E, Colarusso E, Chioffi F, Marras CE, Sarubbo S (2014) Anatomo-functional study of the temporo-parieto-occipital region: dissection, tractographic and brain mapping evidence from a neurosurgical perspective. J Anat 225(2):132–151. https://doi.org/10.1111/joa.12204</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/joa.12204</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24975421</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4111924</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Acheson A, Robinson JL, Glahn DC, Lovallo WR, Fox PT (2009) Differential activation of the anterior cingulate cortex and caudate nucleus during a gambling simulation in persons with a family history of alcoholism: studies from the Oklahoma Family Health Patterns Project. Drug Alcohol Depend 100(1–2):17–23. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.drugalcdep.2008.08.019</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.drugalcdep.2008.08.019</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19026496</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martínez S, Cáceres C, Mataró M, Escudero D, Latorre P, Dávalos A (2010) Is there progressive cognitive dysfunction in Sjögren syndrome? A preliminary study Acta Neurol Scand 122(3):182–188. https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1600-0404.2009.01293.x</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0404.2009.01293.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20096020</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
