<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35582332</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">2220-3206</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>12</Volume>
            <Issue>4</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Apr</Month>
              <Day>19</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>World journal of psychiatry</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>World J Psychiatry</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Role of serendipity in the discovery of classical antidepressant drugs: Applying operational criteria and patterns of discovery.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>588</StartPage>
          <EndPage>602</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>588-602</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.5498/wjp.v12.i4.588</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The role played by serendipity in the origin of modern psychopharmacology has proven to be controversial in scientific literature. In its original meaning (Walpole), serendipity refers to discoveries made through a combination of accidents and sagacity. We have implemented an operational definition of serendipity based on finding something unexpected or unintended, regardless of the systematic process that led to the accidental observation, and we have established four different patterns of serendipitous attributability. In this paper, we have analyzed the role of serendipity in the discovery and development of classical antidepressant drugs, tricyclic antidepressants and monoamine oxidase inhibitors as well as heterocyclic, "atypical" or "second generation" antidepressants. The discovery of the antidepressant properties of imipramine and iproniazid, the prototypes of tricyclic antidepressants and monoamine oxidase inhibitors, respectively, fits the mixed type II pattern; initial serendipitous discoveries (imipramine was an antipsychotic and iproniazid was an anti-tuberculosis agent) led secondarily to non-serendipitous discoveries. But the other components of these two families of drugs were developed specifically as antidepressants, modifying the chemical structure of the series leaders, thereby allowing all of them to be included in the type IV pattern, characterized by the complete absence of serendipity. Among the heterocyclic drugs, mianserin (originally developed as an antihistamine) also falls into the type II pattern.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>©The Author(s) 2022. Published by Baishideng Publishing Group Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>López-Muñoz</LastName>
            <ForeName>Francisco</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Faculty of Health, University Camilo José Cela, Villanueva de la Cañada 28692, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>D'Ocón</LastName>
            <ForeName>Pilar</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology, Faculty of Pharmacy, University of Valencia, Avda. Vicent Andres Estelles, s/n, Valencia 46100, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Romero</LastName>
            <ForeName>Alejandro</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology and Toxicology, Faculty of Veterinary Medicine, Complutense University, Avda. Puerta de Hierro, s/n, Madrid 28040, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Guerra</LastName>
            <ForeName>José A</ForeName>
            <Initials>JA</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pharmacology and Toxicology, Faculty of Pharmacy, Complutense University, Pl. de Ramón y Cajal, s/n, Madrid 28040, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Álamo</LastName>
            <ForeName>Cecilio</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Biomedical Sciences (Pharmacology Area), Faculty of Medicine and Health Sciences, University of Alcalá, Campus Científico-Tecnológico, Crta. de Madrid-Barcelona, Alcalá de Henares 28871, Madrid, Spain.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>04</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>World J Psychiatry</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101610480</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2220-3206</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Antidepressants</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">History of neurosciences</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Imipramine</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Iproniazid</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Psychopharmacology</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Serendipity</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>Conflict-of-interest statement: Nothing to disclosed.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>6</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>2</Hour>
          <Minute>8</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35582332</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9048453</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5498/wjp.v12.i4.588</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cade JF. Lithium salts in the treatment of psychotic excitement. Med J Aust. 1949;2:349–352.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18142718</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>López-Muñoz F, Álamo C, Cuenca E.  La “Década de Oro” de la Psicofarmacología (1950-1960): Trascendencia histórica de la introducción clínica de los psicofármacos clásicos. Psiquiatria.COM 2000. [cited 10 July 2022]. Available from: http://www.psiquiatria.com/psiquiatria/revista/47/1800/?++interactivo .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>López-Muñoz F, Álamo C, Domino E.   History of Psychopharmacology, 4 Volumes. Arlington: NPP Books, 2014.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>López-Muñoz F, Álamo C.   History of the discovery of antidepressant drugs. In: López-Muñoz F, Srinivasan V, De Berardis D, Álamo C, Kato TA, editors. Melatonin, Neuroprotective Agents and Antidepressant Therapy. New Delhi: Springer International, 2016: 365-383.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>López-Muñoz F, Álamo C, Cuenca E.   Fármacos antidepresivos. In: López-Muñoz F, Álamo C, editors. Historia de la Neuropsicofarmacología. Una nueva aportación a la terapéutica farmacológica de los trastornos del Sistema Nervioso Central. Madrid: Ediciones Eurobook S.L. and Servicio de Publicaciones de la Universidad de Alcalá, 1998: 269-303.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rappa LR, Larose-Pierre M, Branch III E, Iglesias AJ, Norwood DA, Simon WA. Desperately seeking serendipity: The past, present, and future of antidepressant therapy. J Pharm Pract . 2001;14:560–569..</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>López-Muñoz F, Álamo C, Cuenca E.   Historia de la Psicofarmacología. In: Vallejo J, Leal C, directors. Tratado de Psiquiatría, 2ª Edition, Volume II. Barcelona: Ars Medica, 2010: 2031-2061.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Healy D.   The antidepressant era. Cambridge: Harvard University Press, 1997.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shorter E.   A history of psychiatry. From the era of the asylum to the age of Prozac. New York: Wiley &amp; Sons: 1997.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Connolly KR, Thase ME. Emerging drugs for major depressive disorder. Exp Opin Emerg Drugs . 2012;17:105–126.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baumeister AA, Hawkins MF.   El papel de la “serendipity” en la ontogenia de la moderna psicofarmacología. In: López-Muñoz F, Álamo C, editors. Historia de la Psicofarmacología. Madrid: Editorial Médica Panamericana, 2007: 1525-1538.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Robinson E. Psychopharmacology: From serendipitous discoveries to rationale design, but what next? Brain Neurosci Adv. 2018;2:2398212818812629.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7058199</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32166162</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>López-Muñoz F, Baumeister AA, Hawkins MF, Álamo C. El papel de la serendipia en el descubrimiento de los efectos clínicos de los psicofármacos: más allá del mito. Actas Esp Psiquiatr . 2012;40:34–42.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22344494</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cobbledick S. The information-seeking behavior of artists: exploratory interviews. Libr Quart . 1996;66:343–372.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Delgadillo R, Lynch BP. Future historians; their quest for information.  College Res Libr. 1999;60:245–259.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kubinyi H. Chance favors the prepared mind. From serendipity to rational drug design. J Receptor Sign Transduct Res . 1999;19:15–39.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hargrave-Thomas E, Yu B, Reynisson J. The Effect of serendipity in drug discovery and development. Chem New Zealand. 2012;4:17–20.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baumeister AA, Hawkins MF, López-Muñoz F. Toward standardized usage of the word serendipity in the historiography of psychopharmacology. J Hist Neurosci. 2010;19:253–270.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20628954</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>López-Muñoz F, Assion HJ, Álamo C, García-García P, Fangmann P. La introducción clínica de la iproniazida y la imipramina: medio siglo de terapéutica antidepresiva. An Psiquiatr. 2008;24:56–70.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fangmann P, Assion HJ, Juckel G, González CA, López-Muñoz F. Half a century of antidepressant drugs: on the clinical introduction of monoamine oxidase inhibitors, tricyclics, and tetracyclics. Part II: tricyclics and tetracyclics.  J Clin Psychopharmacol. 2008;28:1–4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18204333</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Delay J, Deniker P, Harl JM. Utilisation en thérapeutique d’une phenotiazine d’action centrale selective (4560 RP) Ann Méd Psychol. 1952;110:112–117.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kline NS. Use of Rauwolfia serpentina Benth. in neuropsychiatric conditions. Ann N Y Acad Sci. 1954;59:107–132.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13198043</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>López-Muñoz F, Álamo C, Cuenca E. Aspectos históricos del descubrimiento y de la introducción clínica de la clorpromazina: medio siglo de psicofarmacología. Frenia Rev Hist Psiquiatr . 2002;2:77–107.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>López-Muñoz F, Bhatara VS, Álamo C, Cuenca E. Aproximación histórica al descubrimiento de la reserpina y su introducción en la clínica psiquiátrica. Actas Esp Psiquiatr. 2004;32:387–395.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15529229</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>López-Muñoz F, Álamo C, Cuenca E, Shen WW, Clervoy P, Rubio G. History of the discovery and clinical introduction of chlorpromazine. Ann Clin Psychiatr . 2005;17:113–135.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kuhn R.   Geschichte der medikamentösen Depressionsbehandlung. In: Linde OK, editor. Pharmakopsychiatrie im Wandel der Zeit. Klingenmünster: Tilia-Verlag, 1988: 10-27.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schindler W, Häfliger F. Derivate des Iminodibenzyl. Helv Chim Acta. 1954;37:427.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pereira VS, Hiroaki-Sato VA. A brief history of antidepressant drug development: from tricyclics to beyond ketamine. Acta Neuropsychiatr. 2018;30:307–322.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29388517</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Filip KB.  40 Jahre Imipramin. Ein Antidepressivum hat die Welt verändert. [cited 10 July 2022]. Available from: http://www.Medizin-2000.de .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tansey T.   Las instituciones públicas y privadas y el avance de la psicofarmacología. In: López-Muñoz F, Álamo C, editors. Historia de la Psicofarmacología. Madrid: Editorial Médica Panamericana, 2007: 1165-1186.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ban TA.   Psicofarmacología: El nacimiento de una nueva disciplina. In: López-Muñoz F, Álamo C, editors. Historia de la Psicofarmacología. Madrid: Editorial Médica Panamericana, 2007: 577-597.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kuhn R. [Treatment of depressive states with an iminodibenzyl derivative (G 22355)] Schweiz Med Wochenschr. 1957;87:1135–1140.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13467194</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kuhn R. The treatment of depressive states with G 22355 (imipramine hydrochloride) Am J Psychiatry. 1958;115:459–464.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13583250</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kuhn R.   The imipramine story. In: Ayd FJ, Blackwell B, editors. Discoveries in Biological Psychiatry. Philadelphia: JB Lippincott Company, 1970: 205-217.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hofmann A.   LSD My Problem Child. Reflections on Sacred Drugs, Mysticism, and Science. Nueva York: McGraw Hill, 1980.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paioni R.   Chemie der Antidepressiva. In: Langer G, Heimann H, editors. Psychopharmaka, Grundlagen und Therapie. Viena and New York: Springer-Verlag, 1983: 59-65.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lassen N.   Die Geschichte der Thioxanthene. In: Linde OK, editor. Pharmakopsychiatrie im Wandel der Zeit. Klingenmünster: Tilia-Verlag, 1988: 170-183.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lebowitz BD, Harris HW. Drug discovery and mental illness. Dialogues Clin Neurosci. 2002;4:325–328.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3181695</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22033799</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singh H, Becker PM. Novel therapeutic usage of low-dose doxepin hydrochloride. Exp Opin Invest Drugs. 2007;16:1295–1305.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pöldinger W.   Die Geschichte des Doxepin. In: Linde OK, editor. Pharmakopsychiatrie im Wandel der Zeit. Klingenmünster: Tilia-Verlag, 1988: 266-270.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>López-Muñoz F, Alamo C. Monoaminergic neurotransmission: the history of the discovery of antidepressants from 1950s until today. Curr Pharm Des. 2009;15:1563–1586.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19442174</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Selikoff IJ, Robitzek EH, Ornstein GG. Treatment of pulmonary tuberculosis with hydrazine derivatives of isonicotinic acid. JAMA. 1952;150:973–980.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sandler M. Monoamine oxidase inhibitors in depression: history and mythology. J Psychopharmacol. 1990;4:136–139.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22282941</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pletscher A.   Iproniazid: prototype of antidepressant MAO-Inhibitors. In: Ban TA, Healy D, Shorter E, editors. Reflections on twentieth-century psychopharmacology. Budapest: Animula Publishing House, 2004: 174-177.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bosworth DM, Fielding JW, Demarest L, Bonaquist M. Toxicity to iproniazid (Marsilid) as it affects osseous tuberculosis. Quart Bull Sea View Hosp . 1955;16:134–140.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith JA. The use of the isopropyl derivative of isonicotinylhydrazine (marsilid) in the treatment of mental disease; a preliminary report. Am Pract Dig Treat. 1953;4:519–520.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13080562</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kamman GR, Freeman JG, Lucero RJ. The effect of 1-isonicotinyl-2-isopropyl hidrazide (IIH) on the behaviour of long-term mental patients. J Nerv Ment Dis. 1953;118:391–407.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13131066</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Castilla del Pino C. Síndrome hiperesténico. Alteraciones de la personalidad consecutivas a la terapéutica hidrazídica. Actas Luso-Esp Neurol Psiquiat. 1955;14:210–219.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Delay J, Laine B, Buisson JF. Anxiety and depressive states treated with isonicotinyl hydrazide (isoniazid) Arch Neurol Psychiatry. 1952;70:317–324.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Delay J, Lainé B, Buisson JF. Note concernant l’action de l’isonicotinyl-hydrazide utiliseé dans le traitement des états dépressifs. Ann Méd-Psych. 1952;2:689–692.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salzer HM, Lurie ML. Anxiety and depressive states treated with isonicotinyl hydrazid (isoniazid) Arch Neurol Psychiat. 1953;70:317–324.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13079356</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Healy D. The three faces of the antidepressants: a critical commentary on the clinical-economic context of diagnosis. J Nerv Ment Dis. 1999;187:174–180.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10086474</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Crane G. Iproniazid (Marsilid) phosphate, a therapeutic agent for mental disorders and debilitating diseases. Psychiat Res Rep. 1957;8:142–152.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ayd FJ Jr. A preliminary report on marsilid. Am J Psychiatry. 1957;114:459.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13470120</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chessin M, Dubnick B, Kramer ER, Scott CC. Modifications of pharmacology of reserpine and serotonin by iproniazid. Fed Proc. 1956;15:409.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Loomer HP, Saunders IC, Kline NS. A clinical and pharmacodynamic evaluation of iproniazid as a psychic energizer. Psychiat Res Rep Am Psychiat Assoc. 1958;8:129–141.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kline NS.   Monoamine Oxidase Inhibitors: an unfinished picaresque tale. En: Ayd FJ, Blackwell B, editors. Discoveries in Biological Psychiatry. Baltimore: Ayd Medical Communications, 1984: 194-204.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Loomer HP, Saunders IC, Kline NS. Iproniazid, an amine oxidase inhibitor, as an example of a psychic energizer. Congress Rec. 1957;5:1382–1390.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sneader W.   Drug discovery: the evolution of modern medicines. Chichester: John Wiley &amp; Sons: 1985.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zeller EA, Barsky J, Fouts JR, Kirchheimer WF, Van Orden LS. Influence of isonicotinic acid hydrazide (INH) and 1-isonicotinic-2-isopropyl-hydrazide (IIH) on bacterial and mammalian enzymes. Experientia . 1952;8:349.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jacobsen E. The early history of psychotherapeutic drugs. Psychopharmacology (Berl) 1986;89:138–144.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2873606</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Robinson DS, Nies A, Ravaris CL, Lamborn KR. The monoamine oxidase inhibitor, phenelzine, in the treatment of depressive-anxiety states. A controlled clinical trial. Arch Gen Psychiatry . 1973;29:407–413.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4579506</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maass AR, Nimmo MJ. A new inhibitor of serotonin metabolism. Nature. 1959;184(Suppl 8):547–548.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Freyhan FA. The modern treatment of depressive disorders. Am J Psychiatry. 1960;116:1057–1064.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13824958</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ban TA. Pharmacotherapy of depression: a historical analysis. J Neural Transm (Vienna) 2001;108:707–716.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11478422</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Entzeroth M, Ratty AK. Monoamine oxidase inhibitors. Revisiting a therapeutic principle.  Open J Depress. 2017;6:31–68.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Burger A, Yost WL. Arylcycloalkylamines. I. 2-phenylcyclopropylamine. J Am Chem Soc. 1948;70:2198–2201.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tedeschi RE, Tedeschi DH, Ames PL, Cook L, Mattis PA, Fellows EJ. Some neuropharmacological observations on tranylcypromine (SKF trans-385), a potent inhibitor of monoamine oxidase. Proc Soc Exp Biol Med. 1959;102:380–381.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13837261</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Atkinson RM, Ditman KS. Tranylcypromine: a review. Clin Pharmacol Ther. 1965;6:631–655.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5320592</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blackwell B. Hypertensive crisis due to monoamine-oxidase inhibitors. Lancet. 1963;2:849–850.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14056007</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blackwell B.  The process of discovery. In: Ayd FJ, Blackwell B, editors. Discoveries in Biological Psychiatry. Baltimore: Ayd Medical Communications, 1984: 11-29.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alvano SA, Zieher LM. An updated classification of antidepressants: A proposal to simplify treatment. Personal Med Psychiatr. 2020;19-20:100042.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ramachandraih CT, Subramanyam N, Bar KJ, Baker G, Yeragani VK. Antidepressants: From MAOIs to SSRIs and more. Indian J Psychiatr. 2011;53:180–182.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brogden RN, Heel RC, Speight TM, Avery GS. Nomifensine: A review of its pharmacological properties and therapeutic efficacy in depressive illness. Drugs. 1979;18:1–24.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">477572</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stahl SM. Mechanism of action of trazodone: a multifunctional drug. CNS Spectr. 2009;14:536–546.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20095366</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gorecki DK, Verbeeck RK.   Trazodone Hydrochloride. In: Forey K, editor. Profiles of Drug Substances, Excipients and Related Methodology, Vol. 16. Cambridge: Academic Press, 1987: 695.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Silvestrini B. Trazodone: from the mental pain to the “dys-stress” hypothesis of depression. Clin Neuropharmacol . 1989;12 (Suppl 1):S4–10.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2568177</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Van der Burg WJ, Bonta IL, Delobelle J, Ramon C, Vargaftig B. Novel type of substituted piperazine with high antiserotonin potency. J Med Chem. 1970;13:35–39.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5412112</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vargaftig BB, Coignet JL, de Vos CJ, Grijsen H, Bonta IL. Mianserin hydrochloride: peripheral and central effects in relation to antagonism against 5-hydroxytryptamine and tryptamine. Eur J Pharmacol. 1971;16:336–346.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5132561</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saxena PR, van Houwelingen P, Bonta IL. The effects of mianserin hydrochloride on the vascular responses evoked by 5-hydroxytryptamine and related vasoactive substances. Eur J Pharmacol. 1971;13:295–305.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4397032</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Ridder JJ. Mianserin: result of a decade of antidepressant research. Pharm Weekbl Sci Edition . 1982;4:139–145.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Itil TM, Polvan N, Hsu W. Clinical and EEG effects of GB-94, a “tetracyclic” antidepressant (EEG model in discovery of a new psychotropic drug) Curr Ther Res Clin Exp. 1972;14:395–413.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4625520</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Merton RK, Barber E.   The Travels and Adventures of Serendipity. Princeton: Princeton University Press, 2004.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roberts RM.   Accidental discoveries in Science. New York: John Wiley &amp; Sons, 1989.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Diaz de Chumaceiro CL, Yaber OGE Serendipity analogues: approval of modifications of the traditional case study for a psychotherapy research with music.   
Arts Psychother 1995; 22: 155-159.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cade JF.   The story of lithium. En: Ayd FJ, Blackwell B, editors. Discoveries in Biological Psychiatry. Philadelphia: Lippincott Company, 1970: 218-229.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>López-Muñoz F, Álamo C, Cuenca E. Cincuenta años de Psicofarmacología: John Cade y las sales de litio. Psiquiatr Biol. 1999;6:229–230.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>López-Muñoz F, Ramchandani D, Álamo C, Cuenca E. Aproximación histórica al descubrimiento del meprobamato y su introducción en psiquiatría: medio siglo de terapéutica ansiolítica. Arch Psiquiatr . 2005;68:103–122.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>López-Muñoz F, Alamo C, Juckel G, Assion HJ. Half a century of antidepressant drugs: on the clinical introduction of monoamine oxidase inhibitors, tricyclics, and tetracyclics. Part I: monoamine oxidase inhibitors. J Clin Psychopharmacol. 2007;27:555–559.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18004120</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>López-Muñoz F, Ucha-Udabe R, Alamo C. The history of barbiturates a century after their clinical introduction. Neuropsychiatr Dis Treat. 2005;1:329–343.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2424120</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18568113</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>López-Muñoz F, Álamo C, García-García P. The discovery of chlordiazepoxide and the clinical introduction of benzodiazepines: Half a century of anxiolytic drugs. J Anxiety Dis. 2011;25:554–562.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bhatara VS, López-Muñoz F, Álamo C. El papel de la medicina herbal ayurvédica en el descubrimiento de las propiedades neurolépticas de la reserpina: a propósito de la Rauwolfia serpentina y los orígenes de la era antipsicótica. An Psiquiatr. 2004;20:274–281.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>López-Muñoz F, Alamo C. The consolidation of neuroleptic therapy: Janssen, the discovery of haloperidol and its introduction into clinical practice. Brain Res Bull. 2009;79:130–141.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19186209</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Costa E, Garattini S, Valzelli S. Interactions between reserpine, chlorpromazine, and imipramine. Experientia . 1960;16:461–463.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13695781</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coppen A. The biochemistry of affective disorders. Br J Psychiatry. 1967;113:1237–1264.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4169954</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Glowinski J, Axelrod J. Inhibition of uptake of tritiated-noradrenaline in the intact rat brain by imipramine and structurally related compounds. Nature. 1964;204:1318–1319.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14254430</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carlsson A, Fuxe K, Ungerstedt U. The effect of imipramine on central 5-hydroxytryptamine neurons. J Pharm Pharmacol. 1968;20:150–151.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4384540</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pieper AA, Baraban JM. Moving Beyond Serendipity to Mechanism-Driven Psychiatric Therapeutics. Neurotherapeutics. 2017;14:533–536.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5509638</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28653277</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Good IJ.   The Scientist Speculates: An Anthology of Partly-Baked Ideas. New York: Basic Books, Inc., 1963.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
