<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35580482</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1542-233X</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>17</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Eye &amp; contact lens</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Eye Contact Lens</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Change in Risk Score and Behaviors of Soft Contact Lens Wearers After Targeted Patient Education.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/ICL.0000000000000900</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To determine if targeted education can influence the behaviors and scores of soft contact lens (SCL) wearers via the Contact Lens Risk Survey (CLRS).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This was a multicenter, prospective, case-control study. Cases were symptomatic red eye SCL wearers (age, 18-39 years), and controls were age , sex, and site matched. Participants completed the CLRS and were provided targeted patient education at three time points: baseline, one, and six months. Change in scores and behaviors were analyzed using the Wilcoxon signed rank test.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Forty-one cases and 71 controls were analyzed. The mean risk score (mean±SE) from baseline to follow-up improved (reduced) for all participants (-1.96±0.73; P=0.01), mostly driven by the improvement among cases (-2.55±1.32; P=0.05). Case subjects reported a decrease in frequency of wearing lenses while showering (-0.32±0.07; P&lt;0.0001), discarding lens solution (-0.13±0.06; P=0.03), and rinsing lenses with tap water (-0.19±0.08; P=0.02) after targeted education.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Targeted patient education can influence some behaviors of SCL wearers, especially those who experienced a red eye event. Further study is needed to determine how to improve other risk behaviors and whether these changes are sustained long term.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022 Contact Lens Association of Ophthalmologists.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lam</LastName>
            <ForeName>Dawn</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Southern California College of Optometry (D.L.), Marshall B. Ketchum University, Fullerton, CA; The Ohio State University College of Optometry (H.W., A.B.Z., G.L.M.), Columbus, OH; Harvard T.H. Chan School of Public Health (B.R.), Boston MA; Pacific University College of Optometry (B.K.), Forest Grove, OR; Nova Southeastern University College of Optometry (C.M.), Fort Lauderdale, FL; Department of Pediatrics (M.M.), University of Wisconsin-Madison, Madison WI; and College of Optometry (K.R.), University of Houston, Houston, TX.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wagner</LastName>
            <ForeName>Heidi</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zimmerman</LastName>
            <ForeName>Aaron B</ForeName>
            <Initials>AB</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Rosner</LastName>
            <ForeName>Bernard</ForeName>
            <Initials>B</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kinoshita</LastName>
            <ForeName>Beth</ForeName>
            <Initials>B</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mickles</LastName>
            <ForeName>Chandra</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mitchell</LastName>
            <ForeName>G Lynn</ForeName>
            <Initials>GL</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Moreno</LastName>
            <ForeName>Megan</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Richdale</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kathryn</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Eye Contact Lens</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101160941</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1542-2321</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <CoiStatement>There are no conflicts of interest for any of the authors that could have influenced the results of this work.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>17</Day>
          <Hour>18</Hour>
          <Minute>23</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35580482</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ICL.0000000000000900</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">00140068-990000000-00019</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cope JR, Collier SA, Rao MM, et al. Contact lens wearer demographics and risk behaviors for contact lens-related eye infections—United States, 2014. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep 2015;64:865–870.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cope J, Collier S, Nethercut H, et al. Risk behaviors for contact lens-related eye infections among adults and adolescents—United States, 2016. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep 2017;66:841–845.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stapleton F, Keay L, Edwards K, et al. The incidence of contact lens-related microbial keratitis in Australia. Ophthalmology 2008;115:1655–1662.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith AF, Orsborn G. Estimating the annual economic burden of illness caused by contact lens-associated corneal infiltrative events in the United States. Eye Contact Lens 2012;38:164–170.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Konne NM, Collier SA, Spangler J, et al. Healthy contact lens behaviors communicated by eye care providers and recalled by patients—United States, 2018. MMWR Morb Mortal Wkly Rep 2019;68:693–697.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lam DY, Kinoshita BT, Jansen ME, et al. Contact lens assessment in youth: Methods and baseline findings. Optom Vis Sci 2011;88:708–715.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wagner H, Fink BA, Zadnik K. Sex- and gender-based differences in healthy and diseased eyes. Optometry 2008;79:636–652.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chalmers RL, Wagner H, Mitchell GL, et al. Age and other risk factors for corneal infiltrative and inflammatory events in young soft contact lens wearers from the Contact Lens Assessment in Youth (CLAY) study. Invest Ophthalmol Vis Sci 2011;52:6690–6696.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jansen ME, Chalmers R, Mitchell GL, et al. Characterization of patients who report compliant and non-compliant overnight wear of soft contact lenses. Cont Lens Anterior Eye 2011;34:229–235.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Richdale K, Lam DY, Wagner H, et al. Case-control pilot study of soft contact lens wearers with corneal infiltrative events and healthy controls. Invest Ophthalmol Vis Sci 2016;57:47–55.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zimmerman AB, Richdale K, Mitchell GL, et al. Water exposure is a common risk behavior among soft and gas-permeable contact lens wearers. Cornea 2017;36:995–1001.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wagner H, Chalmers RL, Mitchell GL, et al. Risk factors for interruption to soft contact lens wear in children and young adults. Optom Vis Sci 2011;88:973–980.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wagner H, Richdale K, Mitchell GL, et al. Age, behavior, environment, and health factors in the soft contact lens risk survey. Optom Vis Sci 2014;91:252–261.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sorbara L, Zimmerman AB, Mitchell GL, et al. Multicenter testing of a risk assessment survey for soft contact lens wearers with adverse events: A contact lens assessment in youth study. Eye Contact Lens 2018;44:21–28.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mitchell GL, Richdale K, Lam D, et al. Development of a contact Lens risk survey. Cont Lens Anterior Eye 2020;44:101383.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Keay L, Stapleton F, Schein O. Epidemiology of contact lens-related inflammation and microbial keratitis: A 20-year perspective. Eye Contact Lens 2007;33:346–353. discussion 362–363.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Szczotka-Flynn L, Debanne SM, Cheruvu VK, et al. Predictive factors for corneal infiltrates with continuous wear of silicone hydrogel contact lenses. Arch Ophthalmol 2007;125:488–492.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dart JK, Radford CF, Minassian D, et al. Risk factors for microbial keratitis with contemporary contact lenses: A case-control study. Prospective case control series. Ophthalmology 2008;115:1647–1654.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McMonnies CW. Hand hygiene prior to contact lens handling is problematical. Cont Lens Anterior Eye 2012;35:65–70.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mickles CV, Kinoshita BT, Lam D, et al. The contact Lens risk survey to assess risk of soft contact lens-related inflammatory events. Cont Lens Anterior Eye 2020;44:35–41.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dart JK, Radford CF, Minassian D, et al. Risk factors for microbial keratitis with contemporary contact lenses: A case-control study. Ophthalmology 2008;115:1647–1654, 1654.e1–3.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Szczotka-Flynn L, Jiang Y, Raghupathy S, et al. Corneal inflammatory events with daily silicone hydrogel lens wear. Optom Vis Sci 2014;91:3–12.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu YT, Willcox M, Zhu H, et al. Contact lens hygiene compliance and lens case contamination: A review. Cont Lens Anterior Eye 2015;38:307–316.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kilvington S, Gray T, Dart J, et al. Acanthamoeba keratitis: The role of domestic tap water contamination in the United Kingdom. Invest Ophthalmol Vis Sci 2004;45:165–169.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Joslin CE, Tu EY, McMahon TT, et al. Epidemiological characteristics of a Chicago-area Acanthamoeba keratitis outbreak. Am J Ophthalmol 2006;142:212–217.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yoder JS, Verani J, Heidman N, et al. Acanthamoeba keratitis: The persistence of cases following a multistate outbreak. Ophthalmic Epidemiol 2012;19:221–225.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu Y, Carnt N, Stapleton F. Contact lens user profile, attitudes and level of compliance to lens care. Cont Lens Anterior Eye 2010;33:183–188.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Joslin CE, Tu EY, Shoff ME, et al. The association of contact lens solution use and Acanthamoeba keratitis. Am J Ophthalmol 2007;144:169–180.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hickson-Curran S, Chalmers RL, Riley C. Patient attitudes and behavior regarding hygiene and replacement of soft contact lenses and storage cases. Cont Lens Anterior Eye 2011;34:207–215.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carnt N, Keay L, Willcox M, et al. Higher risk taking propensity of contact lens wearers is associated with less compliance. Cont Lens Anterior Eye 2011;34:202–206.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wickman ME, Anderson NL, Greenberg CS. The adolescent perception of invincibility and its influence on teen acceptance of health promotion strategies. J Pediatr Nurs 2008;23:460–468.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morgan PB, Woods CA, Tranoudis IG, et al. International contact lens prescribing in 2020. Contact Lens Spectr 2021;36:30–43.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ebrahimabadi M, Rezaei K, Moini A, et al. Infographics or video; which one is more effective in asthmatic patients' health? A randomized clinical trial. J Asthma 2019;56:1306–1313.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krasnoryadtseva A, Derksen C, Dalbeth N, et al. Not every picture tells a story: A content analysis of visual images in patient educational resources about gout. J Rheumatol 2020;47:1815–1821.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wexler DJ, Beauharnais CC, Regan S, et al. Impact of inpatient diabetes management, education, and improved discharge transition on glycemic control 12 months after discharge. Diabetes Res Clin Pract 2012;98:249–256.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kheir N, Awaisu A, Radoui A, et al. Development and evaluation of pictograms on medication labels for patients with limited literacy skills in a culturally diverse multiethnic population. Res Soc Adm Pharm 2014;10:720–730.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Davis TC, Bocchini JA Jr, Fredrickson D, et al. Parent comprehension of polio vaccine information pamphlets. Pediatrics 1996;97:804–810.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dumbleton K, Richter D, Woods C, et al. Compliance with contact lens replacement in Canada and the United States. Optom Vis Sci 2010;87:131–139.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McMonnies CW. Improving contact lens compliance by explaining the benefits of compliant procedures. Cont Lens Anterior Eye 2011;34:249–252.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
