<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35583512</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1538-4667</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>18</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Ear and hearing</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Ear Hear</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Low Frequency Air-Bone Gap in Meniere's Disease: Relationship With Magnetic Resonance Imaging Features of Endolymphatic Hydrops.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/AUD.0000000000001231</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The appearance of low-frequency air-bone gaps (LFABGs) in Meniere's disease (MD) is a recognized but relatively unexplored phenomenon. Two theories have been proposed to explain their etiology: increased perilymphatic pressure resulting in either reduced stapedial mobility or dampened transmission of acoustic energy, and direct contact between the dilated saccule and the stapes footplate. The aim of this study was to evaluate these two hypotheses by comparing delayed postgadolinium magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) features of two groups of patients with unilateral definite MD, those with and without LFABGs.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">This retrospective case-control study was conducted at a tertiary otolaryngology unit in the United Kingdom. The study included 35 patients who satisfied the 2015 Barany criteria for unilateral definite MD. The cohort was divided into two groups, those with LFABGs (LFABG+ group) and those without (LFABG- group), according to the pure-tone audiometry performed within 6 months of MRI. Alternative potential causes for the LFABGs were excluded on the basis of otologic history, otoscopy, tympanometry, and/or imaging. Using a 4-hr delayed postgadolinium 3-dimensional fluid-attenuated inversion recovery sequence, two observers evaluated the severity of cochlear and vestibular endolymphatic hydrops (EH) and the presence of vestibular endolymphatic space contacting the oval window (VESCO). The air and bone conduction thresholds, ABGs and MRI features were compared between the LFABG+ and LFABG- groups. Where any of the variables were found to be significantly associated with the presence of ABGs, further analysis was performed to determine whether or not they were independent predictors. Continuous variables were compared using the independent t test if normally distributed, and the Mann-Whitney U test or Kruskall-Wallis test if not normally distributed. Categorical variables were compared with Pearson's Chi-squared test or Fishers/Fisher-Freeman-Halton exact tests.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">There were 10 patients in the LFABG+ group (28.6%) and 25 patients in the LFABG- group (71.4%). The mean ABGs in the symptomatic ear at 500 Hz, 1 kHz, and 2 kHz were 15.1 dB ± 6.4, 10.5 dB ± 9.0, and 4.0 dB ± 7.7, respectively, in the LFABG+ group and 2.0 ± 5.8, 2.4 ± 4.4, and -0.8 ± 4.7 dB in the LFABG- group. The differences in ABGs between the two groups were statistically significant at all three test frequencies (p &lt; 0.001 at 500 Hz, p = 0.007 at 1 kHz, and p = 0.041 at 2 kHz). The presence of ABGs was significantly associated with both the grade of vestibular EH (p = 0.049) and VESCO (p = 0.009). Further analysis showed a statistically significant association between the grade of vestibular EH and VESCO (p = 0.007), and only VESCO was an independent variable associated with the presence of LFABGs (p = 0.045).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">The study findings add to the existing body of evidence that LFABGs are a true audiological finding in MD and allow us to propose a mechanism. Analysis of delayed gadolinium-enhanced MRI suggests that direct contact between the distended saccule and the inner surface of the stapes footplate is the more likely underlying pathophysiological mechanism for this audiometric phenomenon.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022 The Authors. Ear &amp; Hearing is published on behalf of the American Auditory Society, by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Pai</LastName>
            <ForeName>Irumee</ForeName>
            <Initials>I</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Otolaryngology, Guy's and St. Thomas' Hospitals, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Biomedical Engineering &amp; Imaging Sciences Clinical Academic Group, King's College London, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>These authors contributed equally to the study design, data collection and analysis, and preparation and review of the final manuscript.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Connor</LastName>
            <ForeName>Steve</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Biomedical Engineering &amp; Imaging Sciences Clinical Academic Group, King's College London, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Radiology, Guy's and St. Thomas'Hospitals, London, United Kingdom.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>These authors contributed equally to the study design, data collection and analysis, and preparation and review of the final manuscript.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Ear Hear</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8005585</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0196-0202</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>11</Hour>
          <Minute>30</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35583512</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/AUD.0000000000001231</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">00003446-990000000-00014</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Andrews J. C., Strelioff D. (1995). Modulation of inner ear pressure in experimental endolymphatic hydrops. Otolaryngol Head Neck Surg, 112, 78–83.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Attyé A., Eliezer M., Boudiaf N., Tropres I., Chechin D., Schmerber S., Dumas G., Krainik A. (2017). MRI of endolymphatic hydrops in patients with Meniere’s disease: A case-controlled study with a simplified classification based on saccular morphology. Eur Radiol, 27, 3138–3146.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baráth K., Schuknecht B., Naldi A. M., Schrepfer T., Bockisch C. J., Hegemann S. C. (2014). Detection and grading of endolymphatic hydrops in Menière disease using MR imaging. AJNR Am J Neuroradiol, 35, 1387–1392.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>British Society of Audiology. (2018a). Recommended procedure: pure-tone air-conduction and bone-conduction threshold audiometry with and without masking. https://www.thebsa.org.uk/resources/</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>British Society of Audiology. (2018b). Recommended procedure: tympanometry. https://www.thebsa.org.uk/resources/</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bykowski J., Harris J. P., Miller M., Du J., Mafee M. F. (2015). Intratympanic contrast in the evaluation of menière disease: Understanding the limits. AJNR Am J Neuroradiol, 36, 1326–1332.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coles R. R., Lutman M. E., Robinson D. W. (1991). The limited accuracy of bone-conduction audiometry: Its significance in medicolegal assessments. J Laryngol Otol, 105, 518–521.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Conte G., Lo Russo F. M., Calloni S. F., Sina C., Barozzi S., Di Berardino F., Scola E., Palumbo G., Zanetti D., Triulzi F. M. (2018a). MR imaging of endolymphatic hydrops in Ménière’s disease: Not all that glitters is gold. Acta Otorhinolaryngol Ital, 38, 369–376.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Conte G., Caschera L., Calloni S., Barozzi S., Di Berardino F., Zanetti D., Scuffi C., Scola E., Sina C., Triulzi F. (2018b). MR imaging in Menière disease: Is the contact between the vestibular endolymphatic space and the oval window a reliable biomarker? AJNR Am J Neuroradiol, 39, 2114–2119.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Counter S. A., Bjelke B., Klason T., Chen Z., Borg E. (1999). Magnetic resonance imaging of the cochlea, spiral ganglia and eighth nerve of the guinea pig. Neuroreport, 10, 473–479.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fraysse B. G., Alonso A., House W. F. (1980). Menière’s disease and endolymphatic hydrops: Clinical-histopathological correlations. Ann Otol Rhinol Laryngol Suppl, 89(6 Pt 3), 2–22.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Holmgren L. (1964). Hearing tests in Menière’s disease. Acta OtoLaryngol Suppl, 192, 115–120.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kobayashi M., Yoshida T., Sugimoto S., Shimono M., Teranishi M., Naganawa S., Sone M. (2020). Effects of endolymphatic hydrops on acoustic energy absorbance. Acta Otolaryngol, 140, 626–631.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee H. J., Jeon J. H., Park S., Kim B. G., Lee W. S., Kim S. H. (2014). Prevalence and clinical significance of spontaneous low-frequency air-bone gaps in Ménière’s disease. Otol Neurotol, 35, 489–494.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lightfoot G. R. (2000). Audiometer calibration: Interpreting and applying the standards. Br J Audiol, 34, 311–316.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lopez-Escamez J. A., Attyé A. (2019). Systematic review of magnetic resonance imaging for diagnosis of Meniere disease. J Vestib Res, 29, 121–129.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lopez-Escamez J. A., Carey J., Chung W. H., Goebel J. A., Magnusson M., Mandalà M., Newman-Toker D. E., Strupp M., Suzuki M., Trabalzini F., Bisdorff A.; Classification Committee of the Barany Society; Japan Society for Equilibrium Research; European Academy of Otology and Neurotology (EAONO); Equilibrium Committee of the American Academy of Otolaryngology-Head and Neck Surgery (AAO-HNS); Korean Balance Society. (2015). Diagnostic criteria for Menière’s disease. J Vestib Res, 25, 1–7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muchnik C., Hildesheimer M., Rubinstein M., Arenberg I. K. (1989). Low frequency air-bone gap in Menière’s disease without middle ear pathology. A preliminary report. Am J Otol, 10, 1–4.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Naganawa S., Nakashima T. (2014). Visualization of endolymphatic hydrops with MR imaging in patients with Ménière’s disease and related pathologies: Current status of its methods and clinical significance. Jpn J Radiol, 32, 191–204.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Naganawa S., Satake H., Kawamura M., Fukatsu H., Sone M., Nakashima T. (2008a). Separate visualization of endolymphatic space, perilymphatic space and bone by a single pulse sequence; 3D-inversion recovery imaging utilizing real reconstruction after intratympanic Gd-DTPA administration at 3 Tesla. Eur Radiol, 18, 920–924.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Naganawa S., Sugiura M., Kawamura M., Fukatsu H., Sone M., Nakashima T. (2008b). Imaging of endolymphatic and perilymphatic fluid at 3T after intratympanic administration of gadolinium-diethylene-triamine pentaacetic acid. AJNR Am J Neuroradiol, 29, 724–726.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Naganawa S., Yamazaki M., Kawai H., Bokura K., Sone M., Nakashima T. (2010). Visualization of endolymphatic hydrops in Ménière’s disease with single-dose intravenous gadolinium-based contrast media using heavily T(2)-weighted 3D-FLAIR. Magn Reson Med Sci, 9, 237–242.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Naganawa S., Kawai H., Taoka T., Sone M. (2019). Improved 3D-real inversion recovery: A robust imaging technique for endolymphatic hydrops after intravenous administration of gadolinium. Magn Reson Med Sci, 18, 105–108.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nakashima T., Naganawa S., Sugiura M., Teranishi M., Sone M., Hayashi H., Nakata S., Katayama N., Ishida I. M. (2007). Visualization of endolymphatic hydrops in patients with Meniere’s disease. Laryngoscope, 117, 415–420.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nakashima T., Naganawa S., Katayama N., Teranishi M., Nakata S., Sugiura M., Sone M., Kasai S., Yoshioka M., Yamamoto M. (2009a). Clinical significance of endolymphatic imaging after intratympanic gadolinium injection. Acta Otolaryngol Suppl, 560, 9–14.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nakashima T., Naganawa S., Pyykko I., Gibson W. P., Sone M., Nakata S., Teranishi M. (2009b). Grading of endolymphatic hydrops using magnetic resonance imaging. Acta Otolaryngol Suppl, 560, 5–8.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Niyazov D. M., Andrews J. C., Strelioff D., Sinha S., Lufkin R. (2001). Diagnosis of endolymphatic hydrops in vivo with magnetic resonance imaging. Otol Neurotol, 22, 813–817.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Okuno T., &amp; Sando I., (1987). Localization, frequency, and severity of endolymphatic hydrops and the pathology of the labyrinthine membrane in Menière's disease. Ann Otol Rhinol Laryngol, 96, 438–445.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shipton M. S., John A. J., Robinson D. W. (1980). Air-radiated sound from bone vibration transducers and its implications for bone conduction audiometry. Br J Audiol, 14, 86–99.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sone M., Naganawa S., Teranishi M., Nakata S., Katayama N., Nakashima T. (2010). Changes in endolymphatic hydrops in a patient with Meniere’s disease observed using magnetic resonance imaging. Auris Nasus Larynx, 37, 220–222.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sugimoto S., Yoshida T., Teranishi M., Okazaki Y., Naganawa S., Sone M. (2018). The relationship between endolymphatic hydrops in the vestibule and low-frequency air-bone gaps. Laryngoscope, 128, 1658–1662.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yetişer S., Kertmen M. (2007). Cochlear conductive hearing loss in patients with Meniere’s disease. Kulak Burun Bogaz Ihtis Derg, 17, 18–21.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
