<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35583023</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">0040-5930</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>79</Volume>
            <Issue>5</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Therapeutische Umschau. Revue therapeutique</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Ther Umsch</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>[Large Vessel Vasculitides: Giant Cell Arteritis and Takayasu Arteritis - Similarities and Differences].</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>221</StartPage>
          <EndPage>228</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>221-228</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1024/0040-5930/a001353</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Large Vessel Vasculitides: Giant Cell Arteritis and Takayasu Arteritis - Similarities and Differences <b>Abstract.</b> According to the Chapel Hill Consensus Conference Nomenclature of 2012, giant cell arteritis (GCA) and Takayasu arteritis (TAK) belong to the idiopathic large vessel vasculitides. While GCA is a typical disease of the elderly, TAK begins in adolescence and young adulthood, sometimes even in childhood. In both diseases, immune-mediated granulomatous vascular wall inflammation of the aorta and its major branches leads to the formation of stenoses, occlusions, and aneurysms. The reduced blood flow to downstream organs causes the characteristic symptoms such as visual disturbance, ischemic muscle pain, and dysesthesias. Typically, a pronounced systemic reaction with constitutional symptoms such as temperature elevation, fatigue, and weight loss is present. If GCA or TAK is suspected, vasculitis should always be confirmed by imaging (ultrasound, MRI, or PET-CT) and/or histology. In addition to induction therapy with glucocorticoids, steroid-sparing immunosuppressants such as tocilizumab and infliximab have become increasingly important in recent years, prompting the EULAR to update its recommendations for the management of large-vessel vasculitis in 2018.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gloor</LastName>
            <ForeName>Andrea Daniela</ForeName>
            <Initials>AD</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Universitätsklinik für Allgemein Innere Medizin, Inselspital Bern.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Christ</LastName>
            <ForeName>Lisa</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Universitätsklinik für Rheumatologie und Immunologie, Inselspital Bern.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>ger</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <VernacularTitle>Grossgefässvaskulitiden.</VernacularTitle>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>Switzerland</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Ther Umsch</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0407224</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0040-5930</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000293" MajorTopicYN="N">Adolescent</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000368" MajorTopicYN="N">Aged</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013700" MajorTopicYN="Y">Giant Cell Arteritis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008279" MajorTopicYN="N">Magnetic Resonance Imaging</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000072078" MajorTopicYN="N">Positron Emission Tomography Computed Tomography</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013625" MajorTopicYN="Y">Takayasu Arteritis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000188" MajorTopicYN="N">drug therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014463" MajorTopicYN="N">Ultrasonography</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D055815" MajorTopicYN="N">Young Adult</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="ger">
        <AbstractText><b>Zusammenfassung.</b> Gemäss der Chapel-Hill-Konsensus-Konferenz-Nomenklatur von 2012 zählen die Riesenzellarteriitis (RZA) und die Takayasu-Arteriitis (TAK) zu den idiopathischen Grossgefässvaskulitiden. Während die RZA eine typische Erkrankung des älteren Menschen ist, beginnt die TAK im Adoleszenten- und jungen Erwachsenenalter, teilweise schon in der Kindheit. Bei beiden Erkrankungen kommt es durch eine immunvermittelte granulomatöse Gefässwandentzündung der Aorta und ihrer Hauptäste zur Ausbildung von Stenosen, Verschlüssen und Aneurysmen. Die Minderdurchblutung nachgeschalteter Organe führt zu den typischen Beschwerden wie Visusstörungen, ischämischen Muskelschmerzen und Dysästhesien. Typischerweise kommt es neben den lokalen Veränderungen zu einer ausgeprägten Systemreaktion mit konstitutionellen Symptomen wie Temperaturerhöhung, Abgeschlagenheit und Gewichtsverlust. Wird eine RZA oder TAK vermutet, sollte diese stets mittels bildgebender Verfahren (Ultraschall, MRI oder PET-CT) und/oder Histologie bestätigt werden. Neben der Induktionstherapie mit Glukokortikoiden haben steroidsparende Immunsuppressiva wie Tocilizumab und Infliximab in den letzten Jahren zunehmend an Bedeutung gewonnen, sodass die EULAR 2018 ihre Empfehlungen zum Management der Grossgefässvaskulitiden aktualisierten.</AbstractText>
      </OtherAbstract>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>33</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35583023</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1024/0040-5930/a001353</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
