<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM" IndexingMethod="Automated">
      <PMID Version="1">35583020</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">0040-5930</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>79</Volume>
            <Issue>5</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Therapeutische Umschau. Revue therapeutique</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Ther Umsch</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>[Cutaneous Vasculitides - Clinical Manifestations, Diagnosis, and Aetiology].</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>238</StartPage>
          <EndPage>246</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>238-246</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1024/0040-5930/a001356</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Cutaneous Vasculitides - Clinical Manifestations, Diagnosis, and Aetiology <b>Abstract.</b> Vasculitides are a heterogeneous group of diseases that are classified differently, for example according to the size of the affected vessel or according to primary and secondary causes. The skin is most frequently affected; it can be involved both as single organ vasculitis and in the context of systemic forms. The combination of skin lesions, their anatomical location and information on the time course provide clues for a differential diagnosis. Purpura, blisters, necrosis, ulcerations and possibly a livedo are characteristic manifestations. Constitutional symptoms such as weight loss, exhaustion, fever, and arthralgias are indicative of a systemic form. It is important to differentiate vasculitides from vasculopathies, which can manifest similarly. The most common form in adults is cutaneous leukocytoclastic angiitis, in children IgA vasculitis (Schönlein-Henoch purpura). Various triggers are possible: infections, drugs, autoimmune diseases, and malignancies, whereby up to 50% remain etiologically unexplained. Skin biopsies and laboratory parameters, if necessary supplemented with imaging, are important steps in the clarification process. Treatment is primarily directed at the elimination of a possible triggering cause. Idiopathic cutaneous leukocytoclastic angiitis usually resolves spontaneously; treatment is symptomatic. In more severe cases, topical corticosteroids or calcineurin antagonists are primarily used. In case of therapeutic resistance, systemic immunosuppressants are recommended.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bircher</LastName>
            <ForeName>Andreas J</ForeName>
            <Initials>AJ</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Facoltà di scienze biomediche, Università della Svizzera italiana, Lugano.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Allergologie, Dermatologische Klinik, Universitätsspital Basel.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Pelloni</LastName>
            <ForeName>Lorenzo</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Servizio di Dermatologia EOC, Ospedale San Giovanni, Bellinzona.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Terrani</LastName>
            <ForeName>Isabella</ForeName>
            <Initials>I</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Servizio di Dermatologia EOC, Ospedale Regionale di Lugano.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Spoerl</LastName>
            <ForeName>David</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Service d'immunologie et d'allergologie, Département de médecine, Hôpitaux Universitaires de Genève.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Beltraminelli</LastName>
            <ForeName>Helmut</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Servizio di Dermatologia EOC, Ospedale San Giovanni, Bellinzona.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Servizio di Dermatopatologia, Istituto Cantonale di Patologia EOC, Locarno.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>ger</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <VernacularTitle>Kutane Vaskulitiden.</VernacularTitle>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>Switzerland</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Ther Umsch</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0407224</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0040-5930</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000328" MajorTopicYN="N">Adult</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D002648" MajorTopicYN="N">Child</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D003937" MajorTopicYN="N">Diagnosis, Differential</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006801" MajorTopicYN="N">Humans</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D011695" MajorTopicYN="Y">IgA Vasculitis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D012867" MajorTopicYN="N">Skin</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000473" MajorTopicYN="N">pathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017445" MajorTopicYN="Y">Skin Diseases, Vascular</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D014657" MajorTopicYN="Y">Vasculitis</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D018366" MajorTopicYN="Y">Vasculitis, Leukocytoclastic, Cutaneous</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000175" MajorTopicYN="N">diagnosis</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000209" MajorTopicYN="N">etiology</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000628" MajorTopicYN="N">therapy</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
      <OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="ger">
        <AbstractText><b>Zusammenfassung.</b> Vaskulitiden sind eine heterogene Gruppe von Erkrankungen, die unterschiedlich klassifiziert werden, zum Beispiel nach der Grösse des betroffenen Gefässes oder nach primärer und sekundärer Ätiologie. Die Haut ist am häufigsten betroffen ist, sie kann sowohl isoliert als auch im Rahmen von systemischen Formen involviert sein. Die Kombination der Hautläsionen, deren anatomischer Lokalisation und Informationen zum Zeitablauf geben Hinweise für die Differenzialdiagnose. Purpura, Blasen, Nekrosen, Ulzerationen und allenfalls eine Livedo sind charakteristische Manifestationen. Konstitutionelle Symptome wie Gewichtsverlust, Abgeschlagenheit, Fieber und Arthralgien sind hinweisend auf eine systemische Form. Wichtig ist die differenzialdiagnostische Abgrenzung von Vaskulopathien, die sich ähnlich manifestieren können. Am häufigsten beim Erwachsenen ist die kutane leukozytoklastische Angiitis, beim Kind die IgA-Vaskulitis (Purpura Schönlein-Henoch). Bei diesen kommen diverse Auslöser in Frage: Infektionen, Medikamente, Autoimmunerkrankungen und Malignome, wobei bis zu 50% ätiologisch ungeklärt bleiben. Hautbiopsien und Laborparameter, allenfalls ergänzt durch Bildgebung, sind wichtige Schritte im Abklärungsprozedere. Die Behandlung richtet sich primär auf die Elimination einer möglichen Ursache. Die idiopathische kutane Form bildet sich meistens spontan zurück, die Behandlung ist symptomatisch. Bei schwererem Verlauf werden primär topisch Kortikosteroide oder Calcineurinantagonisten angewandt. Bei Therapieresistenz werden systemische Immunsuppressiva eingesetzt.</AbstractText>
      </OtherAbstract>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>5</Hour>
          <Minute>33</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35583020</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1024/0040-5930/a001356</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
