<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35587528</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1872-6623</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>19</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Pain</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Pain</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Altered serum bile acid profile in fibromyalgia is associated with specific gut microbiome changes and symptom severity.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/j.pain.0000000000002694</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Alterations in the composition and function of the gut microbiome in women with fibromyalgia have recently been demonstrated, including changes in the relative abundance of certain bile acid metabolizing bacteria. Bile acids can affect multiple physiological processes, including visceral pain, but have yet to be explored for association to the fibromyalgia gut microbiome. In this study, 16S rRNA sequencing and targeted metabolomic approaches were used to characterize the gut microbiome and circulating bile acids in a cohort of 42 women with fibromyalgia and 42 healthy controls. Alterations in the relative abundance of several bacterial species known to metabolize bile acids were observed in women with fibromyalgia, accompanied by significant alterations in the serum concentration of secondary bile acids, including a marked depletion of α-muricholic acid. Statistical learning algorithms could accurately detect individuals with fibromyalgia using the concentration of these serum bile acids. Serum α-muricholic acid was highly correlated with symptom severity, including pain intensity and fatigue. Taken together, these findings suggest serum bile acid alterations are implicated in nociplastic pain. The changes observed in the composition of the gut microbiota and the concentration of circulating secondary bile acids seem congruent with the phenotype of increased nociception, and are quantitatively correlated with symptom severity.This is a first demonstration of circulating bile acid alteration in individuals with fibromyalgia, potentially secondary to upstream gut microbiome alterations. If corroborated in independent studies, these observations may allow for the development of molecular diagnostic aids for fibromyalgia as well as mechanistic insights into the syndrome.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022 International Association for the Study of Pain.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Minerbi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Amir</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4889-0105</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Alan Edwards Pain Management Unit, McGill University Health Centre, Montreal, Quebec, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute for Pain Medicine, Rambam Health Campus, Haifa, Israel.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Technion Israel Institute of Technology, Haifa, Israel.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gonzalez</LastName>
            <ForeName>Emmanuel</ForeName>
            <Initials>E</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>McGill University and Genome Quebec Innovation Centre, McGill University, Montreal, Quebec, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Canadian Centre for Computational Genomics, McGill University and Genome Quebec Innovation Centre, Montreal, Quebec, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Brereton</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nicholas</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2434-3249</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institut de recherche en biologie végétale, University of Montreal, Montreal, QC H1X 2B2, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Fitzcharles</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mary-Ann</ForeName>
            <Initials>MA</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-1091-3175</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Alan Edwards Pain Management Unit, McGill University Health Centre, Montreal, Quebec, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Rheumatology, McGill University Health Centre, Quebec, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chevalier</LastName>
            <ForeName>Stéphanie</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-8497-1570</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Human Nutrition, McGill University, 21111 Lakeshore Rd, Ste-Anne-de-Bellevue, QC H9X 3V9, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Research Institute of the McGill University Health Centre, 1001 Décarie Blvd, Montreal, QC H4A 3J1, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medicine, McGill University, 845 Sherbrooke St. W, Montreal, QC H3A 0G4, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Shir</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yoram</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-2049-3629</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Alan Edwards Pain Management Unit, McGill University Health Centre, Montreal, Quebec, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Pain</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>7508686</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0304-3959</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <CoiStatement>Conflict of interest statement: The authors have no conflict of interest to declare.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>15</Hour>
          <Minute>2</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35587528</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/j.pain.0000000000002694</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">00006396-990000000-00100</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
