<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35584637</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>18</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1646-0758</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>18</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Acta medica portuguesa</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Acta Med Port</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Breast Implant-Associated Anaplastic Large Cell Lymphoma: Two Distinct Clinical Presentations.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.20344/amp.16578</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Breast implant-associated anaplastic large cell lymphoma (BIA-ALCL) is a rare CD30 positive T cell lymphoma whose incidence has recently increased. Until 2020, 733 cases of BIA-ALCL and 36 deaths have been reported around the world, with only one confirmed case in Portugal. The authors describe two clinical cases of BIA-ALCL after breast cancer reconstruction using macrotextured implants. Case 1: A 45-year-old patient, who presented with a typical late-onset seroma five years after breast reconstruction and underwent capsulectomy, confirming localized disease to the capsule. Case 2: A 43-year-old patient presented with an atypical presentation of pleural effusion and tumor mass, 14 years after reconstruction. She underwent implant removal and chemotherapy, due to metastatic disease. These clinical cases illustrate two very distinct clinical presentations of BIA-ALCL. Early diagnosis of this entity allows for effective treatment of the disease, which should be approached in a multidisciplinary setting.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Miranda</LastName>
            <ForeName>Pedro</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>General Surgery Service. Beatriz Ângelo Hospital. Lisbon. Portugal.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Moita</LastName>
            <ForeName>Filipa</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Hematology Service. Portuguese Oncology Institute Francisco Gentil. Lisbon. Portugal.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Vargas Moniz</LastName>
            <ForeName>João</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Breast Unit. General Surgery Service. Portuguese Oncology Institute Francisco Gentil. Lisbon. Portugal.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Rodrigues Dos Santos</LastName>
            <ForeName>Catarina</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Breast Clinic. General Surgery Service. Portuguese Oncology Institute Francisco Gentil. Lisbon. Portugal.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>Portugal</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Acta Med Port</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>7906803</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0870-399X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <OtherAbstract Type="Publisher" Language="por">
        <AbstractText>O linfoma anaplásico de grandes células associado aos implantes mamários é um linfoma T CD30 positivo raro, cuja incidência tem aumentado recentemente. Até 2020, estavam registados 733 casos de BIA-ALCL e 36 mortes, em todo o mundo e apenas um caso confirmado em Portugal. Os autores descrevem dois casos de BIA-ALCL, após reconstrução mamária por cancro de mama, com próteses macrotexturadas. Caso 1: Doente com 45 anos, que se apresentou com a manifestação típica de seroma tardio, cinco anos após a colocação da prótese, tendo sido submetida a capsulectomia, que confirmou doença localizada à cápsula. Caso 2: Doente de 43 anos, que se manifestou de forma atípica com derrame pleural e massa tumoral, 14 anos após a colocação da prótese. A doente foi submetida a remoção de prótese e quimioterapia, tendo em conta a doença metastática. Os casos clínicos descritos ilustram duas formas distintas de apresentação clínica de BIA-ALCL. O diagnóstico precoce desta patologia possibilita o seu tratamento de forma eficaz e deve ser abordado em equipa multidisciplinar.</AbstractText>
      </OtherAbstract>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Breast Implants</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Breast Neoplasms</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Lymphoma, Large-Cell, Anaplastic</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Portugal</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
          <Hour>18</Hour>
          <Minute>24</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35584637</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.20344/amp.16578</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
