<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35596820</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>21</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1573-2568</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>21</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Digestive diseases and sciences</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Dig Dis Sci</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Retained Food During Esophagogastroduodenoscopy Is a Risk Factor for Gastric-to-Pulmonary Aspiration.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s10620-022-07536-2</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Residual food (RF) during esophagogastroduodenoscopy (EGD) is thought, but not proven, to be a risk factor for gastric-to-pulmonary aspiration.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="AIMS" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The aims of this study were to determine the prevalence of RF during EGD, to investigate whether RF was associated with an increased risk of aspiration, especially when monitored anesthesia care (MAC) or general anesthesia (GA) were administered, and to determine whether aspiration associated with RF led to a more severe clinical outcome.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Patients undergoing EGD between October 2012 and September 2018 were identified. Patient age, sex, aspiration events, RF, sedation type, structural foregut abnormalities, and diagnoses associated with impaired esophageal or gastric motility were noted. The clinical course after an aspiration event was evaluated.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">RF was identified during 4% of 81,367 EGDs. Aspiration events occurred during 41 (5/10,000) procedures. Aspiration was more likely to occur in patients with RF (odds ratio [OR] 15.1) or those receiving MAC or GA (OR 9.6 and 16.8 relative to conscious sedation, respectively). RF and MAC/GA were synergistically associated with increased odds of aspiration. In a multivariate nominal logistic regression model, older age (OR 2.6), MAC (OR 3.8), GA (OR 4.4), vagotomy (OR 5.2), achalasia (OR 3.8), and RF (OR 10.0) were risk factors for aspiration. Aspiration events in the presence or absence of RF led to similar clinical outcomes.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">While aspiration events are rare in patients undergoing EGD, RF and the use of MAC or GA were associated with substantially increased odds of aspiration.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Science+Business Media, LLC, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Feighery</LastName>
            <ForeName>Aoife M</ForeName>
            <Initials>AM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Internal Medicine, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, MN, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Oblizajek</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nicholas R</ForeName>
            <Initials>NR</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, MN, 55905, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Vogt</LastName>
            <ForeName>Matthew N P</ForeName>
            <Initials>MNP</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Anesthesiology and Perioperative Medicine, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, MN, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Danse</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, The John Hopkins Hospital, Baltimore, MD, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>League</LastName>
            <ForeName>John</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <Suffix>3rd</Suffix>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, MN, 55905, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Buttar</LastName>
            <ForeName>Navtej S</ForeName>
            <Initials>NS</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, MN, 55905, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Prichard</LastName>
            <ForeName>David O</ForeName>
            <Initials>DO</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6861-2693</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Gastroenterology and Hepatology, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, MN, 55905, USA. Prichard.david@mayo.edu.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Dig Dis Sci</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>7902782</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0163-2116</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Aspiration pneumonia</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Esophagogastroduodenoscopy</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gastric emptying</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Instrumentation: anesthesia</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pneumonitis</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>10</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>11</Hour>
          <Minute>15</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35596820</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10620-022-07536-2</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s10620-022-07536-2</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peery AF, Crockett SD, Murphy CC et al. Burden and cost of gastrointestinal, liver, and pancreatic diseases in the United States: update 2021. Gastroenterology. 2022;162:621–644.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.gastro.2021.10.017</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bohman JK, Jacob AK, Nelsen KA et al. Incidence of gastric-to-pulmonary aspiration in patients undergoing elective upper gastrointestinal endoscopy. Clin Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2018;16:1163–1164.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cgh.2017.11.024</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>American Society of Anesthesiologists. Practice guidelines for preoperative fasting and the use of pharmacologic agents to reduce the risk of pulmonary aspiration: application to healthy patients undergoing elective procedures: an updated report by the American Society of Anesthesiologists Task Force on preoperative fasting and the use of pharmacologic agents to reduce the risk of pulmonary aspiration. Anesthesiology. 2017;126:376–393.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/ALN.0000000000001452</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bi D, Choi C, League J, Camilleri M, Prichard DO. Food residue during esophagogastroduodenoscopy is commonly encountered and is not pathognomonic of delayed gastric emptying. Dig Dis Sci. 2020. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10620-020-06718-0 .</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10620-020-06718-0</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33237388</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Friedrich K, Scholl SG, Beck S et al. Respiratory complications in outpatient endoscopy with endoscopist-directed sedation. J Gastrointest Liver Dis JGLD. 2014;23:255–259.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15403/jgld.2014.1121.233.kf1</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>El Chafic AH, Eckert G, Rex DK. Prospective description of coughing, hemodynamic changes, and oxygen desaturation during endoscopic sedation. Dig Dis Sci. 2012;57:1899–1907. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10620-012-2057-z .</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10620-012-2057-z</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22271416</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>von Elm E, Altman DG, Egger M, Pocock SJ, Gøtzsche PC, Vandenbroucke JP. The strengthening the reporting of observational studies in epidemiology (STROBE) statement: guidelines for reporting observational studies. Lancet (London, England). 2007;370:1453–1457.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(07)61602-X</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Warner MA, Warner ME, Weber JG. Clinical significance of pulmonary aspiration during the perioperative period. Anesthesiology. 1993;78:56–62.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00000542-199301000-00010</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cowley LE, Farewell DM, Maguire S, Kemp AM. Methodological standards for the development and evaluation of clinical prediction rules: a review of the literature. Diagn Progn Res. 2019;3:16.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s41512-019-0060-y</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sakai T, Planinsic RM, Quinlan JJ, Handley LJ, Kim TY, Hilmi IA. The incidence and outcome of perioperative pulmonary aspiration in a university hospital: a 4-year retrospective analysis. Anesth Analg. 2006;103:941–947.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1213/01.ane.0000237296.57941.e7</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Olsson GL, Hallen B, Hambraeus-Jonzon K. Aspiration during anaesthesia: a computer-aided study of 185,358 anaesthetics. Acta Anaesthesiol Scand. 1986;30:84–92.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1399-6576.1986.tb02373.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lienhart A, Auroy Y, Péquignot F et al. Survey of anesthesia-related mortality in France. Anesthesiology. 2006;105:1087–1097.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00000542-200612000-00008</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bouvet L, Desgranges FP, Aubergy C et al. Prevalence and factors predictive of full stomach in elective and emergency surgical patients: a prospective cohort study. Br J Anaesth. 2017;118:372–379.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/bja/aew462</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith I, Kranke P, Murat I et al. Perioperative fasting in adults and children: guidelines from the European Society of Anaesthesiology. Eur J Anaesthesiol. 2011;28:556–569.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/EJA.0b013e3283495ba1</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brady M, Kinn S, Stuart P. Preoperative fasting for adults to prevent perioperative complications. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2003;2003:Cd004423.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Exarhos ND, Logan WD, Abbott OA, Hatcher CR. The importance of pH and volume in tracheobronchial aspiration* *from the Division of Thoracic and Cardiovascular Surgery, Emory University School of Medicine. Dis Chest. 1965;47:167–169.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1378/chest.47.2.167</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>James CF, Modell JH, Gibbs CP, Kuck EJ, Ruiz BC. Pulmonary aspiration–effects of volume and pH in the rat. Anesth Analg. 1984;63:665–668.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6731893</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schwartz DJ, Wynne JW, Gibbs CP, Hood CI, Kuck EJ. The pulmonary consequences of aspiration of gastric contents at pH values greater than 2.5. Am Rev Respir Dis. 1980;121:119–126.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7352695</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Knight PR, Rutter T, Tait AR, Coleman E, Johnson K. Pathogenesis of gastric particulate lung injury: a comparison and interaction with acidic pneumonitis. Anesth Analg. 1993;77:754–760.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1213/00000539-199310000-00017</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
