<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35594477</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>20</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2053-1095</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>20</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Veterinary medicine and science</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Vet Med Sci</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Diode laser-assisted transcanal endoscopic removal of an aural polyp in the external auditory canal of a dog.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/vms3.845</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">In humans, aural polyps comprise fibrovascular tissue covered by the respiratory epithelium. Aural polyps with ciliated epithelium are common in cats but are rarely reported in dogs. In a previous case, a mass filled the tympanic cavity alone, and it was surgically removed.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To report a case of a canine aural polyp with ciliated epithelium extending from the dorsal tympanic cavity to the external auditory canal with detailed otological features and to demonstrate the usefulness of the transcanal endoscopic procedure (TEP) with a diode laser as a less-invasive therapy.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A 12-year-old castrated male Cavalier King Charles Spaniel presented with a 6-month history of unilateral chronic otorrhoea. Video-otoscope examination revealed a protruding, reddish and soft-to-rubbery round mass in the right horizontal ear canal. Computed tomography and magnetic resonance imaging further revealed a smooth mass extending from the dorsal portion of the tympanic cavity into the horizontal part of the external auditory canal. However, it showed no lesions in the dorsal tympanic cavity.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The mass was removed using aural forceps by a traction-torsion manoeuvre. The suspected base of the mass on the caudal side of the upper tympanic cavity was confirmed by a rigid scope, and it was completely vaporised with a diode laser. Histopathology revealed foci of columnar ciliated epithelium embedded in the connective tissue encapsulated by stratified squamous epithelium. No recurrence was observed at 3 years and 8 months.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">We describe a rare case of an aural polyp with ciliated epithelium extending from the upper-middle ear to the external auditory canal in a dog. The TEP using a diode laser may be a useful minimally invasive treatment option for managing external auditory canal polyps.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Authors. Veterinary Medicine and Science published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hoshino</LastName>
            <ForeName>Tomoya</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7382-0769</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Dermatology Service, Veterinary Specialists Emergency Centre, Saitama, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Fukuda</LastName>
            <ForeName>Shoko</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Diagnostic Iimaging Service, Veterinary Specialists Emergency Centre, Saitama, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nagata</LastName>
            <ForeName>Masahiko</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0494-9710</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Dermatology Service, Veterinary Specialists Emergency Centre, Saitama, Japan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D002363">Case Reports</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Vet Med Sci</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101678837</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2053-1095</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">CT</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">MRI</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">dog</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ear</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">histopathology</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">laser</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
          <Hour>15</Hour>
          <Minute>42</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35594477</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/vms3.845</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blutke, A., Parzefall, B., Steger, A., Goedde, T., &amp; Hermanns, W. (2010). Inflammatory polyp in the middle ear of a dog: A case report. Veterinarni Medicina, 55(6), 289-293.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gliklich, R. E., Cunningham, M. J., &amp; Eavey, R. D. (1993). The cause of aural polyps in children. Archives of Otolaryngology Head &amp; Neck Surgery, 119(6), 669-671.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Greci, V., Vernia, E., &amp; Mortellaro, C. M. (2014). Per-endoscopic trans-tympanic traction for the management of feline aural inflammatory polyps: A case review of 37 cats. Journal of Feline Medicine and Surgery, 16(8), 645-650.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Greci, V., &amp; Mortellaro, C. M. (2016). Management of otic and nasopharyngeal, and nasal polyps in cats and dogs. Veterinary Clinics of North America Small Animal Practice, 46(4), 643-661.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Imai, A., Kondo, H., Suganuma, T., &amp; Nagata, M. (2019). Clinical analysis and non-surgical management of 11 dogs with aural cholesteatoma. Veterinary Dermatology, 30(1), 42-e12.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Milroy, C. M., Slack, R. W., Maw, A. R., &amp; Bradfield, J. W. (1989). Aural polyps as predictors of underlying cholesteatoma. Journal of Clinical Pathology, 42(5), 460-465.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pratschke, K. M. (2003). Inflammatory polyps of the middle ear in 5 dogs. Veterinary Surgery, 32(3), 292-296.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sogebi, O. A. (2012). Clinicopathological characteristics of aural polyps. East and Central African Journal of Surgery, 17(3), 58-66.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Travetti, O., Giudice, C., Greci, V., Lombardo, R., Mortellaro, C. M., &amp; Giancamillo, M. D. (2010). Computed tomography features of middle ear cholesteatoma in dogs. Veterinary Radiology &amp; Ultrasound, 51(4), 374-379.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Usui, R., Okada, Y., Fukui, E., &amp; Hasegawa, A. (2015). A canine case of otitis media examined and cured using a video otoscope. Journal of Veterinary Medical Science, 77(2), 237-239.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wilcock, B. P. (2007). Eye and ear. In M. G. Maxie (Ed.), Jubb, Kennedy &amp; Palmers pathology of domestic animals (5th ed., pp. 460-552). Saunders.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zong, S., Wen, Y., Guan, Y., Liu, T., Luo, P., Qu, Y., Du, P., Chen, P., &amp; Xiao, H. (2019). Efficacy of laser myringotomy compared with incisional myringotomy for the treatment of otitis media with effusion in pediatric patients: A systematic review. International Journal of Pediatric Otorhinolaryngology, 123, 181-186.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
