<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35590480</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>20</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1865-1682</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>19</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Transboundary and emerging diseases</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Transbound Emerg Dis</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Modeling the ecological niche of naturally occurring anthrax at global and circumpolar extents using an ensemble modeling framework.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1111/tbed.14602</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Bacillus anthracis, the causative agent of anthrax, is a spore-forming bacterium that primarily affects herbivorous livestock, wildlife, and humans exposed to direct contact with infected animal carcasses or products. To date, there are a limited number of studies that have delineated the potential global distribution of anthrax, despite the importance of the disease from both an economic and public health standpoint. This study compiled occurrence data (n = 874) of confirmed human and animal cases from 1954 to 2021 in 94 countries. Using an ensemble ecological niche model (ENM) framework, we developed updated maps of the global predicted environmental suitability of anthrax to measure relative risk at multiple scales of analysis, including a model for circumpolar regions. Additionally, we produced maps quantifying the disease transmission risk associated with anthrax to cattle, sheep, and goat populations. Environmental suitability for B. anthracis globally is concentered throughout Eurasia, sub-Saharan Africa, the Americas, Southeast Asia, Australia, and Oceania. Suitable environments for B. anthracis at the circumpolar extent extend above the Arctic Circle into portions of Russia, Canada, Iceland, Alaska, and northern Scandinavia. Environmental factors driving B. anthracis suitability globally include vegetation (EVI), land surface temperature (LST), soil characteristics, primary climate conditions, and topography. While, at the circumpolar scale, suitability is influenced by soil factors, topography, and the derived climate characteristics. The greatest risk to livestock is concentrated within the Indian Subcontinent, eastern Australia, Anatolia, the Caucasus region, Central Asia, the Balkans, Spain, Uruguay, eastern China, United States, Canada, and East Africa. This study expands on previous work that predicted the potential environmental niche of anthrax by providing enhanced knowledge on the potential spatial distribution of anthrax risk in the Southern Hemisphere, sub-Saharan Africa, Asia, and circumpolar regions of the Northern Hemisphere. We conclude that these updated maps will provide pertinent information to guide disease control programs, inform policymakers, and raise awareness at the global level to lessen morbidity and mortality among animals and humans located in environmentally suitable areas. This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Deka</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mark A</ForeName>
            <Initials>MA</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6379-0132</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, Atlanta, GA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Vieira</LastName>
            <ForeName>Antonio R</ForeName>
            <Initials>AR</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, Atlanta, GA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bower</LastName>
            <ForeName>William A</ForeName>
            <Initials>WA</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, Atlanta, GA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>Germany</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Transbound Emerg Dis</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101319538</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1865-1674</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">anthrax</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ensemble ecological niche modeling</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">epidemiology</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">precision mapping</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>31</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
          <Hour>1</Hour>
          <Minute>2</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35590480</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/tbed.14602</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
