<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35597841</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>21</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1534-4681</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>21</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Annals of surgical oncology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Ann Surg Oncol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Clinical Manifestations and Surgical Management of Breast Implant-Associated Anaplastic Large Cell Lymphoma: Beyond the NCCN Guidelines.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1245/s10434-022-11838-0</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Breast implant-associated anaplastic large cell lymphoma (BIA-ALCL) is an uncommon peripheral T cell lymphoma arising in response to textured-surface breast implants. Frequently, BIA-ALCL is indolent and typically presents with peri-implant swelling after breast reconstruction or cosmetic augmentation. However, patients can present with an invasive breast or chest wall mass, palpable lymphadenopathy, or metastatic disease. The current literature is limited regarding surgical recommendations for patients with a more aggressive presentation of BIA-ALCL. This report aims to review the various clinical manifestations of BIA-ALCL, including the more advanced and less frequently encountered presentations, with an emphasis on a multidisciplinary approach, with early involvement of a surgical oncologist.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022. Society of Surgical Oncology.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lillemoe</LastName>
            <ForeName>Heather A</ForeName>
            <Initials>HA</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Surgical Oncology, The University of Texas at MD Anderson Cancer Center, Houston, TX, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Miranda</LastName>
            <ForeName>Roberto N</ForeName>
            <Initials>RN</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Hematopathology, The University of Texas at MD Anderson Cancer Center, Houston, TX, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nastoupil</LastName>
            <ForeName>Loretta J</ForeName>
            <Initials>LJ</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Lymphoma-Myeloma, The University of Texas at MD Anderson Cancer Center, Houston, TX, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Clemens</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mark W</ForeName>
            <Initials>MW</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Plastic Surgery, The University of Texas at MD Anderson Cancer Center, Houston, TX, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hunt</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kelly K</ForeName>
            <Initials>KK</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Surgical Oncology, The University of Texas at MD Anderson Cancer Center, Houston, TX, USA. khunt@mdanderson.org.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Breast Surgical Oncology, The University of Texas at MD Anderson Cancer Center, Houston, TX, USA. khunt@mdanderson.org.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Ann Surg Oncol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9420840</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1068-9265</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>23</Hour>
          <Minute>18</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35597841</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1245/s10434-022-11838-0</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1245/s10434-022-11838-0</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leberfinger AN, Behar BJ, Williams NC, et al. Breast implant-associated anaplastic large cell lymphoma: a systematic review. JAMA Surg. 2017;152:1161–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamasurg.2017.4026</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang Y, Zhang Q, Tan Y, et al. Current progress in breast implant-associated anaplastic large cell lymphoma. Front Oncol. 2021;11:785887.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fonc.2021.785887</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>U.S. Food and Drug Administration. Allergen Recalls Natrelle Biocell Textured Breast Implants Due to Risk of BIA-ALCL Cancer. Retrieved 24 October 2021 at https://www.fda.gov/medical-devices/safety-communications/fda-requests-allergan-voluntarily-recall-natrelle-biocell-textured-breast-implants-and-tissue .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cordeiro PG, Ghione P, Ni A, et al. Risk of breast implant associated anaplastic large cell lymphoma (BIA-ALCL) in a cohort of 3546 women prospectively followed long term after reconstruction with textured breast implants. J Plast Reconstr Aesthet Surg. 2020;73:841–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bjps.2019.11.064</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marra A, Viale G, Pileri SA, et al. Breast implant-associated anaplastic large cell lymphoma: a comprehensive review. Cancer Treat Rev. 2020;84:101963.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ctrv.2020.101963</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clemens MW, Horwitz SM. NCCN consensus guidelines for the diagnosis and management of breast implant-associated anaplastic large cell lymphoma. Aesthet Surg J. 2017;37:285–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/asj/sjw259</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>NCCN. National Comprehensive Cancer Network. Retrieved 24 October 2021 at https://www.nccn.org/professionals/physician_gls/pdf/t-cell.pdf .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tevis SE, Hunt KK, Miranda RN, et al. Breast implant-associated anaplastic large cell lymphoma: a prospective series of 52 patients. Ann Surg. 2022;275(1):e245–9. https://doi.org/10.1097/SLA.0000000000004035 .</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/SLA.0000000000004035</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32568749</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clemens MW, Medeiros LJ, Butler CE, et al. Complete surgical excision is essential for the management of patients with breast implant-associated anaplastic large-cell lymphoma. J Clin Oncol. 2016;34:160–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2015.63.3412</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McCarthy CM, Loyo-Berríos N, Qureshi AA, et al. Patient Registry and Outcomes for Breast Implants and Anaplastic Large Cell Lymphoma Etiology and Epidemiology (PROFILE): initial report of findings 2012–2018 (a review of breast implant-associated anaplastic large cell lymphoma). Plast Reconstr Surg. 2019;143(3S):65s–73s.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PRS.0000000000005571</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pro B, Advani R, Brice P, et al. Brentuximab vedotin (SGN-35) in patients with relapsed or refractory systemic anaplastic large cell lymphoma: results of a phase II study. J Clin Oncol. 2012;30:2190–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1200/JCO.2011.38.0402</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Younes A, Bartlett NL, Leonard JP, et al. Brentuximab vedotin (SGN-35) for relapsed CD30-positive lymphomas. N Engl J Med. 2010;363:1812–21.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1002965</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lamaris GA, Butler CE, Deva AK, et al. Breast reconstruction following breast implant-associated anaplastic large cell lymphoma. Plast Reconstr Surg. 2019;143(3S):51S–58S. https://doi.org/10.1097/PRS.0000000000005569 .</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PRS.0000000000005569</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30817556</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alotaibi S, Hamadani M, Al-Mansour M, Aljurf M. Breast implant-associated anaplastic large cell lymphoma. Clin Lymphoma Myeloma Leukemia. 2021;21:e272–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clml.2020.12.005</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ferrufino-Schmidt MC, Medeiros LJ, Liu H, et al. Clinicopathologic features and prognostic impact of lymph node involvement in patients with breast implant-associated anaplastic large cell lymphoma. Am J Surg Pathol. 2018;42:293–305.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PAS.0000000000000985</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Evans MG, Medeiros LJ, Marques-Piubelli ML, et al. Breast implant-associated anaplastic large cell lymphoma: clinical follow-up and analysis of sequential pathologic specimens of untreated patients shows persistent or progressive disease. Mod Pathol. 2021;34:2148–53.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41379-021-00842-6</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>ASAPS and ASPS BIA-ALCL Advisory Update. Retrieved 14 February 2022 at https://www.surgery.org/sites/default/files/BIA-7-31-18.pdf .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Horwitz S, O’Connor OA, Pro B, et al. Brentuximab vedotin with chemotherapy for CD30-positive peripheral T-cell lymphoma (ECHELON-2): a global, double-blind, randomised, phase 3 trial. Lancet. 2019;393:229–40.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(18)32984-2</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Collins MS, Miranda RN, Medeiros LJ, et al. Characteristics and treatment of advanced breast implant-associated anaplastic large cell lymphoma. Plast Reconstr Surg. 2019;143(3S):41S–50S. https://doi.org/10.1097/PRS.0000000000005568 .</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PRS.0000000000005568</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30817555</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shahriari N, Ferenczi K, Heald PW. Breast implant-associated anaplastic large cell lymphoma: a review and assessment of cutaneous manifestations. Int J Womens Dermatol. 2017;3:140–4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijwd.2017.05.005</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim B, Roth C, Chung KC, et al. Anaplastic large cell lymphoma and breast implants: a systematic review. Plast Reconstr Surg. 2011;127:2141–50.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/PRS.0b013e3182172418</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alcalá R, Llombart B, Lavernia J, Traves V, Guillén C, Sanmartín O. Skin involvement as the first manifestation of breast implant-associated anaplastic large cell lymphoma. J Cutan Pathol. 2016;43:602–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/cup.12697</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
