<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35597391</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>21</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1873-3476</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>18</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>International journal of pharmaceutics</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Int J Pharm</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Development and evaluation of raloxifene hydrochloride-loaded subdermal implants using hot-melt extrusion technology.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>121834</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>121834</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.ijpharm.2022.121834</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0378-5173(22)00389-1</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Implantable drug delivery systems are known to provide great patient compliance and allow for controlled delivery of drugs over a prolonged period of time. This study aimed to prepare novel polycaprolactone/polyethylene glycol-based raloxifene hydrochloride subdermal solid cylindrical implants using a single-step hot-melt extrusion (HME) continuous process, for the provision of a sustained and prolonged release of RX-HCl as a cornerstone and alternative treatment and prevention option of osteoporosis, most especially post-menopausal osteoporosis, and invasive breast cancer, while providing better clinical outcomes by circumventing clinical and biopharmaceutical hurdles like first-pass metabolism and patient non-adherence and incompliance associated with the oral dosage forms of raloxifene hydrochloride. The 11-mm co-rotating twin-screw extruder was used to prepare the implants. The prepared cylindrical-shaped solid implants with dimensions of 10 mm (length) by 2 mm (diameter) were characterized by DSC, PXRD, FTIR, SEM, and in vitro dissolution analysis. Based on the physicochemical characterization of the prepared implants, the HME fabrication technology and optimized process parameters were determined to be acceptable and suitable. The prepared implants showed no obvious burst release and no significant amounts of drug on the surface of the implants. F-1, F-2, and F-3 implant batches showed a maximum cumulative percent drug release of 82.9 %, 42.2 %, and 20.6 %, respectively, in a period of 30 days, and 100 % drug release would be expected in a period of about 40 days (F-1), 72 days (F-2), and up to 150 days (F-3) by simple extrapolation. Interestingly, implant batches with a low drug load exhibited a relatively faster and higher rate of release of the drug compared to implant batches with high drug loading. In the present study, a single-step HME process was successfully used to fabricate RX-HCl-loaded subdermal implants, that could potentially be used as a cornerstone regimen in the treatment and prevention of osteoporosis, most especially post-menopausal osteoporosis, by providing release of RX-HCl over a long time period, and avoiding the clinical inconveniences and possible patient incompliance caused by daily administration of the drug.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022. Published by Elsevier B.V.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Muhindo</LastName>
            <ForeName>Derick</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutics and Drug Delivery, School of Pharmacy, University of Mississippi, University, Mississippi 38677.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ashour</LastName>
            <ForeName>Eman A</ForeName>
            <Initials>EA</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutics and Drug Delivery, School of Pharmacy, University of Mississippi, University, Mississippi 38677.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Almutairi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Mashan</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutics and Drug Delivery, School of Pharmacy, University of Mississippi, University, Mississippi 38677; Department of Pharmaceutics, College of Pharmacy, University of Hail, Hail, 81442, Saudi Arabia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Repka</LastName>
            <ForeName>Michael A</ForeName>
            <Initials>MA</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pharmaceutics and Drug Delivery, School of Pharmacy, University of Mississippi, University, Mississippi 38677; Pii Center for Pharmaceutical Technology, School of Pharmacy, University of Mississippi, University, Mississippi 38677.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>Netherlands</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Int J Pharm</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>7804127</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0378-5173</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">biodegradable</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">extended drug release</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">hot-melt extrusion</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">osteoporosis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">polycaprolactone</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">raloxifene hydrochloride</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">subdermal implants</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>Declaration of Competing Interest The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>19</Hour>
          <Minute>25</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35597391</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijpharm.2022.121834</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">S0378-5173(22)00389-1</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
