<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35598779</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>22</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1872-9096</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>19</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Antiviral research</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Antiviral Res</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Immunodetection assays for the quantification of seasonal common cold coronaviruses OC43, NL63, or 229E infection confirm nirmatrelvir as broad coronavirus inhibitor.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>105343</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>105343</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.antiviral.2022.105343</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S0166-3542(22)00112-7</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Besides pandemic SARS-CoV-2, also endemic seasonal human common cold coronaviruses (hCoVs) have a significant impact on human health and economy. Studies on hCoVs and the identification of antivirals are therefore crucial to improve human well-being. However, hCoVs have long been neglected and the methodology to study virus infection, replication and inhibition warrants being updated. We here evaluated the established plaque-based assays to determine viral titers and cell-to-cell spread and developed protocols for the immunodetection of the viral nucleocapsid protein by flow cytometry and in-cell ELISA to study infection rates at early time points. The developed protocols allow detection of hCoV-229E infection after 2, and hCoV-NL63 and -OC43 infection after 3 days at a single cell level or in a 96 well microtiter format, in large sample numbers without being laborious or expensive. Both assays can be applied to assess the susceptibility of cells to hCoV infection and replication, and to determine the antiviral efficacy of antiviral compounds as well as neutralizing antibodies in a sensitive and quantitative manner. Application revealed that clinically applied SARS-CoV-2 targeting monoclonal antibodies are inactive against hCoVs, but that the viral polymerase targeting antivirals remdesivir and molnupiravir are broadly active also against all three hCoVs. Further, the in-cell ELISA provided evidence that nirmatrelvir, previously shown to broadly inhibit coronavirus proteases, also prevents replication of authentic hCoVs. Importantly, the protocols described here can be easily adapted to other coronavirus strains and species as well as viruses of other families within a short time. This will facilitate future research on known and emerging (corona)viruses, support the identification of antivirals and increase the preparedness for future virus outbreaks.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022. Published by Elsevier B.V.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Weil</LastName>
            <ForeName>Tatjana</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Molecular Virology, Ulm University Medical Center, 89081, Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lawrenz</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jan</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Molecular Virology, Ulm University Medical Center, 89081, Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Seidel</LastName>
            <ForeName>Alina</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Molecular Virology, Ulm University Medical Center, 89081, Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Münch</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jan</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Molecular Virology, Ulm University Medical Center, 89081, Ulm, Germany; Core Facility Functional Peptidomics, Ulm University Medical Center, 89081, Ulm, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Müller</LastName>
            <ForeName>Janis A</ForeName>
            <Initials>JA</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Molecular Virology, Ulm University Medical Center, 89081, Ulm, Germany; Institute of Virology, Philipps University of Marburg, 35043, Marburg, Germany. Electronic address: Janis.mueller@uni-ulm.de.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>Netherlands</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Antiviral Res</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8109699</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0166-3542</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Antiviral testing</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Drug screening</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">In-cell ELISA</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Seasonal coronaviruses</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
          <Hour>19</Hour>
          <Minute>32</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35598779</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.antiviral.2022.105343</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">S0166-3542(22)00112-7</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
