<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedBookArticle><BookDocument><PMID Version="1">35593798</PMID><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="bookaccession">NBK580473</ArticleId></ArticleIdList><Book><Publisher><PublisherName>StatPearls Publishing</PublisherName><PublisherLocation>Treasure Island (FL)</PublisherLocation></Publisher><BookTitle book="statpearls">StatPearls</BookTitle><PubDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></PubDate><BeginningDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>01</Month></BeginningDate><Medium>Internet</Medium></Book><ArticleTitle book="statpearls" part="article-142044">Duffy Blood Group System</ArticleTitle><Language>eng</Language><AuthorList Type="authors" CompleteYN="Y"><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Maheshwari</LastName><ForeName>Ashish</ForeName><Initials>A</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>Institute of Liver and Biliary Sciences</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author><Author ValidYN="Y"><LastName>Killeen</LastName><ForeName>Robert B.</ForeName><Initials>RB</Initials><AffiliationInfo><Affiliation>University of Illinois</Affiliation></AffiliationInfo></Author></AuthorList><PublicationType UI="D000072643">Study Guide</PublicationType><Abstract><AbstractText>The Duffy blood group system is complex, highly immunogenic glycoprotein antigens found on the surface of Red Blood Cells (RBC), vasculature endothelial cells, alveolar epithelial cells, collecting tubules of the kidney, and on the surface of Purkinje cells in the brain, but are absent on the adult liver. Duffy antigens are absent on platelets, lymphocytes, monocytes, and granulocytes.  Duffy antigens act as receptors for chemokines and attract immune system cells. Duffy antigens also act as receptors for the <i>Plasmodium</i> species responsible for malaria. Antibodies against the Duffy blood group antigens are implicated in hemolytic transfusion reactions (HTR) and hemolytic disease of the fetus and newborn (HDFN). Duffy blood group system International Society of Blood Transfusion (ISBT) symbol: FY ISBT Number: 008 <b>History</b> Duffy blood group antigen (Fy) was first discovered in 1950 in a patient named Duffy with multiple transfusions who presented with hemolytic transfusion reactions by Cutbush et al. Duffy glycoprotein or CD234 (Cluster of Differentiation 234) is a multi-pass protein. It spans the RBC membrane seven times with an exocellular N- terminal and an endocellular C-terminal, while multi-pass proteins in the other blood group system, both N and C terminals, are endocellular.  The Duffy antigens, FYa and FYb, are the gene products of DARC (Duffy antigen chemokine receptor; AKA ACKR1, atypical chemokine receptor 1).  <b>Genetics</b> Atypical Chemokine Receptor 1 (ACKR1) gene encodes the glycoprotein expressing the Duffy blood group antigens, or CD234 protein (Cluster of Differentiation 234 protein) and is encoded by a gene located at 1q23.2 position on the long arm of chromosome 1. This ACKR1 gene produces two mRNA variants and yields two protein isoforms with 338 and 336 amino acids. The Duffy antigens, i.e., Fya and Fyb, are encoded by FYA and FYB codominant alleles, respectively, which differ at position 125, where guanine in Fy-a is replaced by adenosine in Fy-b, which changes the glycine amino acid to aspartic amino acid at position 42 in Duffy glycoprotein.  Duffy antigens gene locus is syntenic to the gene locus for Rh antigen gene locus at chromosome 1. In most Duffy negative individuals, a silent Fy-b allele with T to C substitution near the gene transcription initiation site at nucleotide-46 is present. It impairs the promoter activity in human erythroid cells by disrupting the binding site for the erythroid transcription factor, i.e., GATA1. Still, the same gene is transcribed in the nonerythroid cells due to substitution mutation.  ACKRs receptors do not couple with G-proteins as its structure Asp-Arg-Tyr-Leu-Ala-Ile-Val (DRYLAIV) motif is absent on the second intracellular loop, leading to no GPCR dependant signaling pathways and chemotaxis. However, they function as scavenge, transport, and regulator of the bioavailability of chemokines. <b>Antigens</b> A total of five antigens are present in the Duffy blood group system: Fya, Fyb, Fy3, Fy5, and Fy6. <b>Fya Antigen: </b> ISBT symbol: FY1. ISBT number: 008.001. Antithetical antigen: Fyb (FY2). The expression on the cord blood RBCs: Expressed. The antigen can be demonstrated on the fetal RBCs as early as six weeks gestation. The adult level of Fya expression is attained approximately 12 weeks after birth. Fya antigens are sensitive to ficin, papain, and α-chymotrypsin and resistant to trypsin. <b>Fyb Antigen: </b> ISBT symbol: FY2. ISBT number: 008.002. Antithetical antigen: Fy(FY1). Expression on the cord blood RBCs: Expressed. Effect of enzymes: Fyb antigens are sensitive to ficin, papain, and α-chymotrypsin and resistant to trypsin. . <b>Fy3 Antigen: </b> ISBT symbol: FY3. ISBT number: 008003. Expression on the cord blood RBCs: Expressed and increases with age. Effect of enzymes: Fy3 antigens are resistant to ficin, papain, trypsin, and α-chymotrypsin. <b>Fy5 Antigen: </b> ISBT symbol: FY5. ISBT number: 008005. The expression on the cord blood RBCs: Expressed. Weak antigenic expression on D negative RBCs and absence in Rh null phenotype red cells show possible interaction between Duffy and Rh proteins. Effect of enzymes: Fy5 antigens are resistant to ficin and papain. <b>Fy6 Antigen: </b> ISBT symbol: FY6. ISBT number: 008.006. The expression on the cord blood RBCs. Effect of enzymes: Fy6 antigens are sensitive to ficin, papain, and α-chymotrypsin and resistant to trypsin. Epitopes of Fy6 antigen are required for invasion of <i>P. vivax</i>. Only murine monoclonal antibodies have defined this antigen, not human antibodies. Note: Fy4 antigen is obsolete in this system due to no evidence of antibodies against this antigen. <b>Duffy Antibodies: </b> Antibodies in the Duffy blood group system are mainly IgG type, and IgM type is rare. Duffy antibodies generally do not bind to complement, but some anti-Fyantibodies have been reported to bind with complement. These antibodies are not naturally occurring and are acquired by exposure to blood transfusion, pregnancy, and transplantation. Fya antibody is most common among other Duffy antibodies. The majority of Duffy antibodies show their reactivity at body temperature; hence they may cause red hemolysis and are clinically significant. These clinically significant antibodies can lead to both acute and delayed types of HTR and hemolytic disease of the fetus and newborn (HDFN). Dosage phenomena: Duffy blood group system shows dosage phenomena where Duffy antibodies react more strongly to homozygous cells {Fy(a−b+) or Fy(a+b−)} than heterozygous {Fy(a+b+)}. <b>Duffy Phenotypes</b> Four major Duffy phenotypes: - Fy(a+b-), Fy(a+b+), Fy(a-b+), Fy(a-b-): The Fya and Fyb antigens are found commonly in Europeans (Fya 66% and Fyb 83%) and Asians (Fya 99% and Fyb18.5%), while less common in Africans (Fya 10% and Fyb 23%). Further, Fy(a-b-) phenotype in African origins is found in two-thirds of populations and rare in Europeans. Major antigenic frequencies are shown in Table 1. Additionally, a minor Duffy phenotype is the Fyx or [Fy(b+x)]. In this phenotype, the antigen is weakly expressed as Fyb and is determined by serological adsorption and elution techniques and DNA sequencing. FYX allele encodes weakly expressed Fyb antigen, which sometimes may not be detected by anti-Fy. The Fy(a–b–) phenotype, most commonly found in Blacks, occurs primarily due to a GATA promoter region mutation upstream of the FY allele. This mutation prevents the expression of Duffy glycoprotein on erythrocytes only while permitting expression on nonerythroid cells. <b>Table 1 Major antigenic frequencies of Duffy Blood Group system in the world</b></AbstractText><CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022, StatPearls Publishing LLC.</CopyrightInformation></Abstract><Sections><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-142044" sec="article-142044.s1">Continuing Education Activity</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-142044" sec="article-142044.s2">Introduction</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-142044" sec="article-142044.s3">Function</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-142044" sec="article-142044.s4">Issues of Concern</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-142044" sec="article-142044.s5">Clinical Significance</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-142044" sec="article-142044.s6">Enhancing Healthcare Team Outcomes</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-142044" sec="article-142044.s7">Nursing, Allied Health, and Interprofessional Team Monitoring</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-142044" sec="article-142044.s8">Review Questions</SectionTitle></Section><Section><SectionTitle book="statpearls" part="article-142044" sec="article-142044.s9">References</SectionTitle></Section></Sections><ContributionDate><Year>2022</Year><Month>5</Month><Day>10</Day></ContributionDate><ReferenceList><Reference><Citation>Horuk R, Martin AW, Wang Z, Schweitzer L, Gerassimides A, Guo H, Lu Z, Hesselgesser J, Perez HD, Kim J, Parker J, Hadley TJ, Peiper SC. Expression of chemokine receptors by subsets of neurons in the central nervous system. J Immunol. 1997 Mar 15;158(6):2882-90.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9058825</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neote K, Mak JY, Kolakowski LF, Schall TJ. Functional and biochemical analysis of the cloned Duffy antigen: identity with the red blood cell chemokine receptor. Blood. 1994 Jul 01;84(1):44-52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7517217</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>CUTBUSH M, MOLLISON PL. The Duffy blood group system. Heredity (Edinb) 1950 Dec;4(3):383-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14802995</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lu ZH, Wang ZX, Horuk R, Hesselgesser J, Lou YC, Hadley TJ, Peiper SC. The promiscuous chemokine binding profile of the Duffy antigen/receptor for chemokines is primarily localized to sequences in the amino-terminal domain. J Biol Chem. 1995 Nov 03;270(44):26239-45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7592830</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Donahue RP, Bias WB, Renwick JH, McKusick VA. Probable assignment of the Duffy blood group locus to chromosome 1 in man. Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A. 1968 Nov;61(3):949-55.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC305420</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5246559</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Tournamille C, Colin Y, Cartron JP, Le Van Kim C. Disruption of a GATA motif in the Duffy gene promoter abolishes erythroid gene expression in Duffy-negative individuals. Nat Genet. 1995 Jun;10(2):224-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7663520</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Colledge KI, Pezzulich M, Marsh WL. Anti-Fy5, and antibody disclosing a probable association between the Rhesus and Duffy blood group genes. Vox Sang. 1973 Mar;24(3):193-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4632152</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ulvmar MH, Hub E, Rot A. Atypical chemokine receptors. Exp Cell Res. 2011 Mar 10;317(5):556-68.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3072526</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21272574</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sánchez-Martín L, Sánchez-Mateos P, Cabañas C. CXCR7 impact on CXCL12 biology and disease. Trends Mol Med. 2013 Jan;19(1):12-22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23153575</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Benredjem B, Girard M, Rhainds D, St-Onge G, Heveker N. Mutational Analysis of Atypical Chemokine Receptor 3 (ACKR3/CXCR7) Interaction with Its Chemokine Ligands CXCL11 and CXCL12. J Biol Chem. 2017 Jan 06;292(1):31-42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5217689</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27875312</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Pogo AO, Chaudhuri A. The Duffy protein: a malarial and chemokine receptor. Semin Hematol. 2000 Apr;37(2):122-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10791881</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Chaudhuri A, Zbrzezna V, Johnson C, Nichols M, Rubinstein P, Marsh WL, Pogo AO. Purification and characterization of an erythrocyte membrane protein complex carrying Duffy blood group antigenicity. Possible receptor for Plasmodium vivax and Plasmodium knowlesi malaria parasite. J Biol Chem. 1989 Aug 15;264(23):13770-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2668273</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Storry JR, Castilho L, Daniels G, Flegel WA, Garratty G, Francis CL, Moulds JM, Moulds JJ, Olsson ML, Poole J, Reid ME, Rouger P, van der Schoot E, Scott M, Smart E, Tani Y, Yu LC, Wendel S, Westhoff C, Yahalom V, Zelinski T. International Society of Blood Transfusion Working Party on red cell immunogenetics and blood group terminology: Berlin report. Vox Sang. 2011 Jul;101(1):77-82.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5497848</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21401621</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Geifman-Holtzman O, Wojtowycz M, Kosmas E, Artal R. Female alloimmunization with antibodies known to cause hemolytic disease. Obstet Gynecol. 1997 Feb;89(2):272-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9015034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Caren LD, Bellavance R, Grumet FC. Demonstration of gene dosage effects on antigens in the Duffy, Ss, and Rh systems using an enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay. Transfusion. 1982 Nov-Dec;22(6):475-8.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6815840</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Olteanu H, Gerber D, Partridge K, Sarode R. Acute hemolytic transfusion reaction secondary to anti-Fy3. Immunohematology. 2005;21(2):48-52.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15981343</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Peiper SC, Wang ZX, Neote K, Martin AW, Showell HJ, Conklyn MJ, Ogborne K, Hadley TJ, Lu ZH, Hesselgesser J, Horuk R. The Duffy antigen/receptor for chemokines (DARC) is expressed in endothelial cells of Duffy negative individuals who lack the erythrocyte receptor. J Exp Med. 1995 Apr 01;181(4):1311-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2191961</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7699323</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Sun XL, Yu Y, Guan XZ, Chen LF, Wang DQ. [Influence of "dosage effect" on unexpected antibody identification]. Zhongguo Shi Yan Xue Ye Xue Za Zhi. 2015 Feb;23(1):222-7.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25687077</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thakral B, Saluja K, Sharma RR, Marwaha N. Phenotype frequencies of blood group systems (Rh, Kell, Kidd, Duffy, MNS, P, Lewis, and Lutheran) in north Indian blood donors. Transfus Apher Sci. 2010 Aug;43(1):17-22.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20558108</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>De Silva JR, Lau YL, Fong MY. Genotyping of the Duffy blood group among Plasmodium knowlesi-infected patients in Malaysia. PLoS One. 2014;9(9):e108951.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4182577</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25268233</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Höher G, Fiegenbaum M, Almeida S. Molecular basis of the Duffy blood group system. Blood Transfus. 2018 Jan;16(1):93-100.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5770319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28151395</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Nickel RG, Willadsen SA, Freidhoff LR, Huang SK, Caraballo L, Naidu RP, Levett P, Blumenthal M, Banks-Schlegel S, Bleecker E, Beaty T, Ober C, Barnes KC. Determination of Duffy genotypes in three populations of African descent using PCR and sequence-specific oligonucleotides. Hum Immunol. 1999 Aug;60(8):738-42.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10439320</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lee JS, Frevert CW, Wurfel MM, Peiper SC, Wong VA, Ballman KK, Ruzinski JT, Rhim JS, Martin TR, Goodman RB. Duffy antigen facilitates movement of chemokine across the endothelium in vitro and promotes neutrophil transmigration in vitro and in vivo. J Immunol. 2003 May 15;170(10):5244-51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4357319</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12734373</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Neote K, Darbonne W, Ogez J, Horuk R, Schall TJ. Identification of a promiscuous inflammatory peptide receptor on the surface of red blood cells. J Biol Chem. 1993 Jun 15;268(17):12247-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8389755</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Vescio LA, Fariña D, Rogido M, Sóla A. Hemolytic disease of the newborn caused by anti-Fyb. Transfusion. 1987 Jul-Aug;27(4):366.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3603669</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Lo E, Russo G, Pestana K, Kepple D, Abagero BR, Dongho GBD, Gunalan K, Miller LH, Hamid MMA, Yewhalaw D, Paganotti GM. Contrasting epidemiology and genetic variation of Plasmodium vivax infecting Duffy-negative individuals across Africa. Int J Infect Dis. 2021 Jul;108:63-71.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9004484</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33991680</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Cowman AF, Crabb BS. Invasion of red blood cells by malaria parasites. Cell. 2006 Feb 24;124(4):755-66.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16497586</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Miller LH, Mason SJ, Clyde DF, McGinniss MH. The resistance factor to Plasmodium vivax in blacks. The Duffy-blood-group genotype, FyFy. N Engl J Med. 1976 Aug 05;295(6):302-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">778616</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>McMorran BJ, Wieczorski L, Drysdale KE, Chan JA, Huang HM, Smith C, Mitiku C, Beeson JG, Burgio G, Foote SJ. Platelet factor 4 and Duffy antigen required for platelet killing of Plasmodium falciparum. Science. 2012 Dec 07;338(6112):1348-51.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23224555</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Love MS, Millholland MG, Mishra S, Kulkarni S, Freeman KB, Pan W, Kavash RW, Costanzo MJ, Jo H, Daly TM, Williams DR, Kowalska MA, Bergman LW, Poncz M, DeGrado WF, Sinnis P, Scott RW, Greenbaum DC. Platelet factor 4 activity against P. falciparum and its translation to nonpeptidic mimics as antimalarials. Cell Host Microbe. 2012 Dec 13;12(6):815-23.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3638032</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23245326</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Brown CA, Pappoe-Ashong PJ, Duah N, Ghansah A, Asmah H, Afari E, Koram KA. High frequency of the Duffy-negative genotype and absence of Plasmodium vivax infections in Ghana. Malar J. 2021 Feb 17;20(1):99.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7888148</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33596926</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Haiyambo DH, Aleksenko L, Mumbengegwi D, Bock R, Uusiku P, Malleret B, Rénia L, Quaye IK. Children with Plasmodium vivax infection previously observed in Namibia, were Duffy negative and carried a c.136G &gt; A mutation. BMC Infect Dis. 2021 Aug 21;21(1):856.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8380386</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34418990</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hongfongfa P, Kuesap J. Genotyping of ABO and Duffy blood groups among malaria patients in Thailand. J Parasit Dis. 2022 Mar;46(1):178-185.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8901834</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35299921</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Singh K, Mukherjee P, Shakri AR, Singh A, Pandey G, Bakshi M, Uppal G, Jena R, Rawat A, Kumar P, Bhardwaj R, Yazdani SS, Hans D, Mehta S, Srinivasan A, Anil K, Madhusudhan RL, Patel J, Singh A, Rao R, Gangireddy S, Patil R, Kaviraj S, Singh S, Carter D, Reed S, Kaslow DC, Birkett A, Chauhan VS, Chitnis CE. Malaria vaccine candidate based on Duffy-binding protein elicits strain transcending functional antibodies in a Phase I trial. NPJ Vaccines. 2018;3:48.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Ntumngia FB, Pires CV, Barnes SJ, George MT, Thomson-Luque R, Kano FS, Alves JRS, Urusova D, Pereira DB, Tolia NH, King CL, Carvalho LH, Adams JH. An engineered vaccine of the Plasmodium vivax Duffy binding protein enhances induction of broadly neutralizing antibodies. Sci Rep. 2017 Oct 23;7(1):13779.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5653783</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29062081</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>He W, Neil S, Kulkarni H, Wright E, Agan BK, Marconi VC, Dolan MJ, Weiss RA, Ahuja SK. Duffy antigen receptor for chemokines mediates trans-infection of HIV-1 from red blood cells to target cells and affects HIV-AIDS susceptibility. Cell Host Microbe. 2008 Jul 17;4(1):52-62.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2562426</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18621010</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Walton RT, Rowland-Jones SL. HIV and chemokine binding to red blood cells--DARC matters. Cell Host Microbe. 2008 Jul 17;4(1):3-5.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18621004</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kulkarni H, Marconi VC, He W, Landrum ML, Okulicz JF, Delmar J, Kazandjian D, Castiblanco J, Ahuja SS, Wright EJ, Weiss RA, Clark RA, Dolan MJ, Ahuja SK. The Duffy-null state is associated with a survival advantage in leukopenic HIV-infected persons of African ancestry. Blood. 2009 Sep 24;114(13):2783-92.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2927046</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19620399</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Winkler CA, An P, Johnson R, Nelson GW, Kirk G. Expression of Duffy antigen receptor for chemokines (DARC) has no effect on HIV-1 acquisition or progression to AIDS in African Americans. Cell Host Microbe. 2009 May 08;5(5):411-3; author reply 418-9.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7241868</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19454340</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Hebbel RP, Vercellotti GM. SARS-CoV-2 severity in African Americans - A role for Duffy Null? Haematologica. 2020 Dec 01;105(12):2892.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7716376</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33054139</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kircheis R, Schuster M, Planz O. COVID-19: Mechanistic Model of the African Paradox Supports the Central Role of the NF-κB Pathway. Viruses. 2021 Sep 21;13(9)</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8473087</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34578468</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Duchene J, Novitzky-Basso I, Thiriot A, Casanova-Acebes M, Bianchini M, Etheridge SL, Hub E, Nitz K, Artinger K, Eller K, Caamaño J, Rülicke T, Moss P, Megens RTA, von Andrian UH, Hidalgo A, Weber C, Rot A. Atypical chemokine receptor 1 on nucleated erythroid cells regulates hematopoiesis. Nat Immunol. 2017 Jul;18(7):753-761.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5480598</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28553950</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Naidoo KK, Ngubane A, Gaza P, Moodley A, Ndung'u T, Thobakgale CF. Neutrophil Effector Functions Are Not Impaired in Duffy Antigen Receptor for Chemokines (DARC)-Null Black South Africans. Front Immunol. 2019;10:551.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Rappoport N, Simon AJ, Amariglio N, Rechavi G. The Duffy antigen receptor for chemokines, ACKR1,- 'Jeanne DARC' of benign neutropenia. Br J Haematol. 2019 Feb;184(4):497-507.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Dawson TC, Lentsch AB, Wang Z, Cowhig JE, Rot A, Maeda N, Peiper SC. Exaggerated response to endotoxin in mice lacking the Duffy antigen/receptor for chemokines (DARC). Blood. 2000 Sep 01;96(5):1681-4.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10961863</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Akalin E, Neylan JF. The influence of Duffy blood group on renal allograft outcome in African Americans. Transplantation. 2003 May 15;75(9):1496-500.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12792503</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Katznelson S, Gjertson DW, Cecka JM. The effect of race and ethnicity on kidney allograft outcome. Clin Transpl. 1995:379-94.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8794281</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kläger J, Eskandary F, Böhmig GA, Kozakowski N, Kainz A, Colin Aronovicz Y, Cartron JP, Segerer S, Regele H. Renal allograft DARCness in subclinical acute and chronic active ABMR. Transpl Int. 2021 Aug;34(8):1494-1505.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8453966</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33983671</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Unruh D, Srinivasan R, Benson T, Haigh S, Coyle D, Batra N, Keil R, Sturm R, Blanco V, Palascak M, Franco RS, Tong W, Chatterjee T, Hui DY, Davidson WS, Aronow BJ, Kalfa T, Manka D, Peairs A, Blomkalns A, Fulton DJ, Brittain JE, Weintraub NL, Bogdanov VY. Red Blood Cell Dysfunction Induced by High-Fat Diet: Potential Implications for Obesity-Related Atherosclerosis. Circulation. 2015 Nov 17;132(20):1898-908.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4772773</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26467254</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Wan W, Liu Q, Lionakis MS, Marino AP, Anderson SA, Swamydas M, Murphy PM. Atypical chemokine receptor 1 deficiency reduces atherogenesis in ApoE-knockout mice. Cardiovasc Res. 2015 Jun 01;106(3):478-87.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4447808</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25858253</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Thiriot A, Perdomo C, Cheng G, Novitzky-Basso I, McArdle S, Kishimoto JK, Barreiro O, Mazo I, Triboulet R, Ley K, Rot A, von Andrian UH. Differential DARC/ACKR1 expression distinguishes venular from non-venular endothelial cells in murine tissues. BMC Biol. 2017 May 19;15(1):45.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5438556</ArticleId><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28526034</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Girbl T, Lenn T, Perez L, Rolas L, Barkaway A, Thiriot A, Del Fresno C, Lynam E, Hub E, Thelen M, Graham G, Alon R, Sancho D, von Andrian UH, Voisin MB, Rot A, Nourshargh S. Distinct Compartmentalization of the Chemokines CXCL1 and CXCL2 and the Atypical Receptor ACKR1 Determine Discrete Stages of Neutrophil Diapedesis. Immunity. 2018 Dec 18;49(6):1062-1076.e6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">0</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference><Reference><Citation>Kim HH, Park TS, Oh SH, Chang CL, Lee EY, Son HC. Delayed hemolytic transfusion reaction due to anti-Fyb caused by a primary immune response: a case study and a review of the literature. Immunohematology. 2004;20(3):184-6.</Citation><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15373650</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></Reference></ReferenceList></BookDocument><PubmedBookData><PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus><ArticleIdList><ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35593798</ArticleId></ArticleIdList></PubmedBookData></PubmedBookArticle></PubmedArticleSet>
