<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35590111</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>19</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1433-0350</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>19</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Child's nervous system : ChNS : official journal of the International Society for Pediatric Neurosurgery</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Childs Nerv Syst</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Low occurrence of long-term subsequent fusion in pediatric patients following decompressive surgery for Chiari malformation: an institutional review.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s00381-022-05550-3</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">Chiari I malformation is treated with suboccipital craniectomy with cervical laminectomy, a procedure which has been associated with the possibility of pre-existing or iatrogenic occipitocervical instability. The long-term risk of subsequent spinal deformity and need for occipito cervical fusion after standard Chiari decompression in pediatric patients has not yet been characterized.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">We queried our institutional electronic database for patients aged 18 and under, with at least 5 years of follow-up, that underwent surgical decompression for Chiari I malformation. Occurrence of subsequent occipitocervical fusion at follow-up comprised the primary endpoint. Cases with myelomeningocele, Chiari II, or fusion at time of decompression were excluded.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">A total of 30 patients (median age 5.5 years, 60% males) were analyzed. Age distribution was as follows: n = 3 for 0-1 years, n = 11 for 1-5 years, n = 4 for 5-10 years, and n = 12 for 10-18 years. Median tonsillar descent below the foramen magnum was 12.5 mm (interquartile range [IQR]: 10.8-19.5 mm). Syringomyelia was observed in 43%, retroflexion of the dens in 55%, basilar invagination in 6.7%, and medullary kinking in 27%. The median clivo-axial angle was 142° (132-150°). The majority of patients underwent C1 laminectomy (n = 24, 80%), followed by C1-C2 laminectomy (n = 4, 13%), while one patient had C1-upper C2 and C1-C3 laminectomy each, respectively. At a median follow-up of 6.3 years, there was only one patient (3.3% of overall cohort) that underwent subsequent occipitocervical fusion. The patient (4-year-old male) initially had a suboccipital craniectomy with C1 laminectomy and duraplasty and presented with recurrence of posterior headaches and neck pain 4 months after original surgery. We proceeded with occiput-C2 fusion with subsequent resolution of his symptoms.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Current analysis shows that in the absence of clinical or imaging features suggestive of craniocervical instability, Chiari I decompressive surgery is associated with very low long-term risk of requiring occipitocervical fusion. This observance can be used to guide surgical treatment decisions, especially in young children with Chiari I malformations.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer-Verlag GmbH Germany, part of Springer Nature.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kerezoudis</LastName>
            <ForeName>Panagiotis</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurologic Surgery, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, MN, USA. kerezoudis.panagiotis@mayo.edu.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Everson</LastName>
            <ForeName>Megan C</ForeName>
            <Initials>MC</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurologic Surgery, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, MN, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Miller</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kai J</ForeName>
            <Initials>KJ</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurologic Surgery, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, MN, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Daniels</LastName>
            <ForeName>David J</ForeName>
            <Initials>DJ</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurologic Surgery, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, MN, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ahn</LastName>
            <ForeName>Edward S</ForeName>
            <Initials>ES</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurologic Surgery, Mayo Clinic, Rochester, MN, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>Germany</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Childs Nerv Syst</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8503227</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0256-7040</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chiari</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Decompression</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fusion</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Laminectomy</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Pediatric</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
          <Hour>23</Hour>
          <Minute>39</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35590111</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00381-022-05550-3</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s00381-022-05550-3</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ciaramitaro P, Massimi L, Bertuccio A et al (2022) Diagnosis and treatment of Chiari malformation and syringomyelia in adults: international consensus document. Neurol Sci. Published online June 15, 2021. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10072-021-05347-3</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Massimi L, Peretta P, Erbetta A et al (2021) Diagnosis and treatment of Chiari malformation type 1 in children: the international consensus document. Neurol Sci. Published online. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10072-021-05317-9</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tam SKP, Brodbelt A, Bolognese PA, Foroughi M (2021) Posterior fossa decompression with duraplasty in Chiari malformation type 1: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Acta Neurochir 163(1):229–238</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00701-020-04403-9</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Strahle J, Muraszko KM, Kapurch J, Bapuraj JR, Garton HJL, Maher CO (2011) Chiari malformation Type I and syrinx in children undergoing magnetic resonance imaging. J Neurosurg Pediatr 8(2):205–213</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3171/2011.5.PEDS1121</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bell DF, Walker JL, O’Connor G, Tibshirani R (1994) Spinal deformity after multiple-level cervical laminectomy in children. Spine 19(4):406–411</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00007632-199402001-00005</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Flynn JM, Sodha S, Lou JE et al (2004) Predictors of progression of scoliosis after decompression of an Arnold Chiari I malformation. Spine 29(3):286–292</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/01.BRS.0000109884.05548.68</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bekelis K, Duhaime AC, Missios S, Belden C, Simmons N (2010) Placement of occipital condyle screws for occipitocervical fixation in a pediatric patient with occipitocervical instability after decompression for Chiari malformation. J Neurosurg Pediatr 6(2):171–176</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3171/2010.4.PEDS09551</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bollo RJ, Riva-Cambrin J, Brockmeyer MM, Brockmeyer DL (2012) Complex Chiari malformations in children: an analysis of preoperative risk factors for occipitocervical fusion. J Neurosurg Pediatr 10(2):134–141</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3171/2012.3.PEDS11340</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yasuoka S, Peterson HA, MacCarty CS (1982) Incidence of spinal column deformity after multilevel laminectomy in children and adults. J Neurosurg 57(4):441–445</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3171/jns.1982.57.4.0441</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ravindra VM, Iyer RR, Yahanda AT et al (2021) A multicenter validation of the condylar--C2 sagittal vertical alignment in Chiari malformation type I: a study using the Park-Reeves Syringomyelia Research Consortium. J Neurosurg Pediatr 1(aop):1–7.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nagashima C, Kubota S (1983) Craniocervical abnormalities. Neurosurg Rev 6(4):187–197</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF01743100</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smoker WR (1994) Craniovertebral junction: normal anatomy, craniometry, and congenital anomalies. Radiographics 14(2):255–277</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1148/radiographics.14.2.8190952</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brockmeyer DL, Spader HS (2015) Complex Chiari malformations in children: diagnosis and management. Neurosurg Clin N Am 26(4):555–560</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nec.2015.06.002</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>CreveCoeur TS, Yahanda AT, Maher CO et al (2020) Occipital-cervical fusion and ventral decompression in the surgical management of Chiari-1 malformation and syringomyelia: analysis of data from the Park-Reeves Syringomyelia Research Consortium. Neurosurgery 88(2):332–341</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/neuros/nyaa460</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Katsumi Y, Honma T, Nakamura T (1989) Analysis of cervical instability resulting from laminectomies for removal of spinal cord tumor. Spine 14(11):1171–1176</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00007632-198911000-00007</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ishida Y, Suzuki K, Ohmori K, Kikata Y, Hattori Y (1989) Critical analysis of extensive cervical laminectomy. Neurosurgery 24(2):215–222</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1227/00006123-198902000-00010</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aronson DD, Kahn RH, Canady A, Bollinger RO, Towbin R (1991) Instability of the cervical spine after decompression in patients who have Arnold-Chiari malformation. J Bone Joint Surg Am 73(6):898–906</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2106/00004623-199173060-00012</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McLaughlin MR, Wahlig JB, Pollack IF (1997) Incidence of postlaminectomy kyphosis after Chiari decompression. Spine 22(6):613–617</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00007632-199703150-00007</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Camino Willhuber GO, Bosio ST, Puigdevall MH, Halliburton C, Sola CA, Maenza RA (2017) Craniocervical spinal instability after type 1 Arnold Chiari decompression: a case report. Journal of Pediatric Orthopaedics B 26(1):80</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/BPB.0000000000000346</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
