<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35591890</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>21</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">2168-8184</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>14</Volume>
            <Issue>5</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Cureus</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Cureus</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>A Retrospective Study of 23 Cases: Are Lichenoid Lesions of the Labial Mucosa Induced?</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e25012</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e25012</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">e25012</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.7759/cureus.25012</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Background Lichen planus (LP) is a pathology that affects the skin and the mucosa. The lips are rarely involved but represent a diagnostic challenge in those cases. Oral lichenoid lesions (OLL) are defined as lesions that resemble oral lichen planus (OLP) but do not fully meet the clinical and/or histologic criteria for OLP. This study aimed to present our case series and to study the correlation between the location of the lesion and the dental factor (resin composite, amalgams, crowns, abrasive teeth, and mandibular crossbite) that could cause the lesion. Methods We conducted a retrospective observational study of 23 patients with LP/OLL of the lips treated in the Department of Oral Mucosal Pathology of the Department of Stomatology and Maxillofacial Surgery of the Pitié-Salpêtrière Hospital in Paris between January 2017 and February 2021. We noted the location of the lesion (upper, lower, or both lips), medical history, treatments, smoking habits, and the aspect of the teeth facing the lesion. Patients received a local corticoid treatment and were monitored via follow-up. Results Sixteen patients had lesions on the upper lip, two on the lower lip, and five on both lips, and most patients (n = 14, 60.1%) had a dental factor facing the lesion (e.g., abrasive teeth, resin composites, dental crowns, and mandibular crossbite). Six patients received clobetasol propionate, and 15 patients received a preparation combining betamethasone and benzocaine (Orabase, ConvaTec, Deeside, UK). Fourteen patients returned for post-treatment follow-up consultations approximately two months after treatment. Seven patients saw clinical improvement, five had partial improvement, and two had no improvement. Conclusions Lesions of the labial mucosa appear to be a rare condition in LP/OLL. The difference between LP and OLL can be difficult, even with histological analysis. Its pathogenesis remains unknown, although some studies found evidence of lichenoid reactions of the lips in contact with dental composite restorations. In our study, 14 of our patients had a dental factor facing the lesions. However, our study failed to show a correlation between the presence of an inducing factor and the lesion. In a future study, the potential effect of dental inducing factor removal could be studied. This topic requires further investigations, particularly regarding the inducing factor and the optimal therapeutic approach.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022, Lehner et al.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lehner</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jean</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Oral Surgery, Université Paris-Sorbonne, Paris, FRA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Agbo-Godeau</LastName>
            <ForeName>Scarlette</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Département de Pathologie de la Muqueuse Buccale, Service de Chirurgie Maxillo-Faciale et Stomatologie, Pitié-Salpêtrière Hospital, Paris, FRA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bertolus</LastName>
            <ForeName>Chloé</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Département de Pathologie de la Muqueuse Buccale, Service de Chirurgie Maxillo-Faciale et Stomatologie, Pitié-Salpêtrière Hospital, Paris, FRA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Cureus</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101596737</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2168-8184</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">buccal dermatology</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">clinical research</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">koebner phenomenon</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lichen planus</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">lip lesions</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">oral lichen planus</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">oral lichenoid lesions</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors have declared that no competing interests exist.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
          <Hour>2</Hour>
          <Minute>14</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35591890</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9110071</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7759/cureus.25012</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oral lichen planus and lichenoid reactions: etiopathogenesis, diagnosis, management and malignant transformation. Ismail SB, Kumar SK, Zain RB. J Oral Sci. 2007;49:89–106.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17634721</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Number V oral lichen planus: clinical features and management. Eisen D, Carrozzo M, Bagan Sebastian JV, Thongprasom K. Oral Dis. 2005;11:338–349.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16269024</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>The possible premalignant character of oral lichen planus and oral lichenoid lesions: a prospective five-year follow-up study of 192 patients. van der Meij EH, Mast H, van der Waal I. Oral Oncol. 2007;43:742–748.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17112770</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Worldwide prevalence of oral lichen planus: a systematic review and meta-analysis. González-Moles MÁ, Warnakulasuriya S, González-Ruiz I, et al.  Oral Dis. 2021;27:813–828.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32144836</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Global prevalence and incidence estimates of oral lichen planus: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Li C, Tang X, Zheng X, et al.  JAMA Dermatol. 2020;156:172–181.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6990670</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31895418</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Childhood oral lichen planus: a case series with review of literature. Shikha Shikha, Gupta S, Mahajan A, Ambika Ambika, Garg R, Ghosh S. Eur Arch Paediatr Dent. 2022;23:341–353.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35094367</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>A clinical study of 674 patients with oral lichen planus in China. Xue JL, Fan MW, Wang SZ, Chen XM, Li Y, Wang L. J Oral Pathol Med. 2005;34:467–472.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16091113</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Etiology and pathogenesis of oral lichen planus: an overview. Kurago ZB. Oral Surg Oral Med Oral Pathol Oral Radiol. 2016;122:72–80.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27260276</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oral lichenoid lesions - a review and update. Kamath VV, Setlur K, Yerlagudda K. Indian J Dermatol. 2015;60:102.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clinicopathologic correlation of oral lichen planus and oral lichenoid lesions: a preliminary study. Mravak-Stipetić M, Lončar-Brzak B, Bakale-Hodak I, Sabol I, Seiwerth S, Majstorović M, Grce M. ScientificWorldJournal. 2014;2014:746874.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4229965</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25531004</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>The role of histopathological characteristics in distinguishing amalgam-associated oral lichenoid reactions and oral lichen planus. Thornhill MH, Sankar V, Xu XJ, et al.  J Oral Pathol Med. 2006;35:233–240.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16519771</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lichen sclerosus of the upper lip: report of a case, utilizing Shikata's modified orcein stain, and review of the literature. Katsoulas N, Prodromidis G, Nikitakis NG. J Oral Maxillofac Res. 2018;9:0.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clinical and histologic healing of lichenoid oral lesions following amalgam removal: a prospective study. Montebugnoli L, Venturi M, Gissi DB, Cervellati F. Oral Surg Oral Med Oral Pathol Oral Radiol. 2012;113:766–772.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22668704</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Adverse reactions in the oral mucosa associated with anterior composite restorations. Blomgren J, Axéll T, Sandahl O, Jontell M. J Oral Pathol Med. 1996;25:311–313.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8887075</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oral lichenoid reactions associated with amalgam: improvement after amalgam removal. Dunsche A, Kästel I, Terheyden H, Springer IN, Christophers E, Brasch J. Br J Dermatol. 2003;148:70–76.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12534597</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oral lichenoid tissue reactions: diagnosis and classification. Khudhur AS, Di Zenzo G, Carrozzo M. Expert Rev Mol Diagn. 2014;14:169–184.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24524807</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lichen planus and lichenoid reactions of the oral mucosa. Schlosser BJ. Dermatol Ther. 2010;23:251–267.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20597944</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oral lichen planus: a literature review and update. Alrashdan MS, Cirillo N, McCullough M. Arch Dermatol Res. 2016;308:539–551.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27349424</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Course of oral lichen planus: a retrospective study of 808 northern Italian patients. Carbone M, Arduino PG, Carrozzo M, et al.  Oral Dis. 2009;15:235–243.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19222766</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>The lip in lupus erythematosus. Nico MM, Bologna SB, Lourenço SV. Clin Exp Dermatol. 2014;39:563–569.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24934909</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Differential diagnosis of cheilitis - how to classify cheilitis? Lugović-Mihić L, Pilipović K, Crnarić I, Šitum M, Duvančić T. Acta Clin Croat. 2018;57:342–351.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6531998</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30431729</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Annular atrophic lichen planus of the lip. Sugashima Y, Yamamoto T. https://escholarship.org/uc/item/4bt854wp Dermatol Online J. 2012;18:14.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lichen planus with bullous manifestation on the lip. van Tuyll van Serooskerken AM, van Marion AM, de Zwart-Storm E, Frank J, Poblete-Gutiérrez P. Int J Dermatol. 2007;46:25–26.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17973884</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lichen planus of the lips: an intermediate disease between the skin and mucosa? Retrospective clinical study and review of the literature. Nuzzolo P, Celentano A, Bucci P, Adamo D, Ruoppo E, Leuci S, Mignogna MD. Int J Dermatol. 2016;55:0–81.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Isolated lichen planus of the lip. Petruzzi M, De Benedittis M, Pastore L, Pannone G, Grassi FR, Serpico R. Int J Immunopathol Pharmacol. 2007;20:631–635.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17880776</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>French guidelines for the management of oral lichen planus (excluding pharmacological therapy) Campana F, Lan R, Girard C, et al.  Ann Dermatol Venereol. 2022;149:14–27.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34238586</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>The Koebner phenomenon. Sagi L, Trau H. Clin Dermatol. 2011;29:231–236.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21396563</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>The Koebner phenomenon. Ahad T, Agius E. Br J Hosp Med (Lond) 2015;76:0–2.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Microbial-associated oral lichenoid reactions. Bäckman K, Jontell M. Oral Dis. 2007;13:402–406.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17577327</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Oral lichenoid lesions related to dental restorative materials. Issa Y, Duxbury AJ, Macfarlane TV, Brunton PA. Br Dent J. 2005;198:361–366.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15789104</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
