<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35591755</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>20</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2054-1058</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>19</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Nursing open</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Nurs Open</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>A qualitative analysis of intravenous smart pump usability.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/nop2.1227</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="AIM" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To understand the experience of critical care nurses when performing common, yet error-prone, programming tasks on two unfamiliar intravenous smart pumps.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="DESIGN" NlmCategory="METHODS">A qualitative descriptive study using data collected during a previous quantitative pilot study.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Following completion of common intravenous programming tasks each participant was interviewed using a semi-structured interview guide. All interview data were coded line-by-line and thematic analysis revealed themes across all participants' interviews.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The following four themes were identified: appreciation for attractive design features, the need for efficiency, the importance of intuitive use and concern for patient outcomes. Overall, these themes provide evidence that nurses strongly prefer a more usable intravenous smart pump interface that integrates safeguards to efficiently improve patient outcomes. Findings support the need for intravenous smart pump technology to be developed with an intuitive interface that decreases the level of cognitive demand and will lead to improved patient safety.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Authors. Nursing Open published by John Wiley &amp; Sons Ltd.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Blake</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jeannine W C</ForeName>
            <Initials>JWC</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6717-9496</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Elaine Marieb Center for Nursing and Engineering Innovation, Elaine Marieb College of Nursing &amp; Institute for Applied Life Sciences, University of Massachusetts Amherst, Amherst, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Fiske</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sarah M</ForeName>
            <Initials>SM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Elaine Marieb College of Nursing, University of Massachusetts Amherst, Amherst, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Giuliano</LastName>
            <ForeName>Karen K</ForeName>
            <Initials>KK</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Elaine Marieb Center for Nursing and Engineering Innovation, Elaine Marieb College of Nursing &amp; Institute for Applied Life Sciences, University of Massachusetts Amherst, Amherst, Massachusetts, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Nurs Open</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101675107</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2054-1058</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">critical care nursing</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">infusion pumps</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">intravenous administration</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">intravenous infusions</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">user-centered design</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
          <Hour>1</Hour>
          <Minute>15</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35591755</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/nop2.1227</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Campoe, K. R., &amp; Giuliano, K. K. (2017). Impact of frequent interruption on nurses' patient-controlled analgesia programming performance. Human Factors and Ergonomic Society, 59(8), 1204-1213. https://doi.org/10.1177/0018720817732605</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cassano-Piché, A., Fan, M., Sabovitch, S., Masino, C., Easty, A., &amp; Team HTSR. (2012). Multiple intravenous infusions phase 1b: Practice and training scan. Ontario Health Technology Assessment Series., 12(16), 1.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Di Muzio, M., De Vito, C., Tartaglini, D., &amp; Villari, P. (2017). Knowledge, behaviours, training and attitudes of nurses during preparation and administration of intravenous medications in intensive care units (ICU). A multicenter Italian study. Applied Nursing Research, 38, 129-133. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apnr.2017.10.002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ding, Q., Barker, K. N., Flynn, E. A., Westrick, S. C., Chang, M., Thomas, R. E., Braxton-Lloyd, K., &amp; Sesek, R. (2015). Incidence of intravenous medication errors in a Chinese Hospital. Value in Health Regional Issues, 6, 33-39. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vhri.2015.03.004</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fahimi, F., Sefidani Forough, A., Taghikhani, S., &amp; Saliminejad, L. (2015, Winter). The rate of physicochemical incompatibilities, administration errors. Factors correlating with nurses' errors. Iran Journal of Pharmacy Research, 14(Suppl), 87-93. https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4499430/pdf/ijpr-14-087.pdf</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fan, M., Koczmara, C., Masino, C., Cassano-Piché, A., Trbovich, P., &amp; Easty, A. (2014). Multiple intravenous infusions phase 2a: Ontario survey. Ontario Health Technology Assessment Series, 14(4), 1-141. https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4522693/pdf/ohtas-14-1.pdf</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>FDA. (2016). Applying human factors and usability engineering to medical devices. U.S. Department of Health and Human Services, U.S. Food and Drug Administration, Center for Devices and Radiological Health, &amp; Office of Device Evaluation. https://www.fda.gov/downloads/MedicalDevices/26/UCM259760.pdf</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giuliano, K. K. (2015). IV smart pumps: The impact of a simplified user interface on clinical use. Biomedical Instrumentation &amp; Technology, 49, 13-21. https://doi.org/10.2345/0899-8205-49.s4.13</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giuliano, K. (2018a). Intravenous smart pumps: Usability issues, intravenous medication administration error, and patient safety. Critical Care Nurse, 30, 215-224. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cnc.2018.02.004</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giuliano, K. (2018b). IV smart pumps and error-prone programming tasks: Comparison of four devices. Biomedical Instrumentation and Technology, 52(2), 11. https://doi.org/10.2345/0899-8205-52.s2.17</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giuliano, K. K., &amp; Ruppel, H. (2017). Are smart pumps smart enough? Nursing, 47(3), 64-66. https://doi.org/10.1097/01.NURSE.0000512888.75246.88</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Institute for Safe Medication Practices. (2020). ISMP guidelines for optimizing safe implementation and use of smart infusion pumps. https://www.ismp.org/node/972</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jennings, B. M. (2021). Workflow, turbulence, and cognitive complexity. In M. Baernhodlt &amp; D. K. Boyle (Eds.), Nurses contribution to quality health outcomes (pp. 85-107). Springer. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-69063-2_5</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kuitunen, S. K., Niittynen, I., Airaksinen, M., &amp; Holmström, A. R. (2020, Mar 14). Systemic defenses to prevent intravenous medication errors in hospitals. A systematic review. Journal of Patient Safety, 17(8), e1669-e1680. https://doi.org/10.1097/PTS.0000000000000688</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lindgren, B., Lundman, B., &amp; Graneheim, U. H. (2020). Abstraction and interpretation during the qualitative content analysis process. International Journal of Nursing Studies, 8, 1-6. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijnurstu.2020.103632</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marshall, C., &amp; Rossman, G. (2016). Designing qualitative research (6th ed.). SAGE Publications Inc.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Monroy Aceves, C., Oladimeji, P., Thimbleby, H., &amp; Lee, P. (2013). Are prescribed infusions running as intended? Quantitative analysis of log files from infusion pumps used in a large acute NHS hospital. British Journal of Nursing, 22, 15-21. https://doi.org/10.12968/bjon.2013.22.Sup13.15</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moss, J., Berner, E., Bothe, O., &amp; Rymarchuk, I. (2008). Intravenous medication administration in intensive care: Opportunities for technological solutions. AMIA Annual Symposium Proceedings Archive, 2008, 495-499.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>NQF. (2012). Critical paths for creating data platforms: Intravenous infusion pump devices. http://www.qualityforum.org/publications/2012/10/Critical_Paths_for_Creating_Data_Platforms_Patient_Safety_Intravenous_Infusion_Pump_Devices.aspx</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ohashi, K., Dalleur, O., Dykes, P. C., &amp; Bates, D. W. (2014). Benefits and risks of using smart pumps to reduce medication error rates: A systematic review. Drug Safety, 37(12), 1011-1020. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40264-014-0232-1</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schnock, K., Dykes, P. C., Albert, J., Ariosto, D., Call, R., Cameron, C., Carroll, D. L., Drucker, A., Fang, L., Garcia-Palm, C. A., Husch, M., Maddox, R. R., McDonald, N., McGuire, J., Rafie, S., Robertson, E., Saine, D., Sawyer, M., Smith, L., … Bates, D. W. (2016). The frequency of intravenous medication administration errors related to smart infusion pumps: A multihospital observational study. BMJ Quality &amp; Safety, 12. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmjqs-2015-004465</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schnock, K., Dykes, P., Albert, J., Ariosto, D., Cameron, C., Carroll, D., Donahue, M., Drucker, A., Duncan, R., Fang, L., Husch, M., McDonald, N., Maddox, R., McGuire, J., Rafie, S., Robertson, E., Sawyer, M., Wade, E., Yoon, C., … Bates, D. (2018). A multi-hospital before-after observational study using a point-prevalence approach with an infusion safety intervention bundle to reduce intravenous medication administration errors. Drug Safety, 41(6), 591-602. https://doi.org/10.1007/s40264-018-0637-3</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Snijder, R. A., Konings, M. K., Lucas, P., Egberts, T. C., &amp; Timmerman, A. D. (2015). Aug). Flow variability and its physical causes in infusion technology: A systematic review of in vitro measurement and modeling studies. Biomedical Engineering/Biomedizinische Technik, 60(4), 277-300. https://doi.org/10.1515/bmt-2014-0148</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Streubert, H. J., &amp; Carpenter, D. R. (2011). Qualitative research in nursing: Advancing the humanistic imperative (5th ed.). Lippincott, Williams, &amp; Wilkins.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vincent, C., Taylor-Adams, S., &amp; Stanhope, N. (1998). Framework for analysing risk and safety in clinical medicine. British Medical Journal, 316(7138), 1154-1157. https://doi.org/10.1136/bmj.316.7138.1154</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
