<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35598740</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>22</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1095-9947</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>19</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Fish &amp; shellfish immunology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Fish Shellfish Immunol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>TLR23, a fish-specific TLR, recruits MyD88 and TRIF to activate expression of a range of effectors in melanomacrophages in Nile tilapia (Oreochromis niloticus).</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1050-4648(22)00273-X</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.fsi.2022.05.032</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Nile tilapia (Oreochromis niloticus) is an important food fish species that is mainly cultivated in tropical and subtropical countries. However, microbial diseases have created various difficulties for this industry. The fundamental prerequisite for tackling disease outbreak prevention and disease resistance is to know how hosts' immune responses against invading microbes are initiated. Toll-like receptors (TLRs) are vital pattern recognition receptors and play pivotal roles in the cellular innate immunity defense that is able to recognize pathogen-associated molecular patterns (PAMPs). In this study, Oreochromis niloticus TLR23 (OnTLR23) was cloned and bioinformatic analyses revealed that OnTLR23 is not an ortholog of mammalian TLR13 as previously suggested. The basal transcript level of OnTLR23 was found to be higher in the immune-related organs and was upregulated in the spleen and/or head kidney following Aeromonas hydrophila, Streptococcus agalactiae or poly I:C injections, and increased in the melanomacrophage-like tilapia head kidney (THK) cell line after LPS and zymosan stimulation. Furthermore, we demonstrated for the first time that OnTLR23 locates mainly in the intracellular region in fish cells and the constitutively active form of OnTLR23 promotes the expression of molecules related to antigen presentation, proinflammatory cytokines, antimicrobial peptides and type I interferon in THK cells. A co-immunoprecipitation assay revealed that OnTLR23 can interact with both OnMyD88 and OnTRIF, but not with OnTIRAP. A luciferase assay showed that the NF-κB activity was not elevated in the OnTLR23 overexpressed THK cells after treatment with ligand for TLR13 as well as other known purified bacterial-derived ligands of TLRs. Taken together, OnTLR23 is likely to recruit OnMyD88 and OnTRIF as adaptors to induce the expression of various effectors in melanomacrophages, but its corresponding ligand is an issue awaiting further investigation.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022. Published by Elsevier Ltd.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tan-Phat</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nguyen</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Aquaculture, National Taiwan Ocean University, Keelung, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Trung</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nguyen Bao</ForeName>
            <Initials>NB</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Aquaculture, National Taiwan Ocean University, Keelung, Taiwan; College of Aquaculture and Fisheries, Can Tho University, Viet Nam.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Fan-Hua</ForeName>
            <Initials>FH</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Aquaculture, National Taiwan Ocean University, Keelung, Taiwan; Center of Excellence for Ocean Engineering, National Taiwan Ocean University, Keelung City, 20224, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lee</LastName>
            <ForeName>Meng-Chou</ForeName>
            <Initials>MC</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Aquaculture, National Taiwan Ocean University, Keelung, Taiwan; Center of Excellence for Ocean Engineering, National Taiwan Ocean University, Keelung City, 20224, Taiwan; Center of Excellence for the Oceans, National Taiwan Ocean University, Keelung City, 20224, Taiwan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lee</LastName>
            <ForeName>Po-Tsang</ForeName>
            <Initials>PT</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Aquaculture, National Taiwan Ocean University, Keelung, Taiwan. Electronic address: leepotsang@email.ntou.edu.tw.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Fish Shellfish Immunol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9505220</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1050-4648</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Fish TLR</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Inflammation</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Innate immunity</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Macrophage</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Tilapia</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>Declaration of competing interest There is no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
          <Hour>19</Hour>
          <Minute>25</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35598740</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fsi.2022.05.032</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">S1050-4648(22)00273-X</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
