<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35598086</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>22</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1096-9861</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>21</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>The Journal of comparative neurology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Comp Neurol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Micro-CT visualization of the CNS: Performance of different contrast-enhancing techniques for documenting the spider brain.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1002/cne.25343</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Spider brain and central nervous system (CNS) have remained unexplored, due in part to the difficulty of observing these organs, usually only possible through histological preparations. Recently, internal anatomy studies have been supplemented by the inclusion of X- ray micro-CT. Unmineralized tissue such as the body of invertebrates requires a staining process to enhance tissue X-ray absorption and improve contrast during observation. Many current protocols are based on iodine staining requiring critical point drying (CPD) of the sample for optimal contrast. This process induces shrinking of the soft tissue generating artifacts in the morphology, volume, and even position of internal structures. Phosphotungstic acid (PTA) is an alternative staining agent recently used in marine invertebrate and plant studies. Here, we used several specimens of the common spider Araneus diadematus to visualize the spider brain and compare both contrast-enhancing ethanol-based solutions. We assessed a gradient of staining times, observed and tested the repercussions of CPD, and examined the use of vacuum to accelerate PTA diffusion. We show that PTA provides the best contrast on micro-CT scans in ethanol eliminating the need for CPD, and offering more realistic in situ visualizations of the internal organs. In combination with different scanning settings, PTA allowed observation of internal organs like the CNS, digestive system, muscles, and finer structures like the retina, visual nerves, and optic neuropiles. This fast and less invasive method could facilitate the proper documentation of the internal anatomy in the context of evolutionary, developmental and functional studies.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 Wiley Periodicals LLC.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Rivera-Quiroz</LastName>
            <ForeName>Francisco Andres</ForeName>
            <Initials>FA</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8748-4930</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Understanding Evolution Research Group, Naturalis Biodiversity Center, Leiden, The Netherlands.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute for Biology Leiden (IBL), Leiden University, Leiden, The Netherlands.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Miller</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jeremy A</ForeName>
            <Initials>JA</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-8918-9775</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Understanding Evolution Research Group, Naturalis Biodiversity Center, Leiden, The Netherlands.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Comp Neurol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0406041</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0021-9967</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">X-rays</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">arachnida</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">arthropoda</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cerebrum</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">imaging</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">nervous system</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">neuroanatomy</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">tissue</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>28</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
          <Hour>2</Hour>
          <Minute>33</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35598086</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cne.25343</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Title>REFERENCES</Title>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alba-Alejandre, I., Alba-Tercedor, J., &amp; Hunter, W. B. (2020). Anatomical study of the female reproductive system and bacteriome of Diaphorina citri Kuwayama, (Insecta: Hemiptera, Liviidae) using micro-computed tomography. Scientific Reports, 10(1), 1-14. Nature Publishing Group. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-020-64132-y</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alba-Alejandre, I., Alba-Tercedor, J., &amp; Vega, F. E. (2019). Anatomical study of the coffee berry borer (Hypothenemus hampei) using micro-computed tomography. Scientific Reports, 9(1), 1-16. Nature Publishing Group. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-019-53537-z</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alba-Alejandre, I., Hunter, W. B., &amp; Alba-Tercedor, J. (2018). Micro-CT study of male genitalia and reproductive system of the Asian citrus psyllid, Diaphorina citri Kuwayama, 1908 (Insecta: Hemiptera, Liviidae). PLoS One, 13(8), e0202234. Public Library of Science:e0202234. https://doi.org/10.1371/JOURNAL.PONE.0202234</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alba-Tercedor, J., Hunter, W. B., &amp; Alba-Alejandre, I. (2021). Using micro-computed tomography to reveal the anatomy of adult Diaphorina citri Kuwayama (Insecta: Hemiptera, Liviidae) and how it pierces and feeds within a citrus leaf. Scientific Reports, 11(1), 1-30. Nature Publishing Group. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-020-80404-z</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Babu, K. S., &amp; Barth, F. G. (1984). Neuroanatomy of the central nervous system of the wandering spider, Cupiennius salei (Arachnida, Araneida). Zoomorphology, 104, 344-539. https://doi.org/10.1007/BF00312185</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Castejón, D., Alba-Tercedor, J., Rotllant, G., Ribes, E., Durfort, M., &amp; Guerao, G. (2018). Micro-computed tomography and histology to explore internal morphology in decapod larvae. Scientific Reports, 8(1), 14399. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-018-32709-3</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dederichs, T. M., Müller, C. H. G., Sentenská, L., Lipke, E., Uhl, G., &amp; Michalik, P. (2019). The innervation of the male copulatory organ of spiders (Araneae) - A comparative analysis. Frontiers in Zoology, 16(39), 1-14. https://doi.org/10.1186/s12983-019-0337-6</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dirks-Mulder, A., Ahmed, I., uit het Broek, M., Krol, L., Menger, N., Snier, J., van Winzum, A., de Wolf, A., van't Wout, M., Zeegers, J. J., Butôt, R., Heijungs, R., van Heuven, B. J., Kruizinga, J., Langelaan, R., Smets, E. F., Star, W., Bemer, M., &amp; Gravendeel, B. (2019). Morphological and molecular characterization of orchid fruit development. Frontiers in Plant Science, 10, 137. Frontiers Media S.A.: https://doi.org/10.3389/fpls.2019.00137</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Faulwetter, S., Dailianis, T., Vasileiadou, A., &amp; Arvanitidis, C. (2012). Investigation of contrast enhancing techniques for the application of Micro-CT in marine biodiversity studies. In SkyScan MicroCT User Meeting 2012.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hanstrom, B. (1921). Uber die Histologie und vergleichende Anatomie der Sehganglien und Globuli der Araneen. Kunglica Svenska Vetenskapsakademiens Handligar, 61, 1-39.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hanstrom, B. (1923). Further notes on the central-nervous system of arachnids: scorpions, phalangids, and trap-door spiders. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 35(4), 249-274.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harzsch, S. (2006). Neurophylogeny: Architecture of the nervous system and a fresh view on arthropod phylogeny. Integrative and Comparative Biology, 46(2), 162-194. Integr Comp Biol. https://doi.org/10.1093/icb/icj011</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hill, D. E. (2006). The structure of the central nervous system of jumping spiders of the genus Phidippus (Araneae: Salticidae). Oregon State University, 1-94.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Keklikoglou, K., Faulwetter, S., Chatzinikolaou, E., Wils, P., Brecko, J., Kvaček, J., Metscher, B., &amp; Arvanitidis, C. (2019). Micro-computed tomography for natural history specimens: a handbook of best practice protocols. European Journal of Taxonomy, 522, 1-55. https://doi.org/10.5852/ejt.2019.522</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lesciotto, K. M., Motch Perrine, S. M., Kawasaki, M., Stecko, T., Ryan, T. M., Kawasaki, K., &amp; Richtsmeier, J. T. (2020). Phosphotungstic acid-enhanced microCT: Optimized protocols for embryonic and early postnatal mice. Developmental Dynamics, 249(4), 573-585. John Wiley and Sons Inc. https://doi.org/10.1002/dvdy.136</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lin, S. W., Lopardo, L., &amp; Uhl, G. (2021). Diversification through gustatory courtship: an X-ray micro-computed tomography study on dwarf spiders. Frontiers in Zoology, 18(1), 1-33. BioMed Central: https://doi.org/10.1186/s12983-021-00435-8</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lipke, E., Hammel, J. U., &amp; Michalik, P. (2015). First evidence of neurons in the male copulatory organ of a spider (Arachnida, Araneae). Biology Letters, 11, 20150465. https://doi.org/10.1098/rsbl.2015.0465</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Long, S. M. (2016). Spider brain morphology &amp; behavior. University of Massachusetts Amherst, 239.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Long, S. M. (2021). Variations on a theme: Morphological variation in the secondary eye visual pathway across the order of Araneae. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 529(2), 259-280. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.24945</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Metscher, B. D. (2009). Micro CT for comparative morphology: Simple staining methods allow high-contrast 3D imaging of diverse non-mineralized animal tissues. BMC Physiology, 9(1), 11. https://doi.org/10.1186/1472-6793-9-11</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pramanik, D., Dorst, N., Meesters, N., Spaans, M., Smets, E., Welten, M., &amp; Gravendeel, B. (2020). Evolution and development of three highly specialized floral structures of bee-pollinated Phalaenopsis species. EvoDevo, 11(1), 16. BioMed Central: https://doi.org/10.1186/s13227-020-00160-z</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rivera-Quiroz, F. A., &amp; Miller, J. A. (2021). Old brains in alcohol: The usability of legacy collection material to study the spider neuroarchitecture. Diversity, 13(11), 601. https://doi.org/10.3390/d13110601</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rivera-Quiroz, F. A., Petcharad, B., &amp; Miller, J. A. (2021). First records and three new species of the family Symphytognathidae (Arachnida, Araneae) from Thailand, and the circumscription of the genus Crassignatha Wunderlich, 1995. ZooKeys, 2021(1012), 21-53. https://doi.org/10.3897/zookeys.1012.57047</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saint-Remy, G. (1890). Contribution a l’étude du cerveau chez les arthropodes trachéates. Faculté des Sciences de Paris, 274.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sakurai, Y., &amp; Ikeda, Y. (2019). Development of a contrast-enhanced micro computed tomography protocol for the oval squid (Sepioteuthis lessoniana) brain. Microscopy Research and Technique, 82(11), 1941-1952. Wiley-Liss Inc.:jemt.23363. https://doi.org/10.1002/jemt.23363</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schmid, A., &amp; Becherer, C. (1999). Distribution of histamine in the CNS of different spiders. Microscopy Research and Technique, 44, 81-93. https://doi.org/10.1002/(SICI)1097-0029(19990115/01)44:2/3&lt;81::AID-JEMT3&gt;3.0.CO;2-O</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sombke, A., Klann, A. E., Lipke, E., &amp; Wolf, H. (2019). Primary processing neuropils associated with the malleoli of camel spiders (Arachnida, Solifugae): A re-evaluation of axonal pathways. Zoological Letters, 5(1), 26. https://doi.org/10.1186/s40851-019-0137-z</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sombke, A., Lipke, E., Michalik, P., Uhl, G., &amp; Harzsch, S. (2015). Potential and limitations of X-Ray micro-computed tomography in arthropod neuroanatomy: A methodological and comparative survey. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 523(8), 1281-1295. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.23741</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stafstrom, J. A., Michalik, P., &amp; Hebets, E. A. (2017). Sensory system plasticity in a visually specialized, nocturnal spider. Scientific Reports, 7, 46627. https://doi.org/10.1038/srep46627</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Steinhoff, P. O. M., Liedtke, J., Sombke, A., Schneider, J. M., &amp; Uhl, G. (2018). Early environmental conditions affect the volume of higher-order brain centers in a jumping spider. Journal of Zoology, 304(3), 182-192. https://doi.org/10.1111/jzo.12512</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Steinhoff, P. O. M., Sombke, A., Liedtke, J., Schneider, J. M., Harzsch, S., &amp; Uhl, G. (2017). The synganglion of the jumping spider Marpissa muscosa (Arachnida: Salticidae): Insights from histology, immunohistochemistry and microCT analysis. Arthropod Structure and Development, 46(2), 156-170. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.asd.2016.11.003</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Steinhoff, P. O. M., Uhl, G., Harzsch, S., &amp; Sombke, A. (2020). Visual pathways in the brain of the jumping spider Marpissa muscosa. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 528(11), 1883-1902. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.2486</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Strausfeld, N. J., &amp; Andrew, D. R. (2011). A new view of insect-crustacean relationships I. Inferences from neural cladistics and comparative neuroanatomy. Arthropod Structure and Development, 40(3), 276-288. Arthropod Struct Dev. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.asd.2011.02.002</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Strausfeld, N. J., Barth, F. G., Weltzien, P., &amp; Barth, F. G. (1993). Two visual systems in one brain: Neuropils serving the principal eyes of the spider Cupiennius salei. Journal of Comparative Neurology, 328(1), 63-75. https://doi.org/10.1002/cne.903280105</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Strausfeld, N. J., Wolff, G. H., &amp; Sayre, M. E. (2020). Mushroom body evolution demonstrates homology and divergence across Pancrustacea. ELife, 9, e52411. eLife Sciences Publications Ltd. https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.52411</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swart, P., Wicklein, M., Sykes, D., Ahmed, F., &amp; Krapp, H. G. (2016). A quantitative comparison of micro-CT preparations in Dipteran flies. Scientific Reports, 6(1), 1-12. Nature Publishing Group. https://doi.org/10.1038/srep39380</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ubick, D., Paquin, P., Cushing, P. E., &amp; Roth, V. (2017). Spiders of North America an identification manual. In D. Ubick, P. Paquin, P. E. Cushing, &amp; V. Roth (Eds.), American Arachnological Society (2nd ed.) Keene, New Hampshire, American Arachnological Society, 425.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wickham, H. (2016). Ggplot2 elegant graphics for data analysis. Springer. Use R! Cham: Springer International Publishing. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-0-387-98141-3</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wickham, H., François, R., Henry, L., &amp; Müller, K. (2021). dplyr: A Grammar of Data Manipulation. 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
