<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35592534</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>21</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">2052-2975</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>47</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Season>Apr-May</Season>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>New microbes and new infections</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>New Microbes New Infect</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Potential association between bacterial infections and ischemic stroke based on fifty case-control studies: A systematic review and meta-analysis.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>100980</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>100980</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">100980</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.nmni.2022.100980</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Stroke is considered as one of the most important concerns in health care centers around the world. By definition there are two types of stroke including ischemic stroke and hemorrhagic stroke. Approximately three-quarters of stroke cases are ischemic strokes, which occur due to several risk factors such as hypertension, obesity, atherosclerosis, diabetes mellitus, osteoarthritis, and inflammatory responses. In recent years, infectious diseases have noticed as a new risk factor for ischemic stroke. Given the importance of the issue, some bacteria that cause chronic infections, especially <i>Chlamydia pneumonia</i>, <i>Helicobacter pylori</i>, <i>Mycoplasma pneumonia</i>, <i>Mycobacterium tuberculosis</i>, and <i>Coxiella burnetii</i> have been considered.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">In the present meta-analysis, we reviewed 50 case-control studies and assessed the possible association of bacterial infections with the occurrence of ischemic stroke.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">We analyzed the information of 33,978 participants in several nested case-control studies, and ultimately showed that bacterial infections could increase the risk of ischemic stroke. Our results suggest that bacterial infections significantly increase in the risk of ischemic stroke (OR: 1.704; 1.57-1.84 with 95% CIs; <i>p</i> value = 0.01).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">In this meta-analysis, a significant relationship was observed between infection by three bacteria such as <i>C. pneumoniae</i>, <i>H. pylori</i>, and <i>M. tuberculosis</i> with the occurrence of ischemic stroke. Furthermore, due to the similarity between TLRVYK domain in β2-glycoprotein-I and TLRVYK peptide in various of microorganisms, produced antibodies against pathogens interact with β2-glycoprotein-I, hence the cross-reaction phenomenon increases the positive relationship between infectious diseases and ischemic stroke.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Keikha</LastName>
            <ForeName>M</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Antimicrobial Resistance Research Center, Mashhad University of Medical Sciences, Mashhad, Iran.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Microbiology and Virology, Faculty of Medicine, Mashhad University of Medical Sciences, Mashhad, Iran.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Karbalaei</LastName>
            <ForeName>M</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Microbiology and Virology, School of Medicine, Jiroft University of Medical Sciences, Jiroft, Iran.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>04</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>New Microbes New Infect</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101624750</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2052-2975</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Bacterial infection</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Chlamydia pneumonia</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Helicobacter pylori</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mycobacterium tuberculosis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Mycoplasma pneumonia</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ischemic stroke</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">meta-analysis</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>4</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>8</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
          <Hour>2</Hour>
          <Minute>25</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35592534</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9112101</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.nmni.2022.100980</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">S2052-2975(22)00032-4</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Campbell B.C., De Silva D.A., Macleod M.R., Coutts S.B., Schwamm L.H., Davis S.M., et al.  Ischaemic stroke. Nature Rev Dise Prim. 2019;5(1):1–22.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnson C.O., Nguyen M., Roth G.A., Nichols E., Alam T., Abate D., et al.  Global, regional, and national burden of stroke, 1990–2016: a systematic analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2016. Lancet Neurol. 2019;18(5):439–458.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6494974</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30871944</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Budzyński J., Wiśniewska J., Ciecierski M., Kędzia A. Association between bacterial infection and peripheral vascular disease: a review. Int J Angiol. 2016;25(1):3–13.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4760071</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26900306</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roth G.A., Johnson C., Abajobir A., Abd-Allah F., Abera S.F., Abyu G., et al.  Global, regional, and national burden of cardiovascular diseases for 10 causes, 1990 to 2015. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2017;70(1):1–25.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5491406</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28527533</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lucchese G., Flöel A., Stahl B. Cross-reactivity as a mechanism linking infections to stroke. Front Neurol. 2019;10:469.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6528689</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31156531</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Budzyński J., Koziński M., Kłopocka M., Kubica J.M., Kubica J. Clinical significance of Helicobacter pylori infection in patients with acute coronary syndromes: an overview of current evidence. Clin Res Cardiol. 2014;103(11):855–886.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24817551</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kukreja N., Koslowski M., Insall R. Angiolymphoid hyperplasia with eosinophilia presenting as an axillary artery aneurysm. Case Rep. 2011;2011</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sessa R., Di Pietro M., Filardo S., Turriziani O. Infectious burden and atherosclerosis: a clinical issue. World J Clin Case: WJCC. 2014;2(7):240.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen B.F., Xu X., Deng Y., Ma S.C., Tang L.Q., Zhang S.B., et al.  Relationship between Helicobacter pylori infection and serum interleukin-18 in patients with carotid atherosclerosis. Helicobacter. 2013;18(2):124–128.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23121308</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen J., Zhu M., Ma G., Zhao Z., Sun Z. Chlamydia pneumoniae infection and cerebrovascular disease: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Neurol. 2013;13(1):183.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4222774</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24261578</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen Y.-W., Umeda M., Nagasawa T., Takeuchi Y., Huang Y., Inoue Y., et al.  Periodontitis may increase the risk of peripheral arterial disease. Europ J Vasc Endovasc Surg. 2008;35(2):153–158.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McCaughey C., Murray L.J., McKenna J.P., Coyle P.V., O'Neill H.J., Wyatt D.E., et al.  Lack of association between serological evidence of past Coxiella burnetii infection and incident ischaemic heart disease: nested case-control study. BMC Infect Dise. 2005;5(1):1–5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Keikha M., Eslami M., Yousefi B., Ali-Hassanzadeh M., Kamali A., Yousefi M., et al.  HCV genotypes and their determinative role in hepatitis C treatment. Virusdisease. 2020;31(3):235–240.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7459022</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32904762</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kelton J.G., Neame P.B., Gauldie J., Hirsh J. Elevated platelet-associated IgG in the thrombocytopenia of septicemia. New England J Med. 1979;300(14):760–764.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">423910</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Whincup P.H., Mendall M.A., Perry I.J., Strachan D.P., Walker M. Prospective relations between Helicobacter pylori infection, coronary heart disease, and stroke in middle aged men. Heart. 1996;75(6):568–572.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC484378</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8697158</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elkind M.S., Lin I.-F., Grayston J., Sacco R.L. Chlamydia pneumoniae and the risk of first ischemic stroke: the Northern Manhattan Stroke Study. Stroke. 2000;31(7):1521–1525.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10884447</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grau A.J., Buggle F., Lichy C., Brandt T., Becher H., Rudi J. Helicobacter pylori infection as an independent risk factor for cerebral ischemia of atherothrombotic origin. J Neurol Sci. 2001;186(1–2):1–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11412864</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Antonio Ponzetto M., Alberto Marchet M., Rinaldo Pellicano M., Nicoletta Lovera M., Gigliola Chianale M., Marcello Nobili M. Association of H elicobacter pylori infection with ischemic stroke of non-cardiac origin: the BAT. MA. N. Project study. Hepato-gastroenterology. 2002;49:631–634.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12063957</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pietroiusti A., Diomedi M., Silvestrini M., Cupini L.M., Luzzi I., Gomez-Miguel M.J., et al.  Cytotoxin-associated gene-A–positive Helicobacter pylori strains are associated with atherosclerotic stroke. Circulation. 2002;106(5):580–584.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12147540</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Majka J., Róg T., Konturek P.C., Konturek S., Bielanski W., Kowalsky M., et al.  Influence of chronic Helicobacter pylori infection on CR ischemic cerebral stroke risk factors. Med Sci Monitor. 2002;8(10)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Madre J.G., Garcia J.R., Gonzalez R.C., Montero J.M., Paniagua E.B., Escribano J.G., et al.  Association between seropositivity to Chlamydia pneumoniae and acute ischaemic stroke. Europ J Neurol. 2002;9(3):303–306.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tarnacka B., Gromadzka Gy, Członkowska A. Increased circulating immune complexes in acute stroke: the triggering role of Chlamydia pneumoniae and cytomegalovirus. Stroke. 2002;33(4):936–940.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11935040</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tanne D., Haim M., Boyko V., Goldbourt U., Reshef T., Adler Y., et al.  Prospective study of Chlamydia pneumoniae IgG and IgA seropositivity and risk of incident ischemic stroke. Cerebrovasc Dise. 2003;16(2):166–170.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Müller J., Møller D.S., Kjær M., Nyvad O., Larsen N.A., Pedersen E.B. Chlamydia pneumoniae DNA in peripheral blood mononuclear cells in healthy control subjects and patients with diabetes mellitus, acute coronary syndrome, stroke, and arterial hypertension. Scand J Infect Dise. 2003;35(10):704–712.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kawamoto R., Kajiwara T., Oka Y., Takagi Y. An association between an antibody against Chlamydia pneumoniae and ischemic stroke in elderly Japanese. Intern Med. 2003;42(7):571–575.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12879948</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gabrielli M., Santoliquido A., Cremonini F., Cicconi V., Candelli M., Serricchio M., et al.  CagA-positive cytotoxic H. pylori strains as a link between plaque instability and atherosclerotic stroke. Europ Heart J. 2004;25(1):64–68.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moayyedi P., Carter A., Braunholtz D., Catto A. Helicobacter pylori infection in subjects with acute ischaemic stroke. Digest Liver Dise. 2003;35(1):16–19.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ngeh J., Goodbourn C. Chlamydia pneumoniae, Mycoplasma pneumoniae, and Legionella pneumophila in elderly patients with stroke (C-PEPS, M-PEPS, L-PEPS) A case-control study on the infectious burden of atypical respiratory pathogens in elderly patients with acute cerebrovascular disease. Stroke. 2005;36(2):259–265.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15625297</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Voorend M., Faber C.G., van der Ven A.J., Kessels F., Bruggeman C.A., Lodder J. Chlamydia pneumoniae is a likely risk factor for ischemic stroke in young patients. J Stroke Cerebrovasc Dise. 2004;13(2):85–91.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ngeh J., Gupta S., Goodbourn C., Panayiotou B., McElligott G. Chlamydia pneumoniae in elderly patients with stroke (C-PEPS): a case-control study on the seroprevalence of Chlamydia pneumoniae in elderly patients with acute cerebrovascular disease. Cerebrovasc Dise. 2003;15(1–2):11–16.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Anzini A., Cassone A., Rasura M., Ciervo A., Beccia M., Di Lisi F., et al.  Chlamydia pneumoniae infection in young stroke patients: a case–control study. Europ J Neurol. 2004;11(5):321–327.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Masoud S., Arami M., Kucheki E. Association between infection with Helicobacter pylori and cerebral noncardioembolic ischemic stroke. Neurol India. 2005;53(3):303.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16230797</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kongoji M., Kamo T., Ikejima H., Yamamoto H., Yamamoto Y., Matsuda T. Detection of Chlamydia pneumoniae in blood of stroke patients. Ensho Saisei. 2005;25(1):55–59.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wohlschlaeger J., Wimmer M.L., Nägler D.K., Haberl R., Weis S. Identification of Chlamydia pneumoniae in intracranial and extracranial arteries in patients with stroke and in controls: combined immunohistochemical and polymerase chain reaction analyses. Human Pathol. 2005;36(4):395–402.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15892001</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sawayama Y., Ariyama I., Hamada M., Otaguro S., Machi T., Taira Y., et al.  Association between chronic Helicobacter pylori infection and acute ischemic stroke: Fukuoka Harasanshin Atherosclerosis Trial (FHAT) Atherosclerosis. 2005;178(2):303–309.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15694938</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johnsen S.P., Overvad K., Østergaard L., Tjønneland A., Husted S.E., Sørensen H.T. Chlamydia pneumoniae seropositivity and risk of ischemic stroke. Europ J Epidemiol. 2005;20(1):59–65.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elkind M.S., Tondella M.L.C., Feikin D.R., Fields B.S., Homma S., Di Tullio M.R. Seropositivity to Chlamydia pneumoniae is associated with risk of first ischemic stroke. Stroke. 2006;37(3):790–795.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16424371</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Park M.H., Min J.Y., Koh S.B., Kim B.J., Park M.K., Park K.W., et al.  Helicobacter pylori infection and the CD14 C (− 260) T gene polymorphism in ischemic stroke. Thrombosis Res. 2006;118(6):671–677.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Njamnshi A.K., Blackett K.N., Mbuagbaw J.N., Gumedze F., Gupta S., Wiysonge C.S. Chronic Chlamydia pneumoniae infection and stroke in Cameroon: a case-control study. Stroke. 2006;37(3):796–799.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16469962</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Piechowski-Jóźwiak B., Mickielewicz A., Gaciong Z., Berent H., Kwieciński H. Elevated levels of anti-Chlamydia pneumoniae IgA and IgG antibodies in young adults with ischemic stroke. Acta Neurol Scand. 2007;116(3):144–149.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17714326</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ashtari F., Shaigannezhad V., Saberi A., Rabiei E.  2008. Relationship between Helicobacter pylori immunoglobulin G antibody and thrombotic ischemic stroke.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lin T.-M., Chen C.-H., Wu H.-L., Wang C.-H., Chen Y.-L., Eng H.-L. The association of C (–260)→ T polymorphism in CD14 promoter and Chlamydia pneumoniae infection in ischemic stroke patients. Am J Clin Pathol. 2008;130(4):595–601.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18794053</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bandaru V., Laxmi V., Neeraja M., Alladi S., Meena A., Borgohain R., et al.  Chlamydia pneumoniae antibodies in various subtypes of ischemic stroke in Indian patients. J Neurol Sci. 2008;272(1–2):115–122.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18571201</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Bastiani R., Gabrielli M., Ubaldi E., Benedetto E., Sanna G., Cottone C., et al.  High prevalence of Cag-A positive H. pylori strains in ischemic stroke: a primary care multicenter study. Helicobacter. 2008;13(4):274–277.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18665936</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bandaru V.S., Boddu D.B., Laxmi V., Neeraja M., Kaul S. Seroprevalence of Chlamydia pneumoniae antibodies in stroke in young. Canad J Neurol Sci. 2009;36(6):725–730.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19960750</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gagliardi R.J., Caiaffa-Filho H.H. Chlamydia pneumoniae and stroke: is there a direct relationship? Arquivos de neuro-psiquiatria. 2009;67(3A):600–604.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19722034</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mousavi S.A., Ataei B., Karimi I., Ashrafi K. Helicobacter pylori serum antibody titers in patients with cerebral non-cardioembolic ischemic stroke. J Res Med Sci: Off J Isfahan Univ Med Sci. 2011;16(Suppl. 1):S407.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rai N., Choudhary R., Bhatia R., Singh M., Tripathi M., Prasad K., et al.  Chlamydia pneumoniae seropositivity in adults with acute ischemic stroke: a case–control study. Ann Indian Acad Neurol. 2011;14(2):93.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3141495</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21808469</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ķēniņa V., Auce P., Priede Z., Millers A. The relationship between seropositivity against chlamydia pneumoniae and stroke and its subtypes in a Latvian population. Medicina. 2011;47(12):96.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hasan Z.N. Association of Chlamydia pneumoniae serology and ischemic stroke. South Med J. 2011;104(5):319–321.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21606708</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bandaru V.S., Boddu D.B., Mridula K.R., Akhila B., Alladi S., Laxmi V., et al.  Outcome of chlamydia pneumoniae associated acute ischemic stroke in elderly patients: a case–control study. Clin Neurol Neurosurg. 2012;114(2):120–123.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22030154</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rasura M., Anzini A., Mascellino M.T. Chlamydia pneumoniae infection and PFO-associated ischemic stroke. Stroke. 2000;31(10):2517–2527.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11022264</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hassanein K.M., Mostafa M.S., Monaeim A.A. The effect of cag A-positive Helicobacter pylori infection on vascular risk factors and the development of ischemic stroke. Int J. 2014;2(9):576–582.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eini P., Keramat F., Farajpoor N. The association between Chlamydia pneumoniae infection and ischemic stroke. Avicenna J Clin Microbiol Infect. 2014;1(3):22165.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reza E.R., Melody O.N., Mahdie M., Masoume A., Nargess G.  2014. Comparison of antibody against chlamydophila pneumoniae in patients with brain ischemic stroke.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu C.-H., Chen L.-S., Yen M.-F., Chiu Y.-H., Fann C.-Y., Chen H.-H., et al.  Does non-central nervous system tuberculosis increase the risk of ischemic stroke? A population-based propensity score-matched follow-up study. PloS One. 2014;9(7)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sheu J.-J., Chiou H.-Y., Kang J.-H., Chen Y.-H., Lin H.-C. Tuberculosis and the risk of ischemic stroke: a 3-year follow-up study. Stroke. 2010;41(2):244–249.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20035070</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Srivastava M.P., Bhasin A., Chaudhry R., Sharma S., Subbaiah V., Bhatia R., et al.  Novel inflammatory biomarkers and their correlation to Chlamydia pneumoniae titres in acute ischemic stroke. J Stroke Cerebrovasc Dise. 2014;23(9):2391–2396.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sagar V., Zafar K.S., Kumar G., Veeramachaneni R., Indurkar P.S. A study of Helicobacter pylori infection in patients of ischemic cerebro vascular stroke. Int J Res Med Sci. 2016;4:589–592.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cook P.J., Honeybourne D., Lip G.Y., Beevers D.G., Wise R., Davies P. Chlamydia pneumoniae antibody titers are significantly associated with acute stroke and transient cerebral ischemia: the West Birmingham Stroke Project. Stroke. 1998;29(2):404–410.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9472881</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heuschmann P.U., Neureiter D., Gesslein M., Craiovan B., Maass M., Faller G., et al.  Association between infection with Helicobacter pylori and Chlamydia pneumoniae and risk of ischemic stroke subtypes: results from a population-based case-control study. Stroke. 2001;32(10):2253–2258.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11588309</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roham M., Anbari K., Mirhabibi S., Goudarzi G. The seroprevalence of Mycoplasma pneumoniae IgM and IgG antibodies in patients with ischemic stroke. Iran J Microbiol. 2016;8(6):383.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5420393</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28491249</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ahmadi-Salmasi B., Amiri-Nikpour M.R., Faraj S.  2017. Investigating the correlation between level OF igg antibodies against H. PYLORI and acute NON-cardioembolic ischemic stroke IN adults.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mrđen A., Včev A., Nakić D., Balen S., Ivanac K., Duka Glavor K. Helicobacter pylori infection and acute stroke. Coll Antropol. 2017;41(4):371–375.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rasura M., Anzini A., Mascellino M.T. Chlamydia pneumoniae infection and PFO-associated ischemic stroke. Stroke. 2000;31(10):2519–2520.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11022089</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hassanein K.M., Mostafa M.S., Monaeim A.A. The effect of cag A-positive Helicobacter pylori infection on vascular risk factors and the development of ischemic stroke. Int J. 2014;2(9):576–582.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Simanek A.M., Dowd J.B., Pawelec G., Melzer D., Dutta A., Aiello A.E. Seropositivity to cytomegalovirus, inflammation, all-cause and cardiovascular disease-related mortality in the United States. PloS One. 2011;6(2)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grau A.J., Urbanek C., Palm F. Common infections and the risk of stroke. Nature Rev Neurol. 2010;6(12):681–694.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21060340</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fugate J.E., Lyons J.L., Thakur K.T., Smith B.R., Hedley-Whyte E.T., Mateen F.J. Infectious causes of stroke. Lancet Infect Dise. 2014;14(9):869–880.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Feingold K.R., Grunfeld C. The effect of inflammation and infection on lipids and lipoproteins. Endotext. 2019 [Internet]</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Szeto C.-C., Chow K.-M., Woo K.-S., Chook P., Kwan B.C.-H., Leung C.-B., et al.  Carotid intima media thickness predicts cardiovascular diseases in Chinese predialysis patients with chronic kidney disease. J Am Soc Nephrol. 2007;18(6):1966–1972.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17494886</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blank M., Israeli E., Cervera R.  Infection and autoimmunity. Elsevier; 2015. The infectious origin of the anti-phospholipid syndrome; pp. 681–696.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Christen U.  Elsevier; Autoantibodies: 2014. Molecular mimicry; pp. 35–42.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blank M., Krause I., Fridkin M., Keller N., Kopolovic J., Goldberg I., et al.  Bacterial induction of autoantibodies to β2-glycoprotein-I accounts for the infectious etiology of antiphospholipid syndrome. J Clin Invest. 2002;109(6):797–804.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC150905</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11901188</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pierangeli S.S., Blank M., Liu X., Espinola R., Fridkin M., Ostertag M.V., et al.  A peptide that shares similarity with bacterial antigens reverses thrombogenic properties of antiphospholipid antibodies in vivo. J Autoimmun. 2004;22(3):217–225.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15041042</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Horn M. Chlamydiae as symbionts in eukaryotes. Annu Rev Microbiol. 2008;62:113–131.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18473699</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Joshi R., Khandelwal B., Joshi D., Gupta O.P. Chlamydophila pneumoniae infection and cardiovascular disease. N Am J Med Sci. 2013;5(3):169.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3632020</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23626952</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sander D., Winbeck K., Klingelhöfer, Etgen T., Conrad B. Progression of early carotid atherosclerosis is only temporarily reduced after antibiotic treatment of Chlamydia pneumoniae seropositivity. Circulation. 2004;109(8):1010–1015.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14769704</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Illoh K.O., Illoh O.C., Feseha H.B., Hallenbeck J.M. Antibiotics for vascular diseases: a meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Atherosclerosis. 2005;179(2):403–412.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15777560</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Keikha M., Karbalaei M. Correlation between the geographical origin of Helicobacter pylori homB-positive strains and their clinical outcomes: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Gastroenterol. 2021;21(1):1–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7789364</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33407176</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Keikha M., Ali-Hassanzadeh M., Karbalaei M. Association of Helicobacter pylori vacA genotypes and peptic ulcer in Iranian population: a systematic review and meta-analysis. BMC Gastroenterol. 2020;20(1):1–11.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kodaman N., Pazos A., Schneider B.G., Piazuelo M.B., Mera R., Sobota R.S., et al.  Human and Helicobacter pylori coevolution shapes the risk of gastric disease. Proc National Acad Sci. 2014;111(4):1455–1460.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Youssefi M., Ghazvini K., Farsiani H., Tafaghodi M., Keikha M. A systematic review and meta-analysis of outcomes of infection with Helicobacter pylori dupA+ strains in Iranian patients. Gene Rep. 2020;19:100650.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Amieva M., Peek R.M., Jr. Pathobiology of Helicobacter pylori–induced gastric cancer. Gastroenterology. 2016;150(1):64–78.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4691563</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26385073</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kusters J.G., Van Vliet A.H., Kuipers E.J. Pathogenesis of Helicobacter pylori infection. Clin Microbiol Rev. 2006;19(3):449–490.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1539101</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16847081</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huang W.-S., Tseng C.-H., Lin C.-L., Tsai C.-H., Kao C.-H. Helicobacter pylori infection increases subsequent ischemic stroke risk: a nationwide population-based retrospective cohort study. QJM: Int J Med. 2014;107(12):969–975.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khademi F., Vaez H., Momtazi-Borojeni A.A., Majnooni A., Banach M., Sahebkar A. Bacterial infections are associated with cardiovascular disease in Iran: a meta-analysis. Arch Med Sci: AMS. 2019;15(4):902.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6657263</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31360186</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guleria R., Nisar N., Chawla T.C., Biswas N.R. Mycoplasma pneumoniae and central nervous system complications: a review. J Lab Clin Med. 2005;146(2):55–63.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16099235</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parrott G.L., Kinjo T., Fujita J. A compendium for Mycoplasma pneumoniae. Front Microbiol. 2016;7:513.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4828434</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27148202</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ionita C.C., Siddiqui A.H., Levy E.I., Hopkins L.N., Snyder K.V., Gibbons K.J. Acute ischemic stroke and infections. J Stroke Cerebrovasc Dise. 2011;20(1):1–9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Keikha M., Soleimanpour S., Eslami M., Yousefi B., Karbalaei M. The mystery of tuberculosis pathogenesis from the perspective of T regulatory cells. Meta Gene. 2020;23:100632.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Keikha M., Karbalaei M. Overview on coinfection of HTLV-1 and tuberculosis: mini-review. J Clin Tubercul Other Mycobacter Dise. 2021;23:100224.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salindri A.D., Wang J.-Y., Lin H.-H., Magee M.J. Post-tuberculosis incidence of diabetes, myocardial infarction, and stroke: retrospective cohort analysis of patients formerly treated for tuberculosis in Taiwan, 2002–2013. Int J Infect Dise. 2019;84:127–130.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Authority E.F.S. The European Union one health 2019 zoonoses report. Efsa J. 2021;19(2)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vinacci G., Tcheumeni C.N., Coskun O., Saddiki F.Z., Maria F.D., Dinu M., et al.  White thrombus as a possible feature of atypical stroke etiology: Coxiella burnetii as the primary cause of acute ischemic stroke. Int Neuroradiol. 2021</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Million M., Bardin N., Bessis S., Nouiakh N., Douliery C., Edouard S., et al.  Thrombosis and antiphospholipid antibody syndrome during acute Q fever: a cross-sectional study. Medicine. 2017;96(29)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Melenotte C., Protopopescu C., Million M., Edouard S., Carrieri M.P., Eldin C., et al.  Clinical features and complications of Coxiella burnetii infections from the French National Reference Center for Q fever. JAMA Network Open. 2018;1(4):e181580.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6324270</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30646123</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>González-Quijada S., Mora-Simón M., Martin-Ezquerro A. Reply: Coxiella burnetii and complicated atherosclerosis: perhaps neither innocent nor bystanders. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2015;21(4):e30–e31.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25658570</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>González-Quijada S., Mora-Simón M., Martin-Ezquerro A. Association between serological evidence of past Coxiella burnetii infection and atherosclerotic cardiovascular disease in elderly patients. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2014;20(9):873–878.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24438335</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>González-Quijada S., Salazar-Thieroldt E., Mora-Simón M. Persistent Q fever and ischaemic stroke in elderly patients. Clin Microbiol Infect. 2015;21(4):362–367.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25630457</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
