<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35591876</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>21</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2230-2034</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>13</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Veterinary medicine (Auckland, N.Z.)</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Vet Med (Auckl)</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>A Seroprevalence Study of Brucellosis in Boran (Zebu) Breeds of Pastoral Area.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>91</StartPage>
          <EndPage>99</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>91-99</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.2147/VMRR.S361226</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The economic and health implications of brucellosis are of particular concern in developing countries, primarily in the vulnerable sector of rural herders. A cross-sectional study was done in Boran breeds to estimate the seroprevalence of bovine brucellosis, identify risk variables and assess public health implications in Borena zone, Oromia region, Ethiopia in the questionnaire survey.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The sampling animals were chosen from smallholders using a simple random sampling procedure. The study involved a total of 788 animals. Animals of both sex and different age groups with the age of 6 months or above found during the study interval were included. The Rose Bengal plate test was used to screen sera, and positive samples were subsequently retested using a Direct Enzyme-Linked Immunosorbent Assay for confirmation.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The overall seroprevalence of bovine brucellosis was 7.6% (60/788) in the Direct Enzyme-Linked Immunosorbent Assay test. Herd size, age, history of abortion, testicular hygroma, and retained fetal membrane were statistical significance for the <i>Brucella</i> seropositivity (P&lt;0.05). Whereas, district, sex, body condition score, and management did not influence the disease occurrence (P&gt;0.05). The majority of the participants, 91.7% (55/60) did not aware of the zoonotic implications of brucellosis. Only 10% (6/60) of interviewed respondents disposed of aborted fetuses and retained fetal membrane properly and the rest 90% (54/60) left in the environment. Ninety percent and 83.3% of the respondents revealed that they consumed raw milk and meat, respectively.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The presence of <i>Brucella</i> infection is highly correlated with age, history of abortion, and testicular hygroma. According to the collected data: sex, body condition score, district, and management had no statistically significant effect on <i>Brucella</i> occurrence. The majority of respondents were unaware of the disease's zoonotic consequences. Finally, creating community awareness about its transmission, zoonotic significance, and hygienic practices were recommended.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 Tilahun et al.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tilahun</LastName>
            <ForeName>Alebachew</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-1624-6606</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>University of Gondar, College of Veterinary Medicine and Animal Science, Department of Veterinary Clinical Medicine, Gondar, Ethiopia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kegno</LastName>
            <ForeName>Silto</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Wolaita Sodo University, School of Veterinary Medicine, Sodo, Ethiopia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Adugna</LastName>
            <ForeName>Takele</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>University of Gondar, College of Veterinary Medicine and Animal Science, Department of Veterinary Clinical Medicine, Gondar, Ethiopia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mamuye</LastName>
            <ForeName>Dinberu</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Dilla University, Dilla, Ethiopia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Vet Med (Auckl)</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101724251</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2230-2034</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Boran breed</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">D-ELISA</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rose Bengal plate test</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">bovine brucellosis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">seroprevalence</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors report no conflicts of interest in relation to this work.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
          <Hour>2</Hour>
          <Minute>14</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35591876</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9113493</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/VMRR.S361226</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">361226</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>OIE. Bovine Brucellosis: In Manual of Diagnostic Tests and Vaccines for Terrestrial Animals. Paris: OIE; 2009:409–435.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Godfroid J, Scholz H, Barbier T, et al. Brucellosis at the animal/ecosystem/human interface at the beginning of the 21st century. Prev Vet Med. 2011;102(2):118–131. doi:10.1016/j.prevetmed.2011.04.007</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.prevetmed.2011.04.007</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21571380</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>OIE. Infection with Brucella Abortus, Brucella Melitensis and Brucella Suis. Rome: OIE (World Organization for Animal Health); 2016.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ragan VE. The animal and plant health inspection service (APHIS) brucellosis eradication program in the United States. Vet Microbiol. 2002;90(1–4):11–18. doi:10.1016/S0378-1135(02)00240-7</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0378-1135(02)00240-7</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12414129</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bekele A, Molla B, Asfaw Y, et al. Bovine brucellosis in ranches and farms in South-eastern Ethiopia. Bull Anim Health Prod Afr. 2000;48:13–17.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kassahun A
Epidemiology of bovine brucellosis in cattle and its seroprevalence in animal health professionals in Sidama Zone, Southern Ethiopia. Master of Science thesis Addis Ababa University, Faculty of Veterinary Medicine. Debre Zeit, Ethiopia; 2004.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Berhe G, Belihu K, Asfaw Y. Seroepidemiological investigation of bovine brucellosis in the extensive cattle production system of Tigray region of Ethiopia. Int J Appl Res Vet Med. 2007;5:65.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kebede T, Ejeta G, Ameni G. Seroprevalence of bovine brucellosis in smallholder farms in central Ethiopia (Wuchale-Jida district). Rev Med Vet. 2008;159:3.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Adane B, Kemal K, Begna F. Survey of bovine brucellosis in pastoral and agro-pastoral production systems of Borana zone, Southern Ethiopia and its public health implications. Ethiop Vet J. 2012;16(1):1–3.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Radostits O, Gay C, Hinchcliff K, et al. Veterinary Medicine, a Textbook of the Disease of Cattle, Sheep, Goat, Pigs and Horses. 10th ed. London, New York: Saunders Elsevier; 2007:2047.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bayemi P, Mah G, Ndamukong K, et al. Bovine brucellosis in cattle production Systems in the Western Highlands of Cameroon. Int J Anim Biol. 2015;1:38–44.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thrusfield M. Veterinary Epidemiology. 3rd ed. Burgh, U.K: LTD Black well science; 2007:182–189.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sayour AE, Elbauomy EM, Abdel-Hamid NH, et al. Validation of different versions of the card or rose-Bengal test for the diagnosis of Brucella melitensis infection in ruminants. Alex J Vet Sci. 2017;53:1</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nour B, Tawor B, Gebril A, et al. Evaluation of simple and rapid specific IgM/IgG flow assay and some methods used in diagnosis of brucellosis in Gezira and Blue Nile States, Sudan. Clin Microbiol. 2015;4:1000187. doi:10.4172/2327-5073.1000187</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4172/2327-5073.1000187</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mekonnen H, Kalayou S, Kyule M. Serological survey of bovine brucellosis in barka and arado breeds (Bos indicus) of Western Tigray, Ethiopia. Prev Vet Med. 2010;94(1–2):28–35. doi:10.1016/j.prevetmed.2009.12.001</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.prevetmed.2009.12.001</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20034690</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gebreyohans T. A survey of bovine brucellosis in Addis Ababa dairy farms. DVM Thesis FVM, AAU. Debre-Zeit, Ethiopia; 2004.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Degefu H, Mohamud M, Hailemelekot M, et al. Seroprevalence of bovine brucellosis in agro pastoral areas of Jijjiga zone of Somali National Regional State, Eastern Ethiopia. Ethiop Vet J. 2011;15. doi:10.2147/VMRR.S338930</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/VMRR.S338930</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yayeh T. A survey of bovine brucellosis in selected areas of North Gondar Zone, Ethiopia. Debre Zeit, Ethiopia: DVM Thesis Faculty of Veterinary Medicine, Addis Ababa University; 2003.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eshetu Y, Kassahun J, Abebe P, et al. Seroprevalence study of brucellosis on dairy cattle in Addis Ababa, Ethiopia. Bulletin of Animal health and Production in Africa; 2005.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mussie H, Hailemelekot M. Sero-prevalence study of brucellosis in cattle and human in Bahirdar milk shed. Master’s Thesis, FVM, AAU. Debre Zeit, Ethiopia; 2005.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Junaidu A, Oboegbulem S, Salihu M. Seroprevalence of brucellosis in prison farm in Sokoto. Nigeria; 2008.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bedane AK, Feyissa K, Fanos B, Demelash T, Asseged B. Survey of bovine brucellosis in pastoral and agro-pastoral production systems of borana zone, southern Ethiopia and its public health implications. LARCJI. 2012;3:53–59.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hirsh D, Zee Y. Veterinary Microbiology. USA: Black well science. Inc Pp; 1999:115–249.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Megersa B, Biffa D, Abunna F, et al. Seroprevalence of brucellosis and its contribution to abortion in cattle, camel, and goat kept under pastoral management in Borana, Ethiopia. Trop Anim Health Prod. 2011;43:651–656. doi:10.1007/s11250-010-9748-2</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11250-010-9748-2</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21088890</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Awah-Ndukum J, Mouiche M, Bayang H, et al. Seroprevalence and associated risk factors of brucellosis among indigenous cattle in the Adamawa and north regions of Cameroon. Vet Med Int. 2018;2018. doi:10.1155/2018/3468596</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1155/2018/3468596</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kungu JM. Seroprevalence and risk factors of brucellosis in cattle in Gulu and Amuru Districts, Northern Uganda. Makerere University; 2011.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muma J, Munyeme M, Matope G, et al. Brucella seroprevalence of the Kafue lechwe (Kobus leche kafuensis) and Black lechwe (Kobus leche smithemani): exposure associated to contact with cattle. Prev Vet Med. 2011;100(3–4):256–260. doi:10.1016/j.prevetmed.2011.03.013</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.prevetmed.2011.03.013</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21536335</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Asmare K, Asfaw Y, Gelaye E, et al. Brucellosis in extensive management system of Zebu cattle in Sidama Zone, Southern Ethiopia. Afr J Agric Res. 2010;5:257–263.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ibrahim N, Belihu K, Lobago F, et al. Sero-prevalence of bovine brucellosis and its risk factors in Jimma zone of Oromia Region, South-western Ethiopia. Trop Anim Health Prod. 2010;42:35–40. doi:10.1007/s11250-009-9382-z</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11250-009-9382-z</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19543803</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Megersa B. An epidemiological study of major camel diseases in the Borana lowland, Southern Ethiopia. Oslo: Drylands Coordination Grou; 2010.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Seifert H. Brucellosis. Trop Anim Health. 2nd ed. Dordrecht Kluwer Academic Publishers group; 1996:358–362.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Genene R, Desalew M, Yamuah L, et al. Human brucellosis in traditional pastoral communities in Ethiopia. Int J Trop Med. 2009;4:59–64.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abbas B, Agab H. A review of camel brucellosis. Prev Vet Med. 2002;55(1):47–56. doi:10.1016/S0167-5877(02)00055-7</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0167-5877(02)00055-7</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12324206</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Habtamu T
Pastoralism and agro-pastoralism systems. In the Proceedings of the 18 Annual Conference of the Ethiopian Veterinary Association (EVA) held in Addis Ababa. Ethiopia; 2004.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khan HAA, Akram W, Shad SA, et al. A cross sectional survey of knowledge, attitude and practices related to house flies among dairy farmers in Punjab, Pakistan. J Ethnobiol Ethnomed. 2013;9:1–10. doi:10.1186/1746-4269-9-18</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1746-4269-9-18</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3560114</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23281594</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
