<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35596110</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>20</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1179-2019</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>21</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Paediatric drugs</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Paediatr Drugs</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Impact of Antiseizure Medications on Appetite and Weight in Children.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40272-022-00505-2</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>There are numerous potential factors that may affect growth in children with epilepsy, and these must be evaluated in any child with appetite and weight concerns. Antiseizure medications (ASMs) have potential adverse effects, and many may affect appetite, thus impacting normal growth and weight gain. The aim of this review is to focus on the impact of both epilepsy and ASMs on appetite and weight in children. We systematically reviewed studies using Medline assessing the impact of ASMs on appetite and weight in children. Eligible studies included randomized controlled trials and open-label studies (open-label extension and interventional) that targeted or included the pediatric population (0-18 years of age). Each study was classified using the American Academy of Neurology (AAN) Classification of Evidence for Therapeutic Studies, and the level of evidence for impact on appetite and weight in children was graded. ASMs associated with decreased appetite and/or weight loss include fenfluramine, topiramate, zonisamide, felbamate, rufinamide, stiripentol, cannabidiol, brivaracetam and ethosuximide; ASMs with minimal impact on weight and appetite in children include oxcarbazepine, eslicarbazepine, lamotrigine, levetiracetam, lacosamide, carbamazepine, vigabatrin and clobazam. The ASM most robustly associated with increased appetite and/or weight gain is valproic acid; however, both pregabalin and perampanel may also lead to modest weight gain or increased appetite in children. Certain ASMs may impact both appetite and weight, which may lead to increased morbidity of the underlying disease and impaired adherence to the treatment regimen.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Nature Switzerland AG.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y">
            <LastName>Buraniqi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ersida</ForeName>
            <Initials>E</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Child and Adolescent Neurology, Department of Neurology, Mayo Clinic, 200 First St., SW, Rochester, MN, 55905, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y">
            <LastName>Dabaja</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hicham</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Child and Adolescent Neurology, Department of Neurology, Mayo Clinic, 200 First St., SW, Rochester, MN, 55905, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wirrell</LastName>
            <ForeName>Elaine C</ForeName>
            <Initials>EC</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3015-8282</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Child and Adolescent Neurology, Department of Neurology, Mayo Clinic, 200 First St., SW, Rochester, MN, 55905, USA. Wirrell.Elaine@mayo.edu.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>Switzerland</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Paediatr Drugs</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>100883685</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1174-5878</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
          <Hour>23</Hour>
          <Minute>34</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35596110</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40272-022-00505-2</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40272-022-00505-2</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Camfield CS, Camfield PR, Gordon K, Wirrell E, Dooley JM. Incidence of epilepsy in childhood and adolescence: a population-based study in Nova Scotia from 1977 to 1985. Epilepsia. 1996;37(1):19–23.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8603618</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1157.1996.tb00506.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wirrell EC. Predicting pharmacoresistance in pediatric epilepsy. Epilepsia. 2013;54(s2):19–22.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23646966</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.12179</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sultana B, Panzini MA, Veilleux Carpentier A, Comtois J, Rioux B, Gore G, et al. Incidence and prevalence of drug-resistant epilepsy: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Neurology. 2021;96(17):805–17.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33722992</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000011839</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wirrell EC, Grossardt BR, Wong-Kisiel LC, Nickels KC. Incidence and classification of new-onset epilepsy and epilepsy syndromes in children in Olmsted County, Minnesota from 1980 to 2004: a population-based study. Epilepsy Res. 2011;95(1–2):110–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21482075</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3260338</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eplepsyres.2011.03.009</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eschbach K, Scarbro S, Juarez-Colunga E, Allen V, Hsu S, Knupp K. Growth and endocrine function in children with Dravet syndrome. Seizure. 2017;52:117–22.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29031192</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.seizure.2017.09.021</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fortin O, Vincelette C, Khan AQ, Berrahmoune S, Dassi C, Karimi M, et al. Seizures in Sotos syndrome: phenotyping in 49 patients. Epilepsia Open. 2021;6(2):425–30.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34033256</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">8166795</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/epi4.12484</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reilly S, Skuse D. Characteristics and management of feeding problems of young children with cerebral palsy. Dev Med Child Neurol. 1992;34(5):379–88.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1592191</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1469-8749.1992.tb11449.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stallings VA, Zemel BS, Davies JC, Cronk CE, Charney EB. Energy expenditure of children and adolescents with severe disabilities: a cerebral palsy model. Am J Clin Nutr. 1996;64(4):627–34.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8839510</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ajcn/64.4.627</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nutrition in neurologically impaired children. Paediatr Child Health. 2009;14(6):395–401.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dassa Y, Crosnier H, Chevignard M, Viaud M, Personnier C, Flechtner I, et al. Pituitary deficiency and precocious puberty after childhood severe traumatic brain injury: a long-term follow-up prospective study. Eur J Endocrinol. 2019;180(5):281–90.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30884465</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1530/EJE-19-0034</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bjorholt PG, Nakken KO, Rohme K, Hansen H. Leisure time habits and physical fitness in adults with epilepsy. Epilepsia. 1990;31(1):83–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2303016</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1157.1990.tb05364.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Steinhoff BJ, Neususs K, Thegeder H, Reimers CD. Leisure time activity and physical fitness in patients with epilepsy. Epilepsia. 1996;37(12):1221–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8956856</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1157.1996.tb00557.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Howard GM, Radloff M, Sevier TL. Epilepsy and sports participation. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2004;3(1):15–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14728909</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/00149619-200402000-00004</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wong J, Wirrell E. Physical activity in children/teens with epilepsy compared with that in their siblings without epilepsy. Epilepsia. 2006;47(3):631–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16529632</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1167.2006.00478.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pohl D, Alpous A, Hamer S, Longmuir PE. Higher screen time, lower muscular endurance, and decreased agility limit the physical literacy of children with epilepsy. Epilepsy Behav. 2019;90:260–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30342878</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yebeh.2018.05.010</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Capovilla G, Kaufman KR, Perucca E, Moshe SL, Arida RM. Epilepsy, seizures, physical exercise, and sports: A report from the ILAE Task Force on Sports and Epilepsy. Epilepsia. 2016;57(1):6–12.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26662920</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.13261</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Auvin S, Wirrell E, Donald KA, Berl M, Hartmann H, Valente KD, et al. Systematic review of the screening, diagnosis, and management of ADHD in children with epilepsy Consensus paper of the Task Force on Comorbidities of the ILAE Pediatric Commission. Epilepsia. 2018;59(10):1867–80.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30178479</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.14549</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baweja R, Hale DE, Waxmonsky JG. Impact of CNS stimulants for attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder on growth: epidemiology and approaches to management in children and adolescents. CNS Drugs. 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Serretti A, Mandelli L. Antidepressants and body weight: a comprehensive review and meta-analysis. J Clin Psychiatry. 2010;71(10):1259–72.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21062615</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4088/JCP.09r05346blu</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Osborn DP, Petersen I, Beckley N, Walters K, Nazareth I, Hayes J. Weight change over two years in people prescribed olanzapine, quetiapine and risperidone in UK primary care: Cohort study in THIN, a UK primary care database. J Psychopharmacol. 2018;32(10):1098–103.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29938561</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0269881118780011</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Neurology AAo. Clinical Practice Guideline Process Manual, 2004. https://www.aan.com/siteassets/home-page/policy-and-guidelines/guidelines/about-guidelines/2004_guideline_process.pdf . Last Accessed Nov 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Holmes GL. Cognitive impairment in epilepsy: the role of network abnormalities. Epileptic Disord Int Epilepsy J Videotape. 2015;17(2):101–16.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1684/epd.2015.0739</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schoonjans A-S, Lagae L, Ceulemans B. Low-dose fenfluramine in the treatment of neurologic disorders: experience in Dravet syndrome. Ther Adv Neurol Disord. 2015;8(6):328–38.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26600876</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4643872</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1756285615607726</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fuller RW, Snoddy HD, Robertson DW. Mechanisms of effects of d-Fenfluramine on brain serotonin metabolism in rats: Uptake inhibition versus release. Pharmacol Biochem Behav. 1988;30(3):715–21.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2463643</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0091-3057(88)90089-5</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Samanin R, Mennini T, Bendotti C, Barone D, Caccia S, Garattini S. Evidence that central 5-HT2 receptors do not play an important role in the anorectic activity of d-fenfluramine in the rat. Neuropharmacology. 1989;28(5):465–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2566947</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0028-3908(89)90080-4</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Halford JCG, Boyland EJ, Lawton CL, Blundell JE, Harrold JA. Serotonergic Anti-Obesity Agents. Drugs. 2011;71(17):2247–55.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22085383</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/11596680-000000000-00000</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Choi S, Blake V, Cole S, Fernstrom JD. Effects of chronic fenfluramine administration on hypothalamic neuropeptide mRNA expression. Brain Res. 2006;1087(1):83–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16626640</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.brainres.2006.02.129</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grignaschi G, Sironi F, Samanin R. The 5-HT1B receptor mediates the effect of d-fenfluramine on eating caused by intra-hypothalamic injection of neuropeptide Y. Eur J Pharmacol. 1995;274(1):221–4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7768274</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0014-2999(94)00766-Z</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abenhaim L, Moride Y, Brenot F, Rich S, Benichou J, Kurz X, et al. Appetite-suppressant drugs and the risk of primary pulmonary hypertension. N Engl J Med. 1996;335(9):609–16.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8692238</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJM199608293350901</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ceulemans B, Boel M, Leyssens K, Van Rossem C, Neels P, Jorens PG, et al. Successful use of fenfluramine as an add-on treatment for Dravet syndrome. Epilepsia. 2012;53(7):1131–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22554283</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1167.2012.03495.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schoonjans A-S, Marchau F, Paelinck BP, Lagae L, Gammaitoni A, Pringsheim M, et al. Cardiovascular safety of low-dose fenfluramine in Dravet syndrome: a review of its benefit-risk profile in a new patient population. Curr Med Res Opin. 2017;33(10):1773–81.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28704161</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/03007995.2017.1355781</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lagae L, Sullivan J, Knupp K, Laux L, Polster T, Nikanorova M, et al. Fenfluramine hydrochloride for the treatment of seizures in Dravet syndrome: a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Lancet. 2019;394(10216):2243–54.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31862249</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(19)32500-0</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nabbout R, Mistry A, Zuberi S, Villeneuve N, Gil-Nagel A, Sanchez-Carpintero R, et al. Fenfluramine for treatment-resistant seizures in patients with dravet syndrome receiving stiripentol-inclusive regimens: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Neurol. 2020;77(3):300–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31790543</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaneurol.2019.4113</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gil-Nagel A, Sullivan J, Ceulemans B, Wirrell E, Devinsky O, Nabbout R, et al. Treatment with fenfluramine in patients with Dravet syndrome has no long-term effects on weight and growth. Epilepsy Behav. 2021;122:108212.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34352670</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yebeh.2021.108212</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kawasaki H, Tancredi V, D’Arcangelo G, Avoli M. Multiple actions of the novel anticonvulsant drug topiramate in the rat subiculum in vitro. Brain Res. 1998;807(1):125–34.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9757016</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0006-8993(98)00785-9</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shank RP, Gardocki JF, Streeter AJ, Maryanoff BE. An overview of the preclinical aspects of topiramate: pharmacology, pharmacokinetics, and mechanism of action. Epilepsia. 2000;41(s1):3–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10768292</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1157.2000.tb02163.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ben-Menachem E. Weight issues for people with epilepsy—A review. Epilepsia. 2007;48(s9):42–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18047602</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1167.2007.01402.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ben-Menachem E, Axelsen M, Johanson EH, Stagge A, Smith U. Predictors of weight loss in adults with topiramate-treated epilepsy. Obes Res. 2003;11(4):556–62.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12690085</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/oby.2003.78</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arroyo S, Anhut H, Kugler AR, Lee CM, Knapp LE, Garofalo EA, et al. Pregabalin add-on treatment: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, dose-response study in adults with partial seizures. Epilepsia. 2004;45(1):20–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14692903</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.0013-9580.2004.31203.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Freitag FG, Collins SD, Carlson HA, Goldstein J, Saper J, Silberstein S, et al. A randomized trial of divalproex sodium extended-release tablets in migraine prophylaxis. Neurology. 2002;58(11):1652–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12058094</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.58.11.1652</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dodick DW, Freitag F, Banks J, Saper J, Xiang J, Rupnow M, et al. Topiramate versus amitriptyline in migraine prevention: a 26-week, multicenter, randomized, double-blind, double-dummy, parallel-group noninferiority trial in adult migraineurs. Clin Ther. 2009;31(3):542–59.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19393844</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clinthera.2009.03.020</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wilding J, Gaal LV, Rissanen A, Vercruysse F, Fitchet M, for the O-SG. A randomized double-blind placebo-controlled study of the long-term efficacy and safety of topiramate in the treatment of obese subjects. International Journal of Obesity. 2004;28(11):1399-410.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stenlöf K, Rössner S, Vercruysse F, Kumar A, Fitchet M, Sjöström L, et al. Topiramate in the treatment of obese subjects with drug-naive type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2007;9(3):360–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17391164</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1463-1326.2006.00618.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gadde KM, Allison DB, Ryan DH, Peterson CA, Troupin B, Schwiers ML, et al. Effects of low-dose, controlled-release, phentermine plus topiramate combination on weight and associated comorbidities in overweight and obese adults (CONQUER): a randomised, placebo-controlled, phase 3 trial. Lancet. 2011;377(9774):1341–52.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21481449</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(11)60205-5</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garvey WT, Ryan DH, Look M, Gadde KM, Allison DB, Peterson CA, et al. Two-year sustained weight loss and metabolic benefits with controlled-release phentermine/topiramate in obese and overweight adults (SEQUEL): a randomized, placebo-controlled, phase 3 extension study. Am J Clin Nutr. 2012;95(2):297–308.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22158731</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/ajcn.111.024927</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arroyo S, Dodson WE, Privitera MD, Glauser TA, Naritoku DK, Dlugos DJ, et al. Randomized dose-controlled study of topiramate as first-line therapy in epilepsy. Acta Neurol Scand. 2005;112(4):214–22.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16146489</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0404.2005.00485.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Glauser TA, Dlugos DJ, Dodson WE, Grinspan A, Wang S, Wu SC. Topiramate monotherapy in newly diagnosed epilepsy in children and adolescents. J Child Neurol. 2007;22(6):693–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17641254</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0883073807303997</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gilliam FG, Veloso F, Bomhof MA, Gazda SK, Biton V, Ter Bruggen JP, et al. A dose-comparison trial of topiramate as monotherapy in recently diagnosed partial epilepsy. Neurology. 2003;60(2):196–202.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12552030</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/01.WNL.0000048200.12663.BC</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ford LM, Todd MJ, Polverejan E. Effect of topiramate monotherapy on height in newly diagnosed children with epilepsy. Pediatr Neurol. 2013;48(5):383–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23583056</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pediatrneurol.2012.12.028</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elterman RD, Glauser TA, Wyllie E, Reife R, Wu SC, Pledger G. A double-blind, randomized trial of topiramate as adjunctive therapy for partial-onset seizures in children Topiramate YP Study Group. Neurology. 1999;52(7):1338–44.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10227615</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.52.7.1338</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ritter F, Glauser TA, Elterman RD, Wyllie E. Effectiveness, tolerability, and safety of topiramate in children with partial-onset seizures Topiramate YP Study Group. Epilepsia. 2000;41(S1):82–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10768307</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1157.2000.tb02178.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sachdeo RC, Glauser TA, Ritter F, Reife R, Lim P, Pledger G. A double-blind, randomized trial of topiramate in Lennox-Gastaut syndrome Topiramate YL Study Group. Neurology. 1999;52(9):1882–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10371538</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.52.9.1882</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Glauser TA, Levisohn PM, Ritter F, Sachdeo RC. Topiramate in Lennox-Gastaut syndrome: open-label treatment of patients completing a randomized controlled trial Topiramate YL Study Group. Epilepsia. 2000;41(S1):86–90.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10768308</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1157.2000.tb02179.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grosso S, Franzoni E, Iannetti P, Incorpora G, Cardinali C, Toldo I, et al. Efficacy and safety of topiramate in refractory epilepsy of childhood: long-term follow-up study. J Child Neurol. 2005;20(11):893–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16417859</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/08830738050200110601</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kluger G, Schäuble B, Rettig K, Schreiner A, Holthausen H. Effectiveness of low dose of topiramate following rapid titration in multiply handicapped children and difficult-to-treat epilepsy. Neuropediatrics. 2009;40(2):61–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19809933</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0029-1234103</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coppola G, Caliendo G, Terracciano MM, Buono S, Pellegrino L, Pascotto A. Topiramate in refractory partial-onset seizures in children, adolescents and young adults: a multicentric open trial. Epilepsy Res. 2001;43(3):255–60.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11248537</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0920-1211(00)00202-3</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mikaeloff Y, de Saint-Martin A, Mancini J, Peudenier S, Pedespan JM, Vallée L, et al. Topiramate: efficacy and tolerability in children according to epilepsy syndromes. Epilepsy Res. 2003;53(3):225–32.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12694931</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0920-1211(03)00028-7</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Manitpisitkul P, Shalayda K, Todd M, Wang SS, Ness S, Ford L. Pharmacokinetics and safety of adjunctive topiramate in infants (1–24 months) with refractory partial-onset seizures: a randomized, multicenter, open-label phase 1 study. Epilepsia. 2013;54(1):156–64.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23157581</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.12019</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Puri V, Ness S, Sattaluri SJ, Wang S, Todd M, Yuen E, et al. Long-Term open-label study of adjunctive topiramate in infants with refractory partial-onset seizures. J Child Neurol. 2011;26(10):1271–83.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21673279</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0883073811406982</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Takeoka M, Holmes GL, Thiele E, Bourgeois BF, Helmers SL, Duffy FH, et al. Topiramate and metabolic acidosis in pediatric epilepsy. Epilepsia. 2001;42(3):387–92.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11442157</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1528-1157.2001.04500.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Faught E, Ayala R, Montouris GG, Leppik IE, Group ZT. Randomized controlled trial of zonisamide for the treatment of refractory partial-onset seizures. Neurology. 2001;57(10):1774–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11723262</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.57.10.1774</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shinnar S, Pellock JM, Conry JA. Open-label, long-term safety study of zonisamide administered to children and adolescents with epilepsy. Eur J Paediatr Neurol. 2009;13(1):3–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18343174</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejpn.2008.01.004</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guerrini R, Rosati A, Segieth J, Pellacani S, Bradshaw K, Giorgi L. A randomized phase III trial of adjunctive zonisamide in pediatric patients with partial epilepsy. Epilepsia. 2013;54(8):1473–80.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23837461</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.12233</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guerrini R, Rosati A, Bradshaw K, Giorgi L. Adjunctive zonisamide therapy in the long-term treatment of children with partial epilepsy: results of an open-label extension study of a phase III, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Epilepsia. 2014;55(4):568–78.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24621319</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.12548</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lagae L, Meshram C, Giorgi L, Patten A. Effects of adjunctive zonisamide treatment on weight and body mass index in children with partial epilepsy. Acta Neurol Scand. 2015;131(5):341–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25659828</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ane.12373</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rho JM, Donevan SD, Rogawski MA. Mechanism of action of the anticonvulsant felbamate: opposing effects on N-methyl-D-aspartate and γ-aminobutyric acidA receptors. Ann Neurol. 1994;35(2):229–34.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8109904</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.410350216</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Efficacy of Felbamate in Childhood Epileptic Encephalopathy (Lennox-Gastaut Syndrome). N Engl J Med. 1993;328(1):29-33.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hosain S, Nagarajan L, Carson D, Solomon G, Mast J, Labar D. Felbamate for refractory infantile spasms. J Child Neurol. 1997;12(7):466–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9373806</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/088307389701200711</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pellock JM. Felbamate. Epilepsia. 1999;40(Suppl 5):S57-62.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10530695</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1157.1999.tb00920.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hussain SA, Asilnejad B, Heesch J, Navarro M, Ji M, Shrey DW, et al. Felbamate in the treatment of refractory epileptic spasms. Epilepsy Res. 2020;161:106284.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32058261</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eplepsyres.2020.106284</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cilio MR, Kartashov AI, Vigevano F. The long-term use of felbamate in children with severe refractory epilepsy. Epilepsy Res. 2001;47(1):1–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11673015</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0920-1211(01)00290-X</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bergen DC, Ristanovic RK, Waicosky K, Kanner A, Hoeppner TJ. Weight loss in patients taking felbamate. Clin Neuropharmacol. 1995;18(1)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Canger R, Vignoli A, Bonardi R, Guidolin L. Felbamate in refractory partial epilepsy. Epilepsy Res. 1999;34(1):43–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10194111</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0920-1211(98)00098-9</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wheless JW, Conry J, Krauss G, Mann A, LoPresti A, Narurkar M. Safety and tolerability of rufinamide in children with epilepsy: a pooled analysis of 7 clinical studies. J Child Neurol. 2009;24(12):1520–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19955344</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0883073809350508</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arzimanoglou A, Ferreira JA, Satlin A, Mendes S, Williams B, Critchley D, et al. Safety and pharmacokinetic profile of rufinamide in pediatric patients aged less than 4 years with Lennox-Gastaut syndrome: An interim analysis from a multicenter, randomized, active-controlled, open-label study. Eur J Paediatr Neurol. 2016;20(3):393–402.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26805435</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejpn.2015.12.015</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim SH, Eun SH, Kang HC, Kwon EJ, Byeon JH, Lee YM, et al. Rufinamide as an adjuvant treatment in children with Lennox-Gastaut syndrome. Seizure. 2012;21(4):288–91.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22421185</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.seizure.2012.02.006</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moavero R, Cusmai R, Specchio N, Fusco L, Capuano A, Curatolo P, et al. Rufinamide efficacy and safety as adjunctive treatment in children with focal drug resistant epilepsy: the first Italian prospective study. Epilepsy Res. 2012;102(1):94–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22677424</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eplepsyres.2012.05.004</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coppola G, Grosso S, Franzoni E, Veggiotti P, Zamponi N, Parisi P, et al. Rufinamide in children and adults with Lennox-Gastaut syndrome: First Italian multicenter experience. Seizure. 2010;19(9):587–91.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20888268</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.seizure.2010.09.008</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coppola G, Grosso S, Franzoni E, Veggiotti P, Zamponi N, Parisi P, et al. Rufinamide in refractory childhood epileptic encephalopathies other than Lennox-Gastaut syndrome. Eur J Neurol. 2011;18(2):246–51.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20666837</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1468-1331.2010.03113.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ohtsuka Y, Yoshinaga H, Shirasaka Y, Takayama R, Takano H, Iyoda K. Rufinamide as an adjunctive therapy for Lennox-Gastaut syndrome: a randomized double-blind placebo-controlled trial in Japan. Epilepsy Res. 2014;108(9):1627–36.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25219353</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eplepsyres.2014.08.019</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ohtsuka Y, Yoshinaga H, Shirasaka Y, Takayama R, Takano H, Iyoda K. Long-term safety and seizure outcome in Japanese patients with Lennox-Gastaut syndrome receiving adjunctive rufinamide therapy: An open-label study following a randomized clinical trial. Epilepsy Res. 2016;121:1–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26827266</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eplepsyres.2016.01.002</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Glauser T, Kluger G, Sachdeo R, Krauss G, Perdomo C, Arroyo S. Rufinamide for generalized seizures associated with Lennox-Gastaut syndrome. Neurology. 2008;70(21):1950–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18401024</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/01.wnl.0000303813.95800.0d</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chiron C, Marchand MC, Tran A, Rey E, d’Athis P, Vincent J, et al. Stiripentol in severe myoclonic epilepsy in infancy: a randomised placebo-controlled syndrome-dedicated trial STICLO study group. Lancet. 2000;356(9242):1638–42.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11089822</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(00)03157-3</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Farwell JR, Anderson GD, Kerr BM, Tor JA, Levy RH. Stiripentol in atypical absence seizures in children: an open trial. Epilepsia. 1993;34(2):305–11.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8453942</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1157.1993.tb02416.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thanh TN, Chiron C, Dellatolas G, Rey E, Pons G, Vincent J, et al. Long-term efficacy and tolerance of stiripentaol in severe myoclonic epilepsy of infancy (Dravet’s syndrome). Arch Pediatr. 2002;9(11):1120–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12503502</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0929-693X(02)00090-8</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Perez J, Chiron C, Musial C, Rey E, Blehaut H, d’Athis P, et al. Stiripentol: efficacy and tolerability in children with epilepsy. Epilepsia. 1999;40(11):1618–26.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10565591</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1157.1999.tb02048.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Myers KA, Lightfoot P, Patil SG, Cross JH, Scheffer IE. Stiripentol efficacy and safety in Dravet syndrome: a 12-year observational study. Dev Med Child Neurol. 2018;60(6):574–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29473155</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/dmcn.13704</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rosati A, Boncristiano A, Doccini V, Pugi A, Pisano T, Lenge M, et al. Long-term efficacy of add-on stiripentol treatment in children, adolescents, and young adults with refractory epilepsies: A single center prospective observational study. Epilepsia. 2019;60(11):2255–62.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31630399</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.16363</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Devinsky O, Cross JH, Laux L, Marsh E, Miller I, Nabbout R, et al. Trial of cannabidiol for drug-resistant seizures in the dravet syndrome. N Engl J Med. 2017;376(21):2011–20.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28538134</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1611618</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thiele EA, Marsh ED, French JA, Mazurkiewicz-Beldzinska M, Benbadis SR, Joshi C, et al. Cannabidiol in patients with seizures associated with Lennox-Gastaut syndrome (GWPCARE4): a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled phase 3 trial. Lancet. 2018;391(10125):1085–96.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29395273</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(18)30136-3</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miller I, Scheffer IE, Gunning B, Sanchez-Carpintero R, Gil-Nagel A, Perry MS, et al. Dose-ranging effect of adjunctive oral cannabidiol vs placebo on convulsive seizure frequency in dravet syndrome: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Neurol. 2020;77(5):613–21.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32119035</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaneurol.2020.0073</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>UCB Inc, Smyrna, GA, USA. Briviact® (brivaracetam) Prescribing Information. 2018. https://www.briviact.com/briviact-PI.pdf . Last Accessed Nov 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Feyissa AM. Brivaracetam in the treatment of epilepsy: a review of clinical trial data. Neuropsychiatr Dis Treat. 2019;15:2587–600.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31571877</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6750854</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/NDT.S143548</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu E, Dilley D, McDonough B, Stockis A, Daniels T. Safety and tolerability of adjunctive brivaracetam in pediatric patients &lt; 16 years with epilepsy: an open-label trial. Paediatr Drugs. 2019;21(4):291–301.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31250322</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6682562</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40272-019-00332-y</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Glauser TA, Cnaan A, Shinnar S, Hirtz DG, Dlugos D, Masur D, et al. Ethosuximide, valproic acid, and lamotrigine in childhood absence epilepsy. N Engl J Med. 2010;362(9):790–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20200383</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2924476</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa0902014</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Glauser TA, Cnaan A, Shinnar S, Hirtz DG, Dlugos D, Masur D, et al. Ethosuximide, valproic acid, and lamotrigine in childhood absence epilepsy: initial monotherapy outcomes at 12 months. Epilepsia. 2013;54(1):141–55.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23167925</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.12028</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Owens MJ, Nemeroff CB. Pharmacology of valproate. Psychopharmacol Bull. 2003;37(Suppl 2):17–24.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14624230</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sharpe C, Wolfson T, Trauner DA. Weight gain in children treated with valproate. J Child Neurol. 2009;24(3):338–41.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19258293</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0883073808323023</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Egger J, Brett EM. Effects of sodium valproate in 100 children with special reference to weight. Br Med J (Clin Res Ed). 1981;283(6291):577–81.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.283.6291.577</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verrotti A, D’Egidio C, Mohn A, Coppola G, Chiarelli F. Weight gain following treatment with valproic acid: pathogenetic mechanisms and clinical implications. Obes Rev. 2011;12(5):e32-43.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20880119</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1467-789X.2010.00800.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dinesen H, Gram L, Andersen T, Dam M. Weight gain during treatment with valproate. Acta Neurol Scand. 1984;70(2):65–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6435386</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0404.1984.tb00804.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Isojärvi JI, Rättyä J, Myllylä VV, Knip M, Koivunen R, Pakarinen AJ, et al. Valproate, lamotrigine, and insulin-mediated risks in women with epilepsy. Ann Neurol. 1998;43(4):446–51.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9546324</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.410430406</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Covanis A, Gupta AK, Jeavons PM. Sodium valproate: monotherapy and polytherapy. Epilepsia. 1982;23(6):693–720.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6816580</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1157.1982.tb05085.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lakhanpal D, Kaur G. Valproic acid alters GnRH-GABA interactions in cycling female rats. Cell Mol Neurobiol. 2007;27(8):1069–83.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17823865</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10571-007-9201-x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brown R, Imran SA, Ur E, Wilkinson M. Valproic acid and CEBPalpha-mediated regulation of adipokine gene expression in hypothalamic neurons and 3T3-L1 adipocytes. Neuroendocrinology. 2008;88(1):25–34.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18212493</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000113927</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Howard JK, Flier JS. Attenuation of leptin and insulin signaling by SOCS proteins. Trends Endocrinol Metab. 2006;17(9):365–71.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17010638</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tem.2006.09.007</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lihn AS, Pedersen SB, Richelsen B. Adiponectin: action, regulation and association to insulin sensitivity. Obes Rev. 2005;6(1):13–21.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15655035</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1467-789X.2005.00159.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Qiao L, Schaack J, Shao J. Suppression of adiponectin gene expression by histone deacetylase inhibitor valproic acid. Endocrinology. 2006;147(2):865–74.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16282359</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/en.2005-1030</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rauchenzauner M, Laimer M, Luef G, Kaser S, Engl J, Tatarczyk T, et al. Adiponectin receptor R1 is upregulated by valproic acid but not by topiramate in human hepatoma cell line, HepG2. Seizure. 2008;17(8):723–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18424096</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.seizure.2008.03.002</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rauchenzauner M, Haberlandt E, Scholl-Bürgi S, Ernst B, Hoppichler F, Karall D, et al. Adiponectin and visfatin concentrations in children treated with valproic acid. Epilepsia. 2008;49(2):353–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18070089</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1167.2007.01460.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gungor S, Yücel G, Akinci A, Tabel Y, Ozerol IH, Yologlu S. The role of ghrelin in weight gain and growth in epileptic children using valproate. J Child Neurol. 2007;22(12):1384–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18174556</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0883073807307096</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Greco R, Latini G, Chiarelli F, Iannetti P, Verrotti A. Leptin, ghrelin, and adiponectin in epileptic patients treated with valproic acid. Neurology. 2005;65(11):1808–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16344528</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/01.wnl.0000187074.27586.d1</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Demir E, Aysun S. Weight gain associated with valproate in childhood. Pediatr Neurol. 2000;22(5):361–4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10913727</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0887-8994(00)00133-8</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pylvänen V, Pakarinen A, Knip M, Isojärvi J. Characterization of insulin secretion in Valproate-treated patients with epilepsy. Epilepsia. 2006;47(9):1460–4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16981861</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1167.2006.00546.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pylvänen V, Pakarinen A, Knip M, Isojärvi J. Insulin-related metabolic changes during treatment with valproate in patients with epilepsy. Epilepsy Behav. 2006;8(3):643–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16600693</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yebeh.2006.02.008</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Luef G, Abraham I, Hoppichler F, Trinka E, Unterberger I, Bauer G, et al. Increase in postprandial serum insulin levels in epileptic patients with valproic acid therapy. Metabolism. 2002;51(10):1274–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12370846</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/meta.2002.34708</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shi Y, Kanaani J, Menard-Rose V, Ma YH, Chang PY, Hanahan D, et al. Increased expression of GAD65 and GABA in pancreatic beta-cells impairs first-phase insulin secretion. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2000;279(3):E684–94.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10950838</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.2000.279.3.E684</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beydoun A, Uthman BM, Kugler AR, Greiner MJ, Knapp LE, Garofalo EA. Safety and efficacy of two pregabalin regimens for add-on treatment of partial epilepsy. Neurology. 2005;64(3):475–80.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15699378</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/01.WNL.0000150932.48688.BE</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Belcastro V, D’Egidio C, Striano P, Verrotti A. Metabolic and endocrine effects of valproic acid chronic treatment. Epilepsy Res. 2013;107(1–2):1–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24076030</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eplepsyres.2013.08.016</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Espinosa PS, Salazar JC, Yu L, Mendiondo MS, Robertson WC, Baumann RJ. Lack of valproic acid-associated weight gain in prepubertal children. Pediatr Neurol. 2008;39(3):177–80.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18725062</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pediatrneurol.2008.05.006</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tanamachi Y, Saruwatari J, Noai M, Kamihashi R, Soraoka H, Yoshimori Y, et al. Possible association between moderate intellectual disability and weight gain in valproic acid-treated patients with epilepsy. Neuropsychiatr Dis Treat. 2015;11:1007–14.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25897238</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4397927</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van Hooft JA, Dougherty JJ, Endeman D, Nichols RA, Wadman WJ. Gabapentin inhibits presynaptic Ca(2+) influx and synaptic transmission in rat hippocampus and neocortex. Eur J Pharmacol. 2002;449(3):221–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12167463</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0014-2999(02)02044-7</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lauria-Horner BA, Pohl RB. Pregabalin: a new anxiolytic. Expert Opin Investig Drugs. 2003;12(4):663–72.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12665421</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1517/13543784.12.4.663</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shokry DA, El Nabrawy N, Yassa HD, Gaber SS, Batiha GE, Welson NN. Pregabalin induced reproductive toxicity and body weight changes by affecting caspase3 and leptin expression: protective role of wheat germ oil. Life Sci. 2020;260:118344.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32853651</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lfs.2020.118344</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>DeToledo JC, Toledo C, DeCerce J, Ramsay RE. Changes in body weight with chronic, high-dose gabapentin therapy. Ther Drug Monit. 1997;19(4):394–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9263379</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00007691-199708000-00006</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Appleton R, Fichtner K, LaMoreaux L, Alexander J, Halsall G, Murray G, et al. Gabapentin as add-on therapy in children with refractory partial seizures: a 12-week, multicentre, double-blind, placebo-controlled study Gabapentin Paediatric Study Group. Epilepsia. 1999;40(8):1147–54.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10448830</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1157.1999.tb00833.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Appleton R, Fichtner K, LaMoreaux L, Alexander J, Maton S, Murray G, et al. Gabapentin as add-on therapy in children with refractory partial seizures: a 24-week, multicentre, open-label study. Dev Med Child Neurol. 2001;43(4):269–73.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11305405</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0012162201000500</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Panebianco M, Al-Bachari S, Hutton JL, Marson AG. Gabapentin add-on treatment for drug-resistant focal epilepsy. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2021;1(1):1415.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>French J, Kwan P, Fakhoury T, Pitman V, DuBrava S, Knapp L, et al. Pregabalin monotherapy in patients with partial-onset seizures: a historical-controlled trial. Neurology. 2014;82(7):590–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24415567</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3963419</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000000119</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baulac M, Cavalcanti D, Semah F, Arzimanoglou A, Portal JJ. Gabapentin add-on therapy with adaptable dosages in 610 patients with partial epilepsy: an open, observational study The French Gabapentin Collaborative Group. Seizure. 1998;7(1):55–62.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9548227</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1059-1311(98)90009-7</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Antinew J, Pitrosky B, Knapp L, Almas M, Pitman V, Liu J, et al. Pregabalin as adjunctive treatment for focal onset seizures in pediatric patients: a randomized controlled trial. J Child Neurol. 2019;34(5):248–55.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30688135</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0883073818821035</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mann D, Antinew J, Knapp L, Almas M, Liu J, Scavone J, et al. Pregabalin adjunctive therapy for focal onset seizures in children 1 month to &lt;4 years of age: A double-blind, placebo-controlled, video-electroencephalographic trial. Epilepsia. 2020;61(4):617–26.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32189338</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.16466</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rogawski MA, Hanada T. Preclinical pharmacology of perampanel, a selective non-competitive AMPA receptor antagonist. Acta Neurol Scand Suppl. 2013;197:19–24.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ane.12100</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maldonado-Irizarry CS, Swanson CJ, Kelley AE. Glutamate receptors in the nucleus accumbens shell control feeding behavior via the lateral hypothalamus. J Neurosci. 1995;15(10):6779–88.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7472436</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6578022</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.15-10-06779.1995</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mietlicki-Baase EG, Ortinski PI, Reiner DJ, Sinon CG, McCutcheon JE, Pierce RC, et al. Glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor activation in the nucleus accumbens core suppresses feeding by increasing glutamatergic AMPA/kainate signaling. J Neurosci. 2014;34(20):6985–92.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24828651</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4019807</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.0115-14.2014</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zaccara G, Giovannelli F, Cincotta M, Verrotti A, Grillo E. The adverse event profile of perampanel: meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Eur J Neurol. 2013;20(8):1204–11.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23607817</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.12170</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iwaki H, Jin K, Sugawara N, Nakasato N, Kaneko S. Perampanel-induced weight gain depends on level of intellectual disability and its serum concentration. Epilepsy Res. 2019;152:1–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30852339</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eplepsyres.2019.02.011</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Piña-Garza JE, Espinoza R, Nordli D, Bennett DA, Spirito S, Stites TE, et al. Oxcarbazepine adjunctive therapy in infants and young children with partial seizures. Neurology. 2005;65(9):1370–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16275822</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/01.wnl.0000186800.18456.72</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bourgeois BF, D’Souza J. Long-term safety and tolerability of oxcarbazepine in children: a review of clinical experience. Epilepsy Behav. 2005;7(3):375–82.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16176888</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yebeh.2005.07.017</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coppola G, Franzoni E, Verrotti A, Garone C, Sarajlija J, Operto FF, et al. Levetiracetam or oxcarbazepine as monotherapy in newly diagnosed benign epilepsy of childhood with centrotemporal spikes (BECTS): an open-label, parallel group trial. Brain Dev. 2007;29(5):281–4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17055681</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.braindev.2006.09.008</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kirkham F, Auvin S, Moreira J, Gama H, Falcão AC, Rocha JF, et al. Efficacy and safety of eslicarbazepine acetate as adjunctive therapy for refractory focal-onset seizures in children: a double-blind, randomized, placebo-controlled, parallel-group, multicenter, phase-III clinical trial. Epilepsy Behav. 2020;105:106962.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32151803</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yebeh.2020.106962</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sankar R, Kirkham FJ, Holmes GL, Pina-Garza JE, Wheless J, Gama H, et al. Long-term safety and tolerability of adjunctive eslicarbazepine acetate in children with focal seizures. Epilepsy Behav. 2020;112:107458.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33181890</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yebeh.2020.107458</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Duchowny M, Pellock JM, Graf WD, Billard C, Gilman J, Casale E, et al. A placebo-controlled trial of lamotrigine add-on therapy for partial seizures in children. Lamictal Pediatric Partial Seizure Study Group. Neurology. 1999;53(8):1724–31.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10563619</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.53.8.1724</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coppola G, Pascotto A. Lamotrigine as add-on drug in children and adolescents with refractory epilepsy and mental delay: an open trial. Brain Dev. 1997;19(6):398–402.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9339867</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0387-7604(97)00046-6</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Egunsola O, Choonara I, Sammons HM. Safety of levetiracetam in paediatrics: a systematic review. PLoS ONE. 2016;11(3):149686.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0149686</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fattore C, Boniver C, Capovilla G, Cerminara C, Citterio A, Coppola G, et al. A multicenter, randomized, placebo-controlled trial of levetiracetam in children and adolescents with newly diagnosed absence epilepsy. Epilepsia. 2011;52(4):802–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21320119</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1167.2010.02976.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Glauser TA, Ayala R, Elterman RD, Mitchell WG, Van Orman CB, Gauer LJ, et al. Double-blind placebo-controlled trial of adjunctive levetiracetam in pediatric partial seizures. Neurology. 2006;66(11):1654–60.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16641323</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/01.wnl.0000217916.00225.3a</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Piña-Garza JE, Nordli DR Jr, Rating D, Yang H, Schiemann-Delgado J, Duncan B. Adjunctive levetiracetam in infants and young children with refractory partial-onset seizures. Epilepsia. 2009;50(5):1141–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19243423</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1167.2008.01981.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Farkas V, Steinborn B, Flamini JR, Zhang Y, Yuen N, Borghs S, et al. Efficacy and tolerability of adjunctive lacosamide in pediatric patients with focal seizures. Neurology. 2019;93(12):e1212–26.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31462582</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6808531</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000008126</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ferreira JA, Le Pichon JB, Abdelmoity AT, Dilley D, Dedeken P, Daniels T, et al. Safety and tolerability of adjunctive lacosamide in a pediatric population with focal seizures—an open-label trial. Seizure. 2019;71:166–73.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31374487</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.seizure.2019.05.016</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hmaimess G, Sabbagh S, Dirani M, Hotait M, Beydoun AA, Nasreddine W. Efficacy and tolerability of treatment with lacosamide in children: Postmarketing experience from the Middle East. Seizure. 2020;79:75–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32422546</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.seizure.2020.04.016</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huot S, Palfreyman MG. Effects of gamma-vinyl GABA on food intake of rats. Pharmacol Biochem Behav. 1982;17(1):99–106.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7122673</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0091-3057(82)90269-6</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chadwick D. Safety and efficacy of vigabatrin and carbamazepine in newly diagnosed epilepsy: a multicentre randomised double-blind study Vigabatrin European Monotherapy Study Group. Lancet. 1999;354(9172):13–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10406359</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(98)10531-7</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elterman RD, Shields WD, Mansfield KA, Nakagawa J. Randomized trial of vigabatrin in patients with infantile spasms. Neurology. 2001;57(8):1416–21.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11673582</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.57.8.1416</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lux AL, Edwards SW, Hancock E, Johnson AL, Kennedy CR, Newton RW, et al. The United Kingdom Infantile Spasms Study comparing vigabatrin with prednisolone or tetracosactide at 14 days: a multicentre, randomised controlled trial. Lancet. 2004;364(9447):1773–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15541450</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(04)17400-X</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Munn R, Farrell K. Open study of clobazam in refractory epilepsy. Pediatr Neurol. 1993;9(6):465–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7605555</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0887-8994(93)90026-9</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clobazam in treatment of refractory epilepsy: the Canadian experience. A retrospective study. Canadian Clobazam Cooperative Group. Epilepsia. 1991;32(3):407-16.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ng YT, Conry JA, Drummond R, Stolle J, Weinberg MA. Randomized, phase III study results of clobazam in Lennox-Gastaut syndrome. Neurology. 2011;77(15):1473–81.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21956725</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0b013e318232de76</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Conry JA, Ng YT, Kernitsky L, Mitchell WG, Veidemanis R, Drummond R, et al. Stable dosages of clobazam for Lennox-Gastaut syndrome are associated with sustained drop-seizure and total-seizure improvements over 3 years. Epilepsia. 2014;55(4):558–67.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24580023</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4303987</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.12561</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Conry JA, Ng YT, Paolicchi JM, Kernitsky L, Mitchell WG, Ritter FJ, et al. Clobazam in the treatment of Lennox-Gastaut syndrome. Epilepsia. 2009;50(5):1158–66.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19170737</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1167.2008.01935.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marchand V. Canadian Paediatric Society. NaGC nutrition in neurologically impaired children. Paediatr Child Health. 2009;16(6):395–401.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>White JR, Leppik IE, Beattie JL, Walczak TS, Tran TA, Rarick JO, et al. Long-term use of felbamate: clinical outcomes and effect of age and concomitant antiepileptic drug use on its clearance. Epilepsia. 2009;50(11):2390–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19563346</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1167.2009.02187.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Devinsky O, Patel AD, Thiele EA, Wong MH, Appleton R, Harden CL, et al. Randomized, dose-ranging safety trial of cannabidiol in Dravet syndrome. Neurology. 2018;90(14):1204.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000005254</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Devinsky O, Patel AD, Cross JH, Villanueva V, Wirrell EC, Privitera M, et al. Effect of cannabidiol on drop seizures in the lennox-gastaut syndrome. N Engl J Med. 2018;378(20):1888–97.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29768152</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1714631</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thiele EA, Bebin EM, Bhathal H, Jansen FE, Kotulska K, Lawson JA, et al. Add-on cannabidiol treatment for drug-resistant seizures in tuberous sclerosis complex: a placebo-controlled randomized clinical trial. JAMA Neurol. 2021;78(3):285–92.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33346789</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaneurol.2020.4607</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Devinsky O, Marsh E, Friedman D, Thiele E, Laux L, Sullivan J, et al. Cannabidiol in patients with treatment-resistant epilepsy: an open-label interventional trial. Lancet Neurol. 2016;15(3):270–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26724101</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1474-4422(15)00379-8</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Devinsky O, Nabbout R, Miller I, Laux L, Zolnowska M, Wright S, et al. Long-term cannabidiol treatment in patients with Dravet syndrome: an open-label extension trial. Epilepsia. 2019;60(2):294–302.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30582156</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.14628</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thiele E, Marsh E, Mazurkiewicz-Beldzinska M, Halford JJ, Gunning B, Devinsky O, et al. Cannabidiol in patients with Lennox-Gastaut syndrome: Interim analysis of an open-label extension study. Epilepsia. 2019;60(3):419–28.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30740695</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6850399</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.14670</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Steinhoff BJ, Christensen J, Doherty CP, Majoie M, De Backer M, Hellot S, et al. Effectiveness and tolerability of adjunctive brivaracetam in patients with focal seizures: Second interim analysis of 6-month data from a prospective observational study in Europe. Epilepsy Res. 2020;165:106329.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32623096</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eplepsyres.2020.106329</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schubert-Bast S, Willems LM, Kurlemann G, Knake S, Müller-Schlüter K, Rosenow F, et al. Postmarketing experience with brivaracetam in the treatment of focal epilepsy in children and adolescents. Epilepsy Behav. 2018;89:89–93.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30390435</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yebeh.2018.10.018</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Patel AD, Badalamenti V, Gasalla T, Elmoufti S, Elshoff JP. Safety and tolerability of adjunctive brivaracetam in children with focal seizures: Interim analysis of pooled data from two open-label trials. Eur J Paediatr Neurol. 2020;25:68–76.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31810577</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejpn.2019.11.007</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>O’Brien TJ, Borghs S, He Q, Schulz A-L, Yates S, Biton V. Long-term safety, efficacy, and quality of life outcomes with adjunctive brivaracetam treatment at individualized doses in patients with epilepsy: An up to 11-year, open-label, follow-up trial. Epilepsia. 2020;61(4):636–46.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32221987</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">7384045</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.16484</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Klein P, Schiemann J, Sperling MR, Whitesides J, Liang W, Stalvey T, et al. A randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, multicenter, parallel-group study to evaluate the efficacy and safety of adjunctive brivaracetam in adult patients with uncontrolled partial-onset seizures. Epilepsia. 2015;56(12):1890–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26471380</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.13212</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Toledo M, Brandt C, Quarato PP, Schulz AL, Cleveland JM, Wagener G, et al. Long-term safety, efficacy, and quality of life during adjunctive brivaracetam treatment in patients with uncontrolled epilepsy: An open-label follow-up trial. Epilepsy Behav. 2021;118:107897.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33780735</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yebeh.2021.107897</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Biton V, Levisohn P, Hoyler S, Vuong A, Hammer AE. Lamotrigine versus valproate monotherapy-associated weight change in adolescents with epilepsy: results from a post hoc analysis of a randomized, double-blind clinical trial. J Child Neurol. 2003;18(2):133–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12693782</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/08830738030180021701</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verity CM, Hosking G, Easter DJ. A multicentre comparative trial of sodium valproate and carbamazepine in paediatric epilepsy. The Paediatric EPITEG Collaborative Group. Dev Med Child Neurol. 1995;37(2):97–108.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7851677</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1469-8749.1995.tb11978.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wheless JW, Neto W, Wang S. Topiramate, carbamazepine, and valproate monotherapy: double-blind comparison in children with newly diagnosed epilepsy. J Child Neurol. 2004;19(2):135–41.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15072107</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/08830738040190020901</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coppola G, Auricchio G, Federico R, Carotenuto M, Pascotto A. Lamotrigine versus valproic acid as first-line monotherapy in newly diagnosed typical absence seizures: an open-label, randomized, parallel-group study. Epilepsia. 2004;45(9):1049–53.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15329068</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.0013-9580.2004.40903.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wirrell EC. Valproic acid-associated weight gain in older children and teens with epilepsy. Pediatr Neurol. 2003;28(2):126–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12699863</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0887-8994(02)00505-2</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Biton V, Mirza W, Montouris G, Vuong A, Hammer AE, Barrett PS. Weight change associated with valproate and lamotrigine monotherapy in patients with epilepsy. Neurology. 2001;56(2):172–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11160951</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.56.2.172</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beydoun A, Sackellares JC, Shu V. Safety and efficacy of divalproex sodium monotherapy in partial epilepsy: a double-blind, concentration-response design clinical trial Depakote Monotherapy for Partial Seizures Study Group. Neurology. 1997;48(1):182–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9008516</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.48.1.182</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marson AG, Al-Kharusi AM, Alwaidh M, Appleton R, Baker GA, Chadwick DW, et al. The SANAD study of effectiveness of valproate, lamotrigine, or topiramate for generalised and unclassifiable epilepsy: an unblinded randomised controlled trial. Lancet. 2007;369(9566):1016–26.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17382828</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2039891</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(07)60461-9</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marson A, Burnside G, Appleton R, Smith D, Leach JP, Sills G, et al. The SANAD II study of the effectiveness and cost-effectiveness of valproate versus levetiracetam for newly diagnosed generalised and unclassifiable epilepsy: an open-label, non-inferiority, multicentre, phase 4, randomised controlled trial. Lancet. 2021;397(10282):1375–86.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33838758</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">8047813</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(21)00246-4</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sidhu HS, Srinivas R, Sadhotra A. Evaluate the effects of long-term valproic acid treatment on metabolic profiles in newly diagnosed or untreated female epileptic patients: a prospective study. Seizure. 2017;48:15–21.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28365440</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.seizure.2017.03.007</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Park KM, Kim SH, Nho SK, Shin KJ, Park J, Ha SY, et al. A randomized open-label observational study to compare the efficacy and tolerability between topiramate and valproate in juvenile myoclonic epilepsy. J Clin Neurosci. 2013;20(8):1079–82.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23673144</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jocn.2012.10.020</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stephen LJ, Sills GJ, Leach JP, Butler E, Parker P, Hitiris N, et al. Sodium valproate versus lamotrigine: a randomised comparison of efficacy, tolerability and effects on circulating androgenic hormones in newly diagnosed epilepsy. Epilepsy Res. 2007;75(2–3):122–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17553671</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eplepsyres.2007.04.009</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Levisohn PM, Holland KD. Topiramate or valproate in patients with juvenile myoclonic epilepsy: a randomized open-label comparison. Epilepsy Behav. 2007;10(4):547–52.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17482520</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yebeh.2007.03.003</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Steinhoff BJ, Ueberall MA, Siemes H, Kurlemann G, Schmitz B, Bergmann L. The LAM-SAFE Study: lamotrigine versus carbamazepine or valproic acid in newly diagnosed focal and generalised epilepsies in adolescents and adults. Seizure. 2005;14(8):597–605.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16278088</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.seizure.2005.09.011</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lindberger M, Alenius M, Frisén L, Johannessen SI, Larsson S, Malmgren K, et al. Gabapentin versus vigabatrin as first add-on for patients with partial seizures that failed to respond to monotherapy: a randomized, double-blind, dose titration study. GREAT Study Investigators Group Gabapentin in Refractory Epilepsy Add-on Treatment. Epilepsia. 2000;41(10):1289-95.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marson AG, Al-Kharusi AM, Alwaidh M, Appleton R, Baker GA, Chadwick DW, et al. The SANAD study of effectiveness of carbamazepine, gabapentin, lamotrigine, oxcarbazepine, or topiramate for treatment of partial epilepsy: an unblinded randomised controlled trial. Lancet. 2007;369(9566):1000–15.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17382827</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2080688</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(07)60460-7</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brodie MJ. Pregabalin as adjunctive therapy for partial seizures. Epilepsia. 2004;45(Suppl 6):19–27.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15315512</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.0013-9580.2004.455004.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Piña-Garza JE, Rosenfeld W, Saeki K, Villanueva V, Yoshinaga H, Patten A, et al. Efficacy and safety of adjunctive perampanel in adolescent patients with epilepsy: post hoc analysis of six randomized studies. Epilepsy Behav. 2020;104(Pt A):106876.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31954998</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yebeh.2019.106876</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lagae L, Villanueva V, Meador KJ, Bagul M, Laurenza A, Kumar D, et al. Adjunctive perampanel in adolescents with inadequately controlled partial-onset seizures: A randomized study evaluating behavior, efficacy, and safety. Epilepsia. 2016;57(7):1120–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27221398</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.13417</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rosenfeld W, Conry J, Lagae L, Rozentals G, Yang H, Fain R, et al. Efficacy and safety of perampanel in adolescent patients with drug-resistant partial seizures in three double-blind, placebo-controlled, phase III randomized clinical studies and a combined extension study. Eur J Paediatr Neurol. 2015;19(4):435–45.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25823975</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejpn.2015.02.008</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>French JA, Krauss GL, Steinhoff BJ, Squillacote D, Yang H, Kumar D, et al. Evaluation of adjunctive perampanel in patients with refractory partial-onset seizures: results of randomized global phase III study 305. Epilepsia. 2013;54(1):117–25.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22905857</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1167.2012.03638.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>French JA, Krauss GL, Biton V, Squillacote D, Yang H, Laurenza A, et al. Adjunctive perampanel for refractory partial-onset seizures: randomized phase III study 304. Neurology. 2012;79(6):589–96.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22843280</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3413761</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0b013e3182635735</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>French JA, Krauss GL, Wechsler RT, Wang XF, DiVentura B, Brandt C, et al. Perampanel for tonic-clonic seizures in idiopathic generalized epilepsy A randomized trial. Neurology. 2015;85(11):950–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26296511</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4567458</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000001930</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krauss GL, Serratosa JM, Villanueva V, Endziniene M, Hong Z, French J, et al. Randomized phase III study 306: adjunctive perampanel for refractory partial-onset seizures. Neurology. 2012;78(18):1408–15.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22517103</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0b013e318254473a</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rektor I, Krauss GL, Inoue Y, Kaneko S, Williams B, Patten A, et al. Assessment of the long-term efficacy and safety of adjunctive perampanel in tonic-clonic seizures: Analysis of four open-label extension studies. Epilepsia. 2020;61(7):1491–502.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32645213</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">7497073</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.16573</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krauss GL, Perucca E, Ben-Menachem E, Kwan P, Shih JJ, Clément JF, et al. Long-term safety of perampanel and seizure outcomes in refractory partial-onset seizures and secondarily generalized seizures: results from phase III extension study 307. Epilepsia. 2014;55(7):1058–68.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24867391</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4283992</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.12643</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Montouris G, Yang H, Williams B, Zhou S, Laurenza A, Fain R. Efficacy and safety of perampanel in patients with drug-resistant partial seizures after conversion from double-blind placebo to open-label perampanel. Epilepsy Res. 2015;114:131–40.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26088896</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eplepsyres.2015.04.011</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kälviäinen R, Aikiä M, Saukkonen AM, Mervaala E, Riekkinen PJ Sr. Vigabatrin vs carbamazepine monotherapy in patients with newly diagnosed epilepsy. A randomized, controlled study. Arch Neurol. 1995;52(10):989–96.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7575227</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archneur.1995.00540340081016</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ng YT, Conry J, Mitchell WG, Buchhalter J, Isojarvi J, Lee D, et al. Clobazam is equally safe and efficacious for seizures associated with Lennox-Gastaut syndrome across different age groups: Post hoc analyses of short- and long-term clinical trial results. Epilepsy Behav. 2015;46:221–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25940107</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yebeh.2015.01.037</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Buchanan N. Clobazam in the treatment of epilepsy: prospective follow-up to 8 years. J R Soc Med. 1993;86(7):378–80.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8371242</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">1293003</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35596110</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>20</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1179-2019</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>21</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Paediatric drugs</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Paediatr Drugs</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Impact of Antiseizure Medications on Appetite and Weight in Children.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40272-022-00505-2</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>There are numerous potential factors that may affect growth in children with epilepsy, and these must be evaluated in any child with appetite and weight concerns. Antiseizure medications (ASMs) have potential adverse effects, and many may affect appetite, thus impacting normal growth and weight gain. The aim of this review is to focus on the impact of both epilepsy and ASMs on appetite and weight in children. We systematically reviewed studies using Medline assessing the impact of ASMs on appetite and weight in children. Eligible studies included randomized controlled trials and open-label studies (open-label extension and interventional) that targeted or included the pediatric population (0-18 years of age). Each study was classified using the American Academy of Neurology (AAN) Classification of Evidence for Therapeutic Studies, and the level of evidence for impact on appetite and weight in children was graded. ASMs associated with decreased appetite and/or weight loss include fenfluramine, topiramate, zonisamide, felbamate, rufinamide, stiripentol, cannabidiol, brivaracetam and ethosuximide; ASMs with minimal impact on weight and appetite in children include oxcarbazepine, eslicarbazepine, lamotrigine, levetiracetam, lacosamide, carbamazepine, vigabatrin and clobazam. The ASM most robustly associated with increased appetite and/or weight gain is valproic acid; however, both pregabalin and perampanel may also lead to modest weight gain or increased appetite in children. Certain ASMs may impact both appetite and weight, which may lead to increased morbidity of the underlying disease and impaired adherence to the treatment regimen.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022. The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Nature Switzerland AG.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y">
            <LastName>Buraniqi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ersida</ForeName>
            <Initials>E</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Child and Adolescent Neurology, Department of Neurology, Mayo Clinic, 200 First St., SW, Rochester, MN, 55905, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y">
            <LastName>Dabaja</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hicham</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Child and Adolescent Neurology, Department of Neurology, Mayo Clinic, 200 First St., SW, Rochester, MN, 55905, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wirrell</LastName>
            <ForeName>Elaine C</ForeName>
            <Initials>EC</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3015-8282</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Child and Adolescent Neurology, Department of Neurology, Mayo Clinic, 200 First St., SW, Rochester, MN, 55905, USA. Wirrell.Elaine@mayo.edu.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>Switzerland</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Paediatr Drugs</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>100883685</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1174-5878</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
          <Hour>23</Hour>
          <Minute>34</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35596110</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40272-022-00505-2</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40272-022-00505-2</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Camfield CS, Camfield PR, Gordon K, Wirrell E, Dooley JM. Incidence of epilepsy in childhood and adolescence: a population-based study in Nova Scotia from 1977 to 1985. Epilepsia. 1996;37(1):19–23.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8603618</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1157.1996.tb00506.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wirrell EC. Predicting pharmacoresistance in pediatric epilepsy. Epilepsia. 2013;54(s2):19–22.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23646966</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.12179</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sultana B, Panzini MA, Veilleux Carpentier A, Comtois J, Rioux B, Gore G, et al. Incidence and prevalence of drug-resistant epilepsy: a systematic review and meta-analysis. Neurology. 2021;96(17):805–17.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33722992</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000011839</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wirrell EC, Grossardt BR, Wong-Kisiel LC, Nickels KC. Incidence and classification of new-onset epilepsy and epilepsy syndromes in children in Olmsted County, Minnesota from 1980 to 2004: a population-based study. Epilepsy Res. 2011;95(1–2):110–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21482075</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3260338</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eplepsyres.2011.03.009</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eschbach K, Scarbro S, Juarez-Colunga E, Allen V, Hsu S, Knupp K. Growth and endocrine function in children with Dravet syndrome. Seizure. 2017;52:117–22.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29031192</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.seizure.2017.09.021</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fortin O, Vincelette C, Khan AQ, Berrahmoune S, Dassi C, Karimi M, et al. Seizures in Sotos syndrome: phenotyping in 49 patients. Epilepsia Open. 2021;6(2):425–30.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34033256</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">8166795</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/epi4.12484</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reilly S, Skuse D. Characteristics and management of feeding problems of young children with cerebral palsy. Dev Med Child Neurol. 1992;34(5):379–88.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1592191</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1469-8749.1992.tb11449.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stallings VA, Zemel BS, Davies JC, Cronk CE, Charney EB. Energy expenditure of children and adolescents with severe disabilities: a cerebral palsy model. Am J Clin Nutr. 1996;64(4):627–34.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8839510</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ajcn/64.4.627</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nutrition in neurologically impaired children. Paediatr Child Health. 2009;14(6):395–401.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dassa Y, Crosnier H, Chevignard M, Viaud M, Personnier C, Flechtner I, et al. Pituitary deficiency and precocious puberty after childhood severe traumatic brain injury: a long-term follow-up prospective study. Eur J Endocrinol. 2019;180(5):281–90.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30884465</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1530/EJE-19-0034</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bjorholt PG, Nakken KO, Rohme K, Hansen H. Leisure time habits and physical fitness in adults with epilepsy. Epilepsia. 1990;31(1):83–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2303016</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1157.1990.tb05364.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Steinhoff BJ, Neususs K, Thegeder H, Reimers CD. Leisure time activity and physical fitness in patients with epilepsy. Epilepsia. 1996;37(12):1221–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8956856</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1157.1996.tb00557.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Howard GM, Radloff M, Sevier TL. Epilepsy and sports participation. Curr Sports Med Rep. 2004;3(1):15–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14728909</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1249/00149619-200402000-00004</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wong J, Wirrell E. Physical activity in children/teens with epilepsy compared with that in their siblings without epilepsy. Epilepsia. 2006;47(3):631–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16529632</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1167.2006.00478.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pohl D, Alpous A, Hamer S, Longmuir PE. Higher screen time, lower muscular endurance, and decreased agility limit the physical literacy of children with epilepsy. Epilepsy Behav. 2019;90:260–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30342878</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yebeh.2018.05.010</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Capovilla G, Kaufman KR, Perucca E, Moshe SL, Arida RM. Epilepsy, seizures, physical exercise, and sports: A report from the ILAE Task Force on Sports and Epilepsy. Epilepsia. 2016;57(1):6–12.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26662920</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.13261</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Auvin S, Wirrell E, Donald KA, Berl M, Hartmann H, Valente KD, et al. Systematic review of the screening, diagnosis, and management of ADHD in children with epilepsy Consensus paper of the Task Force on Comorbidities of the ILAE Pediatric Commission. Epilepsia. 2018;59(10):1867–80.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30178479</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.14549</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baweja R, Hale DE, Waxmonsky JG. Impact of CNS stimulants for attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder on growth: epidemiology and approaches to management in children and adolescents. CNS Drugs. 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Serretti A, Mandelli L. Antidepressants and body weight: a comprehensive review and meta-analysis. J Clin Psychiatry. 2010;71(10):1259–72.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21062615</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4088/JCP.09r05346blu</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Osborn DP, Petersen I, Beckley N, Walters K, Nazareth I, Hayes J. Weight change over two years in people prescribed olanzapine, quetiapine and risperidone in UK primary care: Cohort study in THIN, a UK primary care database. J Psychopharmacol. 2018;32(10):1098–103.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29938561</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0269881118780011</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Neurology AAo. Clinical Practice Guideline Process Manual, 2004. https://www.aan.com/siteassets/home-page/policy-and-guidelines/guidelines/about-guidelines/2004_guideline_process.pdf . Last Accessed Nov 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Holmes GL. Cognitive impairment in epilepsy: the role of network abnormalities. Epileptic Disord Int Epilepsy J Videotape. 2015;17(2):101–16.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1684/epd.2015.0739</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schoonjans A-S, Lagae L, Ceulemans B. Low-dose fenfluramine in the treatment of neurologic disorders: experience in Dravet syndrome. Ther Adv Neurol Disord. 2015;8(6):328–38.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26600876</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4643872</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1756285615607726</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fuller RW, Snoddy HD, Robertson DW. Mechanisms of effects of d-Fenfluramine on brain serotonin metabolism in rats: Uptake inhibition versus release. Pharmacol Biochem Behav. 1988;30(3):715–21.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2463643</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0091-3057(88)90089-5</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Samanin R, Mennini T, Bendotti C, Barone D, Caccia S, Garattini S. Evidence that central 5-HT2 receptors do not play an important role in the anorectic activity of d-fenfluramine in the rat. Neuropharmacology. 1989;28(5):465–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2566947</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0028-3908(89)90080-4</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Halford JCG, Boyland EJ, Lawton CL, Blundell JE, Harrold JA. Serotonergic Anti-Obesity Agents. Drugs. 2011;71(17):2247–55.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22085383</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2165/11596680-000000000-00000</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Choi S, Blake V, Cole S, Fernstrom JD. Effects of chronic fenfluramine administration on hypothalamic neuropeptide mRNA expression. Brain Res. 2006;1087(1):83–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16626640</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.brainres.2006.02.129</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grignaschi G, Sironi F, Samanin R. The 5-HT1B receptor mediates the effect of d-fenfluramine on eating caused by intra-hypothalamic injection of neuropeptide Y. Eur J Pharmacol. 1995;274(1):221–4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7768274</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0014-2999(94)00766-Z</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abenhaim L, Moride Y, Brenot F, Rich S, Benichou J, Kurz X, et al. Appetite-suppressant drugs and the risk of primary pulmonary hypertension. N Engl J Med. 1996;335(9):609–16.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8692238</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJM199608293350901</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ceulemans B, Boel M, Leyssens K, Van Rossem C, Neels P, Jorens PG, et al. Successful use of fenfluramine as an add-on treatment for Dravet syndrome. Epilepsia. 2012;53(7):1131–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22554283</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1167.2012.03495.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schoonjans A-S, Marchau F, Paelinck BP, Lagae L, Gammaitoni A, Pringsheim M, et al. Cardiovascular safety of low-dose fenfluramine in Dravet syndrome: a review of its benefit-risk profile in a new patient population. Curr Med Res Opin. 2017;33(10):1773–81.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28704161</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/03007995.2017.1355781</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lagae L, Sullivan J, Knupp K, Laux L, Polster T, Nikanorova M, et al. Fenfluramine hydrochloride for the treatment of seizures in Dravet syndrome: a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Lancet. 2019;394(10216):2243–54.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31862249</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(19)32500-0</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nabbout R, Mistry A, Zuberi S, Villeneuve N, Gil-Nagel A, Sanchez-Carpintero R, et al. Fenfluramine for treatment-resistant seizures in patients with dravet syndrome receiving stiripentol-inclusive regimens: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Neurol. 2020;77(3):300–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31790543</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaneurol.2019.4113</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gil-Nagel A, Sullivan J, Ceulemans B, Wirrell E, Devinsky O, Nabbout R, et al. Treatment with fenfluramine in patients with Dravet syndrome has no long-term effects on weight and growth. Epilepsy Behav. 2021;122:108212.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34352670</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yebeh.2021.108212</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kawasaki H, Tancredi V, D’Arcangelo G, Avoli M. Multiple actions of the novel anticonvulsant drug topiramate in the rat subiculum in vitro. Brain Res. 1998;807(1):125–34.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9757016</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0006-8993(98)00785-9</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shank RP, Gardocki JF, Streeter AJ, Maryanoff BE. An overview of the preclinical aspects of topiramate: pharmacology, pharmacokinetics, and mechanism of action. Epilepsia. 2000;41(s1):3–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10768292</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1157.2000.tb02163.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ben-Menachem E. Weight issues for people with epilepsy—A review. Epilepsia. 2007;48(s9):42–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18047602</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1167.2007.01402.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ben-Menachem E, Axelsen M, Johanson EH, Stagge A, Smith U. Predictors of weight loss in adults with topiramate-treated epilepsy. Obes Res. 2003;11(4):556–62.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12690085</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/oby.2003.78</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arroyo S, Anhut H, Kugler AR, Lee CM, Knapp LE, Garofalo EA, et al. Pregabalin add-on treatment: a randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, dose-response study in adults with partial seizures. Epilepsia. 2004;45(1):20–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14692903</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.0013-9580.2004.31203.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Freitag FG, Collins SD, Carlson HA, Goldstein J, Saper J, Silberstein S, et al. A randomized trial of divalproex sodium extended-release tablets in migraine prophylaxis. Neurology. 2002;58(11):1652–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12058094</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.58.11.1652</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dodick DW, Freitag F, Banks J, Saper J, Xiang J, Rupnow M, et al. Topiramate versus amitriptyline in migraine prevention: a 26-week, multicenter, randomized, double-blind, double-dummy, parallel-group noninferiority trial in adult migraineurs. Clin Ther. 2009;31(3):542–59.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19393844</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.clinthera.2009.03.020</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wilding J, Gaal LV, Rissanen A, Vercruysse F, Fitchet M, for the O-SG. A randomized double-blind placebo-controlled study of the long-term efficacy and safety of topiramate in the treatment of obese subjects. International Journal of Obesity. 2004;28(11):1399-410.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stenlöf K, Rössner S, Vercruysse F, Kumar A, Fitchet M, Sjöström L, et al. Topiramate in the treatment of obese subjects with drug-naive type 2 diabetes. Diabetes Obes Metab. 2007;9(3):360–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17391164</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1463-1326.2006.00618.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gadde KM, Allison DB, Ryan DH, Peterson CA, Troupin B, Schwiers ML, et al. Effects of low-dose, controlled-release, phentermine plus topiramate combination on weight and associated comorbidities in overweight and obese adults (CONQUER): a randomised, placebo-controlled, phase 3 trial. Lancet. 2011;377(9774):1341–52.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21481449</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(11)60205-5</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garvey WT, Ryan DH, Look M, Gadde KM, Allison DB, Peterson CA, et al. Two-year sustained weight loss and metabolic benefits with controlled-release phentermine/topiramate in obese and overweight adults (SEQUEL): a randomized, placebo-controlled, phase 3 extension study. Am J Clin Nutr. 2012;95(2):297–308.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22158731</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3945/ajcn.111.024927</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arroyo S, Dodson WE, Privitera MD, Glauser TA, Naritoku DK, Dlugos DJ, et al. Randomized dose-controlled study of topiramate as first-line therapy in epilepsy. Acta Neurol Scand. 2005;112(4):214–22.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16146489</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0404.2005.00485.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Glauser TA, Dlugos DJ, Dodson WE, Grinspan A, Wang S, Wu SC. Topiramate monotherapy in newly diagnosed epilepsy in children and adolescents. J Child Neurol. 2007;22(6):693–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17641254</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0883073807303997</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gilliam FG, Veloso F, Bomhof MA, Gazda SK, Biton V, Ter Bruggen JP, et al. A dose-comparison trial of topiramate as monotherapy in recently diagnosed partial epilepsy. Neurology. 2003;60(2):196–202.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12552030</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/01.WNL.0000048200.12663.BC</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ford LM, Todd MJ, Polverejan E. Effect of topiramate monotherapy on height in newly diagnosed children with epilepsy. Pediatr Neurol. 2013;48(5):383–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23583056</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pediatrneurol.2012.12.028</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elterman RD, Glauser TA, Wyllie E, Reife R, Wu SC, Pledger G. A double-blind, randomized trial of topiramate as adjunctive therapy for partial-onset seizures in children Topiramate YP Study Group. Neurology. 1999;52(7):1338–44.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10227615</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.52.7.1338</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ritter F, Glauser TA, Elterman RD, Wyllie E. Effectiveness, tolerability, and safety of topiramate in children with partial-onset seizures Topiramate YP Study Group. Epilepsia. 2000;41(S1):82–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10768307</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1157.2000.tb02178.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sachdeo RC, Glauser TA, Ritter F, Reife R, Lim P, Pledger G. A double-blind, randomized trial of topiramate in Lennox-Gastaut syndrome Topiramate YL Study Group. Neurology. 1999;52(9):1882–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10371538</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.52.9.1882</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Glauser TA, Levisohn PM, Ritter F, Sachdeo RC. Topiramate in Lennox-Gastaut syndrome: open-label treatment of patients completing a randomized controlled trial Topiramate YL Study Group. Epilepsia. 2000;41(S1):86–90.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10768308</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1157.2000.tb02179.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grosso S, Franzoni E, Iannetti P, Incorpora G, Cardinali C, Toldo I, et al. Efficacy and safety of topiramate in refractory epilepsy of childhood: long-term follow-up study. J Child Neurol. 2005;20(11):893–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16417859</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/08830738050200110601</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kluger G, Schäuble B, Rettig K, Schreiner A, Holthausen H. Effectiveness of low dose of topiramate following rapid titration in multiply handicapped children and difficult-to-treat epilepsy. Neuropediatrics. 2009;40(2):61–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19809933</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1055/s-0029-1234103</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coppola G, Caliendo G, Terracciano MM, Buono S, Pellegrino L, Pascotto A. Topiramate in refractory partial-onset seizures in children, adolescents and young adults: a multicentric open trial. Epilepsy Res. 2001;43(3):255–60.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11248537</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0920-1211(00)00202-3</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mikaeloff Y, de Saint-Martin A, Mancini J, Peudenier S, Pedespan JM, Vallée L, et al. Topiramate: efficacy and tolerability in children according to epilepsy syndromes. Epilepsy Res. 2003;53(3):225–32.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12694931</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0920-1211(03)00028-7</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Manitpisitkul P, Shalayda K, Todd M, Wang SS, Ness S, Ford L. Pharmacokinetics and safety of adjunctive topiramate in infants (1–24 months) with refractory partial-onset seizures: a randomized, multicenter, open-label phase 1 study. Epilepsia. 2013;54(1):156–64.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23157581</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.12019</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Puri V, Ness S, Sattaluri SJ, Wang S, Todd M, Yuen E, et al. Long-Term open-label study of adjunctive topiramate in infants with refractory partial-onset seizures. J Child Neurol. 2011;26(10):1271–83.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21673279</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0883073811406982</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Takeoka M, Holmes GL, Thiele E, Bourgeois BF, Helmers SL, Duffy FH, et al. Topiramate and metabolic acidosis in pediatric epilepsy. Epilepsia. 2001;42(3):387–92.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11442157</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1528-1157.2001.04500.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Faught E, Ayala R, Montouris GG, Leppik IE, Group ZT. Randomized controlled trial of zonisamide for the treatment of refractory partial-onset seizures. Neurology. 2001;57(10):1774–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11723262</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.57.10.1774</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shinnar S, Pellock JM, Conry JA. Open-label, long-term safety study of zonisamide administered to children and adolescents with epilepsy. Eur J Paediatr Neurol. 2009;13(1):3–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18343174</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejpn.2008.01.004</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guerrini R, Rosati A, Segieth J, Pellacani S, Bradshaw K, Giorgi L. A randomized phase III trial of adjunctive zonisamide in pediatric patients with partial epilepsy. Epilepsia. 2013;54(8):1473–80.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23837461</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.12233</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guerrini R, Rosati A, Bradshaw K, Giorgi L. Adjunctive zonisamide therapy in the long-term treatment of children with partial epilepsy: results of an open-label extension study of a phase III, randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled trial. Epilepsia. 2014;55(4):568–78.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24621319</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.12548</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lagae L, Meshram C, Giorgi L, Patten A. Effects of adjunctive zonisamide treatment on weight and body mass index in children with partial epilepsy. Acta Neurol Scand. 2015;131(5):341–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25659828</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ane.12373</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rho JM, Donevan SD, Rogawski MA. Mechanism of action of the anticonvulsant felbamate: opposing effects on N-methyl-D-aspartate and γ-aminobutyric acidA receptors. Ann Neurol. 1994;35(2):229–34.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8109904</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.410350216</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Efficacy of Felbamate in Childhood Epileptic Encephalopathy (Lennox-Gastaut Syndrome). N Engl J Med. 1993;328(1):29-33.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hosain S, Nagarajan L, Carson D, Solomon G, Mast J, Labar D. Felbamate for refractory infantile spasms. J Child Neurol. 1997;12(7):466–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9373806</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/088307389701200711</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pellock JM. Felbamate. Epilepsia. 1999;40(Suppl 5):S57-62.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10530695</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1157.1999.tb00920.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hussain SA, Asilnejad B, Heesch J, Navarro M, Ji M, Shrey DW, et al. Felbamate in the treatment of refractory epileptic spasms. Epilepsy Res. 2020;161:106284.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32058261</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eplepsyres.2020.106284</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cilio MR, Kartashov AI, Vigevano F. The long-term use of felbamate in children with severe refractory epilepsy. Epilepsy Res. 2001;47(1):1–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11673015</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0920-1211(01)00290-X</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bergen DC, Ristanovic RK, Waicosky K, Kanner A, Hoeppner TJ. Weight loss in patients taking felbamate. Clin Neuropharmacol. 1995;18(1)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Canger R, Vignoli A, Bonardi R, Guidolin L. Felbamate in refractory partial epilepsy. Epilepsy Res. 1999;34(1):43–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10194111</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0920-1211(98)00098-9</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wheless JW, Conry J, Krauss G, Mann A, LoPresti A, Narurkar M. Safety and tolerability of rufinamide in children with epilepsy: a pooled analysis of 7 clinical studies. J Child Neurol. 2009;24(12):1520–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19955344</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0883073809350508</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arzimanoglou A, Ferreira JA, Satlin A, Mendes S, Williams B, Critchley D, et al. Safety and pharmacokinetic profile of rufinamide in pediatric patients aged less than 4 years with Lennox-Gastaut syndrome: An interim analysis from a multicenter, randomized, active-controlled, open-label study. Eur J Paediatr Neurol. 2016;20(3):393–402.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26805435</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejpn.2015.12.015</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim SH, Eun SH, Kang HC, Kwon EJ, Byeon JH, Lee YM, et al. Rufinamide as an adjuvant treatment in children with Lennox-Gastaut syndrome. Seizure. 2012;21(4):288–91.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22421185</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.seizure.2012.02.006</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moavero R, Cusmai R, Specchio N, Fusco L, Capuano A, Curatolo P, et al. Rufinamide efficacy and safety as adjunctive treatment in children with focal drug resistant epilepsy: the first Italian prospective study. Epilepsy Res. 2012;102(1):94–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22677424</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eplepsyres.2012.05.004</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coppola G, Grosso S, Franzoni E, Veggiotti P, Zamponi N, Parisi P, et al. Rufinamide in children and adults with Lennox-Gastaut syndrome: First Italian multicenter experience. Seizure. 2010;19(9):587–91.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20888268</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.seizure.2010.09.008</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coppola G, Grosso S, Franzoni E, Veggiotti P, Zamponi N, Parisi P, et al. Rufinamide in refractory childhood epileptic encephalopathies other than Lennox-Gastaut syndrome. Eur J Neurol. 2011;18(2):246–51.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20666837</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1468-1331.2010.03113.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ohtsuka Y, Yoshinaga H, Shirasaka Y, Takayama R, Takano H, Iyoda K. Rufinamide as an adjunctive therapy for Lennox-Gastaut syndrome: a randomized double-blind placebo-controlled trial in Japan. Epilepsy Res. 2014;108(9):1627–36.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25219353</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eplepsyres.2014.08.019</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ohtsuka Y, Yoshinaga H, Shirasaka Y, Takayama R, Takano H, Iyoda K. Long-term safety and seizure outcome in Japanese patients with Lennox-Gastaut syndrome receiving adjunctive rufinamide therapy: An open-label study following a randomized clinical trial. Epilepsy Res. 2016;121:1–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26827266</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eplepsyres.2016.01.002</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Glauser T, Kluger G, Sachdeo R, Krauss G, Perdomo C, Arroyo S. Rufinamide for generalized seizures associated with Lennox-Gastaut syndrome. Neurology. 2008;70(21):1950–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18401024</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/01.wnl.0000303813.95800.0d</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chiron C, Marchand MC, Tran A, Rey E, d’Athis P, Vincent J, et al. Stiripentol in severe myoclonic epilepsy in infancy: a randomised placebo-controlled syndrome-dedicated trial STICLO study group. Lancet. 2000;356(9242):1638–42.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11089822</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(00)03157-3</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Farwell JR, Anderson GD, Kerr BM, Tor JA, Levy RH. Stiripentol in atypical absence seizures in children: an open trial. Epilepsia. 1993;34(2):305–11.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8453942</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1157.1993.tb02416.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thanh TN, Chiron C, Dellatolas G, Rey E, Pons G, Vincent J, et al. Long-term efficacy and tolerance of stiripentaol in severe myoclonic epilepsy of infancy (Dravet’s syndrome). Arch Pediatr. 2002;9(11):1120–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12503502</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0929-693X(02)00090-8</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Perez J, Chiron C, Musial C, Rey E, Blehaut H, d’Athis P, et al. Stiripentol: efficacy and tolerability in children with epilepsy. Epilepsia. 1999;40(11):1618–26.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10565591</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1157.1999.tb02048.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Myers KA, Lightfoot P, Patil SG, Cross JH, Scheffer IE. Stiripentol efficacy and safety in Dravet syndrome: a 12-year observational study. Dev Med Child Neurol. 2018;60(6):574–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29473155</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/dmcn.13704</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rosati A, Boncristiano A, Doccini V, Pugi A, Pisano T, Lenge M, et al. Long-term efficacy of add-on stiripentol treatment in children, adolescents, and young adults with refractory epilepsies: A single center prospective observational study. Epilepsia. 2019;60(11):2255–62.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31630399</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.16363</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Devinsky O, Cross JH, Laux L, Marsh E, Miller I, Nabbout R, et al. Trial of cannabidiol for drug-resistant seizures in the dravet syndrome. N Engl J Med. 2017;376(21):2011–20.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28538134</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1611618</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thiele EA, Marsh ED, French JA, Mazurkiewicz-Beldzinska M, Benbadis SR, Joshi C, et al. Cannabidiol in patients with seizures associated with Lennox-Gastaut syndrome (GWPCARE4): a randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled phase 3 trial. Lancet. 2018;391(10125):1085–96.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29395273</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(18)30136-3</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miller I, Scheffer IE, Gunning B, Sanchez-Carpintero R, Gil-Nagel A, Perry MS, et al. Dose-ranging effect of adjunctive oral cannabidiol vs placebo on convulsive seizure frequency in dravet syndrome: a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Neurol. 2020;77(5):613–21.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32119035</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaneurol.2020.0073</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>UCB Inc, Smyrna, GA, USA. Briviact® (brivaracetam) Prescribing Information. 2018. https://www.briviact.com/briviact-PI.pdf . Last Accessed Nov 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Feyissa AM. Brivaracetam in the treatment of epilepsy: a review of clinical trial data. Neuropsychiatr Dis Treat. 2019;15:2587–600.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31571877</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6750854</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2147/NDT.S143548</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu E, Dilley D, McDonough B, Stockis A, Daniels T. Safety and tolerability of adjunctive brivaracetam in pediatric patients &lt; 16 years with epilepsy: an open-label trial. Paediatr Drugs. 2019;21(4):291–301.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31250322</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6682562</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40272-019-00332-y</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Glauser TA, Cnaan A, Shinnar S, Hirtz DG, Dlugos D, Masur D, et al. Ethosuximide, valproic acid, and lamotrigine in childhood absence epilepsy. N Engl J Med. 2010;362(9):790–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20200383</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2924476</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa0902014</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Glauser TA, Cnaan A, Shinnar S, Hirtz DG, Dlugos D, Masur D, et al. Ethosuximide, valproic acid, and lamotrigine in childhood absence epilepsy: initial monotherapy outcomes at 12 months. Epilepsia. 2013;54(1):141–55.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23167925</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.12028</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Owens MJ, Nemeroff CB. Pharmacology of valproate. Psychopharmacol Bull. 2003;37(Suppl 2):17–24.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14624230</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sharpe C, Wolfson T, Trauner DA. Weight gain in children treated with valproate. J Child Neurol. 2009;24(3):338–41.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19258293</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0883073808323023</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Egger J, Brett EM. Effects of sodium valproate in 100 children with special reference to weight. Br Med J (Clin Res Ed). 1981;283(6291):577–81.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/bmj.283.6291.577</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verrotti A, D’Egidio C, Mohn A, Coppola G, Chiarelli F. Weight gain following treatment with valproic acid: pathogenetic mechanisms and clinical implications. Obes Rev. 2011;12(5):e32-43.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20880119</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1467-789X.2010.00800.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dinesen H, Gram L, Andersen T, Dam M. Weight gain during treatment with valproate. Acta Neurol Scand. 1984;70(2):65–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6435386</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1600-0404.1984.tb00804.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Isojärvi JI, Rättyä J, Myllylä VV, Knip M, Koivunen R, Pakarinen AJ, et al. Valproate, lamotrigine, and insulin-mediated risks in women with epilepsy. Ann Neurol. 1998;43(4):446–51.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9546324</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.410430406</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Covanis A, Gupta AK, Jeavons PM. Sodium valproate: monotherapy and polytherapy. Epilepsia. 1982;23(6):693–720.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6816580</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1157.1982.tb05085.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lakhanpal D, Kaur G. Valproic acid alters GnRH-GABA interactions in cycling female rats. Cell Mol Neurobiol. 2007;27(8):1069–83.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17823865</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10571-007-9201-x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brown R, Imran SA, Ur E, Wilkinson M. Valproic acid and CEBPalpha-mediated regulation of adipokine gene expression in hypothalamic neurons and 3T3-L1 adipocytes. Neuroendocrinology. 2008;88(1):25–34.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18212493</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1159/000113927</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Howard JK, Flier JS. Attenuation of leptin and insulin signaling by SOCS proteins. Trends Endocrinol Metab. 2006;17(9):365–71.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17010638</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tem.2006.09.007</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lihn AS, Pedersen SB, Richelsen B. Adiponectin: action, regulation and association to insulin sensitivity. Obes Rev. 2005;6(1):13–21.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15655035</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1467-789X.2005.00159.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Qiao L, Schaack J, Shao J. Suppression of adiponectin gene expression by histone deacetylase inhibitor valproic acid. Endocrinology. 2006;147(2):865–74.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16282359</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1210/en.2005-1030</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rauchenzauner M, Laimer M, Luef G, Kaser S, Engl J, Tatarczyk T, et al. Adiponectin receptor R1 is upregulated by valproic acid but not by topiramate in human hepatoma cell line, HepG2. Seizure. 2008;17(8):723–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18424096</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.seizure.2008.03.002</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rauchenzauner M, Haberlandt E, Scholl-Bürgi S, Ernst B, Hoppichler F, Karall D, et al. Adiponectin and visfatin concentrations in children treated with valproic acid. Epilepsia. 2008;49(2):353–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18070089</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1167.2007.01460.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gungor S, Yücel G, Akinci A, Tabel Y, Ozerol IH, Yologlu S. The role of ghrelin in weight gain and growth in epileptic children using valproate. J Child Neurol. 2007;22(12):1384–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18174556</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0883073807307096</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Greco R, Latini G, Chiarelli F, Iannetti P, Verrotti A. Leptin, ghrelin, and adiponectin in epileptic patients treated with valproic acid. Neurology. 2005;65(11):1808–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16344528</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/01.wnl.0000187074.27586.d1</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Demir E, Aysun S. Weight gain associated with valproate in childhood. Pediatr Neurol. 2000;22(5):361–4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10913727</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0887-8994(00)00133-8</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pylvänen V, Pakarinen A, Knip M, Isojärvi J. Characterization of insulin secretion in Valproate-treated patients with epilepsy. Epilepsia. 2006;47(9):1460–4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16981861</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1167.2006.00546.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pylvänen V, Pakarinen A, Knip M, Isojärvi J. Insulin-related metabolic changes during treatment with valproate in patients with epilepsy. Epilepsy Behav. 2006;8(3):643–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16600693</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yebeh.2006.02.008</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Luef G, Abraham I, Hoppichler F, Trinka E, Unterberger I, Bauer G, et al. Increase in postprandial serum insulin levels in epileptic patients with valproic acid therapy. Metabolism. 2002;51(10):1274–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12370846</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/meta.2002.34708</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shi Y, Kanaani J, Menard-Rose V, Ma YH, Chang PY, Hanahan D, et al. Increased expression of GAD65 and GABA in pancreatic beta-cells impairs first-phase insulin secretion. Am J Physiol Endocrinol Metab. 2000;279(3):E684–94.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10950838</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1152/ajpendo.2000.279.3.E684</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beydoun A, Uthman BM, Kugler AR, Greiner MJ, Knapp LE, Garofalo EA. Safety and efficacy of two pregabalin regimens for add-on treatment of partial epilepsy. Neurology. 2005;64(3):475–80.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15699378</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/01.WNL.0000150932.48688.BE</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Belcastro V, D’Egidio C, Striano P, Verrotti A. Metabolic and endocrine effects of valproic acid chronic treatment. Epilepsy Res. 2013;107(1–2):1–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24076030</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eplepsyres.2013.08.016</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Espinosa PS, Salazar JC, Yu L, Mendiondo MS, Robertson WC, Baumann RJ. Lack of valproic acid-associated weight gain in prepubertal children. Pediatr Neurol. 2008;39(3):177–80.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18725062</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.pediatrneurol.2008.05.006</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tanamachi Y, Saruwatari J, Noai M, Kamihashi R, Soraoka H, Yoshimori Y, et al. Possible association between moderate intellectual disability and weight gain in valproic acid-treated patients with epilepsy. Neuropsychiatr Dis Treat. 2015;11:1007–14.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25897238</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4397927</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>van Hooft JA, Dougherty JJ, Endeman D, Nichols RA, Wadman WJ. Gabapentin inhibits presynaptic Ca(2+) influx and synaptic transmission in rat hippocampus and neocortex. Eur J Pharmacol. 2002;449(3):221–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12167463</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0014-2999(02)02044-7</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lauria-Horner BA, Pohl RB. Pregabalin: a new anxiolytic. Expert Opin Investig Drugs. 2003;12(4):663–72.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12665421</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1517/13543784.12.4.663</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shokry DA, El Nabrawy N, Yassa HD, Gaber SS, Batiha GE, Welson NN. Pregabalin induced reproductive toxicity and body weight changes by affecting caspase3 and leptin expression: protective role of wheat germ oil. Life Sci. 2020;260:118344.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32853651</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.lfs.2020.118344</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>DeToledo JC, Toledo C, DeCerce J, Ramsay RE. Changes in body weight with chronic, high-dose gabapentin therapy. Ther Drug Monit. 1997;19(4):394–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9263379</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00007691-199708000-00006</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Appleton R, Fichtner K, LaMoreaux L, Alexander J, Halsall G, Murray G, et al. Gabapentin as add-on therapy in children with refractory partial seizures: a 12-week, multicentre, double-blind, placebo-controlled study Gabapentin Paediatric Study Group. Epilepsia. 1999;40(8):1147–54.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10448830</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1157.1999.tb00833.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Appleton R, Fichtner K, LaMoreaux L, Alexander J, Maton S, Murray G, et al. Gabapentin as add-on therapy in children with refractory partial seizures: a 24-week, multicentre, open-label study. Dev Med Child Neurol. 2001;43(4):269–73.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11305405</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0012162201000500</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Panebianco M, Al-Bachari S, Hutton JL, Marson AG. Gabapentin add-on treatment for drug-resistant focal epilepsy. Cochrane Database Syst Rev. 2021;1(1):1415.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>French J, Kwan P, Fakhoury T, Pitman V, DuBrava S, Knapp L, et al. Pregabalin monotherapy in patients with partial-onset seizures: a historical-controlled trial. Neurology. 2014;82(7):590–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24415567</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3963419</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000000119</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baulac M, Cavalcanti D, Semah F, Arzimanoglou A, Portal JJ. Gabapentin add-on therapy with adaptable dosages in 610 patients with partial epilepsy: an open, observational study The French Gabapentin Collaborative Group. Seizure. 1998;7(1):55–62.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9548227</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1059-1311(98)90009-7</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Antinew J, Pitrosky B, Knapp L, Almas M, Pitman V, Liu J, et al. Pregabalin as adjunctive treatment for focal onset seizures in pediatric patients: a randomized controlled trial. J Child Neurol. 2019;34(5):248–55.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30688135</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0883073818821035</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mann D, Antinew J, Knapp L, Almas M, Liu J, Scavone J, et al. Pregabalin adjunctive therapy for focal onset seizures in children 1 month to &lt;4 years of age: A double-blind, placebo-controlled, video-electroencephalographic trial. Epilepsia. 2020;61(4):617–26.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32189338</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.16466</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rogawski MA, Hanada T. Preclinical pharmacology of perampanel, a selective non-competitive AMPA receptor antagonist. Acta Neurol Scand Suppl. 2013;197:19–24.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ane.12100</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maldonado-Irizarry CS, Swanson CJ, Kelley AE. Glutamate receptors in the nucleus accumbens shell control feeding behavior via the lateral hypothalamus. J Neurosci. 1995;15(10):6779–88.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7472436</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6578022</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.15-10-06779.1995</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mietlicki-Baase EG, Ortinski PI, Reiner DJ, Sinon CG, McCutcheon JE, Pierce RC, et al. Glucagon-like peptide-1 receptor activation in the nucleus accumbens core suppresses feeding by increasing glutamatergic AMPA/kainate signaling. J Neurosci. 2014;34(20):6985–92.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24828651</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4019807</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.0115-14.2014</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zaccara G, Giovannelli F, Cincotta M, Verrotti A, Grillo E. The adverse event profile of perampanel: meta-analysis of randomized controlled trials. Eur J Neurol. 2013;20(8):1204–11.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23607817</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ene.12170</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iwaki H, Jin K, Sugawara N, Nakasato N, Kaneko S. Perampanel-induced weight gain depends on level of intellectual disability and its serum concentration. Epilepsy Res. 2019;152:1–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30852339</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eplepsyres.2019.02.011</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Piña-Garza JE, Espinoza R, Nordli D, Bennett DA, Spirito S, Stites TE, et al. Oxcarbazepine adjunctive therapy in infants and young children with partial seizures. Neurology. 2005;65(9):1370–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16275822</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/01.wnl.0000186800.18456.72</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bourgeois BF, D’Souza J. Long-term safety and tolerability of oxcarbazepine in children: a review of clinical experience. Epilepsy Behav. 2005;7(3):375–82.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16176888</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yebeh.2005.07.017</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coppola G, Franzoni E, Verrotti A, Garone C, Sarajlija J, Operto FF, et al. Levetiracetam or oxcarbazepine as monotherapy in newly diagnosed benign epilepsy of childhood with centrotemporal spikes (BECTS): an open-label, parallel group trial. Brain Dev. 2007;29(5):281–4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17055681</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.braindev.2006.09.008</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kirkham F, Auvin S, Moreira J, Gama H, Falcão AC, Rocha JF, et al. Efficacy and safety of eslicarbazepine acetate as adjunctive therapy for refractory focal-onset seizures in children: a double-blind, randomized, placebo-controlled, parallel-group, multicenter, phase-III clinical trial. Epilepsy Behav. 2020;105:106962.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32151803</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yebeh.2020.106962</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sankar R, Kirkham FJ, Holmes GL, Pina-Garza JE, Wheless J, Gama H, et al. Long-term safety and tolerability of adjunctive eslicarbazepine acetate in children with focal seizures. Epilepsy Behav. 2020;112:107458.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33181890</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yebeh.2020.107458</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Duchowny M, Pellock JM, Graf WD, Billard C, Gilman J, Casale E, et al. A placebo-controlled trial of lamotrigine add-on therapy for partial seizures in children. Lamictal Pediatric Partial Seizure Study Group. Neurology. 1999;53(8):1724–31.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10563619</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.53.8.1724</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coppola G, Pascotto A. Lamotrigine as add-on drug in children and adolescents with refractory epilepsy and mental delay: an open trial. Brain Dev. 1997;19(6):398–402.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9339867</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0387-7604(97)00046-6</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Egunsola O, Choonara I, Sammons HM. Safety of levetiracetam in paediatrics: a systematic review. PLoS ONE. 2016;11(3):149686.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0149686</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fattore C, Boniver C, Capovilla G, Cerminara C, Citterio A, Coppola G, et al. A multicenter, randomized, placebo-controlled trial of levetiracetam in children and adolescents with newly diagnosed absence epilepsy. Epilepsia. 2011;52(4):802–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21320119</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1167.2010.02976.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Glauser TA, Ayala R, Elterman RD, Mitchell WG, Van Orman CB, Gauer LJ, et al. Double-blind placebo-controlled trial of adjunctive levetiracetam in pediatric partial seizures. Neurology. 2006;66(11):1654–60.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16641323</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/01.wnl.0000217916.00225.3a</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Piña-Garza JE, Nordli DR Jr, Rating D, Yang H, Schiemann-Delgado J, Duncan B. Adjunctive levetiracetam in infants and young children with refractory partial-onset seizures. Epilepsia. 2009;50(5):1141–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19243423</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1167.2008.01981.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Farkas V, Steinborn B, Flamini JR, Zhang Y, Yuen N, Borghs S, et al. Efficacy and tolerability of adjunctive lacosamide in pediatric patients with focal seizures. Neurology. 2019;93(12):e1212–26.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31462582</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6808531</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000008126</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ferreira JA, Le Pichon JB, Abdelmoity AT, Dilley D, Dedeken P, Daniels T, et al. Safety and tolerability of adjunctive lacosamide in a pediatric population with focal seizures—an open-label trial. Seizure. 2019;71:166–73.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31374487</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.seizure.2019.05.016</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hmaimess G, Sabbagh S, Dirani M, Hotait M, Beydoun AA, Nasreddine W. Efficacy and tolerability of treatment with lacosamide in children: Postmarketing experience from the Middle East. Seizure. 2020;79:75–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32422546</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.seizure.2020.04.016</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huot S, Palfreyman MG. Effects of gamma-vinyl GABA on food intake of rats. Pharmacol Biochem Behav. 1982;17(1):99–106.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7122673</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0091-3057(82)90269-6</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chadwick D. Safety and efficacy of vigabatrin and carbamazepine in newly diagnosed epilepsy: a multicentre randomised double-blind study Vigabatrin European Monotherapy Study Group. Lancet. 1999;354(9172):13–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10406359</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(98)10531-7</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Elterman RD, Shields WD, Mansfield KA, Nakagawa J. Randomized trial of vigabatrin in patients with infantile spasms. Neurology. 2001;57(8):1416–21.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11673582</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.57.8.1416</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lux AL, Edwards SW, Hancock E, Johnson AL, Kennedy CR, Newton RW, et al. The United Kingdom Infantile Spasms Study comparing vigabatrin with prednisolone or tetracosactide at 14 days: a multicentre, randomised controlled trial. Lancet. 2004;364(9447):1773–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15541450</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(04)17400-X</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Munn R, Farrell K. Open study of clobazam in refractory epilepsy. Pediatr Neurol. 1993;9(6):465–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7605555</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0887-8994(93)90026-9</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Clobazam in treatment of refractory epilepsy: the Canadian experience. A retrospective study. Canadian Clobazam Cooperative Group. Epilepsia. 1991;32(3):407-16.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ng YT, Conry JA, Drummond R, Stolle J, Weinberg MA. Randomized, phase III study results of clobazam in Lennox-Gastaut syndrome. Neurology. 2011;77(15):1473–81.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21956725</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0b013e318232de76</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Conry JA, Ng YT, Kernitsky L, Mitchell WG, Veidemanis R, Drummond R, et al. Stable dosages of clobazam for Lennox-Gastaut syndrome are associated with sustained drop-seizure and total-seizure improvements over 3 years. Epilepsia. 2014;55(4):558–67.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24580023</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4303987</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.12561</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Conry JA, Ng YT, Paolicchi JM, Kernitsky L, Mitchell WG, Ritter FJ, et al. Clobazam in the treatment of Lennox-Gastaut syndrome. Epilepsia. 2009;50(5):1158–66.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19170737</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1167.2008.01935.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marchand V. Canadian Paediatric Society. NaGC nutrition in neurologically impaired children. Paediatr Child Health. 2009;16(6):395–401.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>White JR, Leppik IE, Beattie JL, Walczak TS, Tran TA, Rarick JO, et al. Long-term use of felbamate: clinical outcomes and effect of age and concomitant antiepileptic drug use on its clearance. Epilepsia. 2009;50(11):2390–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19563346</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1167.2009.02187.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Devinsky O, Patel AD, Thiele EA, Wong MH, Appleton R, Harden CL, et al. Randomized, dose-ranging safety trial of cannabidiol in Dravet syndrome. Neurology. 2018;90(14):1204.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000005254</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Devinsky O, Patel AD, Cross JH, Villanueva V, Wirrell EC, Privitera M, et al. Effect of cannabidiol on drop seizures in the lennox-gastaut syndrome. N Engl J Med. 2018;378(20):1888–97.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29768152</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1714631</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thiele EA, Bebin EM, Bhathal H, Jansen FE, Kotulska K, Lawson JA, et al. Add-on cannabidiol treatment for drug-resistant seizures in tuberous sclerosis complex: a placebo-controlled randomized clinical trial. JAMA Neurol. 2021;78(3):285–92.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33346789</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/jamaneurol.2020.4607</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Devinsky O, Marsh E, Friedman D, Thiele E, Laux L, Sullivan J, et al. Cannabidiol in patients with treatment-resistant epilepsy: an open-label interventional trial. Lancet Neurol. 2016;15(3):270–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26724101</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1474-4422(15)00379-8</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Devinsky O, Nabbout R, Miller I, Laux L, Zolnowska M, Wright S, et al. Long-term cannabidiol treatment in patients with Dravet syndrome: an open-label extension trial. Epilepsia. 2019;60(2):294–302.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30582156</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.14628</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thiele E, Marsh E, Mazurkiewicz-Beldzinska M, Halford JJ, Gunning B, Devinsky O, et al. Cannabidiol in patients with Lennox-Gastaut syndrome: Interim analysis of an open-label extension study. Epilepsia. 2019;60(3):419–28.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30740695</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6850399</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.14670</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Steinhoff BJ, Christensen J, Doherty CP, Majoie M, De Backer M, Hellot S, et al. Effectiveness and tolerability of adjunctive brivaracetam in patients with focal seizures: Second interim analysis of 6-month data from a prospective observational study in Europe. Epilepsy Res. 2020;165:106329.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32623096</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eplepsyres.2020.106329</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schubert-Bast S, Willems LM, Kurlemann G, Knake S, Müller-Schlüter K, Rosenow F, et al. Postmarketing experience with brivaracetam in the treatment of focal epilepsy in children and adolescents. Epilepsy Behav. 2018;89:89–93.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30390435</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yebeh.2018.10.018</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Patel AD, Badalamenti V, Gasalla T, Elmoufti S, Elshoff JP. Safety and tolerability of adjunctive brivaracetam in children with focal seizures: Interim analysis of pooled data from two open-label trials. Eur J Paediatr Neurol. 2020;25:68–76.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31810577</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejpn.2019.11.007</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>O’Brien TJ, Borghs S, He Q, Schulz A-L, Yates S, Biton V. Long-term safety, efficacy, and quality of life outcomes with adjunctive brivaracetam treatment at individualized doses in patients with epilepsy: An up to 11-year, open-label, follow-up trial. Epilepsia. 2020;61(4):636–46.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32221987</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">7384045</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.16484</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Klein P, Schiemann J, Sperling MR, Whitesides J, Liang W, Stalvey T, et al. A randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled, multicenter, parallel-group study to evaluate the efficacy and safety of adjunctive brivaracetam in adult patients with uncontrolled partial-onset seizures. Epilepsia. 2015;56(12):1890–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26471380</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.13212</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Toledo M, Brandt C, Quarato PP, Schulz AL, Cleveland JM, Wagener G, et al. Long-term safety, efficacy, and quality of life during adjunctive brivaracetam treatment in patients with uncontrolled epilepsy: An open-label follow-up trial. Epilepsy Behav. 2021;118:107897.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33780735</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yebeh.2021.107897</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Biton V, Levisohn P, Hoyler S, Vuong A, Hammer AE. Lamotrigine versus valproate monotherapy-associated weight change in adolescents with epilepsy: results from a post hoc analysis of a randomized, double-blind clinical trial. J Child Neurol. 2003;18(2):133–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12693782</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/08830738030180021701</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verity CM, Hosking G, Easter DJ. A multicentre comparative trial of sodium valproate and carbamazepine in paediatric epilepsy. The Paediatric EPITEG Collaborative Group. Dev Med Child Neurol. 1995;37(2):97–108.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7851677</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1469-8749.1995.tb11978.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wheless JW, Neto W, Wang S. Topiramate, carbamazepine, and valproate monotherapy: double-blind comparison in children with newly diagnosed epilepsy. J Child Neurol. 2004;19(2):135–41.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15072107</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/08830738040190020901</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coppola G, Auricchio G, Federico R, Carotenuto M, Pascotto A. Lamotrigine versus valproic acid as first-line monotherapy in newly diagnosed typical absence seizures: an open-label, randomized, parallel-group study. Epilepsia. 2004;45(9):1049–53.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15329068</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.0013-9580.2004.40903.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wirrell EC. Valproic acid-associated weight gain in older children and teens with epilepsy. Pediatr Neurol. 2003;28(2):126–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12699863</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0887-8994(02)00505-2</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Biton V, Mirza W, Montouris G, Vuong A, Hammer AE, Barrett PS. Weight change associated with valproate and lamotrigine monotherapy in patients with epilepsy. Neurology. 2001;56(2):172–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11160951</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.56.2.172</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beydoun A, Sackellares JC, Shu V. Safety and efficacy of divalproex sodium monotherapy in partial epilepsy: a double-blind, concentration-response design clinical trial Depakote Monotherapy for Partial Seizures Study Group. Neurology. 1997;48(1):182–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9008516</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.48.1.182</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marson AG, Al-Kharusi AM, Alwaidh M, Appleton R, Baker GA, Chadwick DW, et al. The SANAD study of effectiveness of valproate, lamotrigine, or topiramate for generalised and unclassifiable epilepsy: an unblinded randomised controlled trial. Lancet. 2007;369(9566):1016–26.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17382828</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2039891</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(07)60461-9</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marson A, Burnside G, Appleton R, Smith D, Leach JP, Sills G, et al. The SANAD II study of the effectiveness and cost-effectiveness of valproate versus levetiracetam for newly diagnosed generalised and unclassifiable epilepsy: an open-label, non-inferiority, multicentre, phase 4, randomised controlled trial. Lancet. 2021;397(10282):1375–86.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33838758</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">8047813</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(21)00246-4</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sidhu HS, Srinivas R, Sadhotra A. Evaluate the effects of long-term valproic acid treatment on metabolic profiles in newly diagnosed or untreated female epileptic patients: a prospective study. Seizure. 2017;48:15–21.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28365440</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.seizure.2017.03.007</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Park KM, Kim SH, Nho SK, Shin KJ, Park J, Ha SY, et al. A randomized open-label observational study to compare the efficacy and tolerability between topiramate and valproate in juvenile myoclonic epilepsy. J Clin Neurosci. 2013;20(8):1079–82.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23673144</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jocn.2012.10.020</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stephen LJ, Sills GJ, Leach JP, Butler E, Parker P, Hitiris N, et al. Sodium valproate versus lamotrigine: a randomised comparison of efficacy, tolerability and effects on circulating androgenic hormones in newly diagnosed epilepsy. Epilepsy Res. 2007;75(2–3):122–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17553671</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eplepsyres.2007.04.009</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Levisohn PM, Holland KD. Topiramate or valproate in patients with juvenile myoclonic epilepsy: a randomized open-label comparison. Epilepsy Behav. 2007;10(4):547–52.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17482520</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yebeh.2007.03.003</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Steinhoff BJ, Ueberall MA, Siemes H, Kurlemann G, Schmitz B, Bergmann L. The LAM-SAFE Study: lamotrigine versus carbamazepine or valproic acid in newly diagnosed focal and generalised epilepsies in adolescents and adults. Seizure. 2005;14(8):597–605.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16278088</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.seizure.2005.09.011</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lindberger M, Alenius M, Frisén L, Johannessen SI, Larsson S, Malmgren K, et al. Gabapentin versus vigabatrin as first add-on for patients with partial seizures that failed to respond to monotherapy: a randomized, double-blind, dose titration study. GREAT Study Investigators Group Gabapentin in Refractory Epilepsy Add-on Treatment. Epilepsia. 2000;41(10):1289-95.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Marson AG, Al-Kharusi AM, Alwaidh M, Appleton R, Baker GA, Chadwick DW, et al. The SANAD study of effectiveness of carbamazepine, gabapentin, lamotrigine, oxcarbazepine, or topiramate for treatment of partial epilepsy: an unblinded randomised controlled trial. Lancet. 2007;369(9566):1000–15.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17382827</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2080688</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(07)60460-7</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brodie MJ. Pregabalin as adjunctive therapy for partial seizures. Epilepsia. 2004;45(Suppl 6):19–27.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15315512</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.0013-9580.2004.455004.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Piña-Garza JE, Rosenfeld W, Saeki K, Villanueva V, Yoshinaga H, Patten A, et al. Efficacy and safety of adjunctive perampanel in adolescent patients with epilepsy: post hoc analysis of six randomized studies. Epilepsy Behav. 2020;104(Pt A):106876.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31954998</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yebeh.2019.106876</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lagae L, Villanueva V, Meador KJ, Bagul M, Laurenza A, Kumar D, et al. Adjunctive perampanel in adolescents with inadequately controlled partial-onset seizures: A randomized study evaluating behavior, efficacy, and safety. Epilepsia. 2016;57(7):1120–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27221398</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.13417</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rosenfeld W, Conry J, Lagae L, Rozentals G, Yang H, Fain R, et al. Efficacy and safety of perampanel in adolescent patients with drug-resistant partial seizures in three double-blind, placebo-controlled, phase III randomized clinical studies and a combined extension study. Eur J Paediatr Neurol. 2015;19(4):435–45.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25823975</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejpn.2015.02.008</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>French JA, Krauss GL, Steinhoff BJ, Squillacote D, Yang H, Kumar D, et al. Evaluation of adjunctive perampanel in patients with refractory partial-onset seizures: results of randomized global phase III study 305. Epilepsia. 2013;54(1):117–25.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22905857</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1528-1167.2012.03638.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>French JA, Krauss GL, Biton V, Squillacote D, Yang H, Laurenza A, et al. Adjunctive perampanel for refractory partial-onset seizures: randomized phase III study 304. Neurology. 2012;79(6):589–96.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22843280</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">3413761</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0b013e3182635735</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>French JA, Krauss GL, Wechsler RT, Wang XF, DiVentura B, Brandt C, et al. Perampanel for tonic-clonic seizures in idiopathic generalized epilepsy A randomized trial. Neurology. 2015;85(11):950–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26296511</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4567458</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0000000000001930</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krauss GL, Serratosa JM, Villanueva V, Endziniene M, Hong Z, French J, et al. Randomized phase III study 306: adjunctive perampanel for refractory partial-onset seizures. Neurology. 2012;78(18):1408–15.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22517103</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1212/WNL.0b013e318254473a</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rektor I, Krauss GL, Inoue Y, Kaneko S, Williams B, Patten A, et al. Assessment of the long-term efficacy and safety of adjunctive perampanel in tonic-clonic seizures: Analysis of four open-label extension studies. Epilepsia. 2020;61(7):1491–502.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32645213</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">7497073</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.16573</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krauss GL, Perucca E, Ben-Menachem E, Kwan P, Shih JJ, Clément JF, et al. Long-term safety of perampanel and seizure outcomes in refractory partial-onset seizures and secondarily generalized seizures: results from phase III extension study 307. Epilepsia. 2014;55(7):1058–68.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24867391</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4283992</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/epi.12643</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Montouris G, Yang H, Williams B, Zhou S, Laurenza A, Fain R. Efficacy and safety of perampanel in patients with drug-resistant partial seizures after conversion from double-blind placebo to open-label perampanel. Epilepsy Res. 2015;114:131–40.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26088896</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.eplepsyres.2015.04.011</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kälviäinen R, Aikiä M, Saukkonen AM, Mervaala E, Riekkinen PJ Sr. Vigabatrin vs carbamazepine monotherapy in patients with newly diagnosed epilepsy. A randomized, controlled study. Arch Neurol. 1995;52(10):989–96.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7575227</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archneur.1995.00540340081016</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ng YT, Conry J, Mitchell WG, Buchhalter J, Isojarvi J, Lee D, et al. Clobazam is equally safe and efficacious for seizures associated with Lennox-Gastaut syndrome across different age groups: Post hoc analyses of short- and long-term clinical trial results. Epilepsy Behav. 2015;46:221–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25940107</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yebeh.2015.01.037</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Buchanan N. Clobazam in the treatment of epilepsy: prospective follow-up to 8 years. J R Soc Med. 1993;86(7):378–80.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8371242</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">1293003</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
