<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35599670</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>24</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">1205-7088</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>27</Volume>
            <Issue>2</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Paediatrics &amp; child health</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Paediatr Child Health</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Anticholinergic treatment for sialorrhea in children: A systematic review.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>82</StartPage>
          <EndPage>87</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>82-87</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1093/pch/pxab051</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Sialorrhea in children can be associated with adverse physical and social effects. Treatment using anticholinergic medications has been shown to offer symptomatic relief, but there is no consensus regarding which treatment is the most efficacious.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVE" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">To examine the effectiveness of anticholinergic medications for sialorrhea in children.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">A systematic review was carried out in Medline, EMBASE, Cochrane, Scopus, and the Web of Science from inception until April 29, 2020. Studies reporting original data on the efficacy of anticholinergic medications in the management of sialorrhea in children aged 0 to 17 years of age were included. This review adhered to PRISMA (Preferred Reporting Items for Systematic Reviews and Meta-Analyses) standards. Data on study design, setting, population, pharmacologic intervention(s), comparator(s), outcomes, and results were extracted and summarized.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The search strategy identified 2,800 studies of which 27 articles were included in the synthesis, including five randomized controlled trials. Each anticholinergic undergoing experimental study (glycopyrrolate, scopolamine/hyoscine, trihexyphenidyl/benzhexol, benztropine, and atropine) showed evidence of efficacy. Adverse side effects were common. Significant heterogeneity exists in the studies' methodology and the variability of outcome measures used between studies precluded a meta-analysis.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Glycopyrrolate, scopolamine/hyoscine, trihexyphenidyl/benzhexol, benztropine, and atropine have all shown efficacy in the treatment of sialorrhea in children. The small number of reports and the variability in study design precluded a meta-analysis. More studies are needed with uniformity in outcome measures to help guide evidence-based decision making. A guidance table is presented.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© The Author(s) 2021. Published by Oxford University Press on behalf of the Canadian Paediatric Society. All rights reserved. For permissions, please e-mail: journals.permissions@oup.com.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>You</LastName>
            <ForeName>Peng</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6573-5735</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Otolaryngology - Head and Neck Surgery, Schulich School of Medicine and Dentistry, Western University, London, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Strychowsky</LastName>
            <ForeName>Julie</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Otolaryngology - Head and Neck Surgery, Schulich School of Medicine and Dentistry, Western University, London, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gandhi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Karan</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Schulich School of Medicine and Dentistry, Western University, London, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Breanna A</ForeName>
            <Initials>BA</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Paediatrics, Schulich School of Medicine and Dentistry, Western University, London, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Children's Health Research Institute, Lawson Health Research Institute, London, Ontario, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>08</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Paediatr Child Health</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9815960</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1205-7088</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Anticholinergic</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Children</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Drooling</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Paediatric</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sialorrhea</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Treatment</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>26</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>27</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
          <Hour>3</Hour>
          <Minute>41</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35599670</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9113838</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/pch/pxab051</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">pxab051</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Hockstein NG, Samadi DS, Gendron K, Handler SD. Sialorrhea: A management challenge. Am Fam Physician 2004;69(11):2628–34.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15202698</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Fairhurst CB, Cockerill H. Management of drooling in children. Arch Dis Child Educ Pract Ed 2011;96(1):25–30.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20675519</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Nunn JH. Drooling: Review of the literature and proposals for management. J Oral Rehabil 2000;27(9):735–43.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11012847</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Meningaud JP, Pitak-Arnnop P, Chikhani L, Bertrand JC. Drooling of saliva: A review of the etiology and management options. Oral Surg Oral Med Oral Pathol Oral Radiol Endod 2006;101(1):48–57.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16360607</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Speyer R, Cordier R, Kim JH, Cocks N, Michou E, Wilkes-Gillan S. Prevalence of drooling, swallowing, and feeding problems in cerebral palsy across the lifespan: A systematic review and meta-analyses. Dev Med Child Neurol 2019;61(11):1249–58.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31328797</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Walshe M, Smith M, Pennington L. Interventions for drooling in children with cerebral palsy. Cochrane Database Syst Rev 2012;11:CD008624.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23152263</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Myer CM 3rd. Sialorrhea. Pediatr Clin North Am 1989;36(6):1495–500.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2685726</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Garnock-Jones KP. Glycopyrrolate oral solution: For chronic, severe drooling in pediatric patients with neurologic conditions. Paediatr Drugs 2012;14(4):263–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22646067</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Moher D, Liberati A, Tetzlaff J, Altman DG; PRISMA Group . Preferred reporting items for systematic reviews and meta-analyses: The PRISMA statement. PLoS Med 2009;6(7):e1000097.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2707599</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19621072</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Sterne JAC, Savović J, Page MJ, et al. . 
RoB 2: A revised tool for assessing risk of bias in randomised trials. BMJ 2019;366:l4898.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31462531</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Franco JB, Cacita N, Freua KA, Ortega KL, de Melo Peres MPS. Treatment of drooling with scopolamine in pediatric ICU: A case series report. Spec Care Dentist 2018;38(6):362–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30238487</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Camp-Bruno JA, Winsberg BG, Green-Parsons AR, Abrams JP. Efficacy of benztropine therapy for drooling. Dev Med Child Neurol 1989;31(3):309–19.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2666205</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Lewis DW, Fontana C, Mehallick LK, Everett Y. Transdermal scopolamine for reduction of drooling in developmentally delayed children. Dev Med Child Neurol 1994;36(6):484–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7516297</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Parr JR, Todhunter E, Pennington L, et al. . 
Drooling Reduction Intervention randomised trial (DRI): Comparing the efficacy and acceptability of hyoscine patches and glycopyrronium liquid on drooling in children with neurodisability. Arch Dis Child 2018;103(4):371–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5890631</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29192000</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Mier RJ, Bachrach SJ, Lakin RC, Barker T, Childs J, Moran M. Treatment of sialorrhea with glycopyrrolate: A double-blind, dose-ranging study. Arch Pediatr Adolesc Med 2000;154(12):1214–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11115305</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Zeller RS, Davidson J, Lee HM, Cavanaugh PF. Safety and efficacy of glycopyrrolate oral solution for management of pathologic drooling in pediatric patients with cerebral palsy and other neurologic conditions. Ther Clin Risk Manag 2012;8:25–32.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3269348</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22298951</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Jongerius PH, van den Hoogen FJ, van Limbeek J, Gabreëls FJ, van Hulst K, Rotteveel JJ. Effect of botulinum toxin in the treatment of drooling: A controlled clinical trial. Pediatrics 2004;114(3):620–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15342830</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Táboas-Pereira MA, Paredes-Mercado C, Alonso-Curcó X, Badosa-Pagès J, Muchart J, Póo P. [Drooling therapy in children with neurological disorders]. Rev Neurol 2015;61(2):66–70.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26156441</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Zeller RS, Davidson J, Lee HM, Cavanaugh PF. Safety and efficacy of glycopyrrolate oral solution for management of pathologic drooling in pediatric patients with cerebral palsy and other neurologic conditions. Ther Clin Risk Manag 2012;8:25–32.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3269348</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22298951</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Blasco PA, Stansbury JC. Glycopyrrolate treatment of chronic drooling. Arch Pediatr Adolesc Med 1996;150(9):932–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8790123</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Stern LM. Preliminary study of glycopyrrolate in the management of drooling. J Paediatr Child Health 1997;33(1):52–4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9069045</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Reid SM, Westbury C, Guzys AT, Reddihough DS. Anticholinergic medications for reducing drooling in children with developmental disability. Dev Med Child Neurol 2020;62(3):346–53.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31495925</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Reddihough D, Johnson H, Staples M, Hudson I, Exarchos H. Use of benzhexol hydrochloride to control drooling of children with cerebral palsy. Dev Med Child Neurol 1990;32(11):985–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2269408</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Norderyd J, Graf J, Marcusson A, et al. . 
Sublingual administration of atropine eyedrops in children with excessive drooling - a pilot study. Int J Paediatr Dent 2017;27(1):22–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5324542</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26708211</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Dias BLS, Fernandes AR, Maia Filho HS. Treatment of drooling with sublingual atropine sulfate in children and adolescents with cerebral palsy. Arq Neuropsiquiatr 2017;75(5):282–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28591387</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Montgomery J, McCusker S, Lang K, et al. . 
Managing children with sialorrhoea (drooling): Experience from the first 301 children in our saliva control clinic. Int J Pediatr Otorhinolaryngol 2016;85:33–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27240493</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Carranza-del Rio J, Clegg NJ, Moore A, Delgado MR. Use of trihexyphenidyl in children with cerebral palsy. Pediatr Neurol 2011;44(3):202–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21310336</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Bachrach SJ, Walter RS, Trzcinski K. Use of glycopyrrolate and other anticholinergic medications for sialorrhea in children with cerebral palsy. Clin Pediatr (Phila) 1998;37(8):485–90.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9729704</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Hoon AH Jr, Freese PO, Reinhardt EM, et al. . 
Age-dependent effects of trihexyphenidyl in extrapyramidal cerebral palsy. Pediatr Neurol 2001;25(1):55–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11483397</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Robb AS, Lee RH, Cooper EB, Siedel JV, Nusrat N. Glycopyrrolate for treatment of clozapine-induced sialorrhea in three adolescents. J Child Adolesc Psychopharmacol 2008;18(1):99–107.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18294092</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Owen SE, Stern ML. Management of drooling in cerebral palsy: Three single case studies. Int J Rehabil Res 1992;15(2):166–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1526706</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Siegel LK, Klingbeil MA. Control of drooling with transdermal scopolamine in a child with cerebral palsy. Dev Med Child Neurol 1991;33(11):1013–4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1743423</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Rapoport A. Sublingual atropine drops for the treatment of pediatric sialorrhea. J Pain Symptom Manage 2010;40(5):783–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20541902</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Lee Z-I, Yu KJ, Lee DH, et al. . 
The effect of nebulized glycopyrrolate on posterior drooling in patients with brain injury: Two cases of different brain lesions. Am J Phys Med Rehabil. 2017;96(8):e155–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28081026</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Kobayashi K, Suehiro M, Maihara T, Usami I, Heike T. Excessive salivation as a hidden comorbidity of basal ganglia germ cell tumor. J Pediatr Neurol. 2019;17(05):187–90.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Clinicaltrials.gov. Ipratropium Bromide Spray as Treatment for Sialorrhea in Children. Bethesda, MD: National Library of Medicine (US). Identifier NCT03747536. 2019 [cited October 23, 2020]. https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT03747536</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Clinicaltrials.gov. Evaluation of the Efficacy of the Injection of Botulinum Toxin A vs Scopolamine Patches in the Treatment of Drooling in Children With Cerebral Palsy (TOXSIALO). Bethesda, MD: National Library of Medicine (US). Identifier NCT03616067. 2018 [cited October 23, 2020]. https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT03616067</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
McGuinness LA, Higgins JPT. Risk-of-bias VISualization (robvis): An R package and Shiny web app for visualizing risk-of-bias assessments. Res Synth Methods 2021;12(1):55–61.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32336025</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Toksvang LN, Plovsing RR. Symptoms of central anticholinergic syndrome after glycopyrrolate administration in a 5-year-old child. A A Case Rep 2016;6(2):22–4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26513676</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Begbie F, Walker G, Kubba H, Sabharwal A. Acute colonic pseudo-obstruction in a child taking trihexyphenidyl for drooling: Prescribers beware. Int J Pediatr Otorhinolaryngol 2015;79(6):932–4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25912627</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Chowdhury NA, Sewatsky ML, Kim H. Transdermal scopolamine withdrawal syndrome case report in the pediatric cerebral palsy population. Am J Phys Med Rehabil 2017;96(8):e151–4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28081025</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Reid SM, Johnson HM, Reddihough DS. The Drooling Impact Scale: A measure of the impact of drooling in children with developmental disabilities. Dev Med Child Neurol. 2010;52(2):e23–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19843155</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
van Hulst K, Lindeboom R, van der Burg J, Jongerius P. Accurate assessment of drooling severity with the 5-minute drooling quotient in children with developmental disabilities. Dev Med Child Neurol 2012;54(12):1121–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23094939</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Freudenreich O, Beebe M, Goff DC. Clozapine-induced sialorrhea treated with sublingual ipratropium spray: A case series. J Clin Psychopharmacol 2004;24(1):98–100.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14709958</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Thomas VE, O’Connell F, Harrison AJ, Fuller RW. Ipratropium bromide delivered orally by metered dose inhaler does not decrease salivary flow in normal subjects. Br J Clin Pharmacol 1992;34(3):266–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1381399</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1389952</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
