<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35591610</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>23</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">1996-1944</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>15</Volume>
            <Issue>9</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>03</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Materials (Basel, Switzerland)</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Materials (Basel)</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Seismic Retrofitting of Existing Industrial Steel Buildings: A Case-Study.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">3276</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3390/ma15093276</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Industrial single-storey buildings are the most diffuse typology of steel construction located in Italy. Most of these existing buildings were erected prior to the enforcement of adequate seismic provisions; hence, crucial attention is paid nowadays to the design of low-impact retrofit interventions which can restore a proper structural performance without interrupting productive activities. Within this framework, an existing industrial single-storey steel building located in Nusco (Italy) is selected in this paper as a case-study. The structure, which features moment resisting (MR) truss frames in both directions, is highly deformable and presents undersized MR bolted connections. Structural performance of the case-study was assessed by means of both global and local refined numerical analyses. As expected, the inadequate performance of connections, which fail due to brittle mechanisms, detrimentally affects the global response of the structure both in terms of lateral stiffness and resistance. This effect was accounted for in global analyses by means of properly calibrated non-linear links. Thus, both local and global retrofit interventions were designed and numerically investigated. Namely, lower chord connections were strengthened by means of rib stiffeners and additional rows of M20 10.9 bolts, whereas concentrically braced frames (CBFs) were placed on both directions' facades. Designed interventions proved to be effective for the full structural retrofitting against both seismic and wind actions without limiting building accessibility.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tartaglia</LastName>
            <ForeName>Roberto</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-3379-8675</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Structures for Engineering and Architecture, University of Naples Federico II, Via Forno Vecchio 36, 80134 Naples, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Milone</LastName>
            <ForeName>Aldo</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Structures for Engineering and Architecture, University of Naples Federico II, Via Forno Vecchio 36, 80134 Naples, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Prota</LastName>
            <ForeName>Alessandro</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Structures for Engineering and Architecture, University of Naples Federico II, Via Forno Vecchio 36, 80134 Naples, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Landolfo</LastName>
            <ForeName>Raffaele</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Structures for Engineering and Architecture, University of Naples Federico II, Via Forno Vecchio 36, 80134 Naples, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>03</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Materials (Basel)</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101555929</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1996-1944</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">existing structures</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">finite element analyses</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">seismic retrofitting</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">steel constructions</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
          <Hour>1</Hour>
          <Minute>13</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35591610</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9101308</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ma15093276</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">ma15093276</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>National Institute of Statistics (ISTAT)   16° Censimento Generale della Popolazione e delle Abitazioni. ISTAT; Rome, Italy: 2021.  (In Italian)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dall’Asta A., Landolfo R., Salvatore W.  Edifici Monopiano in Acciaio ad Uso Industriale. Dario Flaccovio Editore; Palermo, Italy: 2022.  (In Italian)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>CNR (Consiglio Nazionale delle Ricerche)   CNR-UNI 10011: Steel Structure–Instruction for Design, Construction, Testing and Maintenance. UNI; Milano, Italy: 1988.  (In Italian)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>CS.LL.PP. (Consiglio Nazionale dei Lavori Pubblici)   Criteri Generali per la Verifica di Sicurezza delle Costruzioni e Norme Tecniche per i Carichi ed i Sovraccarichi. Gazzetta Ufficiale della Repubblica Italiana, Italian Ministry for Infrastructures and Transportations; Rome, Italy: 1982.  (In Italian)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>CS.LL.PP. (Consiglio Nazionale dei Lavori Pubblici)   Circ. 24/05/1982, n. 22631: Istruzioni Relative ai Carichi, ai Sovraccarichi ed ai Criteri Generali per la Verifica di Sicurezza delle Costruzioni. Gazzetta Ufficiale della Repubblica Italiana, Italian Ministry for Infrastructures and Transportations; Rome, Italy: 1982. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>CS.LL.PP. (Consiglio Nazionale dei Lavori Pubblici)   D.M.24/01/1986: Norme Tecniche per le Costruzioni in Zone Sismichel. Gazzetta Ufficiale della Repubblica Italiana, Italian Ministry for Infrastructures and Transportations; Rome, Italy: 1986. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cantisani G., Della Corte G. Modelling and Seismic Response Analysis of Non-residential Existing Steel Buildings in Italy. J. Earthq. Eng. 2022 doi: 10.1080/13632469.2022.2030438.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13632469.2022.2030438</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scozzese F., Terracciano G., Zona A., Della Corte G., Dall’Asta A., Landolfo R. Modelling and seismic response analysis of Italian code-conforming single-storey steel buildings. J. Earthq. Eng. 2018;22:2104–2133. doi: 10.1080/13632469.2018.1528913.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13632469.2018.1528913</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Simões da Silva L., Silva L.C., Tankova T., Craveiro H.D., Simões R., Costa R., D’Aniello M., Landolfo R. Performance of modular hybrid cold-formed/tubular structural system. Structures. 2021;30:1006–1019. doi: 10.1016/j.istruc.2021.01.066.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.istruc.2021.01.066</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Poursadrollah A., D’Aniello M., De Martino A., Landolfo R. Preliminary study on the seismic performance of hybrid steel structures with truss lightweight girders and plug-and-play connections. Ing. Sismica. 2020;37:102–114.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Faggiano B., Formisano A., D’Aniello M., Landolfo R. Steel Constructions in the Framework of the Emilia-Romagna Earthquake. Progett. Sismica. 2012;3:189–200. (In Italian)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Braga F., Gigliotti R., Monti G., Morelli F., Nuti C., Salvatore W., Vanzi I. Speedup of post earthquake community recovery: The case of precast industrial buildings after the Emilia 2012 earthquake. Bull. Earthq. Eng. 2014;12:2405–2418. doi: 10.1007/s10518-014-9583-3.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10518-014-9583-3</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Formisano A., Di Lorenzo G., Iannuzzi I., Landolfo R. Seismic Vulnerability and Fragility of Existing Italian Industrial Steel Buildings. Open Civ. Eng. J. 2017;11:1122–1137. doi: 10.2174/1874149501711011122.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/1874149501711011122</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Di Sarno L., Freddi F., D’Aniello M., Kwon O.-S., Wu J.-R., Gutiérrez-Urzúa F., Landolfo R., Park J., Palios X., Strepelias E. Assessment of existing steel frames: Numerical study, pseudo-dynamic testing and influence of masonry infills. J. Constr. Steel Res. 2021;185:106873. doi: 10.1016/j.jcsr.2021.106873.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcsr.2021.106873</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Romano E., Cascini L., D’Aniello M., Portioli F., Landolfo R. A simplified multi-performance approach to life-cycle assessment of steel structures. Structures. 2020;27:371–382. doi: 10.1016/j.istruc.2020.05.053.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.istruc.2020.05.053</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kazantzi A.K., Vamvatsikos D. Seismic and Vibration Performance Rehabilitation for an Industrial Steel Building. Pract. Period. Struct. Des. Constr. 2020;25:05020001. doi: 10.1061/(ASCE)SC.1943-5576.0000475.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/(ASCE)SC.1943-5576.0000475</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Di Sarno L., Elnashai A. Bracing systems for seismic retrofitting of steel frames. J. Constr. Steel Res. 2009;65:452–465. doi: 10.1016/j.jcsr.2008.02.013.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcsr.2008.02.013</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rinaldin G., Fasan M., Sancin L., Amadio C. On the behaviour of steel CBF for industrial buildings subjected to seismic sequences. Structures. 2020;28:2175–2187. doi: 10.1016/j.istruc.2020.10.050.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.istruc.2020.10.050</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Formisano A., Di Lorenzo G., Landolfo R. Seismic retrofitting of industrial steel buildings hit by the 2012 Emilia-Romagna earthquake: A case study. AIP Conf. Proc. 2019;2116:260021. doi: 10.1063/1.5114272.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1063/1.5114272</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hirde S., Jagtap M. Retrofitting of Damaged Industrial Buildings. Int. J. Civ. Eng. Technol. 2013;4:267–277.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bournas D.A., Negro P., Taucer F.F. Performance of industrial buildings during the Emilia earthquakes in Northern Italy and recommendations for their strengthening. Bull. Earthq. Eng. 2013;12:2383–2404. doi: 10.1007/s10518-013-9466-z.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10518-013-9466-z</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>ReLuis D.P.C.  Progetto Triennale Reluis, DPC-ReLUIS 2019–2021, Working Packages 5 (WP5): Interventi di Rapida Esecuzione a Basso Impatto Ed Integrati. Reluis; Rome, Italy: 2019.  (In Italian)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>M.I.T. (Italian Ministry for Infrastructures and Transportations)   Decreto Ministeriale 17/01/2018-Aggiornamento Delle Norme Tecniche Per le Costruzioni. Italian Ministry for Infrastructures and Transportations; Rome, Italy: 2018.  (In Italian)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>C.S.LL.PP  . Circolare n.7 21/01/2019-Istruzioni Per L’applicazione Dell’ Aggiornamento Delle Norme Tecniche Per le Costruzioni. Italian Ministry for Infrastructures and Transportations; Rome, Italy: 2019.  (In Italian)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>CEN (European Committee for Normalization)   EN1998-1: Eurocode 8: Earthquake Resistance Design of Structures. CEN; Bruxelles, Belgium: 2005. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>CEN (European Committee for Normalization)   EN1993:1-1 Eurocode 3: Design of Steel Structures–Part 1-1: General Rules and Rules for Buildings. CEN; Bruxelles, Belgium: 2005. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu Z.-D., Liao Y.X., Ge T., Xu C. Experimental and Theoretical Study of Viscoelastic Dampers with Different Matrix Rubbers. J. Eng. Mech. 2016;142:04016051. doi: 10.1061/(ASCE)EM.1943-7889.0001101.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1061/(ASCE)EM.1943-7889.0001101</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu Z.-D., Xu F.-H., Chen X. Vibration suppression on a platform by using vibration isolation and mitigation devices. Nonlinear Dyn. 2015;83:1341–1353. doi: 10.1007/s11071-015-2407-4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11071-015-2407-4</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu Z.D., Tu Q., Guo Y.F. Experimental Study on Vertical Performance of Multi-Dimensional Earthquake Isolation and Mitigation Devices for Long-Span Reticulated Structures. J. Vib. Control. 2012;18:1971–1985. doi: 10.1177/1077546311429338.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1077546311429338</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dai J., Xu Z.-D., Gai P.-P., Hu Z.-W. Optimal design of tuned mass damper inerter with a Maxwell element for mitigating the vortex-induced vibration in bridges. Mech. Syst. Signal Process. 2020;148:107180. doi: 10.1016/j.ymssp.2020.107180.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ymssp.2020.107180</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>CEN (European Committee for Normalization)   EN1998:3 Eurocode 8: Design of Structures for Earthquake Resistance–Part 3: Assessment and Retrofitting of Buildings. CEN; Bruxelles, Belgium: 2005. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>CEN/TC 250/SC 8 (European Committee for Normalization)   prEN1998-1-2 SC8 24-02-2021: Eurocode 8: Earthquake Resistance Design of Structures (2021 Draft) CEN; Bruxelles, Belgium: 2021. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>CEN (European Committee for Normalization)   EN1993:1-8 Eurocode 3: Design of Steel Structures–Part 1-8: Design of Joints. CEN; Bruxelles, Belgium: 2005. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>SeismoStruct 2022—A Computer Program for Static and Dynamic Nonlinear Analysis of Framed Structures.  [(accessed on 28 October 2021)].  Available online:  http://www.seismosoft.com.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>ASCE (American Society of Civil Engineers)   ASCE/SEI 41-13: Seismic Evaluation and Retrofit of Existing Buildings. ASCE; Reston, VA, USA: 2014. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dassault  . Abaqus 6.14—Abaqus Analysis User’s Manual, Dassault Systèmes Simulia Corp. Dassault; Velizy-Villacoublay, France: 2014. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>AISC (American Institute of Steel Construction)   ANSI/AISC 341–16: Seismic Provisions for Structural Steel Buildings. AISC; Chicago, IL, USA: 2016. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tartaglia R., D’Aniello M., Landolfo R. The influence of rib stiffeners on the response of extended end-plate joints. J. Constr. Steel Res. 2018;148:669–690. doi: 10.1016/j.jcsr.2018.06.025.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcsr.2018.06.025</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tartaglia R., D’Aniello M., Rassati G.A., Swanson J.A., Landolfo R. Full strength extended stiffened end-plate joints: AISC vs recent European design criteria. Eng. Struct. 2018;159:155–171. doi: 10.1016/j.engstruct.2017.12.053.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engstruct.2017.12.053</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tartaglia R., Milone A., D’Aniello M., Landolfo R. Retrofit of non-code conforming moment resisting beam-to-column joints: A case study. J. Constr. Steel Res. 2021;189:107095. doi: 10.1016/j.jcsr.2021.107095.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jcsr.2021.107095</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tartaglia R., D’Aniello M., Wald F. Behaviour of seismically damaged extended stiffened end-plate joints at elevated temperature. Eng. Struct. 2021;247:113193. doi: 10.1016/j.engstruct.2021.113193.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.engstruct.2021.113193</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dutta A., Dhar S., Acharyya S.K. Material characterization of SS 316 in low-cycle fatigue loading. J. Mater. Sci. 2010;45:1782–1789. doi: 10.1007/s10853-009-4155-7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10853-009-4155-7</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
