<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35605137</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>23</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1535-2900</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>23</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>American journal of health-system pharmacy : AJHP : official journal of the American Society of Health-System Pharmacists</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Am J Health Syst Pharm</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Evaluation of the safety of a novel peripheral vasopressor pilot program and the impact on central line placement in medical and surgical intensive care units.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">zxac144</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1093/ajhp/zxac144</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="DISCLAIMER" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">In an effort to expedite the publication of articles related to the COVID-19 pandemic, AJHP is posting these manuscripts online as soon as possible after acceptance. Accepted manuscripts have been peer-reviewed and copyedited, but are posted online before technical formatting and author proofing. These manuscripts are not the final version of record and will be replaced with the final article (formatted per AJHP style and proofed by the authors) at a later time.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="PURPOSE" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">The purpose of this quality improvement project was to evaluate the safety and feasibility of peripheral vasopressor administration in an attempt to minimize the placement and improve early removal of unnecessary central lines to reduce central line-associated bloodstream infection (CLABSI) rates.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A retrospective chart review was conducted on patients who received vasopressors via peripheral infusion over 3 months, starting at the time of guideline implementation.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">We identified 129 vasopressor orders among 79 patients that were administered peripherally. Among these orders, 3 events were documented as possible extravasation events. Forty-five patients (57%) did not require central line placement due to increasing vasopressor requirements. Standard utilization ratio data suggest minimal central line impact of the protocol implementation. December 2020 to February 2021 was associated with a large second peak of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) in our region. Utilization of central lines was less than predicted in December 2020 to February 2021 in 2 of our 3 intensive care units (ICUs); however, the differences were statistically significant on only 3 occasions. In the third ICU, utilization was greater than predicted, but this unit housed a majority of the most critically ill patients with COVID-19.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSION" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This study suggests that short-term use of select vasopressors at conservative doses is safe for peripheral administration and points toward efficacy at preventing central line placement. Further analysis is required to confirm efficacy.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© American Society of Health-System Pharmacists 2022. All rights reserved. For permissions, please e-mail: journals.permissions@oup.com.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Marti</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kristen</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pharmacy Services, Hartford Hospital, Hartford, CT, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hartley</LastName>
            <ForeName>Christopher</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pharmacy Services, Maine Medical Center, Portland, ME, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sweeney</LastName>
            <ForeName>Elizabeth</ForeName>
            <Initials>E</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Surgical Critical Care, Hartford Hospital, Hartford, CT, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mah</LastName>
            <ForeName>John</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Surgical Critical Care, Hartford Hospital, Hartford, CT.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>University of Connecticut School of Medicine, Farmington, CT, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Pugliese</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nicholas</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Pharmacy Services, Hartford Hospital, Hartford, CT.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>University of Connecticut School of Pharmacy, Storrs, CT, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Am J Health Syst Pharm</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>9503023</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1079-2082</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">central venous catheter</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">peripheral vasopressor</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">quality improvement</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">vasoactive agents</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">vasopressor agents</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>19</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
          <Hour>15</Hour>
          <Minute>12</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35605137</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/ajhp/zxac144</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">6590873</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
