<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35608645</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>24</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1537-1611</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>23</Volume>
            <Issue>4</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
              <Day>01</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of clinical neuromuscular disease</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Neuromuscul Dis</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Academic and Employment Status in Patients With Generalized Myasthenia Gravis Treated With Eculizumab: A Case Series.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>210</StartPage>
          <EndPage>218</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>210-218</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/CND.0000000000000391</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="OBJECTIVES" NlmCategory="OBJECTIVE">To evaluate the impact of treatment with eculizumab, a terminal complement inhibitor, on academic and employment status in patients with refractory generalized myasthenia gravis (MG).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Case review of 7 US patients.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Six patients were aged ≤65 years; one was a full-time student and the remainder were in employment before MG diagnosis. After diagnosis, all patients gave up work (n = 3) or reduced their study/working hours (n = 4). In the 12 months after eculizumab initiation, patients who had stopped work resumed working in some capacity, whereas those who had changed their work/study hours returned to their original work/study pattern. Patients also experienced a reduction in the number of MG exacerbations, and a clinically significant improvement in MG-Activities of Daily Living scores, and were able to reduce other MG medications.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">These results suggest that treatment with eculizumab may help maintain education/employment activity in patients with refractory generalized MG.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022 The Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Seung Ah</ForeName>
            <Initials>SA</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Neurology, University of Missouri Health Care, Columbia, MO.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sweeney</LastName>
            <ForeName>Megan</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Govindarajan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Raghav</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Clin Neuromuscul Dis</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>100887391</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1522-0443</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <CoiStatement>R. Govindarajan has served on advisory committees for Alexion Pharmaceuticals, argenx, and Catalyst Pharmaceuticals, and is a member of the speakers' bureaux for Alexion Pharmaceuticals and Catalyst Pharmaceuticals. The remaining authors report no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>11</Hour>
          <Minute>13</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35608645</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CND.0000000000000391</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">00131402-202206000-00006</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Phillips LH. The epidemiology of myasthenia gravis. Semin Neurol. 2004;24:17–20.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nel M, Heckmann JM. Epidemiology and genetics of myasthenia gravis. In: Kaminski HJ, Kusner LL, eds. Myasthenia Gravis and Related Disorders Third edition. Switzerland: Springer; 2018:71–84.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Beloor Suresh A, Asuncion RMD. Myasthenia Gravis. Treasure Island (FL). StatPearls Publishing LLC; 2020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gilhus NE. Myasthenia gravis. N Engl J Med. 2016;375:2570–2581.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Phillips WD, Vincent A. Pathogenesis of myasthenia gravis: update on disease types, models, and mechanisms. F1000Res. 2016;5:F1000Res.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gilhus NE, Tzartos S, Evoli A, et al. Myasthenia gravis. Nat Rev Dis Primers. 2019;5:30.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Al-Haidar M, Benatar M, Kaminski HJ. Ocular myasthenia. Neurol Clin. 2018;36:241–251.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Stroke. Myasthenia Gravis Fact Sheet; 2020. Available at: https://www.ninds.nih.gov/Disorders/Patient-Caregiver-Education/Fact-Sheets/Myasthenia-Gravis-Fact-Sheet. Accessed April, 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tong O, Delfiner L, Herskovitz S. Pain, headache, and other non-motor symptoms in myasthenia gravis. Curr Pain Headache Rep. 2018;22:39.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ruiter AM, Verschuuren JJGM, Tannemaat MR. Fatigue in patients with myasthenia gravis. A systematic review of the literature. Neuromuscul Disord. 2020;30:631–639.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leonardi M, Raggi A, Antozzi C, et al. Identification of international classification of functioning, disability and health relevant categories to describe functioning and disability of patients with myasthenia gravis. Disabil Rehabil. 2009;31:2041–2046.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vinge L, Jakobsen J, Andersen H. Muscle weakness and functional disability in patients with myasthenia gravis. Muscle Nerve. 2019;59:218–223.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boldingh MI, Dekker L, Maniaol AH, et al. An up-date on health-related quality of life in myasthenia gravis -results from population based cohorts. Health Qual Life Outcomes. 2015;13:115.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schneider-Gold C, Hagenacker T, Melzer N, et al. Understanding the burden of refractory myasthenia gravis. Ther Adv Neurol Disord. 2019;12:1756286419832242.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mantegazza R, Antozzi C. When myasthenia gravis is deemed refractory: clinical signposts and treatment strategies. Ther Adv Neurol Disord. 2018;11:1756285617749134.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bubuioc AM, Kudebayeva A, Turuspekova S, et al. The epidemiology of myasthenia gravis. J Med Life. 2021;14:7–16.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guastafierro E, Tramacere I, Toppo C, et al. Employment in myasthenia gravis: a systematic literature review and meta-analysis. Neuroepidemiology. 2020;54:304–312.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Harris L, Aban IB, Xin H, et al. Employment in refractory myasthenia gravis: a Myasthenia Gravis Foundation of America registry analysis. Muscle Nerve. 2019;60:700–706.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vitturi BK, Kim AIH, Mitre LP, et al. Social, professional and neuropsychiatric outcomes in patients with myasthenia gravis. Neurol Sci. 2021;42:167–173.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alexion Pharmaceuticals Inc. SOLIRIS® (Eculizumab) Injection Prescribing Information; 2020. Available at: https://alexion.com/Documents/Soliris_USPI.pdf. Accessed April, 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Howard JF Jr., Utsugisawa K, Benatar M, et al. Safety and efficacy of eculizumab in anti-acetylcholine receptor antibody-positive refractory generalised myasthenia gravis (REGAIN): a phase 3, randomised, double-blind, placebo-controlled, multicentre study. Lancet Neurol. 2017;16:976–986.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gajdos P, Tranchant C, Clair B, et al. Treatment of myasthenia gravis exacerbation with intravenous immunoglobulin: a randomized double-blind clinical trial. Arch Neurol. 2005;62:1689–1693.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nagane Y, Murai H, Imai T, et al. Social disadvantages associated with myasthenia gravis and its treatment: a multicentre cross-sectional study. BMJ Open. 2017;7:e013278.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Landfeldt E, Pogoryelova O, Sejersen T, et al. Economic costs of myasthenia gravis: a systematic review. Pharmacoeconomics. 2020;38:715–728.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muppidi S, Wolfe GI, Conaway M, et al. MG-ADL: still a relevant outcome measure. Muscle Nerve. 2011;44:727–731.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Moghadam-Kia S, Werth VP. Prevention and treatment of systemic glucocorticoid side effects. Int J Dermatol. 2010;49:239–248.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yasir M, Goyal A, Bansal P, et al. Corticosteroid Adverse Effects. Treasure Island, FL: StatPearls Publishing LLC; 2020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alabdali M, Barnett C, Katzberg H, et al. Intravenous immunoglobulin as treatment for myasthenia gravis: current evidence and outcomes. Expert Rev Clin Immunol. 2014;10:1659–1665.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jowcar A, Goldenberg WD. Myasthenia Gravis Treatment &amp; Management; 2018. Available at: https://emedicine.medscape.com/article/1171206-treatment#d17. Accessed April, 2020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bacci ED, Coyne KS, Poon JL, et al. Understanding side effects of therapy for myasthenia gravis and their impact on daily life. BMC Neurol. 2019;19:335.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thomas TC, Rollins SA, Rother RP, et al. Inhibition of complement activity by humanized anti-C5 antibody and single-chain Fv. Mol Immunol. 1996;33:1389–1401.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Garzón-Orjuela N, van der Werf L, Prieto-Pinto LC, et al. Quality of life in refractory generalized myasthenia gravis: a rapid review of the literature. Intractable Rare Dis Res. 2019;8:231–238.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dong D, Chong MK, Wu Y, et al. Gender differences in quality of life among patients with myasthenia gravis in China. Health Qual Life Outcomes. 2020;18:296.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fan X, Xing C, Yang L, et al. Fatigue, self-efficacy and psychiatric symptoms influence the quality of life in patients with myasthenia gravis in Tianjin, China. J Clin Neurosci. 2020;79:84–89.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Szczudlik P, Sobieszczuk E, Szyluk B, et al. Determinants of quality of life in myasthenia gravis patients. Front Neurol. 2020;11:553626.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alanazy MH, Binabbad RS, Alromaih NI, et al. Severity and depression can impact quality of life in patients with myasthenia gravis. Muscle Nerve. 2020;61:69–73.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muppidi S, Utsugisawa K, Benatar M, et al. Long-term safety and efficacy of eculizumab in generalized myasthenia gravis. Muscle Nerve. 2019;60:14–24.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
