<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35602720</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>24</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">1664-1078</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>13</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Frontiers in psychology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Front Psychol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Points of View and Readers' Immersion in Translation: A Neurocognitive Interpretation of Poetic Translatability.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>877150</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>877150</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">877150</ELocationID>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.3389/fpsyg.2022.877150</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>There have been few attempts at applying cultural neuroscience and psychology to the discussion of poetic translatability. This study employs cultural neuroscience and psychology methodologies and forms of evidence to explore the neurocognitive mechanisms by which cross-cultural variations in perspectives during the translation process influence poetic reception in the target culture. The English translation of Chinese poetry is often tasked with the supplement of perspectives and accompanied by cross-cultural variations of immersion. These changes have been substantially discussed from literary and poetic perspectives but remain understudied in terms of their neurocognitive and psychological implications. Through textual analysis of first-person points of view, this study attempts to apply neuroscience to the interpretation of the impact of differences in cross-cultural perspectives in poetry translation. Our findings suggest that a general tendency toward the supplement of first-person perspectives could boost the immersive experience by activating mirror neurons and the temporal parietal junction. These neuroscientific mechanisms underlying the observable cultural phenomenon offer implications for the translation of Chinese poetry in a way that generates brain responses and neurotransmitters similar to the source text. This study demonstrates how research in neuroscience can illuminate findings in cross-cultural communication.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022 Chen, Shen, Ochs and Xiao.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Chen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Qing</ForeName>
            <Initials>Q</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Interpreting and Translation Studies, Guangdong University of Foreign Studies, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Shen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Lin</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Graduate School of Translation and Interpretation, Beijing Foreign Studies University, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ochs</LastName>
            <ForeName>Shelley</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Beijing Center for China Studies, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Beijing United Family Health Hospital, Beijing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Xiao</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kairong</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>College of International Studies, Southwest University, Chongqing, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>06</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Front Psychol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101550902</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1664-1078</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cognitive neuroscience</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">cultural psychology</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">immersion</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">poetry translation</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">points of view</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">translatability</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors declare that the research was conducted in the absence of any commercial or financial relationships that could be construed as a potential conflict of interest.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
          <Hour>4</Hour>
          <Minute>29</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35602720</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9121805</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2022.877150</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arnheim R. (1970). Visual Thinking. London: Faber.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bassnett S., Lefevere A. (1998). Constructing Cultures: Essays on Literary Translation. Clevedon, Philadelphia: Multilingual Matters.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cai Z. (ed.) (2008). How to Read Chinese Poetry: A Guided Anthology. New York: Columbia University Press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cairns P., Cox A., Nordin A. I. (2014). “Immersion in digital games: review of gaming experience research,” in Handbook of Digital Games. eds. Angelides M. C., Agius H. (United States: John Wiley &amp; Sons, Inc.), 337–361.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cappuccio M. (ed.) (2019). Handbook of Embodied Cognition and Sport Psychology. Cambridge, MA: The MIT Press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carrasco M. (2011). Visual attention: The past 25 years. Vis. Res.
51, 1484–1525. doi: 10.1016/j.visres.2011.04.012, PMID: </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.visres.2011.04.012</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3390154</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21549742</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carrasco M. (2018). How visual spatial attention alters perception. Cogn. Process.
19, 77–88. doi: 10.1007/s10339-018-0883-4, PMID: </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10339-018-0883-4</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6170011</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30062667</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Catford J. C. (1965). A Linguistic Theory of Translation. London: Oxford University Press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen X., Cheng Z., Hu C., Liang T., Liu Q. (2020). Steady-state visual evoked potential and its applications in studying visual selective attention. Chin. Sci. Bull.
65, 2601–2614. doi: 10.1360/TB-2020-0009</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1360/TB-2020-0009</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen C., Liu Z., Jin Z. (2002). The recent development of the neural mechanisms of visual selective attention. Chin. J. App. Psychol.
3, 60–64.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chin T., Meng J., Wang S., Shi Y., Zhang J. (2021a). Cross-cultural metacognition as a prior for humanitarian knowledge: when cultures collide in global health emergencies. J. Knowl. Manag.
26, 88–101. doi: 10.1108/JKM-10-2020-0787</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/JKM-10-2020-0787</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chin T., Shi Y., Rowley C., Meng J. (2021b). Confucian business model canvas in the Asia Pacific: a yin-Yang harmony cognition to value creation and innovation. Asia Pac. Bus. Rev.
27, 342–358. doi: 10.1080/13602381.2020.1795481</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/13602381.2020.1795481</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chin T., Wang S., Rowley C. (2020). Polychronic knowledge creation in cross-border business models: a sea-like heuristic metaphor. J. Knowl. Manag.
25, 1–22. doi: 10.1108/JKM-04-2020-0244</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1108/JKM-04-2020-0244</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chin T., Wang W., Yang M., Duan Y., Chen Y. (2021c). The moderating effect of managerial discretion on block chain technology and the firms’ innovation quality: evidence from Chinese manufacturing firms. Int. J. Prod. Econ.
240:108219. doi: 10.1016/j.ijpe.2021.108219</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ijpe.2021.108219</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cohen J. (2001). Defining identification: A theoretical look at the identification of audiences With media characters. Mass Commun. Soc.
4, 245–264. doi: 10.1207/s15327825mcs0403_01</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1207/s15327825mcs0403_01</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Crick F. (1994). The Astonishing Hypothesis: The Scientific Search for the Soul. New York: New York: Scribner; Maxwell Macmillan International.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>David N., Bewernick B. H., Cohen M. X., Newen A., Lux S., Fink G. R., et al. . (2006). Neural representations of self versus other: visual-spatial perspective taking and Agency in a Virtual Ball-tossing Game. J. Cogn. Neurosci.
18, 898–910. doi: 10.1162/jocn.2006.18.6.898, PMID: </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1162/jocn.2006.18.6.898</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16839298</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Debarba H. G., Molla E., Herbelin B., Boulic R. (2015). “Characterizing embodied interaction in first and third person perspective viewpoints,” in 2015 IEEE Symposium on 3D User Interfaces (3DUI); March 23, 2015.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Denisova A., Cairns P. (2015). “First person vs. third person perspective in digital games: do player preferences affect immersion?” in Proceedings of the 33rd Annual ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems CHI’15; April 18, 2015.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eliot T. S. (1954). Literary Essays of Ezra Pound. London: Faber and Faber.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Escarpit R. (1971). Sociology of Literature. 2nd Edn. London: Cass.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fludernik M. (2009). An Introduction to Narratology. London, New York: Routledge.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Freud S. (2003). An Outline of Psychoanalysis. London: Penguin Books.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gazzaniga M. S., Ivry R. B., Mangun G. R. (2011). Cognitive Neuroscience: The Biology of the Mind. Beijing: China Light Industry Press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Glynn D., Hadley J. (2021). Theorising (un)performability and (un)translatability. Pers. Stu. Trans. Theor. Prac.
29, 20–32. doi: 10.1080/0907676x.2020.1713827</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/0907676x.2020.1713827</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gorisse G., Christmann O., Amato E. A., Richir S. (2017). First- and third-person perspectives in immersive virtual environments: presence and performance analysis of embodied users. Front. Robotics
4:33. doi: 10.3389/frobt.2017.00033</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/frobt.2017.00033</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huang G. (2006). Linguistic Explorations in Translation Studies: Analyses of English Translations of Ancient Chinese Poems and Lyrics. Shanghai: Shanghai Foreign Language Education Press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huang L., Li M., Wang L., Zhang X. (2019). Neural mechanisms of visual selective attention. Acta Physiol. Sinica
71, 11–21. doi: 10.1111/j.1469-8986.1995.tb03400.x</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1469-8986.1995.tb03400.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30778500</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hühn P. (ed.) (2009). Handbook of Narratology. New York: Walter de Gruyter Berlin.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jacobs A. M. (2015). Neurocognitive poetics: methods and models for investigating the neuronal and cognitive-affective bases of literature reception. Front. Hum. Neurosci.
9:186. doi: 10.3389/fnhum.2015.00186, PMID: </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fnhum.2015.00186</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4399337</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25932010</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jacobs A. M., Lüdtke J. (2017). “Chapter 4. Immersion into narrative and poetic worlds: A neurocognitive poetics perspective,” in Linguistic Approaches to Literature. eds. Hakemulder F., Kuijpers M. M., Tan E. S., Bálint K., Doicaru M. M. (Amsterdam: John Benjamins Publishing Company; ), 69–96.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jakobson R. (1987). Language in Literature. United States: Harvard University Press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jatobá J. R. (2019). Poéticas do Traduzir a, na e para a China: uma proposta. Cad. Trad.
39, 120–147. doi: 10.5007/2175-7968.2019v39nespp120</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5007/2175-7968.2019v39nespp120</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kilteni K., Groten R., Slater M. (2012). The sense of embodiment in virtual reality. Presence Teleop. Virt.
21, 373–387. doi: 10.1162/PRES_a_00124</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1162/PRES_a_00124</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Large D., Akashi M., Jóźwikowska W., Rose E. (2019). Untranslatability: Interdisciplinary Perspectives. New York London: Routledge.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee H. (2012). Translatability and untranslatability of tae-sok Oh’s theater. Pers. Stu. Translatol.
20, 165–175. doi: 10.1080/0907676x.2011.574063</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/0907676x.2011.574063</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lin W., Zhao Y. (2017). Translating the concept of Tao in relation to natural law: a comparative approach in countering untranslatability. Pers. Stu. Trans. Theor. Prac.
25, 609–621. doi: 10.1080/0907676x.2016.1245764</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/0907676x.2016.1245764</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu M. (1985). English Varieties and Translation. Beijing: China Translation &amp; Publishing Corporation.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lü S., Xu Y. (1988). A Comparative Study on English Translations of Old Gems. Hongkong: Joint Publishing.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Medeiros D., Dos Anjos R. K., Mendes D., Pereira J. M., Raposo A., Jorge J. (2018). “Keep my Head on my Shoulders! Why Third-Person Is Bad for Navigation in VR,” in Proceedings of the 24th ACM Symposium on Virtual Reality Software and Technology VRST’18; November 28, 2018.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Monteiro D., Liang H.-N., Xu W., Brucker M., Nanjappan V., Yue Y. (2018). Evaluating enjoyment, presence, and emulator sickness in VR games based on first- and third- person viewing perspectives. Comp. Anim. Virtual Worlds
29:e1830. doi: 10.1002/cav.1830</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/cav.1830</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Northoff G., Heinzel A., de Greck M., Bermpohl F., Dobrowolny H., Panksepp J. (2006). Self-referential processing in our brain—A meta-analysis of imaging studies on the self. NeuroImage
31, 440–457. doi: 10.1016/j.neuroimage.2005.12.002, PMID: </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuroimage.2005.12.002</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16466680</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parsons L. M. (1994). Temporal and kinematic properties of motor behavior reflected in mentally simulated action. J. Exp. Psychol. Hum. Percept. Perform.
20, 709–730. doi: 10.1037/0096-1523.20.4.709, PMID: </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0096-1523.20.4.709</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8083630</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Prince G. (1982). Narratology: The Form and Functioning of Narrative. Berlin, New York: Mouton.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Qian Z. (1981). Translation of Lin Shu. Beijing: The Commercial Press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Recupero A., Triberti S., Modesti C., Talamo A. (2018). Mixed reality for cross-cultural integration: using positive technology to share experiences and promote communication. Front. Psychol.
9:1223. doi: 10.3389/fpsyg.2018.01223, PMID: </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyg.2018.01223</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6056812</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30065690</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rizzolatti G., Fadiga L., Gallese V., Fogassi L. (1996). Premotor cortex and the recognition of motor actions. Cogn. Brain Res.
3, 131–141. doi: 10.1016/0926-6410(95)00038-0</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0926-6410(95)00038-0</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salamin P., Tadi T., Blanke O., Vexo F., Thalmann D. (2010). Quantifying effects of exposure to the third and first-person perspectives in virtual-reality-based training. IEEE Trans. Learn. Technol.
3, 272–276. doi: 10.1109/TLT.2010.13</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1109/TLT.2010.13</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saxe R., Kanwisher N. (2003). People thinking about thinking people the role of the temporo-parietal junction in “theory of mind”. NeuroImage
19, 1835–1842. doi: 10.1093/cercor/bhm051, PMID: </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/cercor/bhm051</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12948738</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Seger C. A., Stone M., Keenan J. P. (2004). Cortical activations during judgments about the self and an other person. Neuropsychologia
42, 1168–1177. doi: 10.1016/j.neuropsychologia.2004.02.003, PMID: </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuropsychologia.2004.02.003</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15178169</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shapiro L. A. (2019). Embodied Cognition. 2nd Edn. London, New York: Routledge.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shen D. (2009). Narration, Style and Subtext: Rereading the Classic British and American Short Stories. Beijing: Peking University Press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sun Z. (2001). Translation and treason. Chin. Trans. J.
4, 18–22.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sun Y. (2012). Translatability(un) and cross-cultural readability. Pers. Stu. Translatol.
20, 231–247. doi: 10.1080/0907676x.2012.659746</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/0907676x.2012.659746</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Taylor Y., Everett A. M., Edgar F. (2021). Perception of cross-cultural adjustment by immigrant professionals from three ethnic groups in one host context. Int. J. Cross Cultural Manage.
21, 227–244. doi: 10.1177/14705958211001889</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/14705958211001889</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tsang D. (2014). Translator as co-producer: metempsychosis and metamorphosis in Ezra Pound’s Cathay. Asia Pacific Trans. Inter. Stu.
1, 142–170. doi: 10.1080/23306343.2014.911400</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/23306343.2014.911400</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vogeley K., Bussfeld P., Newen A., Herrmann S., Happé F., Falkai P., et al. . (2001). Mind Reading: neural mechanisms of theory of mind and self-perspective. NeuroImage
14, 170–181. doi: 10.1006/nimg.2001.0789, PMID: </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1006/nimg.2001.0789</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11525326</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vogeley K., Fink G. R. (2003). Neural correlates of the first-person-perspective. Trends Cogn. Sci.
7, 38–42. doi: 10.1016/S1364-6613(02)00003-7</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S1364-6613(02)00003-7</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12517357</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vogeley K., May M., Ritzl A., Falkai P., Zilles K., Fink G. R. (2004). Neural correlates of first-person perspective as one constituent of human self-consciousness. J. Cogn. Neurosci.
16, 817–827. doi: 10.1162/089892904970799, PMID: </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1162/089892904970799</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15200709</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang B. (2001). On untranslatability: theoretical reflections and a case study. Chin. Trans. J.
3, 8–16.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang W., Shen J., Jia Y. (2019). Review of visual attention detection. J. Software
30, 416–439. doi: 10.13328/j.cnki.jos.005636</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.13328/j.cnki.jos.005636</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Washbourne K. (2015). The outer limits of otherness: ideologies of human translation in speculative fiction. Trans. Stu.
8, 284–301. doi: 10.1080/14781700.2014.931817</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/14781700.2014.931817</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wittevrongel B., Khachatryan E., Fahimi Hnazaee M., Carrette E., De Taeye L., Meurs A., et al. . (2018). Representation of steady-state visual evoked potentials elicited by luminance flicker in human occipital cortex: An electrocorticography study. NeuroImage
175, 315–326. doi: 10.1016/j.neuroimage.2018.04.006, PMID: </Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuroimage.2018.04.006</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29630994</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xie T. (1999). Translation Studies. Shanghai: Shanghai Foreign Language Education Press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xie M. (2014). Ezra Pound and the Appropriation of Chinese Poetry: Cathay, Translation, and Imagism. United States: Routledge.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu X., Gong Q. (2012). Translatability vs untranslatability A relevance-theoretic view. Int. J. Trans.
58, 408–422. doi: 10.1075/s58.4.03xiu</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1075/s58.4.03xiu</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu Y. (2012). 300 Tang Poems. Beijing: China Intercontinental Press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang W. (2020). A Cross-Cultural Study of Commercial Media Discourses: From the Perspective of Cognitive Semantics. Beijing: Science Press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhou X., Liu Y. (2004). Cultural Mentality of Ancient Chinese Writers. Chengdu: Bashu Publishing House.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
