<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35608642</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>24</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1537-1611</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>23</Volume>
            <Issue>4</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
              <Day>01</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of clinical neuromuscular disease</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Clin Neuromuscul Dis</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>What is in the Neuromuscular Junction Literature?</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>189</StartPage>
          <EndPage>200</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>189-200</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/CND.0000000000000403</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>This update covers a number of treatment topics starting with Fc receptor inhibitors and the Federal Drug Administration approval of efgartigimod. Some uncertainties regarding the use of corticosteroids are addressed, namely the risk of exacerbation with initiation of treatment and how to taper. The presence and potential importance of antibody overshoot following plasmapheresis is noted and the evolving increase in usefulness of acetylcholine receptor antibodies in diagnosing ocular myasthenia. Several recent series and case reports regarding coronavirus 2019 and myasthenia gravis are reviewed. The topics of myasthenia gravis and pregnancy, and another look at thymectomy in MG are provided. Finally, a couple of case reports on Lambert-Eaton myasthenic syndrome concentrate on the ice pack test and an autoantibody association with paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration and Lambert-Eaton myasthenic syndrome in the same patient.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022 Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Al-Lahham</LastName>
            <ForeName>Tawfiq</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Departments of Neurology and.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lacomis</LastName>
            <ForeName>David</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Departments of Neurology and.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Pathology (Neuropathology), University of Pittsburgh School of Medicine, Pittsburgh, PA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>J Clin Neuromuscul Dis</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>100887391</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1522-0443</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <CoiStatement>The authors report no conflicts of interest.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>11</Hour>
          <Minute>13</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35608642</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/CND.0000000000000403</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">00131402-202206000-00003</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wolfe GI, Ward ES, Haard HD, et al. IgG regulation through FcRn blocking: a novel mechanism for the treatment of myasthenia gravis. J Neurol Sci. 2012;430:118074.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Available at: https://www.fda.gov/news-events/press-announcements/fda-approves-new-treatment-myasthenia-gravis. Accessed December 27, 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Howard JF Jr, Bril V, Vu T, et al. Safety, efficacy, and tolerability of efgartigimod in patients with generalized myasthenia gravis (ADAPT): a multicentre, randomized, placebo-controlled, phase 3 trial. Lancet Neurol. 2021;7:526–536.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bril V, Benatar M, Andersen H, et al. Efficacy and safety of rozanolixizumab in moderate to severe generalized myasthenia gravis: a phase 2 randomized control trial. JAMA Neurol. 2020;77:582–592.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lotan I, Hellmann MA, Wilf-Yarkoni A, et al. Exacerbation of myasthenia gravis following corticosteroid treatment what is the evidence? A systematic review. J Neurol. 2021;268:4573–4586.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Howard FM, Duane DD, Lambert EH, et al. Alternate-day prednisone: preliminary report of a double-blind controlled study. Ann NY Acad Sci. 1976;274:596–607.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bae JS, Go SM, Kim BJ. Clinical predictors of steroid-induced exacerbation in myasthenia gravis. J Clin Neurosci. 2006;13:1006–1010.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sharshar T, Porcher R, Demeret S, et al. Comparison of corticosteroid tapering regimens in myasthenia gravis a randomized clinical trial. JAMA Neurol. 2021;78:426–433.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ching J, Richards D, Lewis RA, et al. Myasthenia gravis exacerbation in association with antibody overshoot following plasmapheresis. Muscle Nerve. 2021;64:483–508.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee I, Sanders D. Rethinking the utility of acetylcholine receptor antibody titer as a pharmacodynamic biomarker for myasthenia gravis. MuscleNerve.2021;64:385–387.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chung Y, Sheth SJ, Wells KK. The usefulness of anti-acetylcholine receptor binding antibody testing in diagnosing ocular myasthenia gravis. J Neuro Opthalmol. 2021;41:627–630.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Monte G, Spagni G, Damato V, et al. Acetylcholine receptor antibody positivity rate in ocular myasthenia gravis: a matter of age? J Neurol. 2021;268:1803–1807.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lacomis D, Wolfe GI. What is in the neuromuscular junction literature? J Clin Neuromusc Dis. 2021;22:147–154.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sole G, Mathis S, Friedman D, et al. Impact of coronavirus disease 2019 in a French cohort of myasthenia gravis. Neurology.2021;96:e2109-e2120.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saied Z, Rachdi A, Thamlaoui S, et al. Myasthenia gravis and COVID-19: a case series and comparison with literature. Acta Neurol Scand. 2021;144:334–340.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Assini A, Gandoglia I, Damato V, et al. Myasthenia gravis associated with anti- MuSK antibodies developed after SARS-CoV-2-infection. Eur J Neurol. 2021;28:3537–3539.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Muhammad L, Baheerathan A, Leite I, et al. MuSK antibody-associated myasthenia gravis with SARS-CoV 2 infection: a case report. Ann Inter Med. 2021;17:872–873.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li Y, Emmett CD, Cobbaert M, et al. Knowledge and perceptions of the COVID-19 pandemic among patients with myasthenia gravis. Muscle Nerve.2021;62:357–364.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Waters J. Management of myasthenia gravis in pregnancy. Neurol Clin. 2019;37:113–120.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sanders DB, Wolfe GI, Benatar M, et al. International consensus guidance for management of myasthenia gravis: executive summary. Neurology. 2016;87:419–425.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alharbi M, Menon D, Barnett C, et al. Myasthenia gravis and pregnancy: Toronto specialty center experience. Can J Neurol Sci. 2021;48:767–771</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tanacan A, Fadiloglu E, Ozten G, et al. Myasthenia gravis and pregnancy: retrospective evaluation of 27 pregnancies in a tertiary center and comparison with previous studies. Ir J Med Sci. 2019;188:1261–1267.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ducci RD, Lorenzoni PJ, Kay CSK, et al. Clinical follow-up of pregnancy in myasthenia gravis patients. Neuromuscul Disord. 2017;27:352–357.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Papazian O. Transient neonatal myasthenia gravis. J Child Neurol. 1992; 7:135–141.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wolfe GI, Kaminski HJ, Aban IB, et al. On behalf of he MGTX study group. Randomized trial of thymectomy in myasthenia gravis. N Engl J Med. 2016;375:511–522.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Solis-Pazmino P, Baiu I, Lincango-Naranjo E, et al. Impact of the surgical approach to thymectomy upon complete stable remission rates in myasthenia gravis: a Meta-analysis. Neurology. 2021;974:e357-e368.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ng WC, Hartley L. Effectiveness of thymectomy in juvenile myasthenia gravis and clinical characteristics associated with better outcomes. Neuromuscul Disord. 2021 ;31:1113–1123.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim A, Choi SJ, Kang CH, et al. Risk factors for developing post-thymectomy myasthenia gravis in patients with thymoma. Muscle Nerve. 2021 ;63:531–537.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mineo TC, Tamburrini A, Schillaci O, et al. Onset and evolution of clinically apparent myasthenia gravis after resection of nonmyasthenic thymomas. Semin Thorac Cardiovasc Surg. 2018;30: 222–227.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Awatare P, Matthew T, John SK, et al. Positive ice pack test in a patient with Lambert-Eaton myasthenic Syndrome. Muscle Nerve.2021;63:14–26.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chatzistefanou KI, Kouris T, Illakis E, et al. The ice pack test in the differential diagnosis of myasthenic diplopia. Ophthalmology. 2009;116:2236–2243.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stich O, Klages E, Bischler P, et al. SOX1 antibodies in sera from patients with paraneoplastic neurological syndromes. Acta Neurol Scand. 2012;125:326–331.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wada S, Kamei M, Uehara N, et al. Paraneoplastic cerebellar degeneration and lambert-Eaton myasthenic syndrome with SOX-1 antibodies. Intern Med. 2021;60:1607–1610.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
