<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35606663</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>23</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">2198-6576</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>23</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Rheumatology and therapy</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Rheumatol Ther</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Disease Control with Upadacitinib in Patients with Psoriatic Arthritis: A Post Hoc Analysis of the Randomized, Placebo-Controlled SELECT-PsA 1 and 2 Phase 3 Trials.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40744-022-00449-6</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Low disease activity (LDA)/remission is the target of treatment in patients with psoriatic arthritis (PsA). We assessed the proportions of patients with PsA receiving upadacitinib who achieved LDA/remission over 1 year.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">This was a post hoc analysis of the double-blind, placebo-controlled SELECT-PsA 1 (also adalimumab-controlled) and SELECT-PsA 2 trials. Treatment targets assessed included LDA/remission defined by Disease Activity in Psoriatic Arthritis (≤ 14/ ≤ 4) and Psoriatic Arthritis Disease Activity Scores (≤ 3.2/ ≤ 1.9), as well as minimal disease activity (MDA)/very low disease activity (VLDA) states (5/7 and 7/7 components, respectively, of MDA criteria). Targets were assessed at 24 and 56 weeks. For binary outcomes, non-responder imputation was used for missing data. Data from patients receiving upadacitinib 30 mg was not included in the analysis.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Overall, 1386 patients were analyzed. Disease control (i.e., LDA/MDA) was achieved at 24 weeks in upadacitinib 15 mg-treated patients across both studies: LDA/MDA was achieved by 25-48% of patients receiving upadacitinib 15 mg versus 2-16% of patients receiving placebo, and remission/VLDA rates were 7-14% with upadacitinib 15 mg versus 0-4% with placebo. The proportions of patients achieving treatment targets were numerically similar to upadacitinib 15 mg and adalimumab. All responses were sustained at 56 weeks.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Remission and LDA are feasible targets with upadacitinib treatment in patients with PsA.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="TRIAL REGISTRATION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">ClinicalTrial.gov identifiers NCT03104400 (SELECT-PsA 1) and NCT03104374 (SELECT-PsA 2).</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mease</LastName>
            <ForeName>Philip</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Rheumatology, Swedish Medical Center/Providence St. Joseph Health and University of Washington, Seattle, WA, USA. pmease@philipmease.com.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kavanaugh</LastName>
            <ForeName>Arthur</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>University of California San Diego, San Diego, CA, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gladman</LastName>
            <ForeName>Dafna</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Schroeder Arthritis Institute, Krembil Research Institute, Toronto Western Hospital, University Health Network, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Rheumatology, Department of Medicine, and Institute of Medical Science, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>FitzGerald</LastName>
            <ForeName>Oliver</ForeName>
            <Initials>O</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Conway Institute for Biomolecular Research, University College Dublin, Dublin, Ireland.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Soriano</LastName>
            <ForeName>Enrique R</ForeName>
            <Initials>ER</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Rheumatology Unit, Internal Medicine Services, Hospital Italiano de Buenos Aires and Instituto Universitario Hospital Italiano de Buenos Aires, Buenos Aires, Argentina.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nash</LastName>
            <ForeName>Peter</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Medicine, Griffith University, Brisbane, Australia.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Feng</LastName>
            <ForeName>Dai</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>AbbVie Inc, North Chicago, IL, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lertratanakul</LastName>
            <ForeName>Apinya</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>AbbVie Inc, North Chicago, IL, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Douglas</LastName>
            <ForeName>Kevin</ForeName>
            <Initials>K</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>AbbVie Inc, North Chicago, IL, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Lippe</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ralph</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>AbbVie Deutschland GmbH &amp; Co. KG, Wiesbaden, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gossec</LastName>
            <ForeName>Laure</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Sorbonne Université, INSERM, Institut Pierre Louis d'Epidémiologie et de Santé Publique, Paris, France.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Rheumatology Department, Pitié-Salpêtrière Hospital, AP-HP, Sorbonne Université, Paris, France.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <DataBankList CompleteYN="Y">
          <DataBank>
            <DataBankName>ClinicalTrials.gov</DataBankName>
            <AccessionNumberList>
              <AccessionNumber>NCT03104400</AccessionNumber>
              <AccessionNumber>NCT03104374</AccessionNumber>
            </AccessionNumberList>
          </DataBank>
        </DataBankList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Rheumatol Ther</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101674543</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2198-6576</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <OtherAbstract Type="plain-language-summary" Language="eng">
        <AbstractText>Psoriatic arthritis is a disease that causes inflammation of the skin and joints. Doctors measure how bad a patient’s disease is by measuring signs and symptoms of the disease, and using these to make a “score.” The aim of treatment is to reduce the score to low levels (known as “low disease activity”) or very low levels (“remission”). This study looked at results from two clinical trials that compared upadacitinib, a medicine used to treat psoriatic arthritis, with no medicine (placebo) to see how many patients had low disease activity or were in remission after 1 year of treatment. The results showed that more patients who were taking upadacitinib had low disease activity or were in remission after the first 6 months of treatment compared with those who took placebo. This difference between upadacitinib and placebo could still be seen after 1 year of treatment. These results show that treatment with upadacitinib is effective enough for some patients with psoriatic arthritis to achieve low disease activity or remission and to stay at this level, even after more than 1 year of treatment.</AbstractText>
        <CopyrightInformation>© 2022. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation>
      </OtherAbstract>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">JAK inhibitor</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Psoriatic arthritis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SELECT-PsA 1</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">SELECT-PsA 2</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Upadacitinib</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
          <Hour>23</Hour>
          <Minute>31</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35606663</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40744-022-00449-6</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s40744-022-00449-6</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smolen JS, Shols M, Braun J, et al. Treating axial spondyloarthritis and peripheral spondyloarthritis, especially psoriatic arthritis, to target: 2017 update of recommendations by an international task force. Ann Rheum Dis. 2018;77:3–17.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/annrheumdis-2017-211734</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singh JA, Guyatt G, Ogdie A, et al. Special article: 2018 American College of Rheumatology/National Psoriasis Foundation guideline for the treatment of psoriatic arthritis. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken). 2019;71:2–29.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/acr.23789</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gossec L, Baraliakos X, Kerschbaumer A, et al. EULAR recommendations for the management of psoriatic arthritis with pharmacological therapies: 2019 update. Ann Rheum Dis. 2020;79:700–12.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32434812</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gorlier C, Orbai A-M, Puyraimond-Zemmour D, et al. Comparing patient-perceived and physician-perceived remission and low disease activity in psoriatic arthritis: an analysis of 410 patients from 14 countries. Ann Rheum Dis. 2019;78:201–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/annrheumdis-2018-214140</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McInnes IB, Anderson JK, Magrey M, et al. Trial of upadacitinib and adalimumab for psoriatic arthritis. N Engl J Med. 2021;384:1227–39.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa2022516</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McInnes IB, Kato K, Magrey M, et al. Upadacitinib in patients with psoriatic arthritis and an inadequate response to non-biologic therapy: 56-week data from the Phase 3 SELECT-PsA 1 study. RMD Open. 2021;7:e001838.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/rmdopen-2021-001838</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mease PJ, Lertratanakul A, Anderson JK, et al. Upadacitinib for psoriatic arthritis refractory to biologics: SELECT-PsA 2. Ann Rheum Dis. 2020;80:312–20.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/annrheumdis-2020-218870</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mease PJ, Lertratanakul A, Papp KA, et al. Upadacitinib in patients with psoriatic arthritis and inadequate response to biologics: 56-week data from the randomized controlled Phase 3 SELECT-PsA 2 study. Rheumatol Ther. 2021;8:903–19.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40744-021-00305-z</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Taylor W, Gladman D, Helliwell P, Marchesoni A, Mease P, Mielants H, on behalf of the CASPAR Study Group. Classification criteria for psoriatic arthritis: development of new criteria from a large international study. Arthritis Rheum. 2006;54:2665–73.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/art.21972</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mease PJ, Coates LC. Considerations for the definition of remission criteria in psoriatic arthritis. Semin Arthritis Rheum. 2018;47:786–96.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.semarthrit.2017.10.021</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coates LC, Helliwell PS. Defining low disease activity states in psoriatic arthritis using novel composite disease instruments. J Rheumatol. 2016;43:371–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3899/jrheum.150826</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coates LC, Mease PJ, Gossec L, et al. Minimal disease activity among active psoriatic arthritis patients treated with secukinumab: 2-year results from a multicenter, randomized, double-blind, parallel-group, placebo-controlled phase III study. Arthritis Care Res (Hoboken). 2018;70:1529–35.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/acr.23537</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coates LC, Gottlieb AB, Merola JF, Boone C, Szumski A, Chhabra A. Comparison of different remission and low disease definitions in psoriatic arthritis and evaluation of their prognostic value. J Rheumatol. 2019;46:160–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3899/jrheum.180249</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coates LC, Nash P, Kvien TK, et al. Comparison of remission and low disease activity states with DAPSA, MDA and VLDA in a clinical trial setting in psoriatic arthritis patients: 2-year results from the FUTURE 2 study. Semin Arthritis Rheum. 2020;50:709–18.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.semarthrit.2020.03.015</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
