<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="In-Process" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35606751</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>23</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1472-6831</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>22</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>23</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>BMC oral health</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>BMC Oral Health</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Impact of agitation/activation strategies on the antibiofilm potential of sodium hypochlorite/etidronate mixture in vitro.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>201</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>201</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1186/s12903-022-02222-1</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="BACKGROUND" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">To investigate the effect of a rotary agitation method or ultrasonically activated irrigation on the antibiofilm effect of a mixture of sodium hypochlorite (NaOCl) and etidronate (1-hydroxyethylidene-1,1-bisphosphonate, HEBP) using a dual-species biofilm model in root canal system.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">Mature dual-species biofilms of Enterococcus faecalis and Streptococcus gordonii were formed in root canals of mandibular premolars. Teeth were randomly allotted (n = 12) to group 1, XP-endo Finisher (XPF); group 2, ultrasonically activated irrigation (UAI); group 3, syringe-and-needle irrigation (SNI). In all groups, canals were instrumented with a rotary instrument (XP-endo Shaper) prior to irrigant agitation/activation. A mixture containing 2.5% NaOCl and 9% HEBP was used throughout the experiment. Bacterial counts from the canal were determined using qPCR before preparation (S1), after preparation (S2), and after final irrigation agitation/activation (S3). Bacterial viability within the dentinal tubules in the coronal, middle and apical root-thirds was quantified using confocal microscopy after Live/Dead staining. The bacterial counts and viability were compared between groups using one-way ANOVA and post-hoc Tukey's tests. Paired t-test was used to compare the bacterial counts within groups.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Instrumentation alone could significantly reduce the microbial counts in all the groups (P &lt; 0.0001). Subsequent agitation/activation resulted in significant microbial reduction only in XPF and UAI (P &lt; 0.05), both of which reduced significantly more microbial counts than SNI (P &lt; 0.05). Live/Dead staining revealed that XPF and UAI showed significantly greater percentage of dead bacteria within the dentinal tubules than SNI in the coronal third (P &lt; 0.05); UAI resulted in the significantly highest percentage of dead bacteria in the middle third (P &lt; 0.05); while there was no significant difference between the groups in the apical third (P &gt; 0.05).</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">When using the sodium hypochlorite/etidronate mixture for irrigation, final irrigant agitation/activation with XP-endo Finisher or ultrasonic can improve disinfection of the main root canal space and the dentinal tubules in the coronal third, while ultrasonically activated irrigation appears to exhibit better disinfection within dentinal tubules in the middle third.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022. The Author(s).</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y">
            <LastName>Cai</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ming</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Operative Dentistry and Endodontics, Hospital of Stomatology, Sun Yat-Sen University, 56 Lingyuan Xi Road, Guangzhou, 510055, Guangdong, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Guangdong Provincial Key Laboratory of Stomatology, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of General Dentistry, School of Stomatology, Kunming Medical University, Kunming, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y">
            <LastName>Cai</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yanling</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Operative Dentistry and Endodontics, Hospital of Stomatology, Sun Yat-Sen University, 56 Lingyuan Xi Road, Guangzhou, 510055, Guangdong, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Guangdong Provincial Key Laboratory of Stomatology, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ruiqi</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Operative Dentistry and Endodontics, Hospital of Stomatology, Sun Yat-Sen University, 56 Lingyuan Xi Road, Guangzhou, 510055, Guangdong, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Guangdong Provincial Key Laboratory of Stomatology, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Xu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Zhezhen</ForeName>
            <Initials>Z</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Operative Dentistry and Endodontics, Hospital of Stomatology, Sun Yat-Sen University, 56 Lingyuan Xi Road, Guangzhou, 510055, Guangdong, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Guangdong Provincial Key Laboratory of Stomatology, Guangzhou, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Neelakantan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Prasanna</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Discipline of Endodontology, Faculty of Dentistry, The University of Hong Kong, The Prince Philip Dental Hospital, 34 Hospital Road, Sai Ying Pun, Pok Fu Lam, Hong Kong SAR, China. prasanna@hku.hk.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wei</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xi</ForeName>
            <Initials>X</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Operative Dentistry and Endodontics, Hospital of Stomatology, Sun Yat-Sen University, 56 Lingyuan Xi Road, Guangzhou, 510055, Guangdong, China. weixi@mail.sysu.edu.cn.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Guangdong Provincial Key Laboratory of Stomatology, Guangzhou, China. weixi@mail.sysu.edu.cn.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>England</Country>
        <MedlineTA>BMC Oral Health</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101088684</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1472-6831</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Biofilm</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Disinfection</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Etidronate</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Sodium hypochlorite</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Ultrasonically activated irrigation</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">XP-endo Finisher</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">XP-endo Shaper</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>21</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
          <Hour>23</Hour>
          <Minute>46</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35606751</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12903-022-02222-1</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1186/s12903-022-02222-1</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Waltimo T, Trope M, Haapasalo M, Ørstavik D. Clinical efficacy of treatment procedures in endodontic infection control and one year follow-up of periapical healing. J Endod. 2005;31:863–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16306819</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/01.don.0000164856.27920.85</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Neelakantan P, Romero M, Vera J, Daood U, Khan AU, Yan A, Cheung GSP. Biofilms in endodontics-current status and future directions. Int J Mol Sci. 2017;18:1748.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5578138</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/ijms18081748</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Siqueira Junior JF, Rôças IDN, Marceliano-Alves MF, Pérez AR, Ricucci D. Unprepared root canal surface areas: causes, clinical implications, and therapeutic strategies. Braz Oral Res. 2018;32(Suppl 1):e65.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30365606</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/1807-3107bor-2018.vol32.0065</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Siqueira JF Jr, Pérez AR, Marceliano-Alves MF, Provenzano JC, Silva SG, Pires FR, Vieira GCS, Rôças IN, Alves FRF. What happens to unprepared root canal walls: a correlative analysis using micro-computed tomography and histology/scanning electron microscopy. Int Endod J. 2018;51:501–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28196289</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/iej.12753</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zehnder M. Root canal irrigants. J Endod. 2006;32:389–98.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16631834</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joen.2005.09.014</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zehnder M, Schmidlin P, Sener B, Waltimo T. Chelation in root canal therapy reconsidered. J Endod. 2005;31:817–20.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16249726</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/01.don.0000158233.59316.fe</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rath PP, Yiu CKY, Matinlinna JP, Kishen A, Neelakantan P. The effects of sequential and continuous chelation on dentin. Dent Mater. 2020;36:1655–65.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33162115</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.dental.2020.10.010</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lottanti S, Gautschi H, Sener B, Zehnder M. Effects of ethylenediaminetetraacetic, etidronic and peracetic acid irrigation on human root dentine and the smear layer. Int Endod J. 2009;42:335–43.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19220516</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2591.2008.01514.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Neelakantan P, Cheng CQ, Mohanraj R, Sriraman P, Subbarao C, Sharma S. Antibiofilm activity of three irrigation protocols activated by ultrasonic, diode laser or Er:YAG laser in vitro. Int Endod J. 2015;48:602–10.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25080240</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/iej.12354</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arias-Moliz MT, Ordinola-Zapata R, Baca P, Ruiz-Linares M, Ferrer-Luque CM. Antimicrobial activity of a sodium hypochlorite/etidronic acid irrigant solution. J Endod. 2014;40:1999–2002.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25266466</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joen.2014.07.031</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Căpută PE, Retsas A, Kuijk L. Ultrasonic irrigant activation during root canal treatment: a systematic review. J Endod. 2019;45:31-44.e13.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30558797</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joen.2018.09.010</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nagendrababu V, Jayaraman J, Suresh A, Kalyanasundaram S, Neelakantan P. Effectiveness of ultrasonically activated irrigation on root canal disinfection: a systematic review of in vitro studies. Clin Oral Investig. 2018;22:655–70.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29372445</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00784-018-2345-x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Silva E, Rover G, Belladonna FG, Herrera DR, De-Deus G, da Silva Fidalgo TK. Effectiveness of passive ultrasonic irrigation on periapical healing and root canal disinfection: a systematic review. Br Dent J. 2019;227:228–34.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31399682</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41415-019-0532-z</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Faria G, Viola KS, Coaguila-Llerena H, Oliveira LRA, Leonardo RT, Aranda-García AJ, Guerreiro-Tanomaru JM. Penetration of sodium hypochlorite into root canal dentine: effect of surfactants, gel form and passive ultrasonic irrigation. Int Endod J. 2019;52:385–92.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30220093</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/iej.13015</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De-Deus G, Belladonna FG, de Siqueira ZA, Perez R, Carvalho MS, Souza EM, Lopes RT, Silva E. Micro-CT comparison of XP-endo Finisher and passive ultrasonic irrigation as final irrigation protocols on the removal of accumulated hard-tissue debris from oval shaped-canals. Clin Oral Investig. 2019;23:3087–93.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30417226</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00784-018-2729-y</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ballal NV, Gandhi P, Shenoy PA, Dummer PMH. Evaluation of various irrigation activation systems to eliminate bacteria from the root canal system: a randomized controlled single blinded trial. J Dent. 2020;99:103412.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32585261</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jdent.2020.103412</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Carvalho MC, Zuolo ML, Arruda-Vasconcelos R, Marinho ACS, Louzada LM, Francisco PA, Pecorari VGA, Gomes B. Effectiveness of XP-Endo Finisher in the reduction of bacterial load in oval-shaped root canals. Braz Oral Res. 2019;33: e021.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31508722</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1590/1807-3107bor-2019.vol33.0021</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pladisai P, Ampornaramveth RS, Chivatxaranukul P. Effectiveness of different disinfection protocols on the reduction of bacteria in enterococcus faecalis biofilm in teeth with large root canals. J Endod. 2016;42:460–4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26830428</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joen.2015.12.016</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Paiva SS, Siqueira JF Jr, Rôças IN, Carmo FL, Ferreira DC, Curvelo JA, Soares RM, Rosado AS. Supplementing the antimicrobial effects of chemomechanical debridement with either passive ultrasonic irrigation or a final rinse with chlorhexidine: a clinical study. J Endod. 2012;38:1202–6.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22892736</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joen.2012.06.023</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kumar Tiwari S, Guo X, Huang Y, Zhou X, Xu HHK, Ren B, Peng X, Weir MD, Li M, Cheng L. The inhibitory effect of quaternary ammonium salt on bacteria in root canal. Sci Rep. 2019;9:12463.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31462657</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6713705</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41598-019-48666-4</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dai S, Xiao G, Dong N, Liu F, He S, Guo Q. Bactericidal effect of a diode laser on Enterococcus faecalis in human primary teeth-an in vitro study. BMC Oral Health. 2018;18:154.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30165840</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6117880</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12903-018-0611-6</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jiang LM, Hoogenkamp MA, van der Sluis LW, Wesselink PR, Crielaard W, Deng DM. Resazurin metabolism assay for root canal disinfectant evaluation on dual-species biofilms. J Endod. 2011;37:31–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21146072</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joen.2010.09.007</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gomes BP, Berber VB, Kokaras AS, Chen T, Paster BJ. Microbiomes of endodontic-periodontal lesions before and after chemomechanical preparation. J Endod. 2015;41:1975–84.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26521147</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">7061340</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joen.2015.08.022</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sedgley C, Nagel A, Dahlén G, Reit C, Molander A. Real-time quantitative polymerase chain reaction and culture analyses of Enterococcus faecalis in root canals. J Endod. 2006;32:173–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16500220</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joen.2005.10.037</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gao Y, Jiang X, Lin D, Chen Y, Tong Z. The starvation resistance and biofilm formation of enterococcus faecalis in coexistence with Candida albicans, Streptococcus gordonii, Actinomyces viscosus, or Lactobacillus acidophilus. J Endod. 2016;42:1233–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27316318</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joen.2016.05.002</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zandi H, Kristoffersen AK, Ørstavik D, Rôças IN, Siqueira JF Jr, Enersen M. Microbial analysis of endodontic infections in root-filled teeth with apical periodontitis before and after irrigation using pyrosequencing. J Endod. 2018;44:372–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29306533</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joen.2017.11.019</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chávez de Paz L, Svensäter G, Dahlén G, Bergenholtz G. Streptococci from root canals in teeth with apical periodontitis receiving endodontic treatment. Oral Surg Oral Med Oral Pathol Oral Radiol Endod. 2005;100:232–41.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16037782</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.tripleo.2004.10.008</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhao Y, Fan W, Xu T, Tay FR, Gutmann JL, Fan B. Evaluation of several instrumentation techniques and irrigation methods on the percentage of untouched canal wall and accumulated dentine debris in C-shaped canals. Int Endod J. 2019;52:1354–65.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30897222</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/iej.13119</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fernandes POF, Freire LG, Iglecias EF, Vieira BR, Zuolo ML, Gavini G. Assessment of mechanical root canal preparation with centric reciprocating or eccentric rotary kinematics: a micro-computed tomographic study. J Endod. 2020;46:1309–16.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32565335</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joen.2020.06.005</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sakamoto M, Siqueira JF Jr, Rôças IN, Benno Y. Bacterial reduction and persistence after endodontic treatment procedures. Oral Microbiol Immunol. 2007;22:19–23.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17241166</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1399-302X.2007.00315.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alves FRF, Paiva PL, Marceliano-Alves MF, Cabreira LJ, Lima KC, Siqueira JF Jr, Rôças IN, Provenzano JC. Bacteria and hard tissue debris extrusion and intracanal bacterial reduction promoted by XP-endo shaper and reciproc instruments. J Endod. 2018;44:1173–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29861066</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joen.2018.04.007</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roy RA, Ahmad M, Crum LA. Physical mechanisms governing the hydrodynamic response of an oscillating ultrasonic file. Int Endod J. 1994;27:197–207.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7814129</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/j.1365-2591.1994.tb00254.x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Leonardi DP, Grande NM, Tomazinho FSF, Marques-da-Silva B, Gonzaga CC, Baratto-Filho F, Plotino G. Influence of activation mode and preheating on intracanal irrigant temperature. Aust Endod J. 2019;45:373–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30724420</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/aej.12336</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mohmmed SA, Vianna ME, Penny MR, Hilton ST, Mordan N, Knowles JC. A novel experimental approach to investigate the effect of different agitation methods using sodium hypochlorite as an irrigant on the rate of bacterial biofilm removal from the wall of a simulated root canal model. Dent Mater. 2016;32:1289–300.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27515530</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.dental.2016.07.013</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alves FR, Andrade-Junior CV, Marceliano-Alves MF, Pérez AR, Rôças IN, Versiani MA, Sousa-Neto MD, Provenzano JC, Siqueira JF Jr. Adjunctive steps for disinfection of the mandibular molar root canal system: a correlative bacteriologic, micro-computed tomography, and cryopulverization approach. J Endod. 2016;42:1667–72.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27641947</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joen.2016.08.003</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen JE, Nurbakhsh B, Layton G, Bussmann M, Kishen A. Irrigation dynamics associated with positive pressure, apical negative pressure and passive ultrasonic irrigations: a computational fluid dynamics analysis. Aust Endod J. 2014;40:54–60.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25244218</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/aej.12027</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pacheco-Yanes J, Provenzano JC, Marceliano-Alves MF, Gazzaneo I, Pérez AR, Gonçalves LS, Siqueira JF Jr. Distribution of sodium hypochlorite throughout the mesial root canal system of mandibular molars after adjunctive irrigant activation procedures: a micro-computed tomographic study. Clin Oral Investig. 2020;24:907–14.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31240405</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00784-019-02970-5</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Galler KM, Grubmüller V, Schlichting R, Widbiller M, Eidt A, Schuller C, Wölflick M, Hiller KA, Buchalla W. Penetration depth of irrigants into root dentine after sonic, ultrasonic and photoacoustic activation. Int Endod J. 2019;52:1210–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30828819</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boutsioukis C, Verhaagen B, Walmsley AD, Versluis M, van der Sluis LW. Measurement and visualization of file-to-wall contact during ultrasonically activated irrigation in simulated canals. Int Endod J. 2013;46:1046–55.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23521118</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/iej.12097</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Giardino L, Del Fabbro M, Morra M, Pereira T. Dual Rinse(®) HEDP increases the surface tension of NaOCl but may increase its dentin disinfection efficacy. Odontology. 2019;107:521–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31197618</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10266-019-00436-4</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Siqueira JF Jr, Alves FR, Rôças IN. Pyrosequencing analysis of the apical root canal microbiota. J Endod. 2011;37:1499–503.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22000451</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joen.2011.08.012</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lin J, Shen Y, Haapasalo M. A comparative study of biofilm removal with hand, rotary nickel-titanium, and self-adjusting file instrumentation using a novel in vitro biofilm model. J Endod. 2013;39:658–63.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23611386</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.joen.2012.11.012</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
