<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35600521</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>24</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">1936-1521</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>15</Volume>
            <Issue>2</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of child &amp; adolescent trauma</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Child Adolesc Trauma</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Childhood Physical Abuse and Antisocial Traits: Mediating Role of Posttraumatic Stress Symptom Clusters.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>249</StartPage>
          <EndPage>259</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>249-259</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s40653-021-00364-y</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Posttraumatic stress symptoms (PTSS) are associated with both childhood physical abuse (CPA) and antisocial (AS) traits, yet their potential as mediators of the CPA-AS traits link is understudied and the specific roles of individual symptom clusters in this relation is unknown. The current study aimed to examine the mediational role of PTSS in the relation between CPA and AS traits in a sample of low-income African American women with histories of intimate partner violence (IPV). It was hypothesized that avoidance would emerge as a significant mediator, whereas reexperiencing, numbing, and hyperarousal would not. Participants (<i>N</i> = 150) were recruited from a level-1 trauma public hospital and evaluated as part of a randomized controlled trial of a group therapy intervention for low-income, African American women suicide attempters with histories of IPV. The Childhood Trauma Questionnaire <i>(</i>CTQ), Posttraumatic Diagnostic Scale (PDS), and International Personality Disorder Examination-Screening Questionnaire (IPDE-SQ) were used to measure variables of interest. Using bootstrapping analyses, a parallel mediation model compared PTSS clusters as potential mediators of the CPA-AS traits relation, controlling for IPV. When reexperiencing, avoidance, numbing, and hyperarousal were entered simultaneously as potential mediators, only avoidance emerged as a significant mediator of the CPA-AS traits link. Avoidance symptoms may play a unique role in the link between early experiences of CPA and later AS traits among multiply traumatized African American women. Findings have implications for understanding AS traits in the context of early life trauma and suggest that targeting specific PTSS clusters (e.g., avoidance) may improve treatment outcomes for women in this population.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© The Author(s), under exclusive licence to Springer Nature Switzerland AG 2021.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Harris</LastName>
            <ForeName>Catherine E</ForeName>
            <Initials>CE</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-5765-3633</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Psychology, John Jay College of Criminal Justice, City University of New York, 524 W. 59th Street, New York, NY 10019 USA.</Affiliation>
              <Identifier Source="GRID">grid.212340.6</Identifier>
              <Identifier Source="ISNI">0000000122985718</Identifier>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Allbaugh</LastName>
            <ForeName>Lucy J</ForeName>
            <Initials>LJ</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-7770-1994</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Psychology, University of Dayton, Dayton, OH USA.</Affiliation>
              <Identifier Source="GRID">grid.266231.2</Identifier>
              <Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0001 2175 167X</Identifier>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Kaslow</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nadine J</ForeName>
            <Initials>NJ</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-0775-8597</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry and Behavioral Sciences, Emory University School of Medicine, Atlanta, GA USA.</Affiliation>
              <Identifier Source="GRID">grid.189967.8</Identifier>
              <Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0001 0941 6502</Identifier>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>29</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>J Child Adolesc Trauma</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101306630</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1936-1521</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">African American women</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Antisocial personality disorder</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Antisocial traits</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Childhood physical abuse</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Posttraumatic stress disorder</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Posttraumatic stress symptoms</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>Conflict of InterestOn behalf of all authors, the corresponding author states that there is no conflict of interest.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>11</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release">
          <Year>2023</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
          <Hour>3</Hour>
          <Minute>55</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35600521</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9120298</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s40653-021-00364-y</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">364</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Allwood MA, Bell DJ. A preliminary examination of emotional and cognitive mediators in the relations between violence exposure and violent behaviors in youth. Journal of Community Psychology. 2008;36:989–1007. doi: 10.1002/jcop.20277.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcop.20277</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>American Psychiatric Association. (2000). Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders (4th ed.). Author. 10.1176/appi.books.9780890420249.dsm-iv-tr</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>American Psychiatric Association. (2013). Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders (5th ed.). Author. 10.1176/appi.books.9780890425596</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Author. (2010). [Title omitted for blind review.]</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ball L, Tully RJ, Egan V. The SAPAS, personality traits, and personality disorder. Journal of Personality Disorders. 2017;31(3):385–398. doi: 10.1521/pedi_2016_30_259.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1521/pedi_2016_30_259</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27387058</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Banducci AN, Hoffman EM, Lejuez CW, Koenen KC. The impact of childhood abuse on inpatient substance users: Specific links with risky sex, aggression, and emotion dysregulation. Child Abuse &amp; Neglect. 2014;38(5):928–938. doi: 10.1016/j.chiabu.2013.12.007.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chiabu.2013.12.007</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4065225</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24521524</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bell CC, Mattis J. The importance of cultural competence in ministering to African American victims of domestic violence. Violence Against Women. 2000;6:515–532. doi: 10.1177/1557085105282897.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1557085105282897</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bernstein DP, Stein JA, Newcomb MD, Walker E, Pogge D, Ahluvalia T, Stokes J, Handelsman L, Medrano M, Desmond D, Zule W. Development and validation of a brief screening version of the childhood trauma questionnaire. Child Abuse &amp; Neglect. 2003;27(2):169–190. doi: 10.1016/S0145-2134(02)00541-0.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0145-2134(02)00541-0</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12615092</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bottoms BL, Peter-Hagene LC, Epstein MA, Wiley TR, Reynolds CE, Rudnicki AG. Abuse characteristics and individual differences related to disclosing childhood sexual, physical, and emotional abuse and witnessed domestic violence. Journal of Interpersonal Violence. 2016;31(7):1308–1339. doi: 10.1177/0886260514564155.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0886260514564155</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25550167</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bovin MJ, Wolf EJ, Resick PA. Longitudinal associations between posttraumatic stress disorder severity and personality disorder features among female rape survivors. Frontiers in Psychiatry. 2017;8(6):1. doi: 10.3389/fpsyt.2017.00006.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fpsyt.2017.00006</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5253387</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28167920</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cavanaugh CE, Hansen NB, Sullivan TP. HIV sexual risk behavior among low income women experiencing intimate partner violence: The role of posttraumatic stress disorder. AIDS and Behavior. 2010;14(2):318–327. doi: 10.1007/s10461-009-9623-1.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10461-009-9623-1</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2866623</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19856093</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cernkovich SA, Lanctôt N, Giordano PC. Predicting adolescent and adult antisocial behavior among adjudicated delinquent females. Crime &amp; Delinquency. 2008;54(1):3–33. doi: 10.1177/0011128706294395.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0011128706294395</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cohen, J. A., Deblinger, E., Mannarino, A. P., &amp; de Arellano, M. A. (2001). The importance of culture in treating abused and neglected children: An empirical review. Child Maltreatment, 6(2), 148–157. 10.1177/1077559501006002007.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cohen LJ, Tanis T, Bhattacharjee R, Nesci C, Halmi W, Galynker I. Are there differential relationships between different types of childhood maltreatment and different types of adult personality pathology? Psychiatry Research. 2014;215(1):192–201. doi: 10.1016/j.psychres.2013.10.036.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.psychres.2013.10.036</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24268580</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Consedine NS, Magai C, Neugut AI. The contribution of emotional characteristics to breast cancer screening among women from six ethnic groups. Preventive Medicine. 2004;38:64–77. doi: 10.1016/j.ypmed.2003.09.030.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ypmed.2003.09.030</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14672643</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cook, S. L., Conrad, L., Bender, M., &amp; Kaslow, N. J. (2003). The internal validity of the Index of Spouse Abuse in African American women. Violence and Victims, 18(6), 641–657. 10.1891/vivi.2003.18.6.641.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Courtois, C. A., &amp; Ford, J. D. (2012). Treatment of complex trauma: A sequenced, relationship-based approach. Guilford Press. 10.1002/anzf.1303.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cross D, Crow T, Powers A, Bradley B. Childhood trauma, PTSD, and problematic alcohol and substance use in low-income, African-American men and women. Child Abuse &amp; Neglect. 2015;44:26–35. doi: 10.1016/j.chiabu.2015.01.007.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chiabu.2015.01.007</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4461539</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25680654</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Daughters, S. B., Sargeant, M. N., Bornovalova, M. A., Gratz, K. L., &amp; Lejuez, C. W. (2008). The relationship between distress tolerance and antisocial personality disorder among male inner-city treatment seeking substance users. Journal of Personality Disorders, 22(5), 509–524. 10.1521/pedi.2008.22.5.509.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>De Bellis MD. Developmental traumatology: The psychobiological development of maltreated children and its implications for research, treatment, and policy. Development and Psychopathology. 2001;13:539–564. doi: 10.1017/S0954579401003078.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1017/S0954579401003078</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11523847</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Donahue JJ, McClure KS, Moon SM. The relationship between emotion regulation difficulties and psychopathic personality characteristics. Personality Disorders, Theory, Research, and Treatment. 2014;5(2):186. doi: 10.1037/per0000025.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/per0000025</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Durbin CE, Hicks BM. Personality and psychopathology: A stagnant field in need of development. European Journal of Personality. 2014;28(4):362–386. doi: 10.1002/per.1962.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/per.1962</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4276423</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25544802</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dworkin, E. R., Wanklyn, S., Stasiewicz, P. R., &amp; Coffey, S. F. (2018). PTSD symptom presentation among people with alcohol and drug use disorders: Comparisons by substance of abuse. Addictive Behaviors, 76, 188–194. 10.1016/j.addbeh.2017.08.019.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fink DS, Gradus JL, Keyes KM, Calabrese JR, Liberzon I, Tamburrino MB, Cohen G, Sampson L, Galea S. Subthreshold PTSD and PTSD in a prospective-longitudinal cohort of military personnel: Potential targets for preventive interventions. Depression and Anxiety. 2018;35(11):1048–1055. doi: 10.1002/da.22819.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/da.22819</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6212313</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30099820</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Florez, I. A., Mekawi, Y., Hunnicutt-Ferguson, K., Visser, K. F., Clunie, A. M., Dunn, S. E., &amp; Kaslow, N. J. (2020). Childhood abuse, posttraumatic stress symptoms, and alcohol misuse among African-American women. Journal of Ethnicity in Substance Abuse, 1–23. 10.1080/15332640.2020.1725707.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Foa EB, Cashman L, Jaycox L, Perry K. The validation of a self-report measure of posttraumatic stress disorder: The posttraumatic diagnostic scale. Psychological Assessment. 1997;9(4):445. doi: 10.1037/1040-3590.9.4.445.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/1040-3590.9.4.445</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gobin RL, Iverson KM, Mitchell K, Vaughn R, Resick PA. The impact of childhood maltreatment on PTSD symptoms among female survivors of intimate partner violence. Violence and Victims. 2013;28(6):984–999. doi: 10.1891/0886-6708.VV-D-12-00090.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1891/0886-6708.VV-D-12-00090</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24547676</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goldmann E, Aiello A, Uddin M, Delva J, Koenen K, Gant LM, Galea S. Pervasive exposure to violence and posttraumatic stress disorder in a predominantly African American Urban Community: The Detroit neighborhood health study. Journal of Traumatic Stress. 2011;24(6):747–751. doi: 10.1002/jts.20705.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jts.20705</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4433006</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22144187</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Goldstein B, Bradley B, Ressler KJ, Powers A. Associations between posttraumatic stress disorder, emotion dysregulation, and alcohol dependence symptoms among inner city females. Journal of Clinical Psychology. 2017;73(3):319–330. doi: 10.1002/jclp.22332.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jclp.22332</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5324595</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27467499</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>González, R. A., Kallis, C., Ullrich, S., Barnicot, K., Keers, R., &amp; Coid, J. W. (2016). Childhood maltreatment and violence: Mediation through psychiatric morbidity. Child Abuse &amp; Neglect, 52, 70–84. 10.1016/j.chiabu.2016.01.002.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Graham JW. Missing data analysis: Making it work in the real world. Annual Review of Psychology. 2009;60:549–576. doi: 10.1146/annurev.psych.58.110405.085530.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1146/annurev.psych.58.110405.085530</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18652544</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Griffin, M. G., Uhlmansiek, M. H., Resick, P. A., &amp; Mechanic, M. B. (2004). Comparison of the posttraumatic stress disorder scale versus the clinician‐administered posttraumatic stress disorder scale in domestic violence survivors. Journal of Traumatic Stress, 17(6), 497–503. 10.1007/s10960-004-5798-4.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hawkins AO, Danielson CK, de Arellano MA, Hanson RF, Ruggiero KJ, Smith DW, Saunders BE, Kilpatrick DG. Ethnic/racial differences in the prevalence of injurious spanking and other child physical abuse in a national survey of adolescents. Child Maltreatment. 2010;15(3):242–249. doi: 10.1177/1077559510367938.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1077559510367938</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20498129</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hayes, A. F. (2013). The PROCESS macro for SPSS and SAS (Version 2.13) [Software].</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hayes, S. C., Strosahl, K. D., &amp; Wilson, K. G. (2011). Acceptance and commitment therapy: Theprocess and practice of mindful change. Guilford Press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hellmuth JC, Jaquier V, Swan SC, Sullivan TP. Elucidating posttraumatic stress symptom profiles and their correlates among women experiencing bidirectional intimate partner violence. Journal of Clinical Psychology. 2014;70(10):1008–1021. doi: 10.1002/jclp.22100.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jclp.22100</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4280565</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24752965</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hood SK, Carter MM. A preliminary examination of trauma history, locus of control, and PTSD symptom severity in African American women. Journal of Black Psychology. 2008;34:179–191. doi: 10.1177/0095798407310541.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0095798407310541</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hudson W, McIntosh S. The index of spouse abuse: Two quantifiable dimensions. Journal of Marriage and Family. 1981;43:873–888. doi: 10.2307/351344.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2307/351344</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Iverson KM, Bauer MR, Shipherd JC, Pineles SL, Harrington EF, Resick PA. Differential associations between partner violence and physical health symptoms among Caucasian and African American help-seeking women. Psychological Trauma Theory Research Practice and Policy. 2013;5(2):158. doi: 10.1037/a0025912.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/a0025912</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3632218</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23616911</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jones MS, Burge SW, Sharp SF, McLeod DA. Childhood adversity, mental health, and the perpetration of physical violence in the adult intimate relationships of women prisoners: A life course approach. Child Abuse &amp; Neglect. 2020;101:104237. doi: 10.1016/j.chiabu.2019.104237.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chiabu.2019.104237</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31981933</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kerig PK, Bennett DC, Thompson M, Becker SP. “Nothing really matters”: Emotional numbing as a link between trauma exposure and callousness in delinquent youth. Journal of Traumatic Stress. 2012;25(3):272–279. doi: 10.1002/jts.21700.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jts.21700</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22615202</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Koenen KC. Developmental origins of posttraumatic stress disorder. Depression and Anxiety. 2010;27(5):413–416. doi: 10.1002/da.20696.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/da.20696</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20455245</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Krause ED, Kaltman S, Goodman L, Dutton MA. Role of distinct PTSD symptoms in intimate partner reabuse: A prospective study. Journal of Traumatic Stress. 2006;19(4):507–516. doi: 10.1002/jts.20136.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jts.20136</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16929505</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lansford JE, Miller-Johnson S, Berlin LJ, Dodge KA, Bates JE, Pettit GS. Early physical abuse and later violent delinquency: A prospective longitudinal study. Child Maltreatment. 2007;12(3):233–245. doi: 10.1177/1077559507301841.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1077559507301841</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2771618</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17631623</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lansford JE, Dodge KA, Pettit GS, Bates JE. Does physical abuse in early childhood predict substance use in adolescence and early adulthood? Child Maltreatment. 2010;15(2):190–194. doi: 10.1177/1077559509352359.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1077559509352359</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2868928</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20019026</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liebschutz JM, Buchanan-Howland K, Chen CA, Frank DA, Richardson MA, Heeren TC, Cabral HJ, Rose-Jacobs R. Childhood trauma questionnaire (CTQ) correlations with prospective violence assessment in a longitudinal cohort. Psychological Assessment. 2018;30(6):841–845. doi: 10.1037/pas0000549.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/pas0000549</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5986087</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29847987</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lobbestael J, Arntz A, Bernstein DP. Disentangling the relationship between different types of childhood maltreatment and personality disorders. Journal of Personality Disorders. 2010;24(3):285–295. doi: 10.1521/pedi.2010.24.3.285.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1521/pedi.2010.24.3.285</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20545495</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Loranger, A. (1999). IPDE: International Personality Disorder Examination: DSM–IV and ICD10 interviews. Retrieved from https://www.parinc.com/Products/Pkey/208.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Loranger AW, Sartorius N, Andreoli A, Berger P, Buchheim P, Channabasavanna SM, Coid B, Dahl A, Diekstra R, Ferguson B, Jacobsberg L, Mombour W, Pull C, Ono Y, Regier D. The international personality disorder examination: The World Health Organization/alcohol, drug abuse, and mental health administration international pilot study of personality disorders. Archives of General Psychiatry. 1994;51(3):215–224. doi: 10.1001/archpsyc.1994.03950030051005.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1001/archpsyc.1994.03950030051005</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8122958</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Luntz BK, Widom CS. Antisocial personality disorder in abused and neglected children grown up. The American Journal of Psychiatry. 1994;151(5):670–674. doi: 10.1176/ajp.151.5.670.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1176/ajp.151.5.670</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8166307</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>MacDonald K, Thomas ML, Sciolla AF, Schneider B, Pappas K, Bleijenberg G, Bohus M, Bekh B, Carpenter L, Carr A, Dannlowski U. Minimization of childhood maltreatment is common and consequential: Results from a large, multinational sample using the childhood trauma questionnaire. PLoS ONE. 2016;11(1):1–16. doi: 10.1371/journal.pone.0146058.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0146058</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Macy RJ, Rizo CF, Ermentrout DM. Characteristics, needs, and help seeking of partner violence victims mandated to community services by courts and child protective services. American Journal of Orthopsychiatry. 2013;83(4):588–599. doi: 10.1111/ajop.12049.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/ajop.12049</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24164530</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maguen S, Stalnaker M, McCaslin S, Litz BT. PTSD subclusters and functional impairment in Kosovo peacekeepers. Military Medicine. 2009;174(8):779–785. doi: 10.7205/MILMED-D-03-2808.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7205/MILMED-D-03-2808</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19743730</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matlow RB, DePrince AP. The influence of victimization history on PTSD symptom expression in women exposed to intimate partner violence. Psychological Trauma Theory Research Practice and Policy. 2013;5(3):241. doi: 10.1037/a0027655.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/a0027655</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Milner JS, Thomsen CJ, Crouch JL, Rabenhorst MM, Martens PM, Dyslin CW, Guimond JM, Stander VA, Merrill LL. Do trauma symptoms mediate the relationship between childhood physical abuse and adult child abuse risk? Child Abuse &amp; Neglect. 2010;34(5):332–344. doi: 10.1016/j.chiabu.2009.09.017.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chiabu.2009.09.017</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20359748</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mordeno IG, Carpio JGE, Nalipay MJN, Saavedra RLJ. PTSD’s underlying dimensions in typhoon Haiyan survivors: Assessing DSM-5 symptomatology-based PTSD models and their relation to posttraumatic cognition. Psychiatric Quarterly. 2017;88(1):9–23. doi: 10.1007/s11126-016-9429-z.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11126-016-9429-z</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26921207</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Müller, M., Vandeleur, C., Rodgers, S., Rössler, W., Castelao, E., Preisig, M., &amp; Ajdacic-Gross, V. (2015). Posttraumatic stress avoidance symptoms as mediators in the development of alcohol use disorders after exposure to childhood sexual abuse in a Swiss community sample. Child Abuse &amp; Neglect, 46, 8–15. 10.1016/j.chiabu.2015.03.006.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ouellet-Morin I, Fisher HL, York-Smith M, Fincham-Campbell S, Moffitt TE, Arseneault L. Intimate partner violence and new-onset depression: A longitudinal study of women's childhood and adult histories of abuse. Depression and Anxiety. 2015;32(5):316–324. doi: 10.1002/da.22347.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/da.22347</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4418177</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25691224</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Overstreet NM, Willie TC, Hellmuth JC, Sullivan TP. Psychological intimate partner violence and sexual risk behavior: Examining the role of distinct posttraumatic stress disorder symptoms in the partner violence–sexual risk link. Women's Health Issues. 2015;25(1):73–78. doi: 10.1016/j.whi.2014.10.005.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.whi.2014.10.005</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4275339</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25498762</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Patel MN, Bhaju J, Thompson MP, Kaslow NJ. Life stress as mediator of the childhood maltreatment–intimate partner violence link in low-income, African American women. Journal of Family Violence. 2012;27(1):1–10. doi: 10.1007/s10896-011-9398-9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10896-011-9398-9</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pegram SE, Abbey A. Associations between sexual assault severity and psychological and physical health outcomes: Similarities and differences among African American and Caucasian survivors. Journal of Interpersonal Violence. 2019;34(19):4020–4040. doi: 10.1177/0886260516673626.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/0886260516673626</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7019196</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27754921</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Perrin M, Vandeleur CL, Castelao E, Rothen S, Glaus J, Vollenweider P, Preisig M. Determinants of the development of post-traumatic stress disorder, in the general population. Social Psychiatry and Psychiatric Epidemiology. 2014;49(3):447–457. doi: 10.1007/s00127-013-0762-3.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00127-013-0762-3</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24022753</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Powers, A., Fani, N., Murphy, L., Briscione, M., Bradley, B., Tone, E. B., et al. (2019). Attention bias toward threatening faces in women with PTSD: eye tracking correlates by symptom cluster. European Journal of Psychotraumatology, 10(1). 10.1080/20008198.2019.1568133.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Resick PA, Schnicke MK. Cognitive processing therapy for sexual assault victims. Journal of Consulting and Clinical Psychology. 1992;60(5):748–756. doi: 10.1037/0022-006X.60.5.748.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/0022-006X.60.5.748</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1401390</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Richie, B. E., &amp; Eife, E. (2020). Black bodies at the dangerous intersection of gender violence and mass criminalization. Journal of Aggression, Maltreatment &amp; Trauma, 1–12. 10.1080/10926771.2019.1703063.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roberts DE. The social and moral cost of mass incarceration in African American communities. Stanford Law Review. 2004;56(5):1271–1305.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roberts, D. E. (2012). Prison, foster care, and the systemic punishment of black mothers. UCLA Law Review, 59(6), 1474–1501.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roche AI, Kroska EB, Miller ML, Kroska SK, O'Hara MW. Childhood trauma and problem behavior: Examining the mediating roles of experiential avoidance and mindfulness processes. Journal of American College Health. 2019;67(1):17–26. doi: 10.1080/07448481.2018.1455689.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/07448481.2018.1455689</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6296903</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29565779</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ruchkin VV, Schwab-Stone M, Koposov R, Vermeiren R, Steiner H. Violence exposure, posttraumatic stress, and personality in juvenile delinquents. Journal of the American Academy of Child &amp; Adolescent Psychiatry. 2002;41(3):322–329. doi: 10.1097/00004583-200203000-00012.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/00004583-200203000-00012</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11886027</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schorr MT, Tietbohl-Santos B, de Oliveira LM, Terra L, de Borba Telles LE, Hauck S. Association between different types of childhood trauma and parental bonding with antisocial traits in adulthood: A systematic review. Child Abuse &amp; Neglect. 2020;107:104621. doi: 10.1016/j.chiabu.2020.104621.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.chiabu.2020.104621</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32603957</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Semiatin, J. N., Torres, S., LaMotte, A. D., Portnoy, G. A., &amp; Murphy, C. M. (2017) Trauma exposure, PTSD symptoms, and presenting clinical problems among male perpetrators of intimate partner violence. Psychology of Violence 7(1), 91–100. 10.1037/vio0000041.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sentencing Project. (2019). Incarcerated Women and Girls. https://www.sentencingproject.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Annual-Report-2019.pdf. Accessed 9 July 2020.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Smith, S. G., Zhang, X., Basile, K. C., Merrick, M. T., Wang, J., Kresnow, M. J., &amp; Chen, J. (2018). National Intimate Partner and sexual violence survey: 2015 data brief.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Spencer C, Mallory A, Cafferky B, Kimmes J, Beck A, Stith S. Mental health factors and intimate partner violence perpetration and victimization: A meta-analysis. Psychology of Violence. 2019;9(1):1–17. doi: 10.1037/vio0000156.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/vio0000156</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Taha F, Zhang H, Snead K, Jones AD, Blackmon B, Bryant RJ, Siegelman AE, Kaslow NJ. Effects of a culturally informed intervention on abused, suicidal African American women. Cultural Diversity and Ethnic Minority Psychology. 2015;21:560–575. doi: 10.1037/cdp0000018.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/cdp0000018</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4433872</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25403027</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thombs BD, Lewis C, Bernstein DP, Medrano MA, Hatch JP. An evaluation of the measurement equivalence of the childhood trauma questionnaire – Short form across gender and race in a sample of drug-abusing adults. Journal of Psychosomatic Research. 2007;63:391–398. doi: 10.1016/j.jpsychores.2007.04.010.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.jpsychores.2007.04.010</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17905047</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verona E, Sprague J, Sadeh N. Inhibitory control and negative emotional processing in psychopathy and antisocial personality disorder. Journal of Abnormal Psychology. 2012;121(2):498. doi: 10.1037/a0025308.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/a0025308</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22288907</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Watt MH, Ranby KW, Meade CS, Sikkema KJ, MacFarlane JC, Skinner D, Pieterse D, Kalichman SC. Posttraumatic stress disorder symptoms mediate the relationship between traumatic experiences and drinking behavior among women attending alcohol-serving venues in a South African township. Journal of Studies on Alcohol and Drugs. 2012;73(4):549–558. doi: 10.15288/jsad.2012.73.549.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.15288/jsad.2012.73.549</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3364321</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22630793</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weiss NH, Johnson CD, Contractor A, Peasant C, Swan SC, Sullivan TP. Racial/ethnic differences moderate associations of coping strategies and posttraumatic stress disorder symptom clusters among women experiencing partner violence: A multigroup path analysis. Anxiety, Stress, and Coping. 2017;30(3):347–363. doi: 10.1080/10615806.2016.1228900.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10615806.2016.1228900</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5357195</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27575609</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Widiger TA, Spitzer RL. Sex bias in the diagnosis of personality disorders: Conceptual and methodological issues. Clinical Psychology Review. 1991;11(1):1–22. doi: 10.1016/0272-7358(91)90135-H.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0272-7358(91)90135-H</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Widiger TA, Livesley WJ, Clark LA. An integrative dimensional classification of personality disorder. Psychological Assessment. 2009;21(3):243. doi: 10.1037/a0016606.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1037/a0016606</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19719338</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Widom, C. S., &amp; Czaja, S. J. (2012). Childhood trauma, psychopathology, and violence: Disentangling causes, consequences, and correlates. In C. S. Widom (Ed.), Trauma, Psychopathology, and Violence: Causes, Correlates, or Consequences (pp. 291–317). Oxford University Press.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Widom CS, Czaja S, Wilson HW, Allwood M, Chauhan P. Do the long-term consequences of neglect differ for children of different races and ethnic backgrounds? Child Maltreatment. 2013;18(1):42–55. doi: 10.1177/1077559512460728.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/1077559512460728</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23076836</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Woods SJ, Wineman NM. Trauma, posttraumatic stress disorder symptom clusters, and physical health symptoms in postabused women. Archives of Psychiatric Nursing. 2004;18(1):26–34. doi: 10.1053/j.apnu.2003.11.005.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1053/j.apnu.2003.11.005</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14986288</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang H, Pittman DM, Lamis DA, Fischer NL, Schwenke TJ, Carr ER, Shah S, Kaslow NJ. Childhood maltreatment and PTSD: Spiritual well-being and intimate partner violence as mediators. Journal of Aggression, Maltreatment &amp; Trauma. 2015;24(5):501–519. doi: 10.1080/10926771.2015.1029182.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/10926771.2015.1029182</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
