<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35603057</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>24</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">1871-4080</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>16</Volume>
            <Issue>3</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Cognitive neurodynamics</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Cogn Neurodyn</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>A dose- and time-dependent effect of oxythiamine on cell growth inhibition in non-small cell lung cancer.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>633</StartPage>
          <EndPage>641</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>633-641</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s11571-021-09725-7</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The high mortality rate of non-small-cell lung cancer (NSCLC) is mostly due to the high risk of recurrence. A comprehensive understanding of proliferation mechanisms of NSCLC would remarkably contribute to blocking up the invasion and metastasis of tumor cells. In our previous study, the remarkable decreased activity of Thiamine-dependent enzymes (TDEs), involving in intermediary metabolism responsible for energy production of tumor, was found under conditions of thiamine deficiency in vivo. To explore the effect of Oxythiamine (OT), a TDEs antimetabolite, on cell growth, we co-cultured A549 cells with OT in vitro at various doses (0.1, 1, 10 and 100 μM) and time periods (6, 12, 24 and 48 h) and subsequent cell proliferation and apoptosis assays were performed respectively. Our findings demonstrated that A549 cells proliferation was significantly downregulated by OT treatment in a progressively dose as well as time dependent manner. Inhibition of TDEs resulted in antagonism of lung cancer growth by inducing cells to cease the cycle as well as apoptotic cell death. We concluded a critical role of OT, a TDEs antagonistic compound, indicating the potential target of its practical use.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© The Author(s) 2021.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Bai</LastName>
            <ForeName>Lin</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Huadong Hospital, Fudan University, 221 West Yan'an Road, Shanghai, 200040 China.</Affiliation>
              <Identifier Source="GRID">grid.8547.e</Identifier>
              <Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0001 0125 2443</Identifier>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Hui-Li</ForeName>
            <Initials>HL</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Respiratory Medicine, Huadong Hospital, Fudan University, 221 West Yan'an Road, Shanghai, 200040 China.</Affiliation>
              <Identifier Source="GRID">grid.8547.e</Identifier>
              <Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0001 0125 2443</Identifier>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>09</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Cogn Neurodyn</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101306907</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1871-4080</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Apoptosis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cell cycle</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">NSCLC</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Oxythiamine</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Thiamine-dependent enzymes</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>Conflict of interestNo conflict of interest needs to declare.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>9</Month>
          <Day>16</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
          <Hour>4</Hour>
          <Minute>34</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35603057</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9120279</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11571-021-09725-7</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">9725</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baumunk D, Reichelt U, Hildebrandt J, Krause H, Ebbing J, Cash H, Miller K, Schostak M, Weikert S. Expression parameters of the metabolic pathway genes pyruvate dehydrogenase kinase-1 (PDK-1) and DJ-1/PARK7 in renal cell carcinoma (RCC) World J Urol. 2013;31(5):1191–1196. doi: 10.1007/s00345-012-0874-5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00345-012-0874-5</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22544372</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Birge RB, Boeltz S, Kumar S, Carlson J, Wanderley J, Calianese D, Barcinski M, Brekken RA, Huang X, Hutchins JT, Freimark B, Empig C, Mercer J, Schroit AJ, Schett G, Herrmann M. Phosphatidylserine is a global immunosuppressive signal in efferocytosis, infectious disease, and cancer. Cell Death Differ. 2016;23(6):962–978. doi: 10.1038/cdd.2016.11.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/cdd.2016.11</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4987730</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26915293</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boros LG, Torday JS, Lim S, Bassilian S, Cascante M, Lee WN. Transforming growth factor beta2 promotes glucose carbon incorporation into nucleic acid ribose through the nonoxidative pentose cycle in lung epithelial carcinoma cells. Can Res. 2000;60(5):1183–1185.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cairns RA, Harris IS, Mak TW. Regulation of cancer cell metabolism. Nat Rev Cancer. 2011;1(2):85–95. doi: 10.1038/nrc2981.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nrc2981</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chauvier A, Picard-Jean F, Berger-Dancause JC, Bastet L, Naghdi MR, Dubé A, Turcotte P, Perreault J, Lafontaine DA. Transcriptional pausing at the translation start site operates as a critical checkpoint for riboswitch regulation. Nat Commun. 2017;8:13892. doi: 10.1038/ncomms13892.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/ncomms13892</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5234074</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28071751</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grimm M, Calgéer B, Teriete P, Biegner T, Munz A, Reinert S. Targeting thiamine-dependent enzymes for metabolic therapies in oral squamous cell carcinoma? Clin Transl Oncol off Publ Fed Span Oncol Soc Natl Cancer Inst Mexico. 2016;18(2):196–205. doi: 10.1007/s12094-015-1352-5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12094-015-1352-5</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Halma M, Doumèche B, Hecquet L, Prévot V, Mousty C, Charmantray F. Thiamine biosensor based on oxidative trapping of enzyme-substrate intermediate. Biosens Bioelectron. 2017;87:850–857. doi: 10.1016/j.bios.2016.09.049.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bios.2016.09.049</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27657847</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Howlader N, Forjaz G, Mooradian MJ, Meza R, Kong CY, Cronin KA, Mariotto AB, Lowy DR, Feuer EJ. The effect of advances in lung-cancer treatment on population mortality. N Engl J Med. 2020;383(7):640–649. doi: 10.1056/NEJMoa1916623.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMoa1916623</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8577315</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32786189</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hur H, Xuan Y, Kim YB, Lee G, Shim W, Yun J, Ham IH, Han SU. Expression of pyruvate dehydrogenase kinase-1 in gastric cancer as a potential therapeutic target. Int J Oncol. 2013;42(1):44–54. doi: 10.3892/ijo.2012.1687.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3892/ijo.2012.1687</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3583751</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23135628</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ji XD, Li G, Feng YX, Zhao JS, Li JJ, Sun ZJ, Shi S, Deng YZ, Xu JF, Zhu YQ, Koeffler HP, Tong XJ, Xie D. EphB3 is overexpressed in non-small-cell lung cancer and promotes tumor metastasis by enhancing cell survival and migration. Can Res. 2011;71(3):1156–1166. doi: 10.1158/0008-5472.CAN-10-0717.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/0008-5472.CAN-10-0717</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lin CC, Chen LC, Tseng VS, Yan JJ, Lai WW, Su WP, Lin CH, Huang CY, Su WC. Malignant pleural effusion cells show aberrant glucose metabolism gene expression. Eur Respir J. 2011;37(6):1453–1465. doi: 10.1183/09031936.00015710.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1183/09031936.00015710</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20884743</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu H, Huang D, McArthur DL, Boros LG, Nissen N, Heaney AP. Fructose induces transketolase flux to promote pancreatic cancer growth. Can Res. 2010;70(15):6368–6376. doi: 10.1158/0008-5472.CAN-09-4615.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/0008-5472.CAN-09-4615</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu CL, Hsu YC, Lee JJ, Chen MJ, Lin CH, Huang SY, Cheng SP. Targeting the pentose phosphate pathway increases reactive oxygen species and induces apoptosis in thyroid cancer cells. Mol Cell Endocrinol. 2020;499:110595. doi: 10.1016/j.mce.2019.110595.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.mce.2019.110595</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31563469</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lu CW, Lin SC, Chien CW, Lin SC, Lee CT, Lin BW, Lee JC, Tsai SJ. Overexpression of pyruvate dehydrogenase kinase 3 increases drug resistance and early recurrence in colon cancer. Am J Pathol. 2011;179(3):1405–1414. doi: 10.1016/j.ajpath.2011.05.050.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ajpath.2011.05.050</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3157210</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21763680</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lu H, Lan WX, Bo L, Niu C, Zhou JJ, Zhu HL. Metabolic response of LLC xenografted mice to oxythiamine, as measured by [1H] NMR spectroscopy. Genet Mol Res GMR. 2015;14(3):11043–11051. doi: 10.4238/2015.September.21.17.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.4238/2015.September.21.17</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26400334</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ortigoza-Escobar JD, Alfadhel M, Molero-Luis M, Darin N, Spiegel R, De Coo IF, Gerards M, Taylor RW, Artuch R, Nashabat M, Rodríguez-Pombo P, Tabarki B, Pérez-Dueñas B, Thiamine Deficiency Study Group  Thiamine deficiency in childhood with attention to genetic causes: survival and outcome predictors. Ann Neurol. 2017;82(3):317–330. doi: 10.1002/ana.24998.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ana.24998</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28856750</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Peterson CT, Rodionov DA, Osterman AL, Peterson SN. B vitamins and their role in immune regulation and cancer. Nutrients. 2020;12(11):3380. doi: 10.3390/nu12113380.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/nu12113380</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Platell C, Kong SE, McCauley R, Hall JC. Branched-chain amino acids. J Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2000;15(7):706–717. doi: 10.1046/j.1440-1746.2000.02205.x.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1046/j.1440-1746.2000.02205.x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10937674</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ramos-Montoya A, Lee WN, Bassilian S, Lim S, Trebukhina RV, Kazhyna MV, Ciudad CJ, Noé V, Centelles JJ, Cascante M. Pentose phosphate cycle oxidative and nonoxidative balance: a new vulnerable target for overcoming drug resistance in cancer. Int J Cancer. 2006;119(12):2733–2741. doi: 10.1002/ijc.22227.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/ijc.22227</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17019714</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reck M, Rabe KF. Precision diagnosis and treatment for advanced non-small-cell lung cancer. N Engl J Med. 2017;377(9):849–861. doi: 10.1056/NEJMra1703413.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1056/NEJMra1703413</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28854088</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ricciardelli C, Lokman NA, Cheruvu S, Tan IA, Ween MP, Pyragius CE, Ruszkiewicz A, Hoffmann P, Oehler MK. Transketolase is upregulated in metastatic peritoneal implants and promotes ovarian cancer cell proliferation. Clin Exp Metas. 2015;32(5):441–455. doi: 10.1007/s10585-015-9718-1.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10585-015-9718-1</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Subba Rao AV, Swapna K, Shaik SP, Lakshma Nayak V, Srinivasa Reddy T, Sunkari S, Shaik TB, Bagul C, Kamal A. Synthesis and biological evaluation of cis-restricted triazole/tetrazole mimics of combretastatin-benzothiazole hybrids as tubulin polymerization inhibitors and apoptosis inducers. Bioorg Med Chem. 2017;25(3):977–999. doi: 10.1016/j.bmc.2016.12.010.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bmc.2016.12.010</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28034647</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sun RC, Dukhande VV, Zhou Z, Young L, Emanuelle S, Brainson CF, Gentry MS. Nuclear glycogenolysis modulates histone acetylation in human non-small cell lung cancers. Cell Metab. 2019;30(5):903–916.e7. doi: 10.1016/j.cmet.2019.08.014.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cmet.2019.08.014</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6834909</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31523006</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thomas AA, Le Huerou Y, De Meese J, Gunawardana I, Kaplan T, Romoff TT, Gonzales SS, Condroski K, Boyd SA, Ballard J, Bernat B, DeWolf W, Han M, Lee P, Lemieux C, Pedersen R, Pheneger J, Poch G, Smith D, Sullivan F, Weiler S, Wright SK, Lin J, Brandhuber B, Vigers G. Synthesis, in vitro and in vivo activity of thiamine antagonist transketolase inhibitors. Bioorg Med Chem Lett. 2008;18(6):2206–2210. doi: 10.1016/j.bmcl.2007.11.101.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bmcl.2007.11.101</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18267359</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang J, Zhang X, Ma D, Lee WP, Xiao J, Zhao Y, Go VL, Wang Q, Yen Y, Recker R, Xiao GG. Inhibition of transketolase by oxythiamine altered dynamics of protein signals in pancreatic cancer cells. Exp Hematol Oncol. 2013;2:18. doi: 10.1186/2162-3619-2-18.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/2162-3619-2-18</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3733980</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23890079</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang CM, Liu YZ, Liao JW, Hu ML. The in vitro and in vivo anti-metastatic efficacy of oxythiamine and the possible mechanisms of action. Clin Exp Metas. 2010;27(5):341–349. doi: 10.1007/s10585-010-9331-2.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10585-010-9331-2</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zargarian S, Shlomovitz I, Erlich Z, Hourizadeh A, Ofir-Birin Y, Croker BA, Regev-Rudzki N, Edry-Botzer L, Gerlic M. Phosphatidylserine externalization, "necroptotic bodies" release, and phagocytosis during necroptosis. PLoS Biol. 2017;15(6):e2002711. doi: 10.1371/journal.pbio.2002711.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pbio.2002711</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5501695</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28650960</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zastre JA, Sweet RL, Hanberry BS, Ye S. Linking vitamin B1 with cancer cell metabolism. Cancer Metab. 2013;1(1):16. doi: 10.1186/2049-3002-1-16.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/2049-3002-1-16</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4178204</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24280319</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang H, Cao R, Lee WN, Deng C, Zhao Y, Lappe J, Recker R, Yen Y, Wang Q, Tsai MY, Go VL, Xiao GG. Inhibition of protein phosphorylation in MIA pancreatic cancer cells: confluence of metabolic and signaling pathways. J Proteome Res. 2010;9(2):980–989. doi: 10.1021/pr9008805.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/pr9008805</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2836017</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20035555</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhao F, Mancuso A, Bui TV, Tong X, Gruber JJ, Swider CR, Sanchez PV, Lum JJ, Sayed N, Melo JV, Perl AE, Carroll M, Tuttle SW, Thompson CB. Imatinib resistance associated with BCR-ABL upregulation is dependent on HIF-1alpha-induced metabolic reprograming. Oncogene. 2010;29(20):2962–2972. doi: 10.1038/onc.2010.67.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/onc.2010.67</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2874611</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20228846</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
