<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35602254</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>24</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">1520-765X</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>24</Volume>
            <Issue>Suppl C</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>European heart journal supplements : journal of the European Society of Cardiology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Eur Heart J Suppl</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>ANMCO position paper 'Appropriateness of prescribing direct oral anticoagulants in stroke and systemic thromboembolism prevention in adult patients with non-valvular atrial fibrillation'.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>C278</StartPage>
          <EndPage>C288</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>C278-C288</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1093/eurheartj/suac015</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The appropriateness of prescribing direct oral anticoagulants [dabigatran, rivaroxaban, apixaban, and edoxaban (DOACs)] is regulated on the criteria established in Phase III trials. These criteria are reported in the summary of the product characteristics of the four DOACs. In clinical practice, prescriptions are not always in compliance with established indications. In particular, the use of lower doses than those recommended in drug data sheets is not uncommon. Literature data show that the inappropriate prescription of reduced doses causes drug underexposure and up to a three-fold increase in the risk of stroke/ischaemic transient attack, systemic thromboembolism, and hospitalization. Possible causes of the deviation between the dose that should be prescribed and that prescribed in the real world include erroneous prescription, an overstated haemorrhagic risk perception, and the presence of frail and complex patients in clinical practice who were not included in pivotal trials, which makes it difficult to apply study results to the real world. For these reasons, we summarize DOAC indications and contraindications. We also suggest the appropriate use of DOACs in common clinical scenarios, in accordance with what international guidelines and national and international health regulatory bodies recommend.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Published on behalf of the European Society of Cardiology. © The Author(s) 2022.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mocini</LastName>
            <ForeName>David</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Clinical and Rehabilitation Cardiology, Emergency Department, P.O. San Filippo Neri - ASL Roma 1, Via G. Martinotti, 20, 00135, Roma, RM, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Di Fusco</LastName>
            <ForeName>Stefania Angela</ForeName>
            <Initials>SA</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Clinical and Rehabilitation Cardiology, Emergency Department, P.O. San Filippo Neri - ASL Roma 1, Via G. Martinotti, 20, 00135, Roma, RM, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>De Luca</LastName>
            <ForeName>Leonardo</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Cardiology, Department of Cardio-Thoraco-Vascular, Ospedale San Camillo, Circonvallazione Gianicolense, 87, 00152, Roma, RM, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Caldarola</LastName>
            <ForeName>Pasquale</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Cardiology-ICU Department, Ospedale San Paolo, Via Caposcardicchio, 1, 70123, Bari, BA, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Cipriani</LastName>
            <ForeName>Manlio</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Cardiology 2-Heart Failure and Transplants, ASST Ospedale Metropolitano Niguarda, Piazza Ospedale Maggiore, 3, 20162, Milano, MI, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Corda</LastName>
            <ForeName>Marco</ForeName>
            <Initials>M</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Cardiology Department, Arnas G. Brotzu, Piazzale Alessandro Ricchi, 1, 09134, Cagliari, CA, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Di Lenarda</LastName>
            <ForeName>Andrea</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Cardiovascolular and Sports Medicine Department, Asugi Trieste, Via Slataper, 9, 34125, Trieste, TS, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>De Nardo</LastName>
            <ForeName>Alfredo</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Cardiology-ICU Department Ospedale Civile G. Jazzolino Piazza Fleming 89900 Vibo Valentia, VV, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Francese</LastName>
            <ForeName>Giuseppina Maura</ForeName>
            <Initials>GM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Cardiology Department, P.O. Garibaldi-Nesima - Arnas Garibaldi, Via Palermo, 636, 95122, Catania, CT, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Napoletano</LastName>
            <ForeName>Cosimo</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Cardiology-ICU Department - Cath Lab, Ospedale Civile G. Mazzini, Piazza Italia, 64100, Teramo, TE, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Navazio</LastName>
            <ForeName>Alessandro</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Hospital Cardiology Department, Po Santa Maria Nuova - Ausl RE IRCCS, Viale Risorgimento, 80, 42100, Reggio Emilia, RE, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Riccio</LastName>
            <ForeName>Carmine</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Follow-up of the Post-Acute Patient, Cardio-Vascular Department, Azienda Ospedaliera S. Anna E S. Sebastiano, Via Palasciano, 1, 81100, Caserta, CE, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Roncon</LastName>
            <ForeName>Loris</ForeName>
            <Initials>L</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Cardiology Department, Ospedale Santa Maria Della Misericordia, Viale Tre Martiri, 140, 45100, Rovigo, RO Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tizzani</LastName>
            <ForeName>Emanuele</ForeName>
            <Initials>E</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Cardiology Department, Ospedale Degli Infermi, Strada Rivalta, 29, 10098, Rivoli, TO, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Nardi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Federico</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Cardiology Department, Ospedale Santo Spirito, Casale Monferrato (AL), Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Urbinati</LastName>
            <ForeName>Stefano</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Cardiology Department, Ospedale Bellaria, Via Altura, 3, 40139, Bologna, BO, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Valente</LastName>
            <ForeName>Serafina</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Cardio-Thoracic Department, AOU Senese Ospedale S. Maria Alle Scotte, Viale Mario Bracci, 13, 53100, Siena, SI, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gulizia</LastName>
            <ForeName>Michele Massimo</ForeName>
            <Initials>MM</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Cardiology Department, P.O. Garibaldi-Nesima - Arnas Garibaldi, Via Palermo, 636, 95122, Catania, CT, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Fondazione per il Tuo cuore - Heart Care Foundation, Via La Marmora, 36, 50121, Firenze, FI, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gabrielli</LastName>
            <ForeName>Domenico</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Cardiology, Department of Cardio-Thoraco-Vascular, Ospedale San Camillo, Circonvallazione Gianicolense, 87, 00152, Roma, RM, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Oliva</LastName>
            <ForeName>Fabrizio</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Unit of Intensive Cardiological Care, Cardiology 1-Hemodynamics, Cardiothoracovascular Department, "A. De Gasperis" ASST Grande Ospedale Metropolitano Niguarda, Piazza Ospedale Maggiore, 3, 20162, Milano, MI, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Colivicchi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Furio</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Division of Clinical and Rehabilitation Cardiology, Emergency Department, P.O. San Filippo Neri - ASL Roma 1, Via G. Martinotti, 20, 00135, Roma, RM, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>18</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Eur Heart J Suppl</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>100886647</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>1520-765X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Apixaban</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Atrial fibrillation</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">DOACs</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Dabigatran</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Direct oral anticoagulants</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Edoxaban</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Rivaroxaban</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
          <Hour>4</Hour>
          <Minute>23</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35602254</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9117907</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/eurheartj/suac015</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">suac015</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>World Health Organization. Regional Office for Europe. Appropriateness in Health Care Services: Report on a WHO Workshop, Koblenz, Germany, 23–25 March 2000. WHO Regional Office for Europe; 2000. https://apps.who.int/iris/handle/10665/108350 (31 October 2021).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Hicks NR.
Some observations on attempts to measure appropriateness of care. BMJ 1994;309:730–733.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2540824</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7950529</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Britten N, Jenkins L, Barber N, Bradley C, Stevenson F.. 
Developing a measure for the appropriateness of prescribing in general practice. Qual Saf Health Care 2003;12:246–250.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1743739</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12897356</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>CODICE DI DEONTOLOGIA MEDICA 2014_aggiornato_febbraio_2020.pdf. https://www1.ordinemediciroma.it/images/Ordine/Deontologia/CODICE%20DI%20DEONTOLOGIA%20MEDICA%202014_aggiornato_febbraio_2020.pdf (16 February 2022).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Godino C, Bodega F, Melillo F, Rubino F, Parlati ALM, Cappelletti A, Mazzone P, Mattiello P, Della Bella P, Castiglioni A, Alfieri O, De Bonis M, Montorfano M, Tresoldi M, Filippi M, Zangrillo A, Salerno A, Cera M, Margonato A; INSIgHT (Italian NOACs San Raffaele Hospital) registry investigators. Inappropriate dose of nonvitamin-K antagonist oral anticoagulants: prevalence and impact on clinical outcome in patients with nonvalvular atrial fibrillation. J Cardiovasc Med 2020;21:751–758.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Jacobs MS, van Hulst M, Campmans Z, Tieleman RG.. 
Inappropriate non-vitamin K antagonist oral anticoagulants prescriptions: be cautious with dose reductions. Neth Heart J 2019;27:371–377.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6639841</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30949972</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Vedovati MC, Giustozzi M, Paciaroni M.. 
Patients with Atrial Fibrillation receiving NOACs: the boundary between appropriate and inappropriate dose. Eur J Intern Med 2021;88:25–27.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33972151</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Steinberg BA, Gao H, Shrader P, Pieper K, Thomas L, Camm AJ, Ezekowitz MD, Fonarow GC, Gersh BJ, Goldhaber S, Haas S, Hacke W, Kowey PR, Ansell J, Mahaffey KW, Naccarelli G, Reiffel JA, Turpie A, Verheugt F, Piccini JP, Kakkar A, Peterson ED, Fox KAA; ORBIT-AF Investigators. International trends in clinical characteristics and oral anticoagulation treatment for patients with atrial fibrillation: results from the GARFIELD-AF, ORBIT-AF I, and ORBIT-AF II registries. Am Heart J 2017;194:132–140.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29223431</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Haas S, Camm AJ, Bassand J-P, Angchaisuksiri P, Cools F, Corbalan R, Gibbs H, Jacobson B, Koretsune Y, Mantovani LG, Misselwitz F, Panchenko E, Ragy HI, Stepinska J, Turpie AG, Sawhney JP, Steffel J, Lim TW, Pieper KS, Virdone S, Verheugt FW, Kakkar AK; GARFIELD-AF Investigators. Predictors of NOAC versus VKA use for stroke prevention in patients with newly diagnosed atrial fibrillation: results from GARFIELD-AF. Am Heart J 2019;213:35–46.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31128503</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Mazurek M, Halperin JL, Huisman MV, et al.Antithrombotic treatment for newly diagnosed atrial fibrillation in relation to patient age: the GLORIA-AF registry programme. EP Eur 2020;22:47–57.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Maura G, Billionnet C, Drouin J, Weill A, Neumann A, Pariente A.. 
Oral anticoagulation therapy use in patients with atrial fibrillation after the introduction of non-vitamin K antagonist oral anticoagulants: findings from the French healthcare databases, 2011–2016. BMJ Open 2019;9:e026645.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Paciaroni M, Agnelli G, Caso V, Silvestrelli G, Seiffge DJ, Engelter S, De Marchis GM, Polymeris A, Zedde ML, Yaghi S, Michel P, Eskandari A, Antonenko K, Sohn S-I, Cappellari M, Tassinari T, Tassi R, Masotti L, Katsanos AH, Giannopoulos S, Acciarresi M, Alberti A, Venti M, Mosconi MG, Vedovati MC, Pierini P, Giustozzi M, Lotti EM, Ntaios G, Kargiotis O, Monaco S, Lochner P, Bandini F, Liantinioti C, Palaiodimou L, Abdul-Rahim AH, Lees K, Mancuso M, Pantoni L, Rosa S, Bertora P, Galliazzo S, Ageno W, Toso E, Angelini F, Chiti A, Orlandi G, Denti L, Flomin Y, Marcheselli S, Mumoli N, Rimoldi A, Verrengia E, Schirinzi E, Del Sette M, Papamichalis P, Komnos A, Popovic N, Zarkov M, Rocco A, Diomedi M, Giorli E, Ciccone A, Mac Grory BC, Furie KL, Bonetti B, Saia V, Guideri F, Acampa M, Martini G, Grifoni E, Padroni M, Karagkiozi E, Perlepe K, Makaritsis K, Mannino M, Maccarrone M, Ulivi L, Giannini N, Ferrari E, Pezzini A, Doronin B, Volodina V, Baldi A, D'Amore C, Deleu D, Corea F, Putaala J, Santalucia P, Nardi K, Risitano A, Toni D, Tsivgoulis G.. 
Causes and risk factors of cerebral ischemic events in patients with atrial fibrillation treated with non-vitamin K antagonist oral anticoagulants for stroke prevention. Stroke 2019;50:2168–2174.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31234756</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Paciaroni M, Agnelli G, Giustozzi M, Caso V, Toso E, Angelini F, Canavero I, Micieli G, Antonenko K, Rocco A, Diomedi M, Katsanos AH, Shoamanesh A, Giannopoulos S, Ageno W, Pegoraro S, Putaala J, Strbian D, Sallinen H, Mac Grory BC, Furie KL, Stretz C, Reznik ME, Alberti A, Venti M, Mosconi MG, Vedovati MC, Franco L, Zepponi G, Romoli M, Zini A, Brancaleoni L, Riva L, Silvestrelli G, Ciccone A, Zedde ML, Giorli E, Kosmidou M, Ntais E, Palaiodimou L, Halvatsiotis P, Tassinari T, Saia V, Ornello R, Sacco S, Bandini F, Mancuso M, Orlandi G, Ferrari E, Pezzini A, Poli L, Cappellari M, Forlivesi S, Rigatelli A, Yaghi S, Scher E, Frontera JA, Masotti L, Grifoni E, Caliandro P, Zauli A, Reale G, Marcheselli S, Gasparro A, Terruso V, Arnao V, Aridon P, Abdul-Rahim AH, Dawson J, Saggese CE, Palmerini F, Doronin B, Volodina V, Toni D, Risitano A, Schirinzi E, Del Sette M, Lochner P, Monaco S, Mannino M, Tassi R, Guideri F, Acampa M, Martini G, Lotti EM, Padroni M, Pantoni L, Rosa S, Bertora P, Ntaios G, Sagris D, Baldi A, D'Amore C, Mumoli N, Porta C, Denti L, Chiti A, Corea F, Acciarresi M, Flomin Y, Popovic N, Tsivgoulis G.. 
Risk factors for intracerebral hemorrhage in patients with atrial fibrillation on non-vitamin K antagonist oral anticoagulants for stroke prevention. Stroke 2021;52:1450–1454.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33657853</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pradaxa. European Medicines Agency. https://www.ema.europa.eu/en/medicines/human/EPAR/pradaxa (19 February 2022).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xarelto. European Medicines Agency. https://www.ema.europa.eu/en/medicines/human/EPAR/xarelto (19 February 2022).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eliquis. European Medicines Agency. https://www.ema.europa.eu/en/medicines/human/EPAR/eliquis (19 February 2022).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lixiana. European Medicines Agency. https://www.ema.europa.eu/en/medicines/human/EPAR/lixiana (19 February 2022).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Hindricks G, Potpara T, Dagres N, Arbelo E, Bax JJ, Blomström-Lundqvist C, Boriani G, Castella M, Dan G-A, Dilaveris PE, Fauchier L, Filippatos G, Kalman JM, La Meir M, Lane DA, Lebeau J-P, Lettino M, Lip GYH, Pinto FJ, Thomas GN, Valgimigli M, Van Gelder IC, Van Putte BP, Watkins CL; ESC Scientific Document Group. 2020 ESC Guidelines for the diagnosis and management of atrial fibrillation developed in collaboration with the European Association for Cardio-Thoracic Surgery (EACTS): the Task Force for the diagnosis and management of atrial fibrillation of the European Society of Cardiology (ESC) Developed with the special contribution of the European Heart Rhythm Association (EHRA) of the ESC. Eur Heart J 2021;42:373–498.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32860505</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Steffel J, Collins R, Antz M, Cornu P, Desteghe L, Haeusler KG, Oldgren J, Reinecke H, Roldan-Schilling V, Rowell N, Sinnaeve P, Vanassche T, Potpara T, Camm AJ, Heidbüchel H; External reviewers. 2021 European Heart Rhythm Association practical guide on the use of non-vitamin K antagonist oral anticoagulants in patients with atrial fibrillation. Europace 2021;23:1612–1676.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33895845</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Overview | Atrial fibrillation: diagnosis and management | Guidance | NICE. https://www.nice.org.uk/guidance/ng196 (31 October 2021).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Connolly SJ, Ezekowitz MD, Yusuf S, Eikelboom J, Oldgren J, Parekh A, Pogue J, Reilly PA, Themeles E, Varrone J, Wang S, Alings M, Xavier D, Zhu J, Diaz R, Lewis BS, Darius H, Diener H-C, Joyner CD, Wallentin L.. 
Dabigatran versus warfarin in patients with atrial fibrillation. N Engl J Med 2009;361:1139–1151.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19717844</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Patel MR, Mahaffey KW, Garg J, Pan G, Singer DE, Hacke W, Breithardt G, Halperin JL, Hankey GJ, Piccini JP, Becker RC, Nessel CC, Paolini JF, Berkowitz SD, Fox KAA, Califf RM; the ROCKET AF Steering Committee. Rivaroxaban versus warfarin in nonvalvular atrial fibrillation. N Engl J Med 2011;365:883–891.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21830957</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Granger CB, Alexander JH, McMurray JJV, Lopes RD, Hylek EM, Hanna M, Al-Khalidi HR, Ansell J, Atar D, Avezum A, Bahit MC, Diaz R, Easton JD, Ezekowitz JA, Flaker G, Garcia D, Geraldes M, Gersh BJ, Golitsyn S, Goto S, Hermosillo AG, Hohnloser SH, Horowitz J, Mohan P, Jansky P, Lewis BS, Lopez-Sendon JL, Pais P, Parkhomenko A, Verheugt FWA, Zhu J, Wallentin L.. 
Apixaban versus warfarin in patients with atrial fibrillation. N Engl J Med 2011;365:981–992.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21870978</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Giugliano RP, Ruff CT, Braunwald E, Murphy SA, Wiviott SD, Halperin JL, Waldo AL, Ezekowitz MD, Weitz JI, Špinar J, Ruzyllo W, Ruda M, Koretsune Y, Betcher J, Shi M, Grip LT, Patel SP, Patel I, Hanyok JJ, Mercuri M, Antman EM.. 
Edoxaban versus warfarin in patients with atrial fibrillation. N Engl J Med 2013;369:2093–2104.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24251359</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Gage BF, Waterman AD, Shannon W, Boechler M, Rich MW, Radford MJ.. 
Validation of clinical classification schemes for predicting stroke: results from the National Registry of Atrial Fibrillation. JAMA 2001;285:2864–2870.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">11401607</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Lip GYH, Nieuwlaat R, Pisters R, Lane DA, Crijns HJGM.. 
Refining clinical risk stratification for predicting stroke and thromboembolism in atrial fibrillation using a novel risk factor-based approach: the euro heart survey on atrial fibrillation. Chest 2010;137:263–272.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19762550</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Ezekowitz MD, Connolly S, Parekh A, Reilly PA, Varrone J, Wang S, Oldgren J, Themeles E, Wallentin L, Yusuf S.. 
Rationale and design of RE-LY: randomized evaluation of long-term anticoagulant therapy, warfarin, compared with dabigatran. Am Heart J 2009;157:805–810, 810.e1–2.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19376304</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>ROCKET AF Study Investigators. Rivaroxaban-once daily, oral, direct factor Xa inhibition compared with vitamin K antagonism for prevention of stroke and Embolism Trial in Atrial Fibrillation: rationale and design of the ROCKET AF study. Am Heart J 2010;159:340–347.e1. doi:10.1016/j.ahj.2009.11.025</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ahj.2009.11.025</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20211293</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Lopes RD, Alexander JH, Al-Khatib SM, Ansell J, Diaz R, Easton JD, Gersh BJ, Granger CB, Hanna M, Horowitz J, Hylek EM, McMurray JJV, Verheugt FWA, Wallentin L; ARISTOTLE Investigators. Apixaban for reduction in stroke and other ThromboemboLic events in atrial fibrillation (ARISTOTLE) trial: design and rationale. Am Heart J 2010;159:331–339.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20211292</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Ruff CT, Giugliano RP, Antman EM, Crugnale SE, Bocanegra T, Mercuri M, Hanyok J, Patel I, Shi M, Salazar D, McCabe CH, Braunwald E.. 
Evaluation of the novel factor Xa inhibitor edoxaban compared with warfarin in patients with atrial fibrillation: design and rationale for the Effective aNticoaGulation with factor xA next GEneration in Atrial Fibrillation-Thrombolysis In Myocardial Infarction study 48 (ENGAGE AF-TIMI 48). Am Heart J 2010;160:635–641.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20934556</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Regitz-Zagrosek V, Roos-Hesselink JW, Bauersachs J, Blomström-Lundqvist C, Cífková R, De Bonis M, Iung B, Johnson MR, Kintscher U, Kranke P, Lang IM, Morais J, Pieper PG, Presbitero P, Price S, Rosano GMC, Seeland U, Simoncini T, Swan L, Warnes CA; ESC Scientific Document Group. 2018 ESC Guidelines for the management of cardiovascular diseases during pregnancy: The Task Force for the Management of Cardiovascular Diseases during Pregnancy of the European Society of Cardiology (ESC). Eur Heart J 2018;39:3165–3241.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30165544</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Pisters R, Lane DA, Nieuwlaat R, de Vos CB, Crijns HJGM, Lip GYH.. 
A novel user-friendly score (HAS-BLED) to assess 1-year risk of major bleeding in patients with atrial fibrillation: the Euro Heart Survey. Chest 2010;138:1093–1100.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20299623</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
O'Brien EC, Simon DN, Thomas LE, Hylek EM, Gersh BJ, Ansell JE, Kowey PR, Mahaffey KW, Chang P, Fonarow GC, Pencina MJ, Piccini JP, Peterson ED.. 
The ORBIT bleeding score: a simple bedside score to assess bleeding risk in atrial fibrillation. Eur Heart J 2015;36:3258–3264.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4670965</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26424865</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Praxbind. European Medicines Agency. https://www.ema.europa.eu/en/medicines/human/EPAR/praxbind (19 February 2022).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Gibson CM, Mehran R, Bode C, Halperin J, Verheugt FW, Wildgoose P, Birmingham M, Ianus J, Burton P, van Eickels M, Korjian S, Daaboul Y, Lip GYH, Cohen M, Husted S, Peterson ED, Fox KA.. 
Prevention of bleeding in patients with atrial fibrillation undergoing PCI. N Engl J Med 2016;375:2423–2434.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27959713</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ondexxya. European Medicines Agency. Published February 27, 2019. https://www.ema.europa.eu/en/medicines/human/EPAR/ondexxya (15 March 2022).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Mocini D, Di Fusco SA, Mocini E, Donini LM, Lavalle C, Di Lenarda A, Riccio C, Caldarola P, De Luca L, Gulizia MM, Oliva F, Gabrielli D, Colivicchi F.. 
Direct oral anticoagulants in patients with obesity and atrial fibrillation: position paper of Italian National Association of Hospital Cardiologists (ANMCO). J Clin Med 2021;10:4185.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8468506</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34575306</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Ezekowitz MD, Pollack CV, Halperin JL, England RD, VanPelt Nguyen S, Spahr J, Sudworth M, Cater NB, Breazna A, Oldgren J, Kirchhof P.. 
Apixaban compared to heparin/vitamin K antagonist in patients with atrial fibrillation scheduled for cardioversion: the EMANATE trial. Eur Heart J 2018;39:2959–2971.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6110194</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29659797</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Cappato R, Ezekowitz MD, Klein AL, Camm AJ, Ma C-S, Le Heuzey J-Y, Talajic M, Scanavacca M, Vardas PE, Kirchhof P, Hemmrich M, Lanius V, Meng IL, Wildgoose P, van Eickels M, Hohnloser SH.. 
Rivaroxaban vs. vitamin K antagonists for cardioversion in atrial fibrillation. Eur Heart J 2014;35:3346–3355.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25182247</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Goette A, Merino JL, Ezekowitz MD, Zamoryakhin D, Melino M, Jin J, Mercuri MF, Grosso MA, Fernandez V, Al-Saady N, Pelekh N, Merkely B, Zenin S, Kushnir M, Spinar J, Batushkin V, de Groot JR, Lip GYH.. 
Edoxaban versus enoxaparin-warfarin in patients undergoing cardioversion of atrial fibrillation (ENSURE-AF): a randomised, open-label, phase 3b trial. Lancet 2016;388:1995–2003.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27590218</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Off-Label. Bollettino d'informazione sui Farmaci, Vol. 13; 2006. p140–141.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>L 94/98. https://www.camera.it/parlam/leggi/98094l.htm (1 November 2021).</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Di Fusco SA, Colivicchi F, Santini M.. 
The hemorrhagic risk: how to evaluate it. Pacing Clin Electrophysiol 2013;36:1191–1197.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23663153</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
