<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35608434</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>24</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1536-5964</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>101</Volume>
            <Issue>20</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>20</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Medicine</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Medicine (Baltimore)</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Miller Fisher syndrome after COVID-19 vaccination: Case report and review of literature.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>e29333</StartPage>
          <MedlinePgn>e29333</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1097/MD.0000000000029333</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="RATIONALE" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">Miller Fisher syndrome (MFS) is a rare variant of Guillain-Barre syndrome, classically diagnosed based on the clinical triad of ataxia, areflexia, and ophthalmoplegia. MFS is usually preceded by viral infections and febrile illness; however, only a few cases have been reported after vaccinations.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="PATIENT CONCERNS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A 53-year-old hypertensive male presented with a 2-day history of progressive ascending paralysis of the lower limbs along with diplopia and ataxia, 8 days after the first dose of the Sinovac-Coronavac coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) vaccination, with no prior history of any predisposing infections or triggers.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="DIAGNOSES" NlmCategory="METHODS">Physical examination showed moderate motor and sensory loss with areflexia in the lower limbs bilaterally. Routine blood investigations and radiological investigations were unremarkable. Cerebrospinal fluid analysis showed albuminocytologic dissociation and nerve conduction studies revealed prolonged latencies with reduced conduction velocities. The diagnosis of MFS was established based on the findings of physical examination, cerebrospinal fluid analysis, and nerve conduction studies.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="INTERVENTIONS" NlmCategory="METHODS">A management plan was devised based on intravenous immunoglobulins, pregabalin, and physiotherapy. However, due to certain socioeconomic factors, the patient was managed conservatively with regular physiotherapy sessions.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="OUTCOMES" NlmCategory="RESULTS">Follow-up after 6 weeks showed remarkable improvement, with complete resolution of symptoms 10 weeks after the discharge.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="LESSONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">This case suggests that MFS is a rare adverse effect after COVID-19 vaccination and additional research is required to substantiate a temporal association. Further studies are needed to understand the pathophysiology behind such complications to enhance the safety of COVID-19 vaccinations in the future.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2022 the Author(s). Published by Wolters Kluwer Health, Inc.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Siddiqi</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ahsun Rizwan</ForeName>
            <Initials>AR</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-4699-6221</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Wah Medical College, Affiliated with University of Health Sciences, Wah, Pakistan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Khan</LastName>
            <ForeName>Tehrim</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-2036-7996</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Wah Medical College, Affiliated with University of Health Sciences, Wah, Pakistan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Tahir</LastName>
            <ForeName>Muhammad Junaid</ForeName>
            <Initials>MJ</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0335-6681</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Lahore General Hospital, Lahore, Pakistan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Asghar</LastName>
            <ForeName>Muhammad Sohaib</ForeName>
            <Initials>MS</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0001-6705-2030</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Dow University of Health Sciences-Ojha Campus, Karachi, Pakistan.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Islam</LastName>
            <ForeName>Md Saiful</ForeName>
            <Initials>MS</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0003-3979-2423</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Public Health and Informatics, Jahangirnagar University, Savar, Dhaka-1342, Bangladesh.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Centre for Advanced Research Excellence in Public Health, Savar, Dhaka-1342, Bangladesh.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yousaf</LastName>
            <ForeName>Zohaib</ForeName>
            <Initials>Z</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4631-9899</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Hamad Medical Corporation, Doha, Qatar.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>20</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>United States</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Medicine (Baltimore)</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>2985248R</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0025-7974</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <CoiStatement>The authors have no funding and conflicts of interest to disclose.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>2</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>10</Hour>
          <Minute>6</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>25</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35608434</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/MD.0000000000029333</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">00005792-202205200-00019</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wakerley BR, Uncini A, Yuki N. GBS Classification Group. Guillain–Barré and Miller Fisher syndromes – new diagnostic classification. Nat Rev Neurol 2014;10:537–44. Erratum in: Nat Rev Neurol. 2014 Nov;10(11):612. PMID: 25072194.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Willison HJ, Jacobs BC, van Doorn PA. Guillain-Barré syndrome. Lancet 2016;388:717–27.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Teener JW. Miller Fisher's syndrome. Semin Neurol 2013;32:512–6.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mori M, Kuwabara S, Yuki N. Fisher syndrome: clinical features, immunopathogenesis and management. Expert Rev Neurother 2012;12:39–51.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yuki N. Fisher syndrome and Bickerstaff brainstem encephalitis (Fisher-Bickerstaff syndrome). J Neuroimmunol 2009;215:01–9.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Haber P, DeStefano F, Angulo FJ, et al. Guillain-Barré syndrome following influenza vaccination. JAMA 2004;292:2478–81.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rao SJ, Khurana S, Murthy G, Dawson ET, Jazebi N, Haas CJ. A case of Guillain-Barre syndrome following Pfizer COVID-19 vaccine. J Community Hosp Intern Med Perspect 2021;11:597–600.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>World Health Organization. Available at: https://www.who.int/news-room/feature-stories/detail/the-sinovac-covid-19-vaccine-what-you-need-to-know. Accessed December 20, 2021.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ismail II, Salama S. A systematic review of cases of CNS demyelination following COVID-19 vaccination. J Neuroimmunol 2021;362:577765.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maramattom BV, Krishnan P, Paul R, et al. Guillain-Barré syndrome following ChAdOx1-S/nCoV-19 vaccine. Ann Neurol 2021;90:312–4.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McKean N, Chircop C. Guillain-Barré syndrome after COVID-19 vaccination. BMJ Case Rep 2021;14:e244125.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hasan T, Khan M, Khan F, Hamza G. Case of Guillain-Barré syndrome following COVID-19 vaccine. BMJ Case Rep 2021;14:e243629.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li Z, Li X, Shen J, Chan MTV, Wu WKK. Miller Fisher syndrome associated with COVID-19: an up-to-date systematic review. Environ Sci Pollut Res Int 2021;28:20939–44.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Reyes-Bueno JA, García-Trujillo L, Urbaneja P, et al. Miller-Fisher syndrome after SARS-CoV-2 infection. Eur J Neurol 2020;27:1759–61.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yuki N, Hartung HP. Guillain-Barré syndrome. N Engl J Med 2012;366:2294–304. Erratum in: N Engl J Med. 2012 Oct 25;367(17):1673. PMID: 22694000.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Principi N, Esposito S. Vaccine-preventable diseases, vaccines and Guillain-Barre’ syndrome. Vaccine 2019;37:5544–50.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Michaelson NM, Lam T, Malhotra A, Schiff ND, MacGowan DJL. Miller Fisher syndrome presenting after a second dose of Pfizer-BioNTech vaccination in a patient with resolved COVID-19: a case report. J Clin Neuromuscul Dis 2021;23:113–5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abičić A, Adamec I, Habek M. Miller Fisher syndrome following Pfizer COVID-19 vaccine [published online ahead of print, 2021 Nov 24]. Neurol Sci 2021;01–3. doi:10.1007/s10072-021-05776-0.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10072-021-05776-0</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nishiguchi Y, Matsuyama H, Maeda K, Shindo A, Tomimoto H. Miller Fisher syndrome following BNT162b2 mRNA coronavirus 2019 vaccination. BMC Neurol 2021;21:452.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dang YL, Bryson A. Miller-Fisher syndrome and Guillain-Barre syndrome overlap syndrome in a patient post Oxford-AstraZeneca SARS-CoV-2 vaccination. BMJ Case Rep 2021;14:e246701.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nishimoto Y, Odaka M, Hirata K, et al. Usefulness of anti-GQ1bIgG antibody testingin Fisher syndrome compared with cerebrospinal fluid examination. J Neuroimmunol 2004;148:200–5.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rivera-Correa J, de Siqueira IC, Mota S, et al. Anti-ganglioside antibodies in patients with Zika virus infection-associated Guillain-Barré syndrome in Brazil. PLoS Negl Trop Dis 2019;13:e0007695.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
