<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35602445</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>24</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">0022-1155</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>59</Volume>
            <Issue>6</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Journal of food science and technology</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Food Sci Technol</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Comparative biological analyses on kenger and kenger coffee as novel functional food products.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>2328</StartPage>
          <EndPage>2338</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>2328-2338</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s13197-021-05248-5</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText Label="ABSTRACT" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">The current research was conducted to investigate neuroprotective, anticancer, antiproliferative and apoptotic DNA fragmentation potentials of the extracts obtained from aerial-parts, raw-fruits, and coffee samples (prepared by roasting and boiled-roasting) of kenger (<i>Gundelia tournefortii</i> var. <i>armata)</i>. Neuroprotection capacities of the samples were screened against enzymes that are linked to the progression of Alzheimer's and Parkinson's diseases. Since the oxidative damage is closely related to the development of neurodegeneration and cancer, the extracts were also analyzed for their antioxidant activities. Anticancer and antiproliferative activities of the samples were evaluated towards A549, MCF-7, and HeLa cells, and they exhibited remarkable anticancer activities in dose-and time-dependent manners. Furthermore, the apoptotic activity regarding DNA fragmentation was also imaged. The extracts obtained from the aerial-parts and raw-fruits of kenger possessed the highest anticancer and antiproliferative activities on HeLa cells with the IC<sub>50</sub> values varied from 290.71 ± 0.69 to 342.46 ± 0.42, whilst kenger coffee samples had the weakest activity on the cell death towards MCF-7. However, the tested extracts exhibited strong antioxidant activities, in which the best reducing antioxidant capacity was defined in the raw-fruits and aerial-parts of the extracts. The roasted-coffee samples had the best inhibition on tyrosinase (88.26 ± 0.15%, p &lt; 0.05), while the raw fruit-EtOH extract showed the highest inhibition on AChE and BChE enzymes (39.10 ± 2.01%, p &lt; 0.01 and 72.69 ± 0.16%, p &lt; 0.016, respectively). Consequently, research outputs provide noteworthy data on the usage of kenger for the nutraceutical and the healthy food industries.</AbstractText>
          <AbstractText Label="GRAPHIC ABSTRACT" NlmCategory="UNASSIGNED">Enhanced light harvesting, higher donor density, appropriate band bending, lowest charge transfer radius of C-Ag-ZnO hybrid signifies that efficient charge transfer and restriction to charge recombination leading to the enhanced PEC performance.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© Association of Food Scientists &amp; Technologists (India) 2021.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gezici</LastName>
            <ForeName>Sevgi</ForeName>
            <Initials>S</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-4856-0221</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Molecular Biology and Genetics, Faculty of Science and Literature, Kilis 7 Aralik University, 79000 Kilis, Turkey.</Affiliation>
              <Identifier Source="GRID">grid.448756.c</Identifier>
              <Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0004 0399 5672</Identifier>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Advanced Technology Application and Research Center (ATARC), Kilis 7 Aralik University, 79000 Kilis, Turkey.</Affiliation>
              <Identifier Source="GRID">grid.448756.c</Identifier>
              <Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0004 0399 5672</Identifier>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sekeroglu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Nazim</ForeName>
            <Initials>N</Initials>
            <Identifier Source="ORCID">0000-0002-0630-0106</Identifier>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Advanced Technology Application and Research Center (ATARC), Kilis 7 Aralik University, 79000 Kilis, Turkey.</Affiliation>
              <Identifier Source="GRID">grid.448756.c</Identifier>
              <Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0004 0399 5672</Identifier>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Horticulture, Faculty of Agricultural Engineering, Kilis 7 Aralik University, 79000 Kilis, Turkey.</Affiliation>
              <Identifier Source="GRID">grid.448756.c</Identifier>
              <Identifier Source="ISNI">0000 0004 0399 5672</Identifier>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>09</Month>
          <Day>09</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>J Food Sci Technol</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>0056471</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0022-1155</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Apoptotic DNA fragmentation</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cancer</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Food industry</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Gundelia sp.</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Herbal coffee</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Kenger</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Neurodegeneration</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>Conflict of interestThe authors declare that they have no conflict of interest and known competing financial interests or personal relationships regarding of MS.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>7</Month>
          <Day>14</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>15</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pmc-release">
          <Year>2023</Year>
          <Month>6</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
          <Hour>4</Hour>
          <Minute>26</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35602445</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9114238</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13197-021-05248-5</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">5248</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abu-Lafi S, Rayan B, Kadan S, Abu-Lafi M, Rayan A. Anticancer activity and phytochemical composition of wild gundelia tournefortii. Oncol Lett. 2019;17(1):713–717. doi: 10.3892/ol.2018.9602.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3892/ol.2018.9602</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6313074</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30655821</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Alipoorfard F, Jouki M, Tavakolipour H. Application of sodium chloride and quince seed gum pretreatments to prevent enzymatic browning, loss of texture and antioxidant activity of freeze dried pear slices. J Food Sci Technol. 2020;57(9):3165–3175. doi: 10.1007/s13197-020-04265-0.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13197-020-04265-0</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7374678</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32728266</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Amigo-Benavent M, Wang S, Mateos R, Sarriá B, Bravo L. Antiproliferative and cytotoxic effects of green coffee and yerba mate extracts, their main hydroxycinnamic acids, methylxanthine and metabolites in different human cell lines. Food Chem Toxicol. 2017;106:125–138. doi: 10.1016/j.fct.2017.05.019.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.fct.2017.05.019</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28506698</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Asadi-Samani M, Rafieian-Kopaei M, Azimi N. Gundelia: a systematic review of medicinal and molecular perspective. Pak J Biol Sci. 2013;16(21):1238–1247. doi: 10.3923/pjbs.2013.1238.1247.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3923/pjbs.2013.1238.1247</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24511731</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ashaolu TJ. Antioxidative peptides derived from plants for human nutrition: their production, mechanisms and applications. Eur Food Res Technol. 2020;246:853–865. doi: 10.1007/s00217-020-03479-y.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00217-020-03479-y</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ashaolu TJ. Immune boosting functional foods and their mechanisms: a critical evaluation of probiotics and prebiotics. Biomed Pharmacother. 2020;130:110625. doi: 10.1016/j.biopha.2020.110625.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.biopha.2020.110625</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32795926</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bagcı E, Hayta S, Kılıc O, Kocak A. Essential oils of two varieties of gundelia tournefortii L. (Asteraceae) from Turkey. Asian J Chem. 2010;22(8):6239–6244.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ceylan S, Cetin S, Camadan Y, Saral O, Ozsen O, Tutus A. Antibacterial and antioxidant activities of traditional medicinal plants from the erzurum region of Turkey. Ir J Med Sci. 2019 doi: 10.1007/s11845-019-01993-x.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11845-019-01993-x</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30805769</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Coruh N, Celep AS, Ozgokce F, Iscan M. Antioxidant Capacities of Gundelia tournefortii L. Extracts and Inhibition on Glutathione-S-transferase Activity. Food Chem. 2007;100(3):1249–1253. doi: 10.1016/j.foodchem.2005.12.008.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodchem.2005.12.008</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ellman GL, Courtney KD, Andres V, Jr, Featherstone RM. A new and rapid colorimetric determination of acetylcholinesterase activity. Biochem Pharmacol. 1961;7:88–95. doi: 10.1016/0006-2952(61)90145-9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0006-2952(61)90145-9</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13726518</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gezici S. Comparative anticancer activity analysis of saffron extracts and a principle component, crocetin for prevention and treatment of human malignancies. J Food Sci Technol. 2019 doi: 10.1007/s13197-019-04014-y.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13197-019-04014-y</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6838258</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31749491</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gezici S, Sekeroglu N. Current perspectives in the application of medicinal plants against cancer: novel therapeutic agents. Anti-Cancer Agent Med Chem. 2019;19(1):101–111. doi: 10.2174/1871520619666181224121004.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.2174/1871520619666181224121004</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gezici S, Sekeroglu N. Neuroprotective potential and phytochemical composition of acorn fruits. Ind Crop Prod. 2019;128:13–17. doi: 10.1016/j.indcrop.2018.10.082.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.indcrop.2018.10.082</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gezici S, Sekeroglu N, Kijjoa A. In vitro anticancer activity and antioxidant properties of essential oils from Populus alba L and Rosmarinus officinalis L from South Eastern Anatolia of Turkey. Indian J Pharm Educ Res. 2017;51(3):498–503. doi: 10.5530/ijper.51.3s.74.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5530/ijper.51.3s.74</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Habtemariam S. Natural products in alzheimer’s disease therapy: would old therapeutic approaches fix the broken promise of modern medicines? Molecules. 2019;24(8):1519–1536. doi: 10.3390/molecules24081519.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules24081519</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Konak M, Ates M, Sahan Y. Evaluation of antioxidant properties of gundelia tournefortii: a wild edible plant. J Agri Fac Uludag. 2017;31(2):101–108.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kumar CH, Ramesh A, Kumar JS, Ishaq BM. A review on hepatoprotective activity of medicinal plants. Int J Pharm Sci Res. 2011;2(3):501–515.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lev-Yadun S, Abbo S. Traditional Use of A'kub (Gundelia tournefortii Asteraceae) in Israel and the Palestinian Authority Area. Econ Bot. 1999;53(2):217–219. doi: 10.1007/BF02866501.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/BF02866501</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mosmann T. Rapid colorimetric assay for cellular growth and survival: application to proliferation and cytotoxicity assays. J Immunol Methods. 1983;65(1–2):55–63. doi: 10.1016/0022-1759(83)90303-4.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0022-1759(83)90303-4</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6606682</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nguyen VT, Bowyer MC, Vuong QV, Van Altena IA, Scarlett CJ. Phytochemicals and antioxidant capacity of xao tam phan (paramignya trimera) root as affected by various solvents and extraction methods. Ind Crop Prod. 2015;67:192–200. doi: 10.1016/j.indcrop.2015.01.0511.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.indcrop.2015.01.0511</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Orhan IE, Senol FS, Gulpinar AR, Sekeroglu N, Kartal M, Sener B. Neuroprotective potential of some terebinth coffee brands and the unprocessed fruits of Pistacia terebinthus L and their fatty and essential oil analyses. Food Chem. 2012;130(4):882–888. doi: 10.1016/j.foodchem.2011.07.119.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodchem.2011.07.119</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rao S, Nadumane VK. Evaluation of the anticancer potential of coffee beans: an in vitro study. Indian J Tradit Know. 2016;15(2):266–271.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rodríguez-Bonilla P, Gandía-Herrero F, Matencio A, García-Carmona F, López-Nicolás JM. Comparative Study of theAntioxidant Capacity of Four Stilbenes using ORAC, ABTS+, and FRAP techniques. Food Anal Methods. 2017;10(9):2994–3000. doi: 10.1007/s12161-017-0871-9y.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12161-017-0871-9y</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Roleira FM, Tavares-da-Silva EJ, Varela CL, Costa SC, Silva T, Garrido J, Borges F. Plant derived and dietary phenolic antioxidants: anticancer properties. Food Chem. 2015;183:235–258. doi: 10.1016/j.foodchem.2015.03.039.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodchem.2015.03.039</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25863633</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sekeroglu N, Senol FS, Orhan IE, Gulpinar AR, Kartal M, Sener B. In vitro prospective effects of various traditional herbal coffees consumed in Anatolia linked to neurodegeneration. Food Res Int. 2012;45:197–203. doi: 10.1016/j.foodres.2011.10.0088.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.foodres.2011.10.0088</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sekeroglu N, Ozkutlu F, Kilic E. Mineral composition of acorn coffees. Indian J Pharm Educ Res. 2017;51:504–507. doi: 10.5530/ijper.51.3s.75.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5530/ijper.51.3s.75</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sekeroglu N, Urlu E, Kulak M, Gezici S, Dang R. Variation in total polyphenolic contents, dna protective potential and antioxidant capacity from aqueous and ethanol extracts in different plant parts of Hypericum perforatum L. Indian J Pharm Educ Res. 2017;51:1–7. doi: 10.5530/ijper.51.2s.43.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.5530/ijper.51.2s.43</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Senol FS, Sekeroglu N, Gezici S, Kilic E, Orhan IE. Neuroprotective potential of the fruit (Acorn) from Quercus coccifera L. Turk J Agric for. 2018;42(2):82–87. doi: 10.3906/tar-1711-18.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3906/tar-1711-18</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shida W, Tateishi H, Fujita M, Koga R, Radwan MO, Ciftci HI, Otsuka M, Husham Al-Saadi D, Watanabe M, Gezici S, Wada M, Sekeroglu N, Watanabe T. Antileukemic activity of twig components of caucasian beech in Turkey. Molecules. 2019;24(21):3850. doi: 10.3390/molecules24213850.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3390/molecules24213850</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Strober W. Trypan blue exclusion test of cell viability. Curr Protoc Immunol. 2015 doi: 10.1002/0471142735.ima03bs111.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/0471142735.ima03bs111</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6716531</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26529666</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
