<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35600969</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>24</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2452-199X</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>19</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2023</Year>
              <Month>Jan</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Bioactive materials</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Bioact Mater</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>A reactive oxygen species-responsive hydrogel encapsulated with bone marrow derived stem cells promotes repair and regeneration of spinal cord injury.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>550</StartPage>
          <EndPage>568</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>550-568</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.bioactmat.2022.04.029</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Spinal cord injury (SCI) is an overwhelming and incurable disabling event accompanied by complicated inflammation-related pathological processes, such as excessive reactive oxygen species (ROS) produced by the infiltrated inflammatory immune cells and released to the extracellular microenvironment, leading to the widespread apoptosis of the neuron cells, glial and oligodendroctyes. In this study, a thioketal-containing and ROS-scavenging hydrogel was prepared for encapsulation of the bone marrow derived mesenchymal stem cells (BMSCs), which promoted the neurogenesis and axon regeneration by scavenging the overproduced ROS and re-building a regenerative microenvironment. The hydrogel could effectively encapsulate BMSCs, and played a remarkable neuroprotective role <i>in vivo</i> by reducing the production of endogenous ROS, attenuating ROS-mediated oxidative damage and downregulating the inflammatory cytokines such as interleukin-1 beta (IL-1β), interleukin-6 (IL-6) and tumor necrosis factor-alpha (TNF-α), resulting in a reduced cell apoptosis in the spinal cord tissue. The BMSCs-encapsulated ROS-scavenging hydrogel also reduced the scar formation, and improved the neurogenesis of the spinal cord tissue, and thus distinctly enhanced the motor functional recovery of SCI rats. Our work provides a combinational strategy against ROS-mediated oxidative stress, with potential applications not only in SCI, but also in other central nervous system diseases with similar pathological conditions.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Authors.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Li</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ziming</ForeName>
            <Initials>Z</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>MOE Key Laboratory of Macromolecular Synthesis and Functionalization, Department of Polymer Science and Engineering, Zhejiang University, Hangzhou 310027, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhao</LastName>
            <ForeName>Tengfei</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, the Second Affiliated Hospital of Zhejiang University, Hangzhou 310009, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ding</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jie</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>MOE Key Laboratory of Macromolecular Synthesis and Functionalization, Department of Polymer Science and Engineering, Zhejiang University, Hangzhou 310027, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Haochen</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Medicine, Zhejiang University, Hangzhou 310009, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Qiaoxuan</ForeName>
            <Initials>Q</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>MOE Key Laboratory of Macromolecular Synthesis and Functionalization, Department of Polymer Science and Engineering, Zhejiang University, Hangzhou 310027, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yifan</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, the Second Affiliated Hospital of Zhejiang University, Hangzhou 310009, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Deteng</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>MOE Key Laboratory of Macromolecular Synthesis and Functionalization, Department of Polymer Science and Engineering, Zhejiang University, Hangzhou 310027, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Neuroregeneration and Neurorehabilitation, Qingdao University, Qingdao 266071, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gao</LastName>
            <ForeName>Changyou</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>MOE Key Laboratory of Macromolecular Synthesis and Functionalization, Department of Polymer Science and Engineering, Zhejiang University, Hangzhou 310027, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Dr. Li Dak Sum &amp; Yip Yio Chin Center for Stem Cell and Regenerative Medicine, Zhejiang University, Hangzhou 310058, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>09</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Bioact Mater</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101685294</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2452-199X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Anti-oxidation</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Axon regeneration</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">BMSCs</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ROS scavenging</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Spinal cord injury (SCI)</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
          <Hour>4</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35600969</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9108756</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bioactmat.2022.04.029</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">S2452-199X(22)00206-7</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cowan H., Lakra C., Desai M. Autonomic dysreflexia in spinal cord injury. BMJ Br. Med. J. (Clin. Res. Ed.) 2020;371:m3596.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jiang W., Li M., He F., Zhu L. Inhibition of NLRP3 inflammasome attenuates spinal cord injury-induced lung injury in mice. J. Cell. Physiol. 2019;234(5):6012–6022.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30589073</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>James S.L., Theadom A., Ellenbogen R.G., Bannick M.S., Montjoy-Venning W., Lucchesi L.R., Abbasi N., Abdulkader R., Abraha H.N., Adsuar J.C., Afarideh M., Agrawal S., et al.  Global, regional, and national burden of traumatic brain injury and spinal cord injury, 1990–2016: a systematic analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2016. Lancet Neurol. 2019;18(1):56–87.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6291456</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30497965</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hutson T.H., Di Giovanni S. The translational landscape in spinal cord injury: focus on neuroplasticity and regeneration. Nat. Rev. Neurol. 2019;15(12):732–745.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31728042</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Badhiwala J.H., Wilson J.R., Witiw C.D., Harrop J.S., Vaccaro A.R., Aarabi B., Grossman R.G., Geisler F.H., Fehlings M.G. The influence of timing of surgical decompression for acute spinal cord injury: a pooled analysis of individual patient data. Lancet Neurol. 2021;20(2):117–126.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33357514</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schwab M.E., Bartholdi D. Degeneration and regeneration of axons in the lesioned spinal cord. Physiol. Rev. 1996;76(2):319–370.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8618960</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pacher P., Beckman J.S., Liaudet L. Nitric oxide and peroxynitrite in health and disease. Physiol. Rev. 2007;87(1):315–424.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2248324</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17237348</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wen Y., Yu S., Wu Y., Ju R., Wang H., Liu Y., Wang Y., Xu Q. Spinal cord injury repair by implantation of structured hyaluronic acid scaffold with PLGA microspheres in the rat. Cell Tissue Res. 2016;364(1):17–28.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26463048</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhao T.-F., Jing Y.-B., Zhou X.-P., Wang J.-K., Huang X.-P., Gao L.-S., Zhu Y.-J., Wang L.-J., Gou Z.-R., Liang C.-Z., Xu K., Li F.-C., et al.  PHBV/PLA/Col-based nanofibrous scaffolds Promote recovery of locomotor function by decreasing reactive astrogliosis in a hemisection spinal cord injury rat model. J. Biomed. Nanotechnol. 2018;14(11):1921–1933.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30165928</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaplan B., Merdler U., Szklanny A.A., Redenski I., Guo S., Bar-Mucha Z., Michael N., Levenberg S. Rapid prototyping fabrication of soft and oriented polyester scaffolds for axonal guidance. Biomaterials. 2020;251:120062.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32388032</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dumont C.M., Carlson M.A., Munsell M.K., Ciciriello A.J., Strnadova K., Park J., Cummings B.J., Anderson A.J., Shea L.D. Aligned hydrogel tubes guide regeneration following spinal cord injury. Acta Biomater. 2019;86:312–322.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6369008</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30610918</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Park J., Zhang Y., Saito E., Gurczynski S.J., Moore B.B., Cummings B.J., Anderson A.J., Shea L.D. Intravascular innate immune cells reprogrammed via intravenous nanoparticles to promote functional recovery after spinal cord injury. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2019;116(30):14947–14954.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6660718</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31285339</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhu R., Zhu X., Zhu Y., Wang Z., He X., Wu Z., Xue L., Fan W., Huang R., Xu Z., Qi X., Xu W., et al.  Immunomodulatory layered double hydroxide nanoparticles enable neurogenesis by targeting transforming growth factor-beta receptor 2. ACS Nano. 2021;15(2):2812–2830.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33527830</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Du X.-J., Chen Y.-X., Zheng Z.-C., Wang N., Wang X.-Y., Kong F.-E. Neural stem cell transplantation inhibits glial cell proliferation and P2X receptor-mediated neuropathic pain in spinal cord injury rats. Neural Regen. Res. 2019;14(5):876–885.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6375052</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30688274</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Takano M., Kawabata S., Shibata S., Yasuda A., Nori S., Tsuji O., Nagoshi N., Iwanami A., Ebise H., Horiuchi K., Okano H., Nakamura M. Enhanced functional recovery from spinal cord injury in aged mice after stem cell transplantation through HGF induction. Stem Cell Rep. 2017;8(3):509–518.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li X., Zhang C., Haggerty A.E., Yan J., Lan M., Seu M., Yang M., Marlow M.M., Maldonado-Lasunción I., Cho B., Zhou Z., Chen L., et al.  The effect of a nanofiber-hydrogel composite on neural tissue repair and regeneration in the contused spinal cord. Biomaterials. 2020;245:119978.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8787820</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32217415</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hong L.T.A., Kim Y.M., Park H.H., Hwang D.H., Cui Y., Lee E.M., Yahn S., Lee J.K., Song S.C., Kim B.G. An injectable hydrogel enhances tissue repair after spinal cord injury by promoting extracellular matrix remodeling. Nat. Commun. 2017;8(1):533.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5599609</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28912446</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chedly J., Soares S., Montembault A., von Boxberg Y., Veron-Ravaille M., Mouffle C., Benassy M.-N., Taxi J., David L., Nothias F. Physical chitosan microhydrogels as scaffolds for spinal cord injury restoration and axon regeneration. Biomaterials. 2017;138:91–107.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28554011</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li L.-M., Han M., Jiang X.-C., Yin X.-Z., Chen F., Zhang T.-Y., Ren H., Zhang J.-W., Hou T.-J., Chen Z., Ou-Yang H.-W., Tabata Y., et al.  Peptide-tethered hydrogel scaffold promotes recovery from spinal cord transection via synergism with mesenchymal stem cells. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces. 2017;9(4):3330–3342.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28058831</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boido M., Ghibaudi M., Gentile P., Favaro E., Fusaro R., Tonda-Turo C. Chitosan-based hydrogel to support the paracrine activity of mesenchymal stem cells in spinal cord injury treatment. Sci. Rep. 2019;9(1):6402.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6483991</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31024032</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li L., Xiao B., Mu J., Zhang Y., Zhang C., Cao H., Chen R., Patra H.K., Yang B., Feng S., Tabata Y., Slater N.K.H., et al.  A MnO2 nanoparticle-dotted hydrogel promotes spinal cord repair via regulating reactive oxygen species microenvironment and synergizing with mesenchymal stem cells. ACS Nano. 2019;13(12):14283–14293.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31769966</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu W., Chi L., Xu R., Ke Y., Luo C., Cai J., Qiu M., Gozal D., Liu R. Increased production of reactive oxygen species contributes to motor neuron death in a compression mouse model of spinal cord injury. Spinal Cord. 2005;43(4):204–213.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15520836</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu Z., Yao X., Jiang W., Li W., Zhu S., Liao C., Zou L., Ding R., Chen J. Advanced oxidation protein products induce microglia-mediated neuroinflammation via MAPKs-NF-κB signaling pathway and pyroptosis after secondary spinal cord injury. J. Neuroinflammation. 2020;17(1):90.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7082940</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32192500</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li X., Zhan J., Hou Y., Hou Y., Chen S., Luo D., Luan J., Wang L., Lin D. Coenzyme Q10 regulation of apoptosis and oxidative stress in H2O2 induced BMSC death by modulating the Nrf-2/NQO-1 signaling pathway and its application in a model of spinal cord injury. Oxid. Med. Cell. Longev. 2019;2019:6493081.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6930770</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31915512</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bhagavan H.N., Chopra R.K. Coenzyme Q10: absorption, tissue uptake, metabolism and pharmacokinetics. Free Radic. 2006;40(5):445–453.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pegoraro N.S., Mattiazzi J., da Silveira E.F., Azambuja J.H., Braganhol E., Cruz L. Improved photostability and cytotoxic effect of coenzyme Q10 by its association with vitamin E acetate in polymeric nanocapsules. Pharmaceut. Dev. Technol. 2018;23(4):400–406.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim J.-W., Mahapatra C., Hong J.-Y., Kim M.S., Leong K.W., Kim H.-W., Hyun J.K. Functional recovery of contused spinal cord in rat with the injection of optimal-dosed cerium oxide nanoparticles. Adv. Sci. 2017;4(10):1700034.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang W., Huang X., Zhang Y., Deng G., Liu X., Fan C., Xi Y., Yu J., Ye X. Se@SiO2 nanocomposites suppress microglia-mediated reactive oxygen species during spinal cord injury in rats. RSC Adv. 2018;8(29):16126–16138.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9088170</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35547361</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pal A., Singh A., Nag T.C., Chattopadhyay P., Mathur R., Jain S. Iron oxide nanoparticles and magnetic field exposure promote functional recovery by attenuating free radical-induced damage in rats with spinal cord transection. Int. J. Nanomed. 2013;8:2259–2272.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hachmeister J.E., Valluru L., Bao F., Liu D. Mn (III) tetrakis (4-benzoic acid) porphyrin administered into the intrathecal space reduces oxidative damage and neuron death after spinal cord injury: a comparison with methylprednisolone. J. Neurotrauma. 2006;23(12):1766–1778.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17184187</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang Y., Li L., Mu J., Chen J., Feng S., Gao J. Implantation of a functional TEMPO-hydrogel induces recovery from rat spinal cord transection through promoting nerve regeneration and protecting bladder tissue. Biomater. Sci. 2020;8(6):1695–1701.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31989134</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang T.-H., Lin F., Liu W.-G., Liu Y.-X., Guo Z.-H., Xiao C.-S., Zhuang X.-L., Chen X.-S. Reactive oxide species-scavenging lipid-polymer nanoparticles for neuroprotection after spinal cord injury. Appl. Mater. Today. 2021;24:101109.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ding J., Yao Y., Li J., Duan Y., Nakkala J.R., Feng X., Cao W., Wang Y., Hong L., Shen L., Mao Z., Zhu Y., et al.  A reactive oxygen species scavenging and O2 generating injectable hydrogel for myocardial infarction treatment in vivo. Small. 2020;16(48):2005038.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yao Y., Ding J., Wang Z., Zhang H., Xie J., Wang Y., Hong L., Mao Z., Gao J., Gao C. ROS-responsive polyurethane fibrous patches loaded with methylprednisolone (MP) for restoring structures and functions of infarcted myocardium in vivo. Biomaterials. 2020;232:119726.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31901502</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yan Z., Bing W., Ding C., Dong K., Ren J., Qu X. A H2O2-free depot for treating bacterial infection: localized cascade reactions to eradicate biofilms in vivo. Nanoscale. 2018;10(37):17656–17662.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30206634</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jovanović V.B., Penezić-Romanjuk A.Z., Pavićević I.D., Aćimović J.M., Mandić L.M. Improving the reliability of human serum albumin-thiol group determination. Anal. Biochem. 2013;439(1):17–22.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23583909</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ge Q., Wang X., Luo Y., Zheng X., Ma L. E7-modified substrates to promote adhesion and maintain stemness of mesenchymal stem cells. Macromol. Biosci. 2021;21(4):2000384.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang D., Yao Y., Duan Y., Yu X., Shi H., Nakkala J.R., Zuo X., Hong L., Mao Z., Gao C. Surface-anchored graphene oxide nanosheets on cell-scale micropatterned poly(d,l-lactide-co-caprolactone) conduits promote peripheral nerve regeneration. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces. 2020;12(7):7915–7930.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31935055</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Niu H., Li X., Li H., Fan Z., Ma J., Guan J. Thermosensitive, fast gelling, photoluminescent, highly flexible, and degradable hydrogels for stem cell delivery. Acta Biomater. 2019;83:96–108.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6296825</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30541703</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lam J., Lowry W.E., Carmichael S.T., Segura T. Delivery of iPS-NPCs to the stroke cavity within a hyaluronic acid matrix promotes the differentiation of transplanted cells. Adv. Funct. Mater. 2014;24(44):7053–7062.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4512237</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26213530</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang Y. Bioadaptability: an innovative concept for biomaterials. J. Mater. Sci. Technol. 2016;32(9):801–809.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Banerjee A., Arha M., Choudhary S., Ashton R.S., Bhatia S.R., Schaffer D.V., Kane R.S. The influence of hydrogel modulus on the proliferation and differentiation of encapsulated neural stem cells. Biomaterials. 2009;30(27):4695–4699.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2743317</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19539367</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sun W., Incitti T., Migliaresi C., Quattrone A., Casarosa S., Motta A. Viability and neuronal differentiation of neural stem cells encapsulated in silk fibroin hydrogel functionalized with an IKVAV peptide. Tissue Eng. Regen. Med. 2017;11(5):1532–1541.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yao Y., Zhang H., Wang Z., Ding J., Wang S., Huang B., Ke S., Gao C. Reactive oxygen species (ROS)-responsive biomaterials mediate tissue microenvironments and tissue regeneration. J. Mater. Chem. B. 2019;7(33):5019–5037.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31432870</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Madl C.M., LeSavage B.L., Dewi R.E., Lampe K.J., Heilshorn S.C. Matrix remodeling enhances the differentiation capacity of neural progenitor cells in 3D hydrogels. Adv. Sci. 2019;6(4):1801716.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Madl C.M., LeSavage B.L., Dewi R.E., Dinh C.B., Stowers R.S., Khariton M., Lampe K.J., Nguyen D., Chaudhuri O., Enejder A., Heilshorn S.C. Maintenance of neural progenitor cell stemness in 3D hydrogels requires matrix remodelling. Nat. Mater. 2017;16(12):1233–1242.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5708569</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29115291</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Šoltés L., Mendichi R., Kogan G., Schiller J., Stankovská M., Arnhold J. Degradative action of reactive oxygen species on hyaluronan. Biomacromolecules. 2006;7(3):659–668.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16529395</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yu S.-J., Kim H.-J., Lee E.S., Park C.-G., Cho S.J., Jeon S.-H. β-catenin accumulation is associated with increased expression of nanog protein and predicts maintenance of MSC self-renewal. Cell Transplant. 2017;26(2):365–377.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5657765</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27684957</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khan A.A., Huat T.J., Al Mutery A., El-Serafi A.T., Kacem H.H., Abdallah S.H., Reza M.F., Abdullah J.M., Jaafar H. Significant transcriptomic changes are associated with differentiation of bone marrow-derived mesenchymal stem cells into neural progenitor-like cells in the presence of bFGF and EGF. Cell Biosci. 2020;10(1):126.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7594431</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33133516</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jimenez Hamann M.C., Tator C.H., Shoichet M.S. Injectable intrathecal delivery system for localized administration of EGF and FGF-2 to the injured rat spinal cord. Exp. Neurol. 2005;194(1):106–119.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15899248</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang P., Wang H., Ma K., Wang S., Yang C., Mu N., Yang F., Feng H., Chen T. Novel cytokine-loaded PCL-PEG scaffold composites for spinal cord injury repair. RSC Adv. 2020;10(11):6306–6314.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9049693</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35495987</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu H., Wang Y., Zhang Y., Xu F., Chen J., Duan L., Zhang T., Wang J., Zhang F. Breaking the vicious loop between inflammation, oxidative stress and coagulation, a novel anti-thrombus insight of nattokinase by inhibiting LPS-induced inflammation and oxidative stress. Redox Biol. 2020;32:101500.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7078552</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32193146</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>da Costa Gonçalves F., Grings M., Nunes N.S., Pinto F.O., Garcez T.N.A., Visioli F., Leipnitz G., Paz A.H. Antioxidant properties of mesenchymal stem cells against oxidative stress in a murine model of colitis. Biotechnol. Lett. 2017;39(4):613–622.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28032203</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kemp K., Mallam E., Hares K., Witherick J., Scolding N., Wilkins A. Mesenchymal stem cells restore frataxin expression and increase hydrogen peroxide scavenging enzymes in Friedreich ataxia fibroblasts. PLoS One. 2011;6(10) e26098-e26098.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>An N., Yang J., Wang H., Sun S., Wu H., Li L., Li M. Mechanism of mesenchymal stem cells in spinal cord injury repair through macrophage polarization. Cell Biosci. 2021;11(1):41.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7903655</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33622388</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu F., Qiu H., Xue M., Zhang S., Zhang X., Xu J., Chen J., Yang Y., Xie J. MSC-secreted TGF-β regulates lipopolysaccharide-stimulated macrophage M2-like polarization via the Akt/FoxO1 pathway. Stem Cell Res. Ther. 2019;10(1):345.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6878630</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31771622</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li C., Li G., Liu M., Zhou T., Zhou H. Paracrine effect of inflammatory cytokine-activated bone marrow mesenchymal stem cells and its role in osteoblast function. J. Biosci. Bioeng. 2016;121(2):213–219.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26315505</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Redondo-Castro E., Cunningham C., Miller J., Martuscelli L., Aoulad-Ali S., Rothwell N.J., Kielty C.M., Allan S.M., Pinteaux E. Interleukin-1 primes human mesenchymal stem cells towards an anti-inflammatory and pro-trophic phenotype in vitro. Stem Cell Res. Ther. 2017;8(1):79.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5393041</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28412968</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gong T., Liu L., Jiang W., Zhou R. DAMP-sensing receptors in sterile inflammation and inflammatory diseases. Nat. Rev. Immunol. 2020;20(2):95–112.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31558839</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu Z., Yao X., Jiang W., Li W., Zhu S., Liao C., Zou L., Ding R., Chen J. Advanced oxidation protein products induce microglia-mediated neuroinflammation via MAPKs-NF-κB signaling pathway and pyroptosis after secondary spinal cord injury. J. Neuroinflammation. 2020;17(1):90.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7082940</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32192500</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu W., Wang S., Liu Q., Wang X., Shan T., Wang Y. Cathelicidin-WA attenuates LPS-induced inflammation and redox imbalance through activation of AMPK signaling. Free Radic. Biol. Med. 2018;129:338–353.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30273672</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhengxing X., Aiying H., Zongqiang Z., zengli M. Carbon monoxide protects neural stem cells against iron overload by modulating the crosstalk between Nrf2 and NF-κB signaling. Neurochem. Res. 2022;47(5):1383–1394.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35258778</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Visavadiya N.P., Patel S.P., VanRooyen J.L., Sullivan P.G., Rabchevsky A.G. Cellular and subcellular oxidative stress parameters following severe spinal cord injury. Redox Biol. 2016;8:59–67.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4712315</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26760911</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hall E.D., Bosken J.M. Measurement of oxygen radicals and lipid peroxidation in neural tissues. Curr. Protoc. Neurosci. 2009;48(1):7.17.1–7.17.51.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rao S., Lin Y., Du Y., He L., Huang G., Chen B., Chen T. Designing multifunctionalized selenium nanoparticles to reverse oxidative stress-induced spinal cord injury by attenuating ROS overproduction and mitochondria dysfunction. J. Mater. Chem. B. 2019;7(16):2648–2656.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32254998</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li Z., Wang Q., Hu H., Zheng W., Gao C. Research advances of biomaterials-based microenvironment-regulation therapies for repair and regeneration of spinal cord injury. Biomed. Mater. 2021;16(5)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Milich L.M., Ryan C.B., Lee J.K. The origin, fate, and contribution of macrophages to spinal cord injury pathology. Acta Neuropathol. 2019;137(5):785–797.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6510275</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30929040</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu L., Botchway B.O.A., Zhang S., Zhou J., Liu X. Inhibition of NF-κB signaling pathway by resveratrol improves spinal cord injury. Front. Neurosci. 2018;12(690)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Feng Z., Min L., Chen H., Deng W., Tan M., Liu H., Hou J. Iron overload in the motor cortex induces neuronal ferroptosis following spinal cord injury. Redox Biol. 2021;43:101984.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8105676</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33933882</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McKenzie B.A., Dixit V.M., Power C. Fiery cell death: pyroptosis in the central nervous system. Trends Neurosci. 2020;43(1):55–73.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31843293</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhu W., Chen X., Ning L., Jin K. Network analysis reveals TNF as a major hub of reactive inflammation following spinal cord injury. Sci. Rep. 2019;9(1):928.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6354014</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30700814</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mukhamedshina Y.O., Akhmetzyanova E.R., Martynova E.V., Khaiboullina S.F., Galieva L.R., Rizvanov A.A. Systemic and local cytokine profile following spinal cord injury in rats: a multiplex analysis. Front. Neurol. 2017;8(581)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sato A., Ohtaki H., Tsumuraya T., Song D., Ohara K., Asano M., Iwakura Y., Atsumi T., Shioda S. Interleukin-1 participates in the classical and alternative activation of microglia/macrophages after spinal cord injury. J. Neuroinflammation. 2012;9(1):65.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3353190</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22483094</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nakamura M., Okada S., Toyama Y., Okano H. Role of IL-6 in spinal cord injury in a mouse model. Clin. Rev. Allergy Immunol. 2005;28(3):197–203.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16129904</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ruzicka J., Machova-Urdzikova L., Gillick J., Amemori T., Romanyuk N., Karova K., Zaviskova K., Dubisova J., Kubinova S., Murali R., Sykova E., Jhanwar-Uniyal M., et al.  A comparative study of three different types of stem cells for treatment of rat spinal cord injury. Cell Transplant. 2017;26(4):585–603.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5661215</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27938489</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pivovarova N.B., Andrews S.B. Calcium-dependent mitochondrial function and dysfunction in neurons. FEBS J. 2010;277(18):3622–3636.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3489481</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20659161</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kotipatruni R.R., Dasari V.R., Veeravalli K.K., Dinh D.H., Fassett D., Rao J.S. p53- and Bax-mediated apoptosis in injured rat spinal cord. Neurochem. Res. 2011;36(11):2063.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21748659</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Springer J.E., Azbill R.D., Knapp P.E. Activation of the caspase-3 apoptotic cascade in traumatic spinal cord injury. Nat. Med. 1999;5(8):943–946.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10426320</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tran A.P., Warren P.M., Silver J. The biology of regeneration failure and success after spinal cord injury. Physiol. Rev. 2018;98(2):881–917.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5966716</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29513146</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wanner I.B., Anderson M.A., Song B., Levine J., Fernandez A., Gray-Thompson Z., Ao Y., Sofroniew M.V. Glial scar borders are formed by newly proliferated, elongated astrocytes that Interact to corral inflammatory and fibrotic cells via STAT3-dependent mechanisms after spinal cord injury. J. Neurosci. 2013;33(31):12870–12886.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3728693</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23904622</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Silva dos Santos J., Gonçalves Cirino J.P., de Oliveira Carvalho P., Ortega M.M. The pharmacological action of kaempferol in central nervous system diseases: a review. Front. Pharnacol. 2021</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang L., Conley B.M., Cerqueira S.R., Pongkulapa T., Wang S., Lee J.K., Lee K.-B. Effective modulation of CNS inhibitory microenvironment using bioinspired hybrid-nanoscaffold-based therapeutic interventions. Adv. Mater. 2020;32(43):2002578.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhu Y., Soderblom C., Trojanowsky M., Lee D.-H., Lee J.K. Fibronectin matrix assembly after spinal cord injury. J. Neurotrauma. 2014;32(15):1158–1167.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nakkala J.R., Li Z., Ahmad W., Wang K., Gao C. Immunomodulatory biomaterials and their application in therapies for chronic inflammation-related diseases. Acta Biomater. 2021;123:1–30.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33484912</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gottipati M.K., D'Amato A.R., Ziemba A.M., Popovich P.G., Gilbert R.J. TGFβ3 is neuroprotective and alleviates the neurotoxic response induced by aligned poly-l-lactic acid fibers on naïve and activated primary astrocytes. Acta Biomater. 2020;117:273–282.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8645246</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33035696</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang L., Conley B.M., Cerqueira S.R., Pongkulapa T., Wang S., Lee J.K., Lee K.-B. Effective modulation of CNS inhibitory microenvironment using bioinspired hybrid-nanoscaffold-based therapeutic interventions. Adv. Mater. 2020;32(43):2002578.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhu Y., Soderblom C., Krishnan V., Ashbaugh J., Bethea J.R., Lee J.K. Hematogenous macrophage depletion reduces the fibrotic scar and increases axonal growth after spinal cord injury. Neurobiol. Dis. 2015;74:114–125.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4323620</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25461258</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang C., Gong Z., Huang X., Wang J., Xia K., Ying L., Shu J., Yu C., Zhou X., Li F., Liang C., Chen Q. An injectable heparin-Laponite hydrogel bridge FGF4 for spinal cord injury by stabilizing microtubule and improving mitochondrial function. Theranostics. 2019;9(23):7016–7032.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6815951</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31660084</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang C., Wang M., Xia K., Wang J., Cheng F., Shi K., Ying L., Yu C., Xu H., Xiao S., Liang C., Li F., et al.  A bioactive injectable self-healing anti-inflammatory hydrogel with ultralong extracellular vesicles release synergistically enhances motor functional recovery of spinal cord injury. Bioact. Mater. 2021;6(8):2523–2534.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7873581</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33615043</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gage F.H. Mammalian neural stem cells. Science. 2000;287(5457):1433–1438.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10688783</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meletis K., Barnabe-Heider F., Carlen M., Evergren E., Tomilin N., Shupliakov O., Frisen J. Spinal cord injury reveals multilineage differentiation of ependymal cells. PLoS Biol. 2008;6(7):e182.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2475541</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18651793</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hamilton L.K., Truong M.K., Bednarczyk M.R., Aumont A., Fernandes K.J. Cellular organization of the central canal ependymal zone, a niche of latent neural stem cells in the adult mammalian spinal cord. Neuroscience. 2009;164(3):1044–1056.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19747531</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bradke F., Di Giovanni S., Fawcett J. Neuronal maturation:challenges and opportunities in a nascent field. Trends Neurosci. 2020;43(6):360–362.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32459989</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Terzi A., Suter D.M. The role of NADPH oxidases in neuronal development. Free Radic. Biol. Med. 2020;154:33–47.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32370993</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fukui K. Reactive oxygen species induce neurite degeneration before induction of cell death. J. Clin. Biochem. Nutr. 2016;59(3):155–159.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5110939</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27895381</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang X., Wang Z., Yao Y., Li J., Zhang X., Li C., Cheng Y., Ding G., Liu L., Ding Z. Essential role of ERK activation in neurite outgrowth induced by α-lipoic acid. Biochim. Biophys. Acta Mol. Cell Res. 2011;1813(5):827–838.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Olguín-Albuerne M., Morán J. ROS produced by NOX2 controls in vitro development of cerebellar granule neurons development. ASN Neuro. 2015;7(2) 1759091415578712.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang C., Wang G., Ma F., Yu B., Chen F., Yang J., Feng J., Wang Q. Repeated injections of human umbilical cord blood-derived mesenchymal stem cells significantly promotes functional recovery in rabbits with spinal cord injury of two noncontinuous segments. Stem Cell Res. Ther. 2018;9(1):136.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5948759</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29751769</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hakim R., Covacu R., Zachariadis V., Frostell A., Sankavaram S.R., Brundin L., Svensson M. Mesenchymal stem cells transplanted into spinal cord injury adopt immune cell-like characteristics. Stem Cell Res. Ther. 2019;10(1):115.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6448247</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30944028</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Qiu X.-C., Jin H., Zhang R.-Y., Ding Y., Zeng X., Lai B.-Q., Ling E.-A., Wu J.-L., Zeng Y.-S. Donor mesenchymal stem cell-derived neural-like cells transdifferentiate into myelin-forming cells and promote axon regeneration in rat spinal cord transection. Stem Cell Res. Ther. 2015;6(1):105.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4482203</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26012641</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang K., Liu Z., Li G., Lai B.-Q., Qin L.-N., Ding Y., Ruan J.-W., Zhang S.-X., Zeng Y.-S. Electro-acupuncture promotes the survival and differentiation of transplanted bone marrow mesenchymal stem cells pre-Induced with neurotrophin-3 and retinoic acid in gelatin sponge scaffold after rat spinal cord transection. Stem Cell Rev. 2014;10(4):612–625.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hawryluk G.W.J., Mothe A., Wang J., Wang S., Tator C., Fehlings M.G. An in vivo characterization of trophic factor production following neural precursor cell or bone marrow stromal cell transplantation for spinal cord injury. Stem Cell. Dev. 2011;21(12):2222–2238.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hejcl A., Ruzicka J., Proks V., Mackova H., Kubinova S., Tukmachev D., Cihlar J., Horak D., Jendelova P. Dynamics of tissue ingrowth in SIKVAV-modified highly superporous PHEMA scaffolds with oriented pores after bridging a spinal cord transection. J. Mater. Sci. Mater. Med. 2018;29(7)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Linnartz B., Wang Y., Neumann H. Microglial immunoreceptor tyrosine-based activation and inhibition motif signaling in neuroinflammation. Int. J. Alzheimer's Dis. 2010</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kroner A., Greenhalgh Andrew D., Zarruk Juan G., Passos dos Santos R., Gaestel M., David S. TNF and increased intracellular iron alter macrophage polarization to a detrimental M1 phenotype in the injured spinal cord. Neuron. 2014;83(5):1098–1116.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25132469</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Francos-Quijorna I., Amo-Aparicio J., Martinez-Muriana A., López-Vales R. IL-4 drives microglia and macrophages toward a phenotype conducive for tissue repair and functional recovery after spinal cord injury. Glia. 2016;64(12):2079–2092.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27470986</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu C., Chen S., Zhou T., Wu K., Qiao Z., Zhang Y., Xin N., Liu X., Wei D., Sun J., Luo H., Zhou L., et al.  Antioxidative and conductive nanoparticles-embedded cell niche for neural differentiation and spinal cord injury repair. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces. 2021;13(44):52346–52361.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen Wei-Hai, Chen Qi-Wei, Chen Qian, Cui Chunyan, Duan Shun, Kang Yongyuan, Liu Yang, Liu Yun, Muhammad Wali, Shao Shiqun, Tang Chengqiang, Wang Jinqiang, Wang Lei, Xiong Meng-Hua, Yin Lichen, Zhang Kuo, Zhang Zhanzhan, Zhen Xu, Feng Jun, Gao Changyou, Gu Zhen, He Chaoliang, Ji Jian, Jiang Xiqun, Liu Wenguang, Liu Zhuang, Peng Huisheng, Shen Youqing, Shi Linqi, Sun Xuemei, Wang Hao, Wang Jun, Xiao Haihua, Xu Fu-Jian, Zhong Zhiyuan, Zhang Xian-Zheng, Chen Xuesi. Biomedical polymers: synthesis, properties, and applications. Science China Chemistry. 2022 doi: 10.1007/s11426-022-1243-5. In press.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11426-022-1243-5</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35600969</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>24</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2452-199X</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>19</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2023</Year>
              <Month>Jan</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Bioactive materials</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Bioact Mater</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>A reactive oxygen species-responsive hydrogel encapsulated with bone marrow derived stem cells promotes repair and regeneration of spinal cord injury.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>550</StartPage>
          <EndPage>568</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>550-568</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.bioactmat.2022.04.029</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Spinal cord injury (SCI) is an overwhelming and incurable disabling event accompanied by complicated inflammation-related pathological processes, such as excessive reactive oxygen species (ROS) produced by the infiltrated inflammatory immune cells and released to the extracellular microenvironment, leading to the widespread apoptosis of the neuron cells, glial and oligodendroctyes. In this study, a thioketal-containing and ROS-scavenging hydrogel was prepared for encapsulation of the bone marrow derived mesenchymal stem cells (BMSCs), which promoted the neurogenesis and axon regeneration by scavenging the overproduced ROS and re-building a regenerative microenvironment. The hydrogel could effectively encapsulate BMSCs, and played a remarkable neuroprotective role <i>in vivo</i> by reducing the production of endogenous ROS, attenuating ROS-mediated oxidative damage and downregulating the inflammatory cytokines such as interleukin-1 beta (IL-1β), interleukin-6 (IL-6) and tumor necrosis factor-alpha (TNF-α), resulting in a reduced cell apoptosis in the spinal cord tissue. The BMSCs-encapsulated ROS-scavenging hydrogel also reduced the scar formation, and improved the neurogenesis of the spinal cord tissue, and thus distinctly enhanced the motor functional recovery of SCI rats. Our work provides a combinational strategy against ROS-mediated oxidative stress, with potential applications not only in SCI, but also in other central nervous system diseases with similar pathological conditions.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Authors.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Li</LastName>
            <ForeName>Ziming</ForeName>
            <Initials>Z</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>MOE Key Laboratory of Macromolecular Synthesis and Functionalization, Department of Polymer Science and Engineering, Zhejiang University, Hangzhou 310027, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhao</LastName>
            <ForeName>Tengfei</ForeName>
            <Initials>T</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, the Second Affiliated Hospital of Zhejiang University, Hangzhou 310009, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Ding</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jie</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>MOE Key Laboratory of Macromolecular Synthesis and Functionalization, Department of Polymer Science and Engineering, Zhejiang University, Hangzhou 310027, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Haochen</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>School of Medicine, Zhejiang University, Hangzhou 310009, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Qiaoxuan</ForeName>
            <Initials>Q</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>MOE Key Laboratory of Macromolecular Synthesis and Functionalization, Department of Polymer Science and Engineering, Zhejiang University, Hangzhou 310027, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Wang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yifan</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Orthopedics, the Second Affiliated Hospital of Zhejiang University, Hangzhou 310009, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Deteng</ForeName>
            <Initials>D</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>MOE Key Laboratory of Macromolecular Synthesis and Functionalization, Department of Polymer Science and Engineering, Zhejiang University, Hangzhou 310027, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Neuroregeneration and Neurorehabilitation, Qingdao University, Qingdao 266071, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Gao</LastName>
            <ForeName>Changyou</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>MOE Key Laboratory of Macromolecular Synthesis and Functionalization, Department of Polymer Science and Engineering, Zhejiang University, Hangzhou 310027, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Dr. Li Dak Sum &amp; Yip Yio Chin Center for Stem Cell and Regenerative Medicine, Zhejiang University, Hangzhou 310058, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>09</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Bioact Mater</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101685294</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2452-199X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Anti-oxidation</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Axon regeneration</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">BMSCs</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">ROS scavenging</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Spinal cord injury (SCI)</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors declare that they have no known competing financial interests or personal relationships that could have appeared to influence the work reported in this paper.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>13</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>22</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
          <Hour>4</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35600969</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9108756</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bioactmat.2022.04.029</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">S2452-199X(22)00206-7</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cowan H., Lakra C., Desai M. Autonomic dysreflexia in spinal cord injury. BMJ Br. Med. J. (Clin. Res. Ed.) 2020;371:m3596.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jiang W., Li M., He F., Zhu L. Inhibition of NLRP3 inflammasome attenuates spinal cord injury-induced lung injury in mice. J. Cell. Physiol. 2019;234(5):6012–6022.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30589073</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>James S.L., Theadom A., Ellenbogen R.G., Bannick M.S., Montjoy-Venning W., Lucchesi L.R., Abbasi N., Abdulkader R., Abraha H.N., Adsuar J.C., Afarideh M., Agrawal S., et al.  Global, regional, and national burden of traumatic brain injury and spinal cord injury, 1990–2016: a systematic analysis for the Global Burden of Disease Study 2016. Lancet Neurol. 2019;18(1):56–87.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6291456</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30497965</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hutson T.H., Di Giovanni S. The translational landscape in spinal cord injury: focus on neuroplasticity and regeneration. Nat. Rev. Neurol. 2019;15(12):732–745.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31728042</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Badhiwala J.H., Wilson J.R., Witiw C.D., Harrop J.S., Vaccaro A.R., Aarabi B., Grossman R.G., Geisler F.H., Fehlings M.G. The influence of timing of surgical decompression for acute spinal cord injury: a pooled analysis of individual patient data. Lancet Neurol. 2021;20(2):117–126.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33357514</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schwab M.E., Bartholdi D. Degeneration and regeneration of axons in the lesioned spinal cord. Physiol. Rev. 1996;76(2):319–370.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8618960</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pacher P., Beckman J.S., Liaudet L. Nitric oxide and peroxynitrite in health and disease. Physiol. Rev. 2007;87(1):315–424.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2248324</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17237348</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wen Y., Yu S., Wu Y., Ju R., Wang H., Liu Y., Wang Y., Xu Q. Spinal cord injury repair by implantation of structured hyaluronic acid scaffold with PLGA microspheres in the rat. Cell Tissue Res. 2016;364(1):17–28.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26463048</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhao T.-F., Jing Y.-B., Zhou X.-P., Wang J.-K., Huang X.-P., Gao L.-S., Zhu Y.-J., Wang L.-J., Gou Z.-R., Liang C.-Z., Xu K., Li F.-C., et al.  PHBV/PLA/Col-based nanofibrous scaffolds Promote recovery of locomotor function by decreasing reactive astrogliosis in a hemisection spinal cord injury rat model. J. Biomed. Nanotechnol. 2018;14(11):1921–1933.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30165928</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kaplan B., Merdler U., Szklanny A.A., Redenski I., Guo S., Bar-Mucha Z., Michael N., Levenberg S. Rapid prototyping fabrication of soft and oriented polyester scaffolds for axonal guidance. Biomaterials. 2020;251:120062.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32388032</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dumont C.M., Carlson M.A., Munsell M.K., Ciciriello A.J., Strnadova K., Park J., Cummings B.J., Anderson A.J., Shea L.D. Aligned hydrogel tubes guide regeneration following spinal cord injury. Acta Biomater. 2019;86:312–322.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6369008</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30610918</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Park J., Zhang Y., Saito E., Gurczynski S.J., Moore B.B., Cummings B.J., Anderson A.J., Shea L.D. Intravascular innate immune cells reprogrammed via intravenous nanoparticles to promote functional recovery after spinal cord injury. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2019;116(30):14947–14954.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6660718</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31285339</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhu R., Zhu X., Zhu Y., Wang Z., He X., Wu Z., Xue L., Fan W., Huang R., Xu Z., Qi X., Xu W., et al.  Immunomodulatory layered double hydroxide nanoparticles enable neurogenesis by targeting transforming growth factor-beta receptor 2. ACS Nano. 2021;15(2):2812–2830.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33527830</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Du X.-J., Chen Y.-X., Zheng Z.-C., Wang N., Wang X.-Y., Kong F.-E. Neural stem cell transplantation inhibits glial cell proliferation and P2X receptor-mediated neuropathic pain in spinal cord injury rats. Neural Regen. Res. 2019;14(5):876–885.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6375052</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30688274</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Takano M., Kawabata S., Shibata S., Yasuda A., Nori S., Tsuji O., Nagoshi N., Iwanami A., Ebise H., Horiuchi K., Okano H., Nakamura M. Enhanced functional recovery from spinal cord injury in aged mice after stem cell transplantation through HGF induction. Stem Cell Rep. 2017;8(3):509–518.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li X., Zhang C., Haggerty A.E., Yan J., Lan M., Seu M., Yang M., Marlow M.M., Maldonado-Lasunción I., Cho B., Zhou Z., Chen L., et al.  The effect of a nanofiber-hydrogel composite on neural tissue repair and regeneration in the contused spinal cord. Biomaterials. 2020;245:119978.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8787820</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32217415</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hong L.T.A., Kim Y.M., Park H.H., Hwang D.H., Cui Y., Lee E.M., Yahn S., Lee J.K., Song S.C., Kim B.G. An injectable hydrogel enhances tissue repair after spinal cord injury by promoting extracellular matrix remodeling. Nat. Commun. 2017;8(1):533.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5599609</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28912446</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chedly J., Soares S., Montembault A., von Boxberg Y., Veron-Ravaille M., Mouffle C., Benassy M.-N., Taxi J., David L., Nothias F. Physical chitosan microhydrogels as scaffolds for spinal cord injury restoration and axon regeneration. Biomaterials. 2017;138:91–107.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28554011</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li L.-M., Han M., Jiang X.-C., Yin X.-Z., Chen F., Zhang T.-Y., Ren H., Zhang J.-W., Hou T.-J., Chen Z., Ou-Yang H.-W., Tabata Y., et al.  Peptide-tethered hydrogel scaffold promotes recovery from spinal cord transection via synergism with mesenchymal stem cells. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces. 2017;9(4):3330–3342.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28058831</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boido M., Ghibaudi M., Gentile P., Favaro E., Fusaro R., Tonda-Turo C. Chitosan-based hydrogel to support the paracrine activity of mesenchymal stem cells in spinal cord injury treatment. Sci. Rep. 2019;9(1):6402.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6483991</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31024032</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li L., Xiao B., Mu J., Zhang Y., Zhang C., Cao H., Chen R., Patra H.K., Yang B., Feng S., Tabata Y., Slater N.K.H., et al.  A MnO2 nanoparticle-dotted hydrogel promotes spinal cord repair via regulating reactive oxygen species microenvironment and synergizing with mesenchymal stem cells. ACS Nano. 2019;13(12):14283–14293.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31769966</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu W., Chi L., Xu R., Ke Y., Luo C., Cai J., Qiu M., Gozal D., Liu R. Increased production of reactive oxygen species contributes to motor neuron death in a compression mouse model of spinal cord injury. Spinal Cord. 2005;43(4):204–213.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15520836</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu Z., Yao X., Jiang W., Li W., Zhu S., Liao C., Zou L., Ding R., Chen J. Advanced oxidation protein products induce microglia-mediated neuroinflammation via MAPKs-NF-κB signaling pathway and pyroptosis after secondary spinal cord injury. J. Neuroinflammation. 2020;17(1):90.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7082940</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32192500</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li X., Zhan J., Hou Y., Hou Y., Chen S., Luo D., Luan J., Wang L., Lin D. Coenzyme Q10 regulation of apoptosis and oxidative stress in H2O2 induced BMSC death by modulating the Nrf-2/NQO-1 signaling pathway and its application in a model of spinal cord injury. Oxid. Med. Cell. Longev. 2019;2019:6493081.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6930770</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31915512</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bhagavan H.N., Chopra R.K. Coenzyme Q10: absorption, tissue uptake, metabolism and pharmacokinetics. Free Radic. 2006;40(5):445–453.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pegoraro N.S., Mattiazzi J., da Silveira E.F., Azambuja J.H., Braganhol E., Cruz L. Improved photostability and cytotoxic effect of coenzyme Q10 by its association with vitamin E acetate in polymeric nanocapsules. Pharmaceut. Dev. Technol. 2018;23(4):400–406.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kim J.-W., Mahapatra C., Hong J.-Y., Kim M.S., Leong K.W., Kim H.-W., Hyun J.K. Functional recovery of contused spinal cord in rat with the injection of optimal-dosed cerium oxide nanoparticles. Adv. Sci. 2017;4(10):1700034.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang W., Huang X., Zhang Y., Deng G., Liu X., Fan C., Xi Y., Yu J., Ye X. Se@SiO2 nanocomposites suppress microglia-mediated reactive oxygen species during spinal cord injury in rats. RSC Adv. 2018;8(29):16126–16138.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9088170</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35547361</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pal A., Singh A., Nag T.C., Chattopadhyay P., Mathur R., Jain S. Iron oxide nanoparticles and magnetic field exposure promote functional recovery by attenuating free radical-induced damage in rats with spinal cord transection. Int. J. Nanomed. 2013;8:2259–2272.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hachmeister J.E., Valluru L., Bao F., Liu D. Mn (III) tetrakis (4-benzoic acid) porphyrin administered into the intrathecal space reduces oxidative damage and neuron death after spinal cord injury: a comparison with methylprednisolone. J. Neurotrauma. 2006;23(12):1766–1778.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17184187</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang Y., Li L., Mu J., Chen J., Feng S., Gao J. Implantation of a functional TEMPO-hydrogel induces recovery from rat spinal cord transection through promoting nerve regeneration and protecting bladder tissue. Biomater. Sci. 2020;8(6):1695–1701.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31989134</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang T.-H., Lin F., Liu W.-G., Liu Y.-X., Guo Z.-H., Xiao C.-S., Zhuang X.-L., Chen X.-S. Reactive oxide species-scavenging lipid-polymer nanoparticles for neuroprotection after spinal cord injury. Appl. Mater. Today. 2021;24:101109.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ding J., Yao Y., Li J., Duan Y., Nakkala J.R., Feng X., Cao W., Wang Y., Hong L., Shen L., Mao Z., Zhu Y., et al.  A reactive oxygen species scavenging and O2 generating injectable hydrogel for myocardial infarction treatment in vivo. Small. 2020;16(48):2005038.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yao Y., Ding J., Wang Z., Zhang H., Xie J., Wang Y., Hong L., Mao Z., Gao J., Gao C. ROS-responsive polyurethane fibrous patches loaded with methylprednisolone (MP) for restoring structures and functions of infarcted myocardium in vivo. Biomaterials. 2020;232:119726.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31901502</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yan Z., Bing W., Ding C., Dong K., Ren J., Qu X. A H2O2-free depot for treating bacterial infection: localized cascade reactions to eradicate biofilms in vivo. Nanoscale. 2018;10(37):17656–17662.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30206634</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jovanović V.B., Penezić-Romanjuk A.Z., Pavićević I.D., Aćimović J.M., Mandić L.M. Improving the reliability of human serum albumin-thiol group determination. Anal. Biochem. 2013;439(1):17–22.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23583909</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ge Q., Wang X., Luo Y., Zheng X., Ma L. E7-modified substrates to promote adhesion and maintain stemness of mesenchymal stem cells. Macromol. Biosci. 2021;21(4):2000384.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang D., Yao Y., Duan Y., Yu X., Shi H., Nakkala J.R., Zuo X., Hong L., Mao Z., Gao C. Surface-anchored graphene oxide nanosheets on cell-scale micropatterned poly(d,l-lactide-co-caprolactone) conduits promote peripheral nerve regeneration. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces. 2020;12(7):7915–7930.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31935055</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Niu H., Li X., Li H., Fan Z., Ma J., Guan J. Thermosensitive, fast gelling, photoluminescent, highly flexible, and degradable hydrogels for stem cell delivery. Acta Biomater. 2019;83:96–108.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6296825</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30541703</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lam J., Lowry W.E., Carmichael S.T., Segura T. Delivery of iPS-NPCs to the stroke cavity within a hyaluronic acid matrix promotes the differentiation of transplanted cells. Adv. Funct. Mater. 2014;24(44):7053–7062.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4512237</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26213530</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang Y. Bioadaptability: an innovative concept for biomaterials. J. Mater. Sci. Technol. 2016;32(9):801–809.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Banerjee A., Arha M., Choudhary S., Ashton R.S., Bhatia S.R., Schaffer D.V., Kane R.S. The influence of hydrogel modulus on the proliferation and differentiation of encapsulated neural stem cells. Biomaterials. 2009;30(27):4695–4699.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2743317</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19539367</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sun W., Incitti T., Migliaresi C., Quattrone A., Casarosa S., Motta A. Viability and neuronal differentiation of neural stem cells encapsulated in silk fibroin hydrogel functionalized with an IKVAV peptide. Tissue Eng. Regen. Med. 2017;11(5):1532–1541.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yao Y., Zhang H., Wang Z., Ding J., Wang S., Huang B., Ke S., Gao C. Reactive oxygen species (ROS)-responsive biomaterials mediate tissue microenvironments and tissue regeneration. J. Mater. Chem. B. 2019;7(33):5019–5037.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31432870</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Madl C.M., LeSavage B.L., Dewi R.E., Lampe K.J., Heilshorn S.C. Matrix remodeling enhances the differentiation capacity of neural progenitor cells in 3D hydrogels. Adv. Sci. 2019;6(4):1801716.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Madl C.M., LeSavage B.L., Dewi R.E., Dinh C.B., Stowers R.S., Khariton M., Lampe K.J., Nguyen D., Chaudhuri O., Enejder A., Heilshorn S.C. Maintenance of neural progenitor cell stemness in 3D hydrogels requires matrix remodelling. Nat. Mater. 2017;16(12):1233–1242.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5708569</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29115291</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Šoltés L., Mendichi R., Kogan G., Schiller J., Stankovská M., Arnhold J. Degradative action of reactive oxygen species on hyaluronan. Biomacromolecules. 2006;7(3):659–668.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16529395</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yu S.-J., Kim H.-J., Lee E.S., Park C.-G., Cho S.J., Jeon S.-H. β-catenin accumulation is associated with increased expression of nanog protein and predicts maintenance of MSC self-renewal. Cell Transplant. 2017;26(2):365–377.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5657765</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27684957</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Khan A.A., Huat T.J., Al Mutery A., El-Serafi A.T., Kacem H.H., Abdallah S.H., Reza M.F., Abdullah J.M., Jaafar H. Significant transcriptomic changes are associated with differentiation of bone marrow-derived mesenchymal stem cells into neural progenitor-like cells in the presence of bFGF and EGF. Cell Biosci. 2020;10(1):126.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7594431</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33133516</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jimenez Hamann M.C., Tator C.H., Shoichet M.S. Injectable intrathecal delivery system for localized administration of EGF and FGF-2 to the injured rat spinal cord. Exp. Neurol. 2005;194(1):106–119.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15899248</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang P., Wang H., Ma K., Wang S., Yang C., Mu N., Yang F., Feng H., Chen T. Novel cytokine-loaded PCL-PEG scaffold composites for spinal cord injury repair. RSC Adv. 2020;10(11):6306–6314.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9049693</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35495987</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu H., Wang Y., Zhang Y., Xu F., Chen J., Duan L., Zhang T., Wang J., Zhang F. Breaking the vicious loop between inflammation, oxidative stress and coagulation, a novel anti-thrombus insight of nattokinase by inhibiting LPS-induced inflammation and oxidative stress. Redox Biol. 2020;32:101500.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7078552</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32193146</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>da Costa Gonçalves F., Grings M., Nunes N.S., Pinto F.O., Garcez T.N.A., Visioli F., Leipnitz G., Paz A.H. Antioxidant properties of mesenchymal stem cells against oxidative stress in a murine model of colitis. Biotechnol. Lett. 2017;39(4):613–622.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28032203</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kemp K., Mallam E., Hares K., Witherick J., Scolding N., Wilkins A. Mesenchymal stem cells restore frataxin expression and increase hydrogen peroxide scavenging enzymes in Friedreich ataxia fibroblasts. PLoS One. 2011;6(10) e26098-e26098.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>An N., Yang J., Wang H., Sun S., Wu H., Li L., Li M. Mechanism of mesenchymal stem cells in spinal cord injury repair through macrophage polarization. Cell Biosci. 2021;11(1):41.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7903655</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33622388</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu F., Qiu H., Xue M., Zhang S., Zhang X., Xu J., Chen J., Yang Y., Xie J. MSC-secreted TGF-β regulates lipopolysaccharide-stimulated macrophage M2-like polarization via the Akt/FoxO1 pathway. Stem Cell Res. Ther. 2019;10(1):345.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6878630</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31771622</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li C., Li G., Liu M., Zhou T., Zhou H. Paracrine effect of inflammatory cytokine-activated bone marrow mesenchymal stem cells and its role in osteoblast function. J. Biosci. Bioeng. 2016;121(2):213–219.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26315505</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Redondo-Castro E., Cunningham C., Miller J., Martuscelli L., Aoulad-Ali S., Rothwell N.J., Kielty C.M., Allan S.M., Pinteaux E. Interleukin-1 primes human mesenchymal stem cells towards an anti-inflammatory and pro-trophic phenotype in vitro. Stem Cell Res. Ther. 2017;8(1):79.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5393041</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28412968</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gong T., Liu L., Jiang W., Zhou R. DAMP-sensing receptors in sterile inflammation and inflammatory diseases. Nat. Rev. Immunol. 2020;20(2):95–112.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31558839</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu Z., Yao X., Jiang W., Li W., Zhu S., Liao C., Zou L., Ding R., Chen J. Advanced oxidation protein products induce microglia-mediated neuroinflammation via MAPKs-NF-κB signaling pathway and pyroptosis after secondary spinal cord injury. J. Neuroinflammation. 2020;17(1):90.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7082940</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32192500</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu W., Wang S., Liu Q., Wang X., Shan T., Wang Y. Cathelicidin-WA attenuates LPS-induced inflammation and redox imbalance through activation of AMPK signaling. Free Radic. Biol. Med. 2018;129:338–353.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30273672</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhengxing X., Aiying H., Zongqiang Z., zengli M. Carbon monoxide protects neural stem cells against iron overload by modulating the crosstalk between Nrf2 and NF-κB signaling. Neurochem. Res. 2022;47(5):1383–1394.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35258778</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Visavadiya N.P., Patel S.P., VanRooyen J.L., Sullivan P.G., Rabchevsky A.G. Cellular and subcellular oxidative stress parameters following severe spinal cord injury. Redox Biol. 2016;8:59–67.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4712315</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26760911</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hall E.D., Bosken J.M. Measurement of oxygen radicals and lipid peroxidation in neural tissues. Curr. Protoc. Neurosci. 2009;48(1):7.17.1–7.17.51.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rao S., Lin Y., Du Y., He L., Huang G., Chen B., Chen T. Designing multifunctionalized selenium nanoparticles to reverse oxidative stress-induced spinal cord injury by attenuating ROS overproduction and mitochondria dysfunction. J. Mater. Chem. B. 2019;7(16):2648–2656.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32254998</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li Z., Wang Q., Hu H., Zheng W., Gao C. Research advances of biomaterials-based microenvironment-regulation therapies for repair and regeneration of spinal cord injury. Biomed. Mater. 2021;16(5)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Milich L.M., Ryan C.B., Lee J.K. The origin, fate, and contribution of macrophages to spinal cord injury pathology. Acta Neuropathol. 2019;137(5):785–797.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6510275</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30929040</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu L., Botchway B.O.A., Zhang S., Zhou J., Liu X. Inhibition of NF-κB signaling pathway by resveratrol improves spinal cord injury. Front. Neurosci. 2018;12(690)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Feng Z., Min L., Chen H., Deng W., Tan M., Liu H., Hou J. Iron overload in the motor cortex induces neuronal ferroptosis following spinal cord injury. Redox Biol. 2021;43:101984.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8105676</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33933882</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McKenzie B.A., Dixit V.M., Power C. Fiery cell death: pyroptosis in the central nervous system. Trends Neurosci. 2020;43(1):55–73.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31843293</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhu W., Chen X., Ning L., Jin K. Network analysis reveals TNF as a major hub of reactive inflammation following spinal cord injury. Sci. Rep. 2019;9(1):928.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6354014</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30700814</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mukhamedshina Y.O., Akhmetzyanova E.R., Martynova E.V., Khaiboullina S.F., Galieva L.R., Rizvanov A.A. Systemic and local cytokine profile following spinal cord injury in rats: a multiplex analysis. Front. Neurol. 2017;8(581)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sato A., Ohtaki H., Tsumuraya T., Song D., Ohara K., Asano M., Iwakura Y., Atsumi T., Shioda S. Interleukin-1 participates in the classical and alternative activation of microglia/macrophages after spinal cord injury. J. Neuroinflammation. 2012;9(1):65.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3353190</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22483094</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nakamura M., Okada S., Toyama Y., Okano H. Role of IL-6 in spinal cord injury in a mouse model. Clin. Rev. Allergy Immunol. 2005;28(3):197–203.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16129904</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ruzicka J., Machova-Urdzikova L., Gillick J., Amemori T., Romanyuk N., Karova K., Zaviskova K., Dubisova J., Kubinova S., Murali R., Sykova E., Jhanwar-Uniyal M., et al.  A comparative study of three different types of stem cells for treatment of rat spinal cord injury. Cell Transplant. 2017;26(4):585–603.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5661215</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27938489</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pivovarova N.B., Andrews S.B. Calcium-dependent mitochondrial function and dysfunction in neurons. FEBS J. 2010;277(18):3622–3636.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3489481</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20659161</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kotipatruni R.R., Dasari V.R., Veeravalli K.K., Dinh D.H., Fassett D., Rao J.S. p53- and Bax-mediated apoptosis in injured rat spinal cord. Neurochem. Res. 2011;36(11):2063.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21748659</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Springer J.E., Azbill R.D., Knapp P.E. Activation of the caspase-3 apoptotic cascade in traumatic spinal cord injury. Nat. Med. 1999;5(8):943–946.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10426320</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tran A.P., Warren P.M., Silver J. The biology of regeneration failure and success after spinal cord injury. Physiol. Rev. 2018;98(2):881–917.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5966716</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29513146</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wanner I.B., Anderson M.A., Song B., Levine J., Fernandez A., Gray-Thompson Z., Ao Y., Sofroniew M.V. Glial scar borders are formed by newly proliferated, elongated astrocytes that Interact to corral inflammatory and fibrotic cells via STAT3-dependent mechanisms after spinal cord injury. J. Neurosci. 2013;33(31):12870–12886.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3728693</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23904622</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Silva dos Santos J., Gonçalves Cirino J.P., de Oliveira Carvalho P., Ortega M.M. The pharmacological action of kaempferol in central nervous system diseases: a review. Front. Pharnacol. 2021</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang L., Conley B.M., Cerqueira S.R., Pongkulapa T., Wang S., Lee J.K., Lee K.-B. Effective modulation of CNS inhibitory microenvironment using bioinspired hybrid-nanoscaffold-based therapeutic interventions. Adv. Mater. 2020;32(43):2002578.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhu Y., Soderblom C., Trojanowsky M., Lee D.-H., Lee J.K. Fibronectin matrix assembly after spinal cord injury. J. Neurotrauma. 2014;32(15):1158–1167.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nakkala J.R., Li Z., Ahmad W., Wang K., Gao C. Immunomodulatory biomaterials and their application in therapies for chronic inflammation-related diseases. Acta Biomater. 2021;123:1–30.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33484912</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gottipati M.K., D'Amato A.R., Ziemba A.M., Popovich P.G., Gilbert R.J. TGFβ3 is neuroprotective and alleviates the neurotoxic response induced by aligned poly-l-lactic acid fibers on naïve and activated primary astrocytes. Acta Biomater. 2020;117:273–282.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8645246</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33035696</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang L., Conley B.M., Cerqueira S.R., Pongkulapa T., Wang S., Lee J.K., Lee K.-B. Effective modulation of CNS inhibitory microenvironment using bioinspired hybrid-nanoscaffold-based therapeutic interventions. Adv. Mater. 2020;32(43):2002578.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhu Y., Soderblom C., Krishnan V., Ashbaugh J., Bethea J.R., Lee J.K. Hematogenous macrophage depletion reduces the fibrotic scar and increases axonal growth after spinal cord injury. Neurobiol. Dis. 2015;74:114–125.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4323620</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25461258</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang C., Gong Z., Huang X., Wang J., Xia K., Ying L., Shu J., Yu C., Zhou X., Li F., Liang C., Chen Q. An injectable heparin-Laponite hydrogel bridge FGF4 for spinal cord injury by stabilizing microtubule and improving mitochondrial function. Theranostics. 2019;9(23):7016–7032.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6815951</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31660084</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang C., Wang M., Xia K., Wang J., Cheng F., Shi K., Ying L., Yu C., Xu H., Xiao S., Liang C., Li F., et al.  A bioactive injectable self-healing anti-inflammatory hydrogel with ultralong extracellular vesicles release synergistically enhances motor functional recovery of spinal cord injury. Bioact. Mater. 2021;6(8):2523–2534.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7873581</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33615043</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gage F.H. Mammalian neural stem cells. Science. 2000;287(5457):1433–1438.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10688783</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meletis K., Barnabe-Heider F., Carlen M., Evergren E., Tomilin N., Shupliakov O., Frisen J. Spinal cord injury reveals multilineage differentiation of ependymal cells. PLoS Biol. 2008;6(7):e182.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2475541</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18651793</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hamilton L.K., Truong M.K., Bednarczyk M.R., Aumont A., Fernandes K.J. Cellular organization of the central canal ependymal zone, a niche of latent neural stem cells in the adult mammalian spinal cord. Neuroscience. 2009;164(3):1044–1056.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19747531</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bradke F., Di Giovanni S., Fawcett J. Neuronal maturation:challenges and opportunities in a nascent field. Trends Neurosci. 2020;43(6):360–362.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32459989</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Terzi A., Suter D.M. The role of NADPH oxidases in neuronal development. Free Radic. Biol. Med. 2020;154:33–47.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32370993</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fukui K. Reactive oxygen species induce neurite degeneration before induction of cell death. J. Clin. Biochem. Nutr. 2016;59(3):155–159.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5110939</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27895381</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang X., Wang Z., Yao Y., Li J., Zhang X., Li C., Cheng Y., Ding G., Liu L., Ding Z. Essential role of ERK activation in neurite outgrowth induced by α-lipoic acid. Biochim. Biophys. Acta Mol. Cell Res. 2011;1813(5):827–838.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Olguín-Albuerne M., Morán J. ROS produced by NOX2 controls in vitro development of cerebellar granule neurons development. ASN Neuro. 2015;7(2) 1759091415578712.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang C., Wang G., Ma F., Yu B., Chen F., Yang J., Feng J., Wang Q. Repeated injections of human umbilical cord blood-derived mesenchymal stem cells significantly promotes functional recovery in rabbits with spinal cord injury of two noncontinuous segments. Stem Cell Res. Ther. 2018;9(1):136.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5948759</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29751769</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hakim R., Covacu R., Zachariadis V., Frostell A., Sankavaram S.R., Brundin L., Svensson M. Mesenchymal stem cells transplanted into spinal cord injury adopt immune cell-like characteristics. Stem Cell Res. Ther. 2019;10(1):115.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6448247</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30944028</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Qiu X.-C., Jin H., Zhang R.-Y., Ding Y., Zeng X., Lai B.-Q., Ling E.-A., Wu J.-L., Zeng Y.-S. Donor mesenchymal stem cell-derived neural-like cells transdifferentiate into myelin-forming cells and promote axon regeneration in rat spinal cord transection. Stem Cell Res. Ther. 2015;6(1):105.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4482203</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26012641</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang K., Liu Z., Li G., Lai B.-Q., Qin L.-N., Ding Y., Ruan J.-W., Zhang S.-X., Zeng Y.-S. Electro-acupuncture promotes the survival and differentiation of transplanted bone marrow mesenchymal stem cells pre-Induced with neurotrophin-3 and retinoic acid in gelatin sponge scaffold after rat spinal cord transection. Stem Cell Rev. 2014;10(4):612–625.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hawryluk G.W.J., Mothe A., Wang J., Wang S., Tator C., Fehlings M.G. An in vivo characterization of trophic factor production following neural precursor cell or bone marrow stromal cell transplantation for spinal cord injury. Stem Cell. Dev. 2011;21(12):2222–2238.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hejcl A., Ruzicka J., Proks V., Mackova H., Kubinova S., Tukmachev D., Cihlar J., Horak D., Jendelova P. Dynamics of tissue ingrowth in SIKVAV-modified highly superporous PHEMA scaffolds with oriented pores after bridging a spinal cord transection. J. Mater. Sci. Mater. Med. 2018;29(7)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Linnartz B., Wang Y., Neumann H. Microglial immunoreceptor tyrosine-based activation and inhibition motif signaling in neuroinflammation. Int. J. Alzheimer's Dis. 2010</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kroner A., Greenhalgh Andrew D., Zarruk Juan G., Passos dos Santos R., Gaestel M., David S. TNF and increased intracellular iron alter macrophage polarization to a detrimental M1 phenotype in the injured spinal cord. Neuron. 2014;83(5):1098–1116.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25132469</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Francos-Quijorna I., Amo-Aparicio J., Martinez-Muriana A., López-Vales R. IL-4 drives microglia and macrophages toward a phenotype conducive for tissue repair and functional recovery after spinal cord injury. Glia. 2016;64(12):2079–2092.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27470986</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu C., Chen S., Zhou T., Wu K., Qiao Z., Zhang Y., Xin N., Liu X., Wei D., Sun J., Luo H., Zhou L., et al.  Antioxidative and conductive nanoparticles-embedded cell niche for neural differentiation and spinal cord injury repair. ACS Appl. Mater. Interfaces. 2021;13(44):52346–52361.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen Wei-Hai, Chen Qi-Wei, Chen Qian, Cui Chunyan, Duan Shun, Kang Yongyuan, Liu Yang, Liu Yun, Muhammad Wali, Shao Shiqun, Tang Chengqiang, Wang Jinqiang, Wang Lei, Xiong Meng-Hua, Yin Lichen, Zhang Kuo, Zhang Zhanzhan, Zhen Xu, Feng Jun, Gao Changyou, Gu Zhen, He Chaoliang, Ji Jian, Jiang Xiqun, Liu Wenguang, Liu Zhuang, Peng Huisheng, Shen Youqing, Shi Linqi, Sun Xuemei, Wang Hao, Wang Jun, Xiao Haihua, Xu Fu-Jian, Zhong Zhiyuan, Zhang Xian-Zheng, Chen Xuesi. Biomedical polymers: synthesis, properties, and applications. Science China Chemistry. 2022 doi: 10.1007/s11426-022-1243-5. In press.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s11426-022-1243-5</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
