<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35600975</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>24</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2452-199X</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>19</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2023</Year>
              <Month>Jan</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Bioactive materials</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Bioact Mater</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Mg-based materials diminish tumor spreading and cancer metastases.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>594</StartPage>
          <EndPage>610</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>594-610</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.bioactmat.2022.05.002</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Cancer metastases are the most common causes of cancer-related deaths. The formation of secondary tumors at different sites in the human body can impair multiple organ function and dramatically decrease the survival of the patients. In this stage, it is difficulty to treat tumor growth and spreading due to arising therapy resistances. Therefore, it is important to prevent cancer metastases and to increase subsequent cancer therapy success. Cancer metastases are conventionally treated with radiation or chemotherapy. However, these treatments elicit lots of side effects, wherefore novel local treatment approaches are currently discussed. Recent studies already showed anticancer activity of specially designed degradable magnesium (Mg) alloys by reducing the cancer cell proliferation. In this work, we investigated the impact of these Mg-based materials on different steps of the metastatic cascade including cancer cell migration, invasion, and cancer-induced angiogenesis. Both, Mg and Mg-6Ag reduced cell migration and invasion of osteosarcoma cells in coculture with fibroblasts. Furthermore, the Mg-based materials used in this study diminished the cancer-induced angiogenesis. Endothelial cells incubated with conditioned media obtained from these Mg and Mg-6Ag showed a reduced cell layer permeability, a reduced proliferation and inhibited cell migration. The tube formation as a last step of angiogenesis was stimulated with the presence of Mg under normoxia and diminished under hypoxia.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 The Authors.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Globig</LastName>
            <ForeName>Philipp</ForeName>
            <Initials>P</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Metallic Biomaterials, Helmholtz-Zentrum Hereon GmbH, 21502, Geesthacht, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Madurawala</LastName>
            <ForeName>Roshani</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Metallic Biomaterials, Helmholtz-Zentrum Hereon GmbH, 21502, Geesthacht, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Willumeit-Römer</LastName>
            <ForeName>Regine</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Metallic Biomaterials, Helmholtz-Zentrum Hereon GmbH, 21502, Geesthacht, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Martini</LastName>
            <ForeName>Fernanda</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medical Sciences, University of Ferrara, 44121, Ferrara, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mazzoni</LastName>
            <ForeName>Elisa</ForeName>
            <Initials>E</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Medical Sciences, University of Ferrara, 44121, Ferrara, Italy.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Luthringer-Feyerabend</LastName>
            <ForeName>Bérengère J C</ForeName>
            <Initials>BJC</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Institute of Metallic Biomaterials, Helmholtz-Zentrum Hereon GmbH, 21502, Geesthacht, Germany.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>10</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Bioact Mater</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101685294</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2452-199X</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Angiogenesis</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cancer</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cell invasion</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Cell migration</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Magnesium degradation</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Osteosarcoma</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>The authors declare no conflict of interest. The funders had no role in the design of the study; in the collection, analyses, or interpretation of data; in the writing of the manuscript, or in the decision to publish the results.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>2</Month>
          <Day>9</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>3</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
          <Hour>4</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35600975</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9108521</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.bioactmat.2022.05.002</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">S2452-199X(22)00213-4</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Seyfried T.N., Huysentruyt L.C. On the origin of cancer metastasis. Crit. Rev. Oncog. 2013;18(1–2):43–73.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3597235</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23237552</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Engel J., Lategahn J., Rauh D. Hope and disappointment: covalent inhibitors to overcome drug resistance in non-small cell lung cancer. ACS Med. Chem. Lett. 2016;7(1):2–5.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4716607</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26819655</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schroeder A., et al.  Treating metastatic cancer with nanotechnology. Nat. Rev. Cancer. 2011;12(1):39–50.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22193407</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Windhagen H., et al.  Biodegradable magnesium-based screw clinically equivalent to titanium screw in hallux valgus surgery: short term results of the first prospective, randomized, controlled clinical pilot study. Biomed. Eng. Online. 2013;12(1):62.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3702514</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23819489</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Plaass C., et al.  Bioabsorbable magnesium versus standard titanium compression screws for fixation of distal metatarsal osteotomies – 3 year results of a randomized clinical trial. J. Orthop. Sci. 2018;23(2):321–327.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29174422</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee J.W., et al.  Long-term clinical study and multiscale analysis of in vivo biodegradation mechanism of Mg alloy. Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U. S. A. 2016;113(3):716–721.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4725539</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26729859</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Verheye S., et al.  Twelve-month outcomes of 400 patients treated with a resorbable metal scaffold: insights from the BIOSOLVE-IV registry. EuroIntervention. 2020;15(15):e1383–e1386.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30666963</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li M., et al.  Cytotoxic effect on osteosarcoma MG-63 cells by degradation of magnesium. J. Mater. Sci. Technol. 2014;30(9):888–893.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang Y., et al.  Preliminary study on cytotoxic effect of biodegradation of magnesium on cancer cells. J. Mater. Sci. Technol. 2012;28(9):769–772.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang Q., et al.  Cytotoxic effects of biodegradation of pure Mg and MAO-Mg on tumor cells of MG63 and KB. J. Mater. Sci. Technol. 2014;30(5):487–492.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gonzalez J., et al.  Magnesium degradation under physiological conditions - best practice. Bioact. Mater. 2018;3(2):174–185.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5935771</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29744455</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Globig P., et al.  Optimizing an osteosarcoma-fibroblast coculture model to study antitumoral activity of magnesium-based biomaterials. Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2020;21(14)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhang X.-F., et al.  Silver nanoparticles cause complications in pregnant mice. Int. J. Nanomed. 2015;10:7057–7071.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lu Z., et al.  Size-dependent antibacterial activities of silver nanoparticles against oral anaerobic pathogenic bacteria. J. Mater. Sci. Mater. Med. 2013;24(6):1465–1471.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23440430</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Nasulewicz A., et al.  Magnesium deficiency inhibits primary tumor growth but favors metastasis in mice. Biochim. Biophys. Acta (BBA) - Mol. Basis Dis. 2004;1739(1):26–32.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Malpuech-Brugère C., et al.  Inflammatory response following acute magnesium deficiency in the rat. Biochim. Biophys. Acta. 2000;1501(2–3):91–98.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10838183</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maier J.A.M., et al.  Low magnesium promotes endothelial cell dysfunction: implications for atherosclerosis, inflammation and thrombosis. Biochim. Biophys. Acta (BBA) - Mol. Basis Dis. 2004;1689(1):13–21.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fidler I.J. Metastasis: quantitative analysis of distribution and fate of tumor emboli labeled with 125 I-5-iodo-2'-deoxyuridine. J. Natl. Cancer Inst. 1970;45(4):773–782.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5513503</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Luzzi K.J., et al.  Multistep nature of metastatic inefficiency: dormancy of solitary cells after successful extravasation and limited survival of early micrometastases. Am. J. Pathol. 1998;153(3):865–873.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1853000</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9736035</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Meazza C., Scanagatta P. Metastatic osteosarcoma: a challenging multidisciplinary treatment. Expet Rev. Anticancer Ther. 2016;16(5):543–556.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chiang A.C., Massagué J. Molecular basis of metastasis. N. Engl. J. Med. 2008;359(26):2814–2823.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4189180</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19109576</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singer C.F., et al.  MMP-2 and MMP-9 expression in breast cancer-derived human fibroblasts is differentially regulated by stromal-epithelial interactions. Breast Cancer Res. Treat. 2002;72(1):69–77.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12000221</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eslami-S Z., Cortés-Hernández L.E., Alix-Panabières C. The metastatic cascade as the basis for liquid biopsy development. Front. Oncol. 2020;10(1055)</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Eccles S.A. Targeting key steps in metastatic tumour progression. Curr. Opin. Genet. Dev. 2005;15(1):77–86.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15661537</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McKeown S.R. Defining normoxia, physoxia and hypoxia in tumours-implications for treatment response. Br. J. Radiol. 2014;87(1035):20130676.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4064601</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24588669</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jensen R.L., et al.  Inhibition of hypoxia inducible factor-1alpha (HIF-1alpha) decreases vascular endothelial growth factor (VEGF) secretion and tumor growth in malignant gliomas. J. Neuro Oncol. 2006;78(3):233–247.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liao D., Johnson R.S. Hypoxia: a key regulator of angiogenesis in cancer. Cancer Metastasis Rev. 2007;26(2):281–290.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17603752</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Morelli C., et al.  Cell morphology, markers, spreading, and proliferation on orthopaedic biomaterials. An innovative cellular model for the "in vitro" study. J. Biomed. Mater. Res. 2007;83(1):178–183.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xu L., Willumeit-Romer R., Luthringer-Feyerabend B.J.C. Effect of magnesium-degradation products and hypoxia on the angiogenesis of human umbilical vein endothelial cells. Acta Biomater. 2019;98:269–283.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30794987</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Globig P., et al.  Slow degrading Mg-based materials induce tumor cell dormancy on an osteosarcoma-fibroblast coculture model. Bioact. Mater. 2021</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wong H.M., et al.  A biodegradable polymer-based coating to control the performance of magnesium alloy orthopaedic implants. Biomaterials. 2010;31(8):2084–2096.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20031201</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Keim S., et al.  Control of magnesium corrosion and biocompatibility with biomimetic coatings. J. Biomed. Mater. Res. B Appl. Biomater. 2011;96(1):84–90.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21053267</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lu P., et al.  Evaluation of magnesium ions release, biocorrosion, and hemocompatibility of MAO/PLLA-modified magnesium alloy WE42. J. Biomed. Mater. Res. B Appl. Biomater. 2011;96(1):101–109.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21053265</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>gu X., et al.  In vitro degradation performance and biological response of a Mg–Zn–Zr alloy. Mater. Sci. Eng.B-adv. Funct. Solid-state Mater. 2011;176:1778–1784.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huan Z.G., et al.  In vitro degradation behavior and cytocompatibility of Mg-Zn-Zr alloys. J. Mater. Sci. Mater. Med. 2010;21(9):2623–2635.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2935537</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20532960</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ralec C., et al.  Calcium-driven DNA synthesis by a high-fidelity DNA polymerase. Nucleic Acids Res. 2017;45(21):12425–12440.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5716173</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29040737</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Williams N.H. Magnesium ion catalyzed ATP hydrolysis. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2000;122(48):12023–12024.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Noorbazargan H., et al.  Anti-cancer &amp; anti-metastasis properties of bioorganic-capped silver nanoparticles fabricated from Juniperus chinensis extract against lung cancer cells. Amb. Express. 2021;11(1):61.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8076435</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33900505</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Satapathy S.R., et al.  Silver-based nanoparticles induce apoptosis in human colon cancer cells mediated through p53. Nanomedicine. 2013;8(8):1307–1322.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23514434</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Franco-Molina M.A., et al.  Antitumor activity of colloidal silver on MCF-7 human breast cancer cells. J. Exp. Clin. Cancer Res. 2010;29(1):148.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2996348</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21080962</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Franková J., et al.  Effects of silver nanoparticles on primary cell cultures of fibroblasts and keratinocytes in a wound-healing model. J. Appl. Biomater. Funct. Mater. 2016;14(2):e137–e142.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26952588</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sokołowska P., et al.  Human brain endothelial barrier cells are distinctly less vulnerable to silver nanoparticles toxicity than human blood vessel cells: a cell-specific mechanism of the brain barrier? Nanomed. Nanotechnol. Biol. Med. 2017;13(7):2127–2130.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Guo H., et al.  Intravenous administration of silver nanoparticles causes organ toxicity through intracellular ROS-related loss of inter-endothelial junction. Part. Fibre Toxicol. 2016;13:21.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4850669</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27129495</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miyazaki K., et al.  Cancer cell migration on elongate protrusions of fibroblasts in collagen matrix. Sci. Rep. 2019;9(1):292.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6342997</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30670761</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Waldeland J.O., Polacheck W.J., Evje S. Collective tumor cell migration in the presence of fibroblasts. J. Biomech. 2020;100:109568.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31902609</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu Y., et al.  Unique antitumor property of the Mg-Ca-Sr alloys with addition of Zn. Sci. Rep. 2016;6:21736.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4764862</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26907515</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang F., et al.  Astrocyte elevated gene-1 (AEG-1) promotes osteosarcoma cell invasion through the JNK/c-Jun/MMP-2 pathway. Biochem. Biophys. Res. Commun. 2014;452(4):933–939.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25204501</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mao L., et al.  Inhibition of breast cancer cell invasion by melatonin is mediated through regulation of the p38 mitogen-activated protein kinase signaling pathway. Breast Cancer Res. 2010;12(6):R107.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3046452</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21167057</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hsu M.J., et al.  Lupeol suppresses migration and invasion via p38/MAPK and PI3K/Akt signaling pathways in human osteosarcoma U-2 OS cells. Biosci. Biotechnol. Biochem. 2019;83(9):1729–1739.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31010399</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Klein T., Bischoff R. Physiology and pathophysiology of matrix metalloproteases. Amino Acids. 2011;41(2):271–290.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3102199</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20640864</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wieczorek E., et al.  Matrix metalloproteinases and genetic mouse models in cancer research: a mini-review. Tumour Biol. : J. Inter. Soc. Oncodevelop. Biol. Med. 2015;36(1):163–175.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Singer C.F., et al.  MMP-2 and MMP-9 expression in breast cancer-derived human fibroblasts is differentially regulated by stromal-epithelial interactions. Breast Cancer Res. Treat. 2002;72(1):69–77.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12000221</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ko K., et al.  Activation of fibroblast-derived matrix metalloproteinase-2 by colon-cancer cells in non-contact Co-cultures. Int. J. Cancer. 2000;87(2):165–171.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10861469</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Globig P., et al.  Optimizing an osteosarcoma-fibroblast coculture model to study antitumoral activity of magnesium-based biomaterials. Int. J. Mol. Sci. 2020;21(14):5099.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Heppner K.J., et al.  Expression of most matrix metalloproteinase family members in breast cancer represents a tumor-induced host response. Am. J. Pathol. 1996;149(1):273–282.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1865221</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8686751</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Boyd R.S., Balkwill F.R. MMP-2 release and activation in ovarian carcinoma: the role of fibroblasts. Br. J. Cancer. 1999;80(3):315–321.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2362343</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10408832</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Aoki M., et al.  CD73 complexes with emmprin to regulate MMP-2 production from co-cultured sarcoma cells and fibroblasts. BMC Cancer. 2019;19(1):912.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6739984</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31510956</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lu X., et al.  Evaluation of MMP-9 and MMP-2 and their suppressor TIMP-1 and TIMP-2 in adenocarcinoma of esophagogastric junction. OncoTargets Ther. 2016;9:4343–4349.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Brehmer B., Biesterfeld S., Jakse G. Expression of matrix metalloproteinases (MMP-2 and -9) and their inhibitors (TIMP-1 and -2) in prostate cancer tissue. Prostate Cancer Prostatic Dis. 2003;6(3):217–222.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12970724</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Anadón A., Castellano V., Martínez-Larrañaga M.R.  In: Biomarkers in Toxicology. Gupta R.C., editor. Academic Press; Boston: 2014. Chapter 55 - biomarkers in drug safety evaluation; pp. 923–945.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yue H., et al.  Effects of magnesium on matrix metalloproteinase-2 production in cultured rat cardiac fibroblasts. Basic Res. Cardiol. 2004;99(4):257–263.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15221343</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pages N., et al.  Structural alterations of the vascular wall in magnesium-deficient mice. A possible role of gelatinases A (MMP-2) and B (MMP-9) Magnes. Res. 2003;16(1):43–48.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12735482</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Amaral S.F.D., et al.  Dynamic influence of pH on metalloproteinase activity in human coronal and radicular dentin. Caries Res. 2018;52(1–2):113–118.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29298447</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kato Y., et al.  Acidic extracellular pH induces matrix metalloproteinase-9 expression in mouse metastatic melanoma cells through the phospholipase D-mitogen-activated protein kinase signaling. J. Biol. Chem. 2005;280(12):10938–10944.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15657063</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Martínez-Zaguilán R., et al.  Acidic pH enhances the invasive behavior of human melanoma cells. Clin. Exp. Metastasis. 1996;14(2):176–186.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8605731</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Razaq S., Wilkins R.J., Urban J.P.G. The effect of extracellular pH on matrix turnover by cells of the bovine nucleus pulposus. Eur. Spine J. : off. Pub. Eur. Spine Soc. Eur. Spinal Deformity Soc. Eur. Sect. Cervical Spine Res. Soc. 2003;12(4):341–349.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Silva A.S., et al.  The potential role of systemic buffers in reducing intratumoral extracellular pH and acid-mediated invasion. Cancer Res. 2009;69(6):2677–2684.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3718046</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19276380</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Estrella V., et al.  Acidity generated by the tumor microenvironment drives local invasion. Cancer Res. 2013;73(5):1524–1535.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3594450</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23288510</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>El-Kenawi A., et al.  Acidity promotes tumour progression by altering macrophage phenotype in prostate cancer. Br. J. Cancer. 2019;121(7):556–566.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6889319</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31417189</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Robey I.F., et al.  Bicarbonate increases tumor pH and inhibits spontaneous metastases. Cancer Res. 2009;69(6):2260–2268.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2834485</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19276390</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ibrahim Hashim A., et al.  Reduction of metastasis using a non-volatile buffer. Clin. Exp. Metastasis. 2011;28(8):841–849.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3213349</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">21861189</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zan R., et al.  Controlled release of hydrogen by implantation of magnesium induces P53-mediated tumor cells apoptosis. Bioact. Mater. 2022;9:385–396.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC8586587</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34820578</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wu Y., et al.  Hydrogen gas from inflammation treatment to cancer therapy. ACS Nano. 2019;13(8):8505–8511.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31329427</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zan R., et al.  Multifunctional magnesium anastomosis staples for wound closure and inhibition of tumor recurrence and metastasis. ACS Biomater. Sci. Eng. 2021;7(11):5269–5278.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34618437</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu M.Y., et al.  Molecular hydrogen suppresses glioblastoma growth via inducing the glioma stem-like cell differentiation. Stem Cell Res. Ther. 2019;10(1):145.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6528353</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31113492</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shang L., et al.  Therapeutic potential of molecular hydrogen in ovarian cancer. Transl. Cancer Res. 2018;7(4):988–995.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Senger D.R., Davis G.E. Angiogenesis. Cold Spring Harbor Perspect. Biol. 2011;3(8) a005090-a005090.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhu D., et al.  Magnesium regulates endothelial barrier functions through TRPM7, MagT1, and S1P1. Adv. Sci. 2019;6(18) 1901166-1901166.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Cullere X., et al.  Regulation of vascular endothelial barrier function by Epac, a cAMP-activated exchange factor for Rap GTPase. Blood. 2005;105(5):1950–1955.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15374886</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Murakami M., et al.  The FGF system has a key role in regulating vascular integrity. J. Clin. Invest. 2008;118(10):3355–3366.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2528913</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18776942</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zougbédé S., et al.  Metabolic acidosis induced by plasmodium falciparum intraerythrocytic stages alters blood—brain barrier integrity. J. Cerebr. Blood Flow Metabol. 2011;31(2):514–526.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Xie K., et al.  Hydrogen-rich medium attenuated lipopolysaccharide-induced monocyte-endothelial cell adhesion and vascular endothelial permeability via rho-associated coiled-coil protein kinase. Shock. 2015;44(1):58–64.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25895142</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salazar N., Zabel B.A. Support of tumor endothelial cells by chemokine receptors. Front. Immunol. 2019;10 147-147.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Han H.-S., et al.  Biodegradable magnesium alloys promote angio-osteogenesis to enhance bone repair. Adv. Sci. 2020;7(15):2000800.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Banai S., et al.  Influence of extracellular magnesium on capillary endothelial cell proliferation and migration. Circ. Res. 1990;67(3):645–650.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1697793</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Maier J.A., et al.  Low magnesium promotes endothelial cell dysfunction: implications for atherosclerosis, inflammation and thrombosis. Biochim. Biophys. Acta. 2004;1689(1):13–21.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15158909</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhao N., Zhu D. Endothelial responses of magnesium and other alloying elements in magnesium-based stent materials. Metallomics : integrated Biomet. Sci. 2015;7(1):118–128.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu C., et al.  Biodegradable Mg-Cu alloys with enhanced osteogenesis, angiogenesis, and long-lasting antibacterial effects. Sci. Rep. 2016;6(1):27374.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4895436</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27271057</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Faes S., et al.  Acidic pH reduces VEGF-mediated endothelial cell responses by downregulation of VEGFR-2; relevance for anti-angiogenic therapies. Oncotarget. 2016;7(52):86026–86038.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5349894</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27852069</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang L.V., et al.  Vascular abnormalities in mice deficient for the G protein-coupled receptor GPR4 that functions as a pH sensor. Mol. Cell Biol. 2007;27(4):1334–1347.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1800706</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17145776</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gao P., et al.  Biofunctional magnesium coated Ti6Al4V scaffold enhances osteogenesis and angiogenesis in vitro and in vivo for orthopedic application. Bioact. Mater. 2020;5(3):680–693.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7226632</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32435721</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
