<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35604486</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>23</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1749-0774</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>May</Month>
              <Day>23</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Human cell</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Hum Cell</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Novel acetylation-related gene signatures for predicting the prognosis of patients with colorectal cancer.</ArticleTitle>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1007/s13577-022-00720-6</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>Histone acetylation may affect the tumorigenesis and prognosis of colorectal cancer (CRC). However, there is still a lack of studies exploring the effect of acetylation-related genes on the prognosis of CRC. To explore the role of acetylation-related genes in CRC prognosis using bioinformatics strategies, the expression data and survival information of CRC patients were collected from the Gene Expression Omnibus. The Molecular Signatures Database was used to select acetylation-related genes. Univariate and least absolute shrinkage and selection operator regression analyses were used to screen prognostic genes. Kaplan-Meier curves were plotted for survival analysis. Cibersort and pRRophetics were used to analyze immune infiltration and predict drug sensitivity, respectively. By implementing independent prognostic factors, a nomogram model was constructed. The result showed that a total of 48 prognostic genes which screened from the acetylation-related gene set were mainly enriched in ABC transporters and acetylation/deacetylation-related pathways. Three gene signatures (SDR16C5, MEAF6, and SOX4) were further defined, and a prognostic model was constructed that showed high sensitivity and specificity for predicting CRC prognosis in both training and validation cohorts. Patients with different prognostic risks also presented differential expression of gene signatures, infiltration of activated CD4 memory T cells, and drug sensitivity to bicalutamide, gefitinib, Lenalidomide, and imatinib. The nomogram suggested the potential of a risk score-based model in predicting 1- and 2-year survival in patients with CRC. In conclusion, we proposed three gene signatures from an acetylation-related gene set as potential targets for epigenetic therapy and constructed a prognostic model for CRC.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022. The Author(s) under exclusive licence to Japan Human Cell Society.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y">
            <LastName>Jing</LastName>
            <ForeName>Zhuang</ForeName>
            <Initials>Z</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Oncology, Huzhou Central Hospital, Affiliated Central Hospital Huzhou University, No.1558, Sanhuan North Road, Wuxing District, Huzhou, 313000, Zhejiangs, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y" EqualContrib="Y">
            <LastName>Ziwang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Feng</ForeName>
            <Initials>F</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Cardiothoracic Surgery, Yi Xing People's Hospital, No.75, Tongzhenguan Road, Yixing, Jiangsu, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yinhang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Wu</ForeName>
            <Initials>W</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Graduate School of Second Clinical Medicine Faculty, Zhejiang Chinese Medical University, No. 548 Binwen Road, Binjiang District, Hangzhou, 310053, Zhejiang, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yani</LastName>
            <ForeName>Zhou</ForeName>
            <Initials>Z</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Graduate School of Medical College, Zhejiang University, No.268 Kaixuan RoadJianggan District, Hangzhou, 310029, Zhejiang, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Jian</LastName>
            <ForeName>Chu</ForeName>
            <Initials>C</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Graduate School of Second Clinical Medicine Faculty, Zhejiang Chinese Medical University, No. 548 Binwen Road, Binjiang District, Hangzhou, 310053, Zhejiang, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Jingwen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Wu</ForeName>
            <Initials>W</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Graduate School of Nursing, Huzhou University, No. 1 Bachelor Road, Huzhou, Zhejiang, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Shuwen</LastName>
            <ForeName>Han</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Department of Oncology, Huzhou Central Hospital, Affiliated Central Hospital Huzhou University, No.1558, Sanhuan North Road, Wuxing District, Huzhou, 313000, Zhejiangs, China. shuwenhan985@163.com.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>05</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <Country>Japan</Country>
        <MedlineTA>Hum Cell</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8912329</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0914-7470</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Acetylation</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Colorectal cancer</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Immune infiltration</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Prognosis</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>4</Month>
          <Day>5</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
          <Hour>11</Hour>
          <Minute>16</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35604486</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13577-022-00720-6</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">10.1007/s13577-022-00720-6</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bray F, Ferlay J, Soerjomataram I, Siegel RL, Torre LA, Jemal A. Erratum: Global cancer statistics 2018: GLOBOCAN estimates of incidence and mortality worldwide for 36 cancers in 185 countries. CA Cancer J Clin. 2020;70(4):313.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Issa IA, Noureddine M. Colorectal cancer screening: an updated review of the available options. World J Gastroenterol. 2017;23(28):5086–96.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28811705</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5537177</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3748/wjg.v23.i28.5086</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Picard E, Verschoor CP, Ma GW, Pawelec G. Relationships between immune landscapes, genetic subtypes and responses to immunotherapy in colorectal cancer. Front Immunol. 2020;11:369.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32210966</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">7068608</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2020.00369</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Van Cutsem E, Cervantes A, Adam R, Sobrero A, Van Krieken JH, Aderka D, Aranda Aguilar E, Bardelli A, Benson A, Bodoky G, et al. ESMO consensus guidelines for the management of patients with metastatic colorectal cancer. Ann Oncol. 2016;27(8):1386–422.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27380959</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/annonc/mdw235</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Johdi NA, Sukor NF. Colorectal cancer immunotherapy: options and strategies. Front Immunol. 2020;11:1624.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33042104</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">7530194</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fimmu.2020.01624</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jung G, Hernández-Illán E, Moreira L, Balaguer F, Goel A. Epigenetics of colorectal cancer: biomarker and therapeutic potential. Nat Rev Gastroenterol Hepatol. 2020;17(2):111–30.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31900466</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">7228650</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41575-019-0230-y</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gayon J. From mendel to epigenetics: history of genetics. CR Biol. 2016;339(7–8):225–30.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.crvi.2016.05.009</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Baretti M, Azad NS. The role of epigenetic therapies in colorectal cancer. Curr Probl Cancer. 2018;42(6):530–47.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29625794</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.currproblcancer.2018.03.001</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Raskov H, Søby JH, Troelsen J, Bojesen RD, Gögenur I. Driver gene mutations and epigenetics in colorectal cancer. Ann Surg. 2020;271(1):75–85.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31188207</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1097/SLA.0000000000003393</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Danese E, Montagnana M. Epigenetics of colorectal cancer: emerging circulating diagnostic and prognostic biomarkers. Ann Trans Med. 2017;5(13):279.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.21037/atm.2017.04.45</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Liu N, Li S, Wu N, Cho KS. Acetylation and deacetylation in cancer stem-like cells. Oncotarget. 2017;8(51):89315–25.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29179522</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5687692</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.18632/oncotarget.19167</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bultman SJ. Interplay between diet, gut microbiota, epigenetic events, and colorectal cancer. Mol Nutr Food Res. 2017;61(1):1500902.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/mnfr.201500902</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>O’Hagan HM. Chromatin modifications during repair of environmental exposure-induced DNA damage: a potential mechanism for stable epigenetic alterations. Environ Mol Mutagen. 2014;55(3):278–91.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24259318</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/em.21830</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Karczmarski J, Rubel T, Paziewska A, Mikula M, Bujko M, Kober P, Dadlez M, Ostrowski J. Histone H3 lysine 27 acetylation is altered in colon cancer. Clin Proteomics. 2014;11(1):24.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24994966</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4071346</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/1559-0275-11-24</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ashktorab H, Belgrave K, Hosseinkhah F, Brim H, Nouraie M, Takkikto M, Hewitt S, Lee EL, Dashwood RH, Smoot D. Global histone H4 acetylation and HDAC2 expression in colon adenoma and carcinoma. Dig Dis Sci. 2009;54(10):2109–17.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19057998</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10620-008-0601-7</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Benard A, Goossens-Beumer IJ, van Hoesel AQ, Horati H, de Graaf W, Putter H, Zeestraten EC, Liefers GJ, van de Velde CJ, Kuppen PJ. Nuclear expression of histone deacetylases and their histone modifications predicts clinical outcome in colorectal cancer. Histopathology. 2015;66(2):270–82.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25307864</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1111/his.12534</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Salek Farrokhi A, Mohammadlou M, Abdollahi M, Eslami M. Histone deacetylase modifications by probiotics in colorectal cancer. J Gastrointest Cancer. 2020;51(3):754–64.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31808058</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s12029-019-00338-2</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Biswas S, Reddy ND. Evaluation of novel 3-hydroxyflavone analogues as HDAC inhibitors against colorectal cancer. Adv Pharmacol Sci. 2018;2018:1–14.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Niinuma T, Kitajima H, Kai M, Yamamoto E, Yorozu A, Ishiguro K, Sasaki H, Sudo G, Toyota M, Hatahira T, et al. UHRF1 depletion and HDAC inhibition reactivate epigenetically silenced genes in colorectal cancer cells. Clin Epigenet. 2019;11(1):70.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s13148-019-0668-3</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li X, Zhang Y, Jiang Y, Wu J, Inks ES, Chou CJ, Gao S, Hou J, Ding Q, Li J, et al. Selective HDAC inhibitors with potent oral activity against leukemia and colorectal cancer: design, structure-activity relationship and anti-tumor activity study. Eur J Med Chem. 2017;134:185–206.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28415009</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5994920</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ejmech.2017.03.069</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Anantharaju PG, Reddy BD, Padukudru MA, Kumari Chitturi CM, Vimalambike MG. Madhunapantula SV (2017) naturally occurring benzoic acid derivatives retard cancer cell growth by inhibiting histone deacetylases (HDAC). Cancer Biol Ther. 2017;18(7):492–504.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28506198</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5639858</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1080/15384047.2017.1324374</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ritchie ME, Phipson B, Wu D, Hu Y, Law CW, Shi W, Smyth GK. limma powers differential expression analyses for RNA-sequencing and microarray studies. Nucleic Acids Res. 2015;43(7): e47.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25605792</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4402510</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gkv007</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Team RC: R: A Language and Environment for Statistical Computing. R Foundation for Statistical Computing, Vienna. 2020. http://www.rproject.org .</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pohar M, Stare J. Relative survival analysis in R. Comput Methods Programs Biomed. 2006;81(3):272–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">16510208</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cmpb.2006.01.004</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhou Y, Zhou B, Pache L, Chang M. Metascape provides a biologist-oriented resource for the analysis of systems-level datasets. Nat Commun. 2019;10(1):1523.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30944313</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6447622</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/s41467-019-09234-6</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Franceschini A, Szklarczyk D, Frankild S, Kuhn M, Simonovic M, Roth A, Lin J, Minguez P, Bork P, von Mering C, et al. STRING v9.1: protein-protein interaction networks, with increased coverage and integration. Nucleic Acids Res. 2013;41:808–15.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1093/nar/gks1094</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang S, Su W, Zhong C, Yang T, Chen W, Chen G, Liu Z, Wu K, Zhong W, Li B, et al. An eight-CircRNA assessment model for predicting biochemical recurrence in prostate cancer. Front Cell Dev Biol. 2020;8: 599494.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33363156</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">7758402</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.3389/fcell.2020.599494</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chen B, Khodadoust MS, Liu CL, Newman AM, Alizadeh AA. Profiling tumor infiltrating immune cells with CIBERSORT. Methods Mol Biol. 2018;1711:243–59.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29344893</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5895181</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-1-4939-7493-1_12</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Geeleher P, Cox N, Huang RS. pRRophetic: an R package for prediction of clinical chemotherapeutic response from tumor gene expression levels. PLoS One. 2014;9(9): e107468.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25229481</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">4167990</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0107468</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Subramanian A, Narayan R, Corsello SM, Peck DD, Natoli TE, Lu X, Gould J, Davis JF, Tubelli AA, Asiedu JK, et al. A next generation connectivity map: L1000 platform and the first 1,000,000 profiles. Cell. 2017;171(6):1437-1452.e1417.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">29195078</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">5990023</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2017.10.049</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dekker E, Tanis PJ, Vleugels JLA, Kasi PM, Wallace MB. Colorectal cancer. Lancet. 2019;394(10207):1467–80.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31631858</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/S0140-6736(19)32319-0</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rezapour S, Hosseinzadeh E, Marofi F, Hassanzadeh A. Epigenetic-based therapy for colorectal cancer: prospect and involved mechanisms. J Cell Physiol. 2019;234(11):19366–83.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31020647</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1002/jcp.28658</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vaish V, Khare T, Verma M, Khare S. Epigenetic therapy for colorectal cancer. Methods Mol Biol. 2015;1238:771–82.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25421691</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/978-1-4939-1804-1_40</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shi B, Xu FF, Xiang CP, Jia R, Yan CH, Ma SQ, Wang N, Wang AJ, Fan P. Effect of sodium butyrate on ABC transporters in lung cancer A549 and colorectal cancer HCT116 cells. Oncol Lett. 2020;20(5):148.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32934716</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">7471751</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang W, Yang J, Edin ML, Wang Y, Luo Y, Wan D, Yang H, Song CQ, Xue W, Sanidad KZ, et al. Targeted metabolomics identifies the cytochrome P450 monooxygenase eicosanoid pathway as a novel therapeutic target of colon tumorigenesis. Cancer Res. 2019;79(8):1822–30.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30803995</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6467714</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/0008-5472.CAN-18-3221</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wang B, Li Y, Tan F, Xiao Z. Increased expression of SOX4 is associated with colorectal cancer progression. Tumour Biol. 2016;37(7):9131–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">26768610</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s13277-015-4756-5</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhao J, Xu J, Zhang R. MicroRNA-539 inhibits colorectal cancer progression by directly targeting SOX4. Oncol Lett. 2018;16(2):2693–700.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30013665</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">6036556</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huang YW, Liu JC, Deatherage DE, Luo J, Mutch DG, Goodfellow PJ, Miller DS, Huang TH. Epigenetic repression of microRNA-129-2 leads to overexpression of SOX4 oncogene in endometrial cancer. Can Res. 2009;69(23):9038–46.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1158/0008-5472.CAN-09-1499</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lan R, Wang Q. Deciphering structure, function and mechanism of lysine acetyltransferase HBO1 in protein acetylation, transcription regulation, DNA replication and its oncogenic properties in cancer. Cell Mol Life Sci. 2020;77(4):637–49.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31535175</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s00018-019-03296-x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Micci F, Gorunova L, Gatius S, Matias-Guiu X, Davidson B, Heim S, Panagopoulos I. MEAF6/PHF1 is a recurrent gene fusion in endometrial stromal sarcoma. Cancer Lett. 2014;347(1):75–8.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24530230</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.canlet.2014.01.030</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matsuura K, Tani N, Usuki S, Torikai-Nishikawa S, Okano M, Niwa H. MEAF6 is essential for cell proliferation and plays a role in the assembly of KAT7 complexes. Exp Cell Res. 2020;396(1): 112279.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32918898</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.yexcr.2020.112279</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jin K, Ren C, Liu Y, Lan H, Wang Z. An update on colorectal cancer microenvironment, epigenetic and immunotherapy. Int Immunopharmacol. 2020;89(Pt A): 107041.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33045561</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.intimp.2020.107041</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Feng M, Zhao Z, Yang M, Ji J, Zhu D. T-cell-based immunotherapy in colorectal cancer. Cancer Lett. 2021;498:201–9.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33129958</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.canlet.2020.10.040</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yang X, Wu W, Pan Y, Zhou Q, Xu J, Han S. Immune-related genes in tumor-specific CD4(+) and CD8(+) T cells in colon cancer. BMC Cancer. 2020;20(1):585.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">32571262</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">7310260</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1186/s12885-020-07075-x</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Saito T, Nishikawa H, Wada H, Nagano Y, Sugiyama D, Atarashi K, Maeda Y, Hamaguchi M, Ohkura N, Sato E, et al. Two FOXP3(+)CD4(+) T cell subpopulations distinctly control the prognosis of colorectal cancers. Nat Med. 2016;22(6):679–84.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27111280</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1038/nm.4086</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kroemer M, Turco C, Spehner L, Viot J, Idirène I, Bouard A, Renaude E, Deschamps M, Godet Y, Adotévi O, et al. Investigation of the prognostic value of CD4 T cell subsets expanded from tumor-infiltrating lymphocytes of colorectal cancer liver metastases. J Immunother Cancer. 2020;8(2):e001478.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33229508</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">7684804</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1136/jitc-2020-001478</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Grimm D, Bauer J, Wise P, Krüger M, Simonsen U, Wehland M, Infanger M, Corydon TJ. The role of SOX family members in solid tumours and metastasis. Semin Cancer Biol. 2020;67(Pt 1):122–53.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30914279</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.semcancer.2019.03.004</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hanieh H, Ahmed EA, Vishnubalaji R, Alajez NM. SOX4: Epigenetic regulation and role in tumorigenesis. Semin Cancer Biol. 2020;67(Pt 1):91–104.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">31271889</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.semcancer.2019.06.022</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bagati A, Kumar S, Jiang P, Pyrdol J, Zou AE, Godicelj A, Mathewson ND, Cartwright ANR, Cejas P, Brown M, et al. Integrin αvβ6-TGFβ-SOX4 pathway drives immune evasion in triple-negative breast cancer. Cancer Cell. 2021;39(1):54-67.e59.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33385331</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ccell.2020.12.001</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huang JL, Wang XK, Liao XW, Han CY, Yu TD, Huang KT, Yang CK, Liu XG, Yu L, Zhu GZ, et al. SOX4 as biomarker in hepatitis B virus-associated hepatocellular carcinoma. J Cancer. 2021;12(12):3486–500.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33995626</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">8120190</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.7150/jca.46579</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sinner D, Kordich JJ, Spence JR, Opoka R, Rankin S, Lin SC, Jonatan D, Zorn AM, Wells JM. Sox17 and Sox4 differentially regulate beta-catenin/T-cell factor activity and proliferation of colon carcinoma cells. Mol Cell Biol. 2007;27(22):7802–15.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17875931</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">2169141</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1128/MCB.02179-06</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Good CR, Aznar MA, Kuramitsu S, Samareh P, Agarwal S, Donahue G, Ishiyama K, Wellhausen N, Rennels AK, Ma Y, et al. An NK-like CAR T cell transition in CAR T cell dysfunction. Cell. 2021;184(25):6081-6100.e6026.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34861191</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cell.2021.11.016</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Newman DM, Voss AK, Thomas T, Allan RS. Essential role for the histone acetyltransferase KAT7 in T cell development, fitness, and survival. J Leukoc Biol. 2017;101(4):887–92.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27733580</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1189/jlb.1MA0816-338R</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Adams MK, Lee SA, Belyaeva OV, Wu L, Kedishvili NY. Characterization of human short chain dehydrogenase/reductase SDR16C family members related to retinol dehydrogenase 10. Chem Biol Interact. 2017;276:88–94.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27793605</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cbi.2016.10.019</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Belyaeva OV, Chang C, Berlett MC, Kedishvili NY. Evolutionary origins of retinoid active short-chain dehydrogenases/reductases of SDR16C family. Chem Biol Interact. 2015;234:135–43.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25451586</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cbi.2014.10.026</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lee SA, Belyaeva OV, Kedishvili NY. Biochemical characterization of human epidermal retinol dehydrogenase 2. Chem Biol Interact. 2009;178(1–3):182–7.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18926804</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.cbi.2008.09.019</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
