<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">35600556</PMID>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>05</Month>
        <Day>24</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Electronic-eCollection">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">2405-6383</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
            <Volume>9</Volume>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>2022</Year>
              <Month>Jun</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Animal nutrition (Zhongguo xu mu shou yi xue hui)</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Anim Nutr</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Tracing enterococci persistence along a pork production chain from feed to food in China.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>223</StartPage>
          <EndPage>232</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>223-232</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.aninu.2022.01.005</ELocationID>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>The prevalence and transmission of vancomycin-resistant <i>Enterococcus</i> (VRE) in enterococci being as probiotics has been neglected in the scientific literature. The application of enterococci in feed, food and health products may cause VRE transmission through the food chain. This study evaluated phenotypic resistance of <i>Enterococcus</i> species to 20 antibiotics along a pork production chain from feed to food. It also assessed the genetic diversity of <i>Enterococcus faecium</i> isolates. A total of 510 samples (feed, <i>n</i> = 70; swine manure, <i>n</i> = 400; swine carcasses, <i>n</i> = 20, and retail pork, <i>n</i> = 20) were collected in Beijing, China. A total of 328 enterococci isolates with 275 <i>E. faecium</i> and 53 <i>Enterococcus faecalis</i> were identified using 16 S rRNA. Antimicrobial susceptibility to all enterococci isolates was conducted using the K-B method for 20 antibiotics from 9 categories. Multilocus sequence typing (MLST) was conducted on the <i>E. faecium</i> isolates to survey the dissemination of enterococci in the pig industry. The results showed that only 26 enterococci isolates were sensitive to the 20 antibiotics, while half of the isolates (164/328) had acquired multi-drug resistance. The resistant rate to furazolidone was 68.60%, followed by 42.99% to tetracycline. One vancomycin-resistant <i>E. faecium</i> isolates were isolated from feed origin and 2 from manure origin, with minimum inhibitory concentrations to vancomycin of 1,024, 64, and 64 μg/mL, respectively. The MLST outcomes showed that the 275 <i>E. faecium</i> isolates belonged to 11 sequence types (ST) including ST40, ST60, ST94, ST160, ST178, ST296, ST361, ST695, ST726, ST812 and ST1014. The ST of the feed-sourced VRE was ST1014, while the 2 manure-sourced VRE was ST69. ST1014 evolved from ST78, which was the dominant clonal complex in most cities of China, leading to the spreading of VRE. These findings revealed the potential safety hazards of commercial probiotic enterococci in China and showed that there is a risk of the VRE horizontally transferring from feed to food.</AbstractText>
          <CopyrightInformation>© 2022 Chinese Association of Animal Science and Veterinary Medicine. Publishing services by Elsevier B.V. on behalf of KeAi Communications Co. Ltd.</CopyrightInformation>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Zhao</LastName>
            <ForeName>Jianfei</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>College of Animal Science and Technology, Northwest Agriculture &amp; Forestry University, Yangling, 712100, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Liu</LastName>
            <ForeName>Rui</ForeName>
            <Initials>R</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>College of Animal Science and Technology, Northwest Agriculture &amp; Forestry University, Yangling, 712100, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Sun</LastName>
            <ForeName>Yanpeng</ForeName>
            <Initials>Y</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>College of Animal Science and Technology, Northwest Agriculture &amp; Forestry University, Yangling, 712100, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yang</LastName>
            <ForeName>Xiaojun</ForeName>
            <Initials>X</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>College of Animal Science and Technology, Northwest Agriculture &amp; Forestry University, Yangling, 712100, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Yao</LastName>
            <ForeName>Junhu</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>College of Animal Science and Technology, Northwest Agriculture &amp; Forestry University, Yangling, 712100, China.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
        <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>02</Month>
          <Day>05</Day>
        </ArticleDate>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Anim Nutr</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>101717655</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>2405-6383</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Antimicrobial resistance</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Multilocus sequence typing</Keyword>
        <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Vancomycin-resistant enterococci</Keyword>
      </KeywordList>
      <CoiStatement>We declare that we have no financial and personal relationships with other people or organizations that can inappropriately influence our work, and there is no professional or other personal interest of any nature or kind in any product, service and/or company that could be construed as influencing the content of this paper.</CoiStatement>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>8</Month>
          <Day>7</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
          <Year>2021</Year>
          <Month>11</Month>
          <Day>12</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>1</Month>
          <Day>30</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>23</Day>
          <Hour>3</Hour>
          <Minute>55</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>2022</Year>
          <Month>5</Month>
          <Day>24</Day>
          <Hour>6</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>epublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">35600556</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC9092396</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.aninu.2022.01.005</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">S2405-6545(22)00021-X</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Arias C.A., Murray B.E. The rise of the Enterococcus: beyond vancomycin resistance. Nat Rev Microbiol. 2012;10(4):266–278.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3621121</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">22421879</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Founou L.L., Founou R.C., Essack S.Y. Antibiotic resistance in the food chain: a developing country-perspective. Front Microbiol. 2016;7:1881.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC5120092</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">27933044</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hammerum A.M., Baig S., Kamel Y., Roer L., Pinholt M., Gumpert H., et al.  Emergence of vanA Enterococcus faecium in Denmark, 2005–15. J Antimicrob Chemother. 2017;72(8):2184–2190.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28541565</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hu C.J., Xing W.G., Liu X.H., Zhang X.Z., Li K., Liu J., et al.  Effects of dietary supplementation of probiotic Enterococcus faecium on growth performance and gut microbiota in weaned piglets. Amb Express. 2019;9(1):1–12.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6318158</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30607514</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Jahan M., Zhanel G.G., Sparling R., Holley A.R. Horizontal transfer of antibiotic resistance from Enterococcus faecium of fermented meat origin to clinical isolates of E. faecium and Enterococcus faecalis. Int J Food Microbiol. 2015;199:78–85.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25647243</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Klare I., Heier H., Claus H., Reissbrodt R., Witte W. vanA-mediated high-level glycopeptide resistance in Enterococcus faecium from animal husbandry. FEMS (Fed Eur Microbiol Soc) Microbiol Lett. 1995;125(2–3):165–171.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lei C.W., Chen X., Liu S.Y., LiT, Chen Y.P., Wang H.N. Clonal spread and horizontal transfer mediate dissemination of phenicol-oxazolidinone-tetracycline resistance gene poxtA in enterococci isolates from a swine farm in China. Vet Microbiol. 2021;262:109219.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">34500344</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li N.  Chinese Agricultural University; Beijing: 2019. The contamination and dissemination mechanism of the vancomycin-resistant gene vanA during pig industry chain; p. 6. Dissertation/doctor’s thesis.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li N., Yu H.T., Liu H.B., Wang Y.M., Zhou J.Y., Ma X., et al.  Horizontal transfer of vanA between probiotic Enterococcus faecium and Enterococcus faecalis in fermented soybean meal and in digestive tract of growing pigs. J Anim Sci Biotechnol. 2019;10(1):1–11.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6330741</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30651985</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mallo M., Wellik D., Deschamps J. Hox genes and regional patterning of the vertebrate body plan. Dev Biol. 2010;344(1):7–15.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2909379</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">20435029</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matsumoto H., Miyagawa M., Yin Y., Oosumi T. Effects of organic acid, Enterococcus faecalis strain EC-12 and sugar cane extract in feed against enterotoxigenic Escherichia coli-induced diarrhea in pigs. AMB Express. 2021;11(1):1–10.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC7778674</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">33389203</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miller W.R., Munita J.M., Arias C.A. Mechanisms of antibiotic resistance in enterococci. Expert Rev Anti-infect Ther. 2014;12(10):1221–1236.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC4433168</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">25199988</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Perreten V., Schwarz F., Cresta L., Boeglin M., Dasen G., Teuber M. Antibiotic resistance spread in food. Nature. 1997;389(6653):801–802.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Terkuran M., Turhan E.Ü., Erginkaya Z.  Springer; Cham: 2019. The risk of vancomycin resistant enterococci infections from food industry//Health and Safety Aspects of Food Processing Technologies; pp. 513–535.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thacker P.A. Alternatives to antibiotics as growth promoters for use in swine production: a review. J Anim Sci Biotechnol. 2013;4(1):1–12.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3623743</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23289727</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Weigel L.M., Clewell D.B., Gill S.R., Clark N.C., McDougal L.K., Flannagan S.E., et al.  Genetic analysis of a high-level vancomycin-resistant isolate of Staphylococcus aureus. Science. 2003;302(5650):1569–1571.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14645850</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Werner G., Coque T.M., Hammerum A.M., Hope R., Hryniewicz W., Johnson A., et al.  Emergence and spread of vancomycin resistance among enterococci in Europe. Euro Surveill. 2008;13(47):19046.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">19021959</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yan J.G., Dong C.Z., Zhao G.M., Zhou W.L., Sun X., Wang Y.L. Drug resistance genes in vancomycin resistant Enterococcus faecium and MLST genotyping. Chin J Nosocomio. 2016;26:92–4097.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Yu H.T., Ding X.L., Shang L.J., Zeng X.F., Liu H.B., Li N., et al.  Protective ability of biogenic antimicrobial peptide microcin J25 against enterotoxigenic Escherichia coli-induced intestinal epithelial dysfunction and inflammatory responses IPEC-J2 cells. Front Cell Infect Microbiol. 2018;8:242.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6053529</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">30057893</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zeyner A., Boldt E. Enterococcus faecium strain supplemented from birth to weaning on diarrhoea patterns and performance of piglets. J Animal Physiol Animal Nutr. 2006;90(1–2):25–31.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Zhu Y.G., Johnson T.A., Su J.Q., Qiao M., Guo G., Stedtfeld R.D. Diverse and abundant antibiotic resistance genes in Chinese swine farms[J] Proc Natl Acad Sci Unit States Am. 2013;110(9):3435–3440.</Citation>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
