<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">8008190</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>1994</Year>
        <Month>07</Month>
        <Day>21</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2019</Year>
        <Month>07</Month>
        <Day>12</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">0306-4522</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>59</Volume>
            <Issue>2</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>1994</Year>
              <Month>Mar</Month>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>Neuroscience</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>Neuroscience</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Synchronization of area CA3 hippocampal pyramidal cells and non-granule cells of the dentate gyrus in bicuculline-treated rat hippocampal slices.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>245</StartPage>
          <EndPage>257</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>245-57</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>A recent study has described synchronous burst discharges of dentate hilar neurons and area CA3 pyramidal cells in the presence of the convulsants 4-aminopyridine and picrotoxin in guinea-pig hippocampal slices [Müller W. and Misgeld U. (1991) J. Neurophysiol. 65, 141-147]. To examine the synchronous activity of dentate cells and area CA3 pyramidal cells further, epileptiform burst discharges were examined in morphologically and/or electrophysiologically identified non-granule cells in the hilus and granule cell layer of the rat dentate gyrus and compared to simultaneously-recorded pyramidal cells of area CA3a, b, and c. Specifically, the types of dentate cells and the types of discharge were examined, as well as the timing of burst discharge of dentate cells relative to different cells of area CA3. In the presence of the GABAA receptor antagonist bicuculline (30 microM), all dentate cell types discharged in rhythmic, spontaneous bursts that were synchronized with area CA3 pyramidal cell epileptiform bursts. The sampled cells included hilar "mossy" cells, hilar fast-spiking cells (putative interneurons) as well as interneurons located in the granule cell layer, such as the pyramidal "basket" cells. Simultaneous recording from dentate non-granule cells and area CA3 pyramidal cells during exposure to bicuculline demonstrated that stimulus-evoked and spontaneous epileptiform bursts occurred almost exactly at the same time; there were only a few milliseconds between the onsets of pyramidal cell bursts and dentate cell bursts, with the pyramidal cell preceding the dentate cell in almost every case. There were no systematic differences among dentate cell types in the extent they lagged behind pyramidal cells, and there were no detectable differences among area CA3 pyramidal cells. In slices that were cut between area CA3 and the dentate gyrus, epileptiform bursts occurred in area CA3 but not in the dentate. These findings suggest that, in the absence of GABAA receptor-mediated inhibition, excitatory pathways from area CA3 to the dentate gyrus are strong and widespread. These pathways, and possibly other mechanisms, can lead to tightly synchronized action potential discharge of pyramidal cells and dentate non-granule cells. The results also suggest that disinhibition alone is insufficient to cause synchronous bursts in the dentate gyrus, in contrast to area CA3.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Scharfman</LastName>
            <ForeName>H E</ForeName>
            <Initials>HE</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Neurology Research Center, Helen Hayes Hospital, West Haverstraw, NY 10993-1195.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <GrantList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>R01 NS038285-04</GrantID>
            <Acronym>NS</Acronym>
            <Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
        </GrantList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>Neuroscience</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>7605074</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0306-4522</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <ChemicalList>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>40709-69-1</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="C017069">bicuculline methiodide</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
        <Chemical>
          <RegistryNumber>Y37615DVKC</RegistryNumber>
          <NameOfSubstance UI="D001640">Bicuculline</NameOfSubstance>
        </Chemical>
      </ChemicalList>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000200" MajorTopicYN="N">Action Potentials</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001640" MajorTopicYN="N">Bicuculline</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000031" MajorTopicYN="Y">analogs &amp; derivatives</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000494" MajorTopicYN="N">pharmacology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004558" MajorTopicYN="N">Electric Stimulation</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D004827" MajorTopicYN="N">Epilepsy</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000503" MajorTopicYN="N">physiopathology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005071" MajorTopicYN="N">Evoked Potentials</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D005260" MajorTopicYN="N">Female</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D006624" MajorTopicYN="N">Hippocampus</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D066298" MajorTopicYN="N">In Vitro Techniques</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008564" MajorTopicYN="N">Membrane Potentials</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017966" MajorTopicYN="N">Pyramidal Cells</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000187" MajorTopicYN="N">drug effects</QualifierName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D051381" MajorTopicYN="N">Rats</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017207" MajorTopicYN="N">Rats, Sprague-Dawley</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013997" MajorTopicYN="N">Time Factors</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>1994</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>1994</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
          <Hour>0</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>1994</Year>
          <Month>3</Month>
          <Day>1</Day>
          <Hour>0</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8008190</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="mid">NIHMS355574</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3286025</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/0306-4522(94)90593-2</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pii">0306-4522(94)90593-2</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Amaral DG. A Golgi study of cell types in the hilar region of the hippocampus in the rat. J. comp. Neurol. 1978;182:851–914.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">730852</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Dingledine R, Gjerstad L. Reduced inhibition during epileptiform activity in the in vitro hippocampal slice. J. Physiol. 1980;305:297–313.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1282973</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7441555</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Frotscher M, Seress L, Schwerdtfeger WK, Buhl EH. The mossy cells of the fascia dentata: a comparative study of their fine structure and synaptic connections in rodents and primates. J. comp. Neurol. 1990;312:145–163.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1744242</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hablitz JJ. Picrotoxin-induced epileptiform activity in hippocampus: role of endogenous versus synaptic factors. J. Neurophysiol. 1984;51:1011–1027.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6327932</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ishizuka N, Weber J, Amaral DG. Organization of intrahippocampal projections originating from CA3 pyramidal cells in the rat. J. comp. Neurol. 1990;295:580–623.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2358523</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kawaguchi Y, Hama K. Fast-spiking non-pyramidal cells in the hippocampal CA3 region, dentate gyrus, and subiculum of rats. Brain Res. 1987a;425:351–355.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3427435</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kosaka T. Neuronal gap junctions in the polymorph layer of the rat dentate gyrus. Brain Res. 1983;277:347–351.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6640301</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kunkel DD, Lacaille J-C, Schwartzkroin PA. Ultrastructure of stratum lacunosum moleculare interneurons of hippocampal CA1 region. Synapse. 1988;2:382–394.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3187908</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lacaille J-C, Kunkel DD, Schwartzkroin PA.  Electrophysiological and morphological characterization of hippocampal interneurons. In: Chan-Palay V, Köhler C, editors. The Hippocampus–New Vistas. New York: Alan R. Liss; 1989. pp. 285–303.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Li X-G, Tepper JM, Jandó G, Buzsáki G. Axon arborization of CA3 pyramidal cells in vivo: an intracellular labelling study. Soc. Neurosci. Abstr. 1992;18:320.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matsumoto H, Ajmone-Marsan C. Cortical cellular phenomena in experimental epilepsy: ictal manifestations. Expl Neurol. 1964;9:305–326.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14142796</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Matsumoto H, Ajmone-Marsan C. Cortical cellular phenomena in experimental epilepsy: interictal manifestations. Expl Neurol. 1964;9:286–304.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">14145629</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Michelson HB, Wong RKS. Excitatory synaptic responses mediated by GABAA receptors in the hippocampus. Science. 1991;253:1420–1423.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1654594</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Miles R, Wong RKS. Excitatory synaptic interactions between CA3 neurons in the guinea pig hippocampus. J. Physiol. 1986;373:397–418.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC1182545</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3018233</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Müller W, Misgeld U. Picrotoxin- and 4-aminopyridine-induced activity in hilar neurons in the guinea-pig hippocampal slice. J. Neurophysiol. 1991;65:141–147.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1999728</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ribak CE, Seress L. Five types of basket cell in the hippocampal dentate gyrus: a combined Golgi and electron microscopic study. J. Neurocytol. 1983;12:577–597.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6619905</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ribak CE, Seress L, Amaral DG. The development, ultrastructure, and synaptic connections of the mossy cells of the dentate gyrus. J. Neurocytol. 1985;14:835–857.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2419523</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scharfman HE.  Differentiation of rat dentate neurons by morphology and electrophysiology in hippocampal slices: granule cells, spiny hilar cells and aspiny “fast-spiking” cells. In: Ribak CE, Gall C, Mody I, editors. The Dentate Gyrus and its Role in Seizures. Amsterdam: Elsevier; 1992. pp. 93–108.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC3281805</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1361334</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Scharfman HE, Kunkel DD, Schwartzkroin PA. Synaptic connections of dentate granule cells and hilar neurons: results of paired intracellular recordings and intracellular horseradish peroxidase injections. Neuroscience. 1990;37:693–701.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2247219</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schwartzkroin PA, Mathers L. Physiological and morphological identification of a nonpyramidal hippocampal cell type. Brain Res. 1978;157:1–10.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">568020</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Schwerdtfeger WK, Sarvey JM. Connectivity of the hilar region of the hippocampal formation in the rat. J. Hirnforsch. 1983;24:201–207.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6886390</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Soriano E, Nitsch R, Frotscher M. Axo-axonic chandelier cells in the rat fascia dentata: Golgi-electron microscopy and immunocytochemical studies. J. comp. Neurol. 1990;293:1–25.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1690225</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swann JW, Brady RJ, Friedman RJ, Smith KJ. The dendritic origins of penicillin-induced epileptogenesis in CA3 hippocampal pyramidal cells. J. Neurophysiol. 1986;56:1718–1738.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3027274</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Swanson LW, Wyss JM, Cowan WM. An autoradiographic study of the organization of intrahippocampal association pathways in the rat. J. comp. Neurol. 1978;181:681–716.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">690280</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wong RKS, Traub RD. Synchronized burst discharge in disinhibited hippocampal slice I. Initiation in CA2–CA3 region. J. Neurophysiol. 1983;49:442–458.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6300343</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
