<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
  <PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
      <PMID Version="1">9870957</PMID>
      <DateCompleted>
        <Year>1999</Year>
        <Month>02</Month>
        <Day>05</Day>
      </DateCompleted>
      <DateRevised>
        <Year>2022</Year>
        <Month>04</Month>
        <Day>08</Day>
      </DateRevised>
      <Article PubModel="Print">
        <Journal>
          <ISSN IssnType="Print">0270-6474</ISSN>
          <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
            <Volume>19</Volume>
            <Issue>1</Issue>
            <PubDate>
              <Year>1999</Year>
              <Month>Jan</Month>
              <Day>01</Day>
            </PubDate>
          </JournalIssue>
          <Title>The Journal of neuroscience : the official journal of the Society for Neuroscience</Title>
          <ISOAbbreviation>J Neurosci</ISOAbbreviation>
        </Journal>
        <ArticleTitle>Oscillatory coupling of hippocampal pyramidal cells and interneurons in the behaving Rat.</ArticleTitle>
        <Pagination>
          <StartPage>274</StartPage>
          <EndPage>287</EndPage>
          <MedlinePgn>274-87</MedlinePgn>
        </Pagination>
        <Abstract>
          <AbstractText>We examined whether excitation and inhibition are balanced in hippocampal cortical networks. Extracellular field and single-unit activity were recorded by multiple tetrodes and multisite silicon probes to reveal the timing of the activity of hippocampal CA1 pyramidal cells and classes of interneurons during theta waves and sharp wave burst (SPW)-associated field ripples. The somatic and dendritic inhibition of pyramidal cells was deduced from the activity of interneurons in the pyramidal layer [int(p)] and in the alveus and st. oriens [int(a/o)], respectively. Int(p) and int(a/o) discharged an average of 60 and 20 degrees before the population discharge of pyramidal cells during the theta cycle, respectively. SPW ripples were associated with a 2.5-fold net increase of excitation. The discharge frequency of int(a/o) increased, decreased ("anti-SPW" cells), or did not change ("SPW-independent" cells) during SPW, suggesting that not all interneurons are innervated by pyramidal cells. Int(p) either fired together with (unimodal cells) or both before and after (bimodal cells) the pyramidal cell burst. During fast-ripple oscillation, the activity of interneurons in both the int(p) and int(a/o) groups lagged the maximum discharge probability of pyramidal neurons by 1-2 msec. Network state changes, as reflected by field activity, covaried with changes in the spike train dynamics of single cells and their interactions. Summed activity of parallel-recorded interneurons, but not of pyramidal cells, reliably predicted theta cycles, whereas the reverse was true for the ripple cycles of SPWs. We suggest that network-driven excitability changes provide temporal windows of opportunity for single pyramidal cells to suppress, enable, or facilitate selective synaptic inputs.</AbstractText>
        </Abstract>
        <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Csicsvari</LastName>
            <ForeName>J</ForeName>
            <Initials>J</Initials>
            <AffiliationInfo>
              <Affiliation>Center for Molecular and Behavioral Neuroscience, Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey, Newark, New Jersey 07102, USA.</Affiliation>
            </AffiliationInfo>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Hirase</LastName>
            <ForeName>H</ForeName>
            <Initials>H</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Czurkó</LastName>
            <ForeName>A</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Mamiya</LastName>
            <ForeName>A</ForeName>
            <Initials>A</Initials>
          </Author>
          <Author ValidYN="Y">
            <LastName>Buzsáki</LastName>
            <ForeName>G</ForeName>
            <Initials>G</Initials>
          </Author>
        </AuthorList>
        <Language>eng</Language>
        <GrantList CompleteYN="Y">
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>1P41RR09754</GrantID>
            <Acronym>RR</Acronym>
            <Agency>NCRR NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>MH54671</GrantID>
            <Acronym>MH</Acronym>
            <Agency>NIMH NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
          <Grant>
            <GrantID>NS34994</GrantID>
            <Acronym>NS</Acronym>
            <Agency>NINDS NIH HHS</Agency>
            <Country>United States</Country>
          </Grant>
        </GrantList>
        <PublicationTypeList>
          <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013485">Research Support, Non-U.S. Gov't</PublicationType>
          <PublicationType UI="D013487">Research Support, U.S. Gov't, P.H.S.</PublicationType>
        </PublicationTypeList>
      </Article>
      <MedlineJournalInfo>
        <MedlineTA>J Neurosci</MedlineTA>
        <NlmUniqueID>8102140</NlmUniqueID>
        <ISSNLinking>0270-6474</ISSNLinking>
      </MedlineJournalInfo>
      <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
      <MeshHeadingList>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D001522" MajorTopicYN="N">Behavior, Animal</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D007395" MajorTopicYN="N">Interneurons</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D016014" MajorTopicYN="N">Linear Models</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D008297" MajorTopicYN="N">Male</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009415" MajorTopicYN="N">Nerve Net</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D009991" MajorTopicYN="N">Oscillometry</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D017966" MajorTopicYN="N">Pyramidal Cells</DescriptorName>
          <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="Y">physiology</QualifierName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D051381" MajorTopicYN="N">Rats</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
        <MeshHeading>
          <DescriptorName UI="D013826" MajorTopicYN="N">Theta Rhythm</DescriptorName>
        </MeshHeading>
      </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
      <History>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
          <Year>1998</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>31</Day>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
          <Year>1998</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>31</Day>
          <Hour>0</Hour>
          <Minute>1</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
        <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
          <Year>1998</Year>
          <Month>12</Month>
          <Day>31</Day>
          <Hour>0</Hour>
          <Minute>0</Minute>
        </PubMedPubDate>
      </History>
      <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
      <ArticleIdList>
        <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9870957</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6782375</ArticleId>
        <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1523/JNEUROSCI.19-01-00274.1999</ArticleId>
      </ArticleIdList>
      <ReferenceList>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abeles M.  Local cortical circuits: an electrophysiological study. Springer; Berlin: 1982. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Abeles M, Goldstein MH. Multispike train analysis. Proc IEEE. 1977;65:762–773.</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ali AB, Deuchars J, Pawelzi H, Thomson A. CA1 pyramidal to basket and bistratified EPSPs: dual intracellular recordings in rat hippocampal slices. J Physiol (Lond) 1998;507:201–217.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC2230771</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9490840</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bair W, Koch C. Temporal precision of spike trains in extrastriate cortex of the behaving macaque monkey. Neural Comput. 1996;8:1185–1202.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8768391</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bankman IN, Johnson KO, Schneide W. Optimal detection, classification, and superposition resolution in neural waveform recordings. IEEE Trans Biomed Eng. 1993;40:836–841.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8258452</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Barlow HB. Single units and sensation: a neuron doctrine for perceptual psychology? Perception. 1972;1:371–394.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4377168</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bland BH. The physiology and pharmacology of hippocampal formation theta rhythms. Prog Neurobiol. 1986;26:1–54.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2870537</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bland BH, Colom LV. Preliminary observations on the physiology and pharmacology of hippocampal theta-off cells. Brain Res. 1989;505:333–336.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2598053</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Blasco-Ibanez JM, Freund TF. Synaptic input of horizontal interneurons in stratum oriens of the hippocampal CA1 subfield: structural basis of feed-back activation. Eur J Neurosci. 1995;7:2170–2180.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8542073</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bragin A, Jando G, Nadasdy Z, Hetke J, Wise K, Buzsaki G. Gamma (40–100 Hz) oscillation in the hippocampus of the behaving rat. J Neurosci. 1995;15:47–60.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6578273</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7823151</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Bragin A, Csicsvari J, Penttonen M, Buzsaki G. Epileptic afterdischarge in the hippocampal-entorhinal system: current source density and unit studies. Neuroscience. 1997;76:1187–1203.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9027878</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Buhl EH, Halasy K, Somogyi P. Diverse sources of hippocampal unitary inhibitory postsynaptic potentials and the number of synaptic release sites. Nature. 1994;368:823–828.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8159242</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Buhl EH, Szilagyi T, Halasy K, Somogyi P. Physiological properties of anatomically identified basket and bistratified cells in the CA1 area of the rat hippocampus in vitro. Hippocampus. 1996;6:294–305.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8841828</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Buzsaki G. Two-stage model of memory trace formation: a role for “noisy” brain states. Neuroscience. 1989;31:551–570.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2687720</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Buzsaki G, Chrobak JJ. Temporal structure in spatially organized neuronal ensembles: a role for interneuronal networks. Curr Opin Neurobiol. 1995;5:504–510.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7488853</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Buzsaki G, Grastyan E, Czopf J, Kellenyi L, Prohaska O. Changes in neuronal transmission in the rat hippocampus during behavior. Brain Res. 1981;225:235–247.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6272929</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Buzsaki G, Leung LW, Vanderwolf CH. Cellular bases of hippocampal EEG in the behaving rat. Brain Res. 1983;287:139–171.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">6357356</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Buzsaki G, Horvath Z, Urioste R, Hetke J, Wise K. High-frequency network oscillation in the hippocampus. Science. 1992;256:1025–1027.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1589772</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Buzsaki G, Penttonen M, Nadasdy Z, Bragin A. Pattern and inhibition-dependent invasion of pyramidal cell dendrites by fast spikes in the hippocampus in vivo. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 1996;93:9921–9925.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC38530</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8790432</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chrobak JJ, Buzsaki G. Selective activation of deep layer (V–VI) retrohippocampal cortical neurons during hippocampal sharp waves in the behaving rat. J Neurosci. 1994;14:6160–6170.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6576977</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7931570</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Chrobak JJ, Buzsaki G. High-frequency oscillations in the output networks of the hippocampal–entorhinal axis of the freely behaving rat. J Neurosci. 1996;16:3056–3066.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6579047</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8622135</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Csicsvari J, Hirase H, Czurko A, Buzsaki G. Reliability and state-dependence of pyramidal cell-interneuron synapses in the hippocampus: an ensemble approach in the behaving rat. Neuron. 1998;21:179–189.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9697862</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Czurko A, Hirase H, Csicsvari J, Buzsaki G (1999) Sustained activation of hippocampal pyramidal cells by “space clamping” in a running wheel. Eur J Neurosci, in press.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9987037</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Draguhn A, Traub RD, Schmitz D, Jefferys JG. Electrical coupling underlies high-frequency oscillations in the hippocampus in vitro. Nature. 1998;394:189–192.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9671303</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fee MS, Mitra PP, Kleinfeld D. Automatic sorting of multiple unit neuronal signals in the presence of anisotropic and non-Gaussian variability. J Neurosci Methods. 1996;69:175–188.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8946321</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fox SE, Ranck JB., Jr Electrophysiological characteristics of hippocampal complex-spike cells and theta cells. Exp Brain Res. 1981;41:399–410.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7215500</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Fox SE, Wolfson S, Ranck JB., Jr Hippocampal theta rhythm and the firing of neurons in walking and urethane anesthetized rats. Exp Brain Res. 1986;62:495–508.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3720881</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Freund TF, Buzsaki G. Interneurons of the hippocampus. Hippocampus. 1996;6:347–470.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8915675</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gray CM, Singer W. Stimulus-specific neuronal oscillations in orientation columns of cat visual cortex. Proc Natl Acad Sci USA. 1989;86:1698–1702.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC286768</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2922407</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Gray CM, Maldonado PE, Wilson M, McNaughton B. Tetrodes markedly improve the reliability and yield of multiple single-unit isolation from multi-unit recordings in cat striate cortex. J Neurosci Methods. 1995;63:43–54.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8788047</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Green JD, Arduini AA. Hippocampal electrical activity in arousal. J Neurophysiol. 1954;17:533–557.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">13212425</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Hopfield JJ. Pattern recognition computation using action potential timing for stimulus representation. Nature. 1995;376:33–36.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7596429</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Huerta PT, Lisman JE. Bidirectional synaptic plasticity induced by a single burst during cholinergic theta oscillation in CA1 in vitro. Neuron. 1995;15:1053–1063.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7576649</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kamondi A, Acsady L, Buzsaki G. Dendritic spikes are enhanced by cooperative network activity in the intact hippocampus. J Neurosci. 1998a;18:3919–3928.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6793142</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9570819</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Kamondi A, Acsády L, Wang XJ, Buzsáki G. Theta oscillations in somata and dendrites of hippocampal pyramidal cells in vivo: activity dependent phase-precession of action potentials. Hippocampus. 1998b;8:244–261.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9662139</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Katsumaru H, Kosaka T, Heizmann CW, Hama K. Gap junctions on GABAergic neurons containing the calcium-binding protein parvalbumin in the rat hippocampus (CA1 region). Exp Brain Res. 1988;72:363–370.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3066635</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lacaille JC, Mueller AL, Kunkel DD, Schwartzkroin PA. Local circuit interactions between alveus/oriens interneurons and CA1 pyramidal cells in hippocampal slices: electrophysiology and morphology. J Neurosci. 1987;7:1979–1993.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6568928</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3612227</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Lisman JE, Idiart MA. Storage of 7 ± 2 short-term memories in oscillatory subcycles. Science. 1995;267:1512–1515.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7878473</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>McMahon LL, Williams JH, Kauer JA. Functionally distinct groups of interneurons identified during rhythmic carbachol oscillations in hippocampus in vitro. J Neurosci. 1998;18:5640–5651.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6793057</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9671655</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Mizumori SJ, Barnes CA, McNaughton BL. Behavioral correlates of theta-on and theta-off cells recorded from hippocampal formation of mature young and aged rats. Exp Brain Res. 1990;80:365–373.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2358049</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>O’Keefe J, Dostrovsky J. The hippocampus as a spatial map. Preliminary evidence from unit activity in the freely-moving rat. Brain Res. 1971;34:171–175.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">5124915</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>O’Keefe J, Recce ML. Phase relationship between hippocampal place units and the EEG theta rhythm. Hippocampus. 1993;3:317–330.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8353611</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Parra P, Gulyas AI, Miles R. How many subtypes of inhibitory cells in the hippocampus. Neuron. 1998;20:983–993.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9620702</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Pavlides C, Greenstein YJ, Grudman M, Winson J. Long-term potentiation in the dentate gyrus is induced preferentially on the positive phase of theta-rhythm. Brain Res. 1988;439:383–387.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">3359196</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Press WH, Teukolsky SA, Vettering WT, Flannery BP.  Numerical recipes in C: the art of scientific computing, Ed 2. Cambridge UP; Cambridge, MA: 1992. </Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ranck JB., Jr Studies on single neurons in dorsal hippocampal formation and septum in unrestrained rats. I. Behavioral correlates and firing repertoires. Exp Neurol. 1973;41:461–531.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4355646</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>
Recce ML, O’Keefe J.
1989. The tetrode: a new technique for multiunit extracellular recording. Soc Neurosci Abstr</Citation>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Rudell AP, Fox SE, Ranck JB., Jr Hippocampal excitability phase-locked to the theta rhythm in walking rats. Exp Neurol. 1980;68:87–96.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7363990</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Shadlen MN, Newsome WT. The variable discharge of cortical neurons: implications for connectivity, computation, and information coding. J Neurosci. 1998;18:3870–3896.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6793166</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9570816</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sik A, Ylinen A, Penttonen M, Buzsaki G. Inhibitory CA1-CA3-hilar region feedback in the hippocampus. Science. 1994;265:1722–1724.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8085161</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Sik A, Penttonen M, Ylinen A, Buzsaki G. Hippocampal CA1 interneurons: an in vivo intracellular labeling study. J Neurosci. 1995;15:6651–6665.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6577981</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7472426</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Skaggs WE, McNaughton BL, Wilson MA, Barnes CA. Theta phase precession in hippocampal neuronal populations and the compression of temporal sequences. Hippocampus. 1996;6:149–172.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8797016</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Softky WR, Koch C. The highly irregular firing of cortical cells is inconsistent with temporal integration of random EPSPs. J Neurosci. 1993;13:334–360.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6576320</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8423479</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Spruston N, Jaffe DB, Williams SH, Johnston D. Voltage- and space-clamp errors associated with the measurement of electrotonically remote synaptic events. J Neurophysiol. 1993;70:781–802.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8410172</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Stewart M, Fox SE. Do septal neurons pace the hippocampal theta rhythm? Trends Neurosci. 1990;13:163–168.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">1693232</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Thompson LT, Best PJ. Place cells and silent cells in the hippocampus of freely-behaving rats. J Neurosci. 1989;9:2382–2390.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6569761</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">2746333</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Tsubokawa H, Ross WN. IPSPs modulate spike backpropagation and associated [Ca2+]i changes in the dendrites of hippocampal CA1 pyramidal neurons. J Neurophysiol. 1996;76:2896–2906.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8930242</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Vanderwolf CH. Hippocampal electrical activity and voluntary movement in the rat. Electroencephalogr Clin Neurophysiol. 1969;26:407–418.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4183562</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wilson MA, McNaughton BL. Dynamics of the hippocampal ensemble code for space. Science. 1993;261:1055–1058.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8351520</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Wilson MA, McNaughton BL. Reactivation of hippocampal ensemble memories during sleep. Science. 1994;265:676–679.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">8036517</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Winson J. Patterns of hippocampal theta rhythm in the freely moving rat. Electroencephalogr Clin Neurophysiol. 1974;36:291–301.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">4130608</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ylinen A, Bragin A, Nadasdy Z, Jando G, Szabo I, Sik A, Buzsaki G. Sharp wave-associated high-frequency oscillation (200 Hz) in the intact hippocampus: network and intracellular mechanisms. J Neurosci. 1995a;15:30–46.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pmc">PMC6578299</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7823136</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
        <Reference>
          <Citation>Ylinen A, Soltesz I, Bragin A, Penttonen M, Sik A, Buzsaki G. Intracellular correlates of hippocampal theta rhythm in identified pyramidal cells, granule cells and basket cells. Hippocampus. 1995b;5:78–90.</Citation>
          <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">7787949</ArticleId>
          </ArticleIdList>
        </Reference>
      </ReferenceList>
    </PubmedData>
  </PubmedArticle>
</PubmedArticleSet>
